<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/242</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-03-09T01:36:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Survey of Mosquitoes on Lake Houston and surrounding Houston Areas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hanson, Maci</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">After a move from a suburb in the Houston area to Lake Houston (Northeast of downtown Houston), it was observed that the mosquitoes during the summer seemed to be much more prominent on Lake Houston than previously in the suburb. This noticeable difference triggered the question of what types of mosquitoes preferred what kinds of locations and why. To understand and evaluate this question, a survey of various mosquito types across the Houston metropolitan areas was performed. Traps were set up in five cities of different environments, mainly varying in their proximity to specific environmental differences (i.e. lakes, woody areas, downtown etc.) Mosquitoes were collected over a weekend in April, a month reported to have one of the highest rates of mosquitoes present (Nava, 2016). Through research, it was determined that the most prevalent mosquito types in all of the Houston area were Culex species, Anopheles species and Aedes species. Each of this mosquito types have been reported in high numbers during the late Spring and Summer months in all of Houston, but there is little data on how each type is distributed in each area. Through the research, it was hypothesized that Anopheles species would be most prevalent in areas near water and was upheld by the data from the experiment. Knowing this information about the prevalence of certain types of mosquitoes in each area can better help create a mechanism for trapping in each place. Each types of mosquitoes are drawn to various things, for instance, Anopheles prefer to stay on standing water and knowing these preferences can be applied to a better prevention (Mosquito World). With the rise of many serious mosquito transmitted diseases like Zika and West Nile, knowing specifically what mosquitoes are in which area are helpful to each community in protecting themselves from these threats that are associated with each mosquito type. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/242</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/242/248</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
