<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/18</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-08T21:24:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Alternative IPM Methods for Varroa destructor (Parasitiformes: Varroidae) (Anderson and Trueman) Mite Control in East Texas apiaries</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martinez, Alejandro</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The parasitic mite Varroa destructor (Anderson and Trueman) is a major pest of the honey bee (Apis mellifera (L.)), because large quantities of the mites can cause colony collapse disorder. Over the last two decades, prophylactic treatment of V. destructor using pyrethroid and organophosphate chemicals has caused increased resistance, requiring higher maintenance and treatment costs for beekeepers. This study examines the therapeutic effects of three different IPM methods for the control of V. destructor in two apiaries in East Texas. 24 colonies were separated into four different groups: untreated control colonies, colonies in which the queens were caged, colonies treated with powdered sugar using the “Dustructor” apparatus (Brushy Mountain Bee Farm, Moravian Falls, NC), or colonies treated with thymol (active ingredient ApiLife Var® (Mann Lake Ltd., Hackensack, MN)).  V. destructor populations in each colony were monitored for 54 days using the powdered sugar shake method or via a sticky board hung up for 24-hours.  Powdered sugar shake mite counts reflected lower populations of V. destructor in all colonies treated with any of the three IPM methods compared to those of the untreated controls.  Conversely, sticky board mite counts showed no statistical difference in mite counts based on IPM treatments compared to untreated controls.  These results suggest that the powdered sugar shake method is more accurate when monitoring V. destructor populations than the 24-hour sticky board method. Alternative IPM methods for V. destructor control are effective and serve as a promising new avenue for non-intrusive control of this major honey bee pest.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-04-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/18</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 1 (2014): Instars: A Journal of Undergraduate Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/18/37</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
