<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/746</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effects of White Distilled Vinegar and Bleach on the Individual Characteristics of Shoe Soles</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sellers, Gwendolyn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">White distilled vinegar and bleach are two common cleaning products employed in the deep cleaning of household surfaces and objects. Many use these substances to wipe down commonly shared surfaces of germs and grime due to their cleaning strength. A similarity in these two substances is their proficiency in removing blood and blood stains from objects and clothing, being commonly utilized for this task. Therefore, if a crime scene had large amounts of blood, it could be concluded that white distilled vinegar and bleach could be likely useful in high quantities to clean the scene properly. Individual characteristics within shoe prints can be caused by wear and tear on the shoe sole, often made of rubber and other materials. It is generally advised to dilute white distilled vinegar and bleach for use in cleaning rubber household items due to the deterioration and weakening the two substances often cause within rubbers. White distilled vinegar due to its acidic nature, acetic acid, and bleach, sodium hypochlorite, as a caustic cleaner. It is often that shoe prints are employed as proof of a person’s presence at the crime scene. However, this could be pushed further if shoe prints could be used as evidence to link a person to activities that occurred within the crime scene as well, specifically cleaning. With this information, it can be concluded that extended contact of shoe soles with white distilled vinegar and bleach will cause distinct individual characteristics on the soles that can be viewed when shoe printing.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/746</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/746/275</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Gwendolyn Sellers</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
