<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/937</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Investigating the Impact of Common Drugs (Caffeine, Advil, and Benadryl) on Tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) Detection</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wijethunga, Malshi</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Forensic science covers numerous distinct areas of specialization. One of these is drug detection, in which investigators test for drugs in human fluid samples such as urine, blood etc. Some commonly used medications and substances can affect the accuracy of drug detection. THC (Tetrahydrocannabinol) is one of the main psychoactive compounds in cannabis. This study focused on the impact of caffeine, Advil, and Benadryl on THC detection. In this study, a lemonade drink with THC (THC lemonade), 0.14 mg of THC in 10 mL of lemonade, was used as a reference fluid sample instead of human bodily fluids. The observed results showed that there is no impact of caffeine until 400 mg is dissolved in 10 mL of THC lemonade. An extremely high concentration of caffeine (600 mg of caffeine in 10 mL of THC lemonade) is required to show negative THC detection results. Whereas lower concentrations of both Advil (10 mg), and Benadryl (25) mg in 10 mL of THC lemonade are enough to show negative THC results. Further experiments need to be done to determine the lowest amounts of Advil and Benadryl required for the negative test results.  These results showed that Advil and Benadryl have a higher impact on the detection of THC compared to caffeine.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/937</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/937/283</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Malshi Wijethunga</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
