<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/677</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Accuracy of Eyewitness Testimonies After Viewing a Staged Assault</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Espinoza, Fernando</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Eyewitness testimonies attempt to show an objective, third party perspective of crimes and crime scenes during court hearings. Judges and juries wait with bated breath to hear the retelling of the events through eyes who do not care who is innocent nor who is guilty. The thin line between the real and the staged leads to incorrect retelling of stories, better yet, the innocent being incarcerated for years to come. Eyewitness statements are not always reliable, there are far too many inconsistencies when put next to the actual situations at hand. Both the verbiage and timing of questioning is crucial to how bystanders and victims recall their information, especially when questioned by tens, if not hundreds of highly respected individuals. Not to mention, lawyers and attorneys pressuring their clients to recall information that does not quite exactly exist. In this study, we ask participants to sit through a staged assault, taking a mental note of every important detail. Then, we ask them to recall the people’s sex, race, demeanor, and even their outfits to get a general idea of the perpetrator. Some participants recalled the entirety of the situation, a few only recalled a small amount, and some did not remember a single detail. Some questioned were formulated in a way to bait participants into straying away from what occurred in their video. Lastly, the study shows that participants were quick to remember the perpetrators race and implemented some of their personal biases into the mix when asked for questions and statements from those proctoring the questions.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/677</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/677/269</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Fernando Espinoza</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
