<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/803</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Food Attraction in Two Domestic Populations of Young Blaptica Dubia (Blattodea: Blaberidae) (Serville, 1838)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stout, Kiley</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Blaptica dubia (Blattodea: Blaberidae), or the dubia roach, has become a popular feeder insect for reptiles and amphibians because of their easy care and high protein content. Despite the captive dubia roach growing in numbers, research on this insect is sparse. This study aimed to fill a knowledge gap on the subject of the preference of dubia roach nymphs under a month of age and to compare possible differences between two population samples from different dubia roach companies. One population was derived from Dubia Roach Depot (population A), and one from the All About Feeders (population B). Two plastic bins were placed with cat food (control), banana, and cheese for a protein, carb, and fat, respectively, for each of seven trials, and feeding visitations were counted over an hour to determine attraction. The results provided no significant differences in the food attraction within each population or between the populations. These results could be important for understanding the generalist behavior of the Blaptica dubia and how this topic can apply in insect production and pest management industries.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/803</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/803/256</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Kiley Stout</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
