<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/110</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T17:29:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Comparison of Longevity Between Sexes of Cochliomyia macellaria (Fabricius) (Diptera: Calliphoridae)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Holmes, Valerie Renee</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Comprehension of the lifecycle and life expectancy of Cochliomyia homnivorax (Diptera: Calliphoridae) and Cochliomyia macellaria (Diptera: Calliphoridae), the primary and secondary screwworm, respectively have historically been of the utmost concern to researchers in medical, livestock and entomological research fields. As a notoriously detrimental agricultural pest, C. homnivorax has been strictly monitored for decades since its eradication in the United States, and the less dangerous Cochliomyia macellaria has taken the place of C. macellaria for research purposes given that the two species share markedly similar life histories. In order to develop a thorough compilation of data regarding the primary screwworm, life history must be assessed extensively. This being said, this experiment was designed to determine lifespan differences between the sexes of C. macellaria, and results obtained showed no significant difference between the lifespans of males and females when exposed to laboratory conditions. Given this information, researchers can logically deduce that similar lifespans between the sexes are most conducive to maximized efficiency of C. macellaria, and potentially C. homnivorax.Keywords: Cochliomyia macellaria, myiasis, Cochliomyia homnivorax, longevity, life history  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/110</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 3 (2017): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/110/91</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
