<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/367</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-28T04:18:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of Funnel Cone Traps with Different Baits for Capturing Nuisance Arthropods in College Station, Texas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Williams, Kenesha</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ali, Anisah</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zandy, Clare</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The intent of this study was to test the effectiveness of small funnel traps in attracting and killing nuisance arthropods such as various species of flies, ants, and cockroaches in College Station, Texas. A total number of 6 plastic funnel traps were placed across the campus of Texas A&amp;amp;M University, in five different locations. Three of the units had blue cones and three had glow cones and three different baits were used. Traps were set for 36 hours between checking and trapping was conducted from March 27 to April 28, 2018. Insects were overall more attracted to the molasses bait most likely due to its high sugar content and sweet smell. Among all the insects collected, the most common were ants were Brachymyrmex patagonicus (rover ant) followed by Solenopsis invicta (red imported fire ant). Among all the nuisance arthropods collected, this was the first report of Nylanderia fulva (tawny crazy ant) being present on the campus of Texas A&amp;amp;M University (Lebrun, et al 2017). </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/367</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 1 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/367/167</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Kenesha Williams</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
