<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/38</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T16:08:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Survey of Insect Species Associated with Dog Parks in College Station, Texas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Eilers, Autumn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">For a span of 4 weeks between March and April of 2015, insect traps were set up in 3 different parks identified as “canine stations” or “dog parks” by the City of College Station Parks and Recreation Department. The aim of this study was to survey and collect all insect species in the area, and then evaluate them by level of veterinary importance. Homemade traps were filled with brown sugar, water, and yeast; the insects were collected and sugar yeast mixture refilled 3 times a week.   10 species were collected, of the orders Diptera, Coleoptera, Lepidoptera, and Hymenoptera. The most dominant insect collected was the Drosophila spp. at 141 of the 175 specimens. No species were found that pose a direct threat toward canines or their outdoor areas. It is important to understand that these findings could have been due to the safety of the area or the use of inefficient traps. A survey of the different insects collected were recorded for the three locations in the specific region. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/38</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 2 (2015): Instars: A Journal of Undergraduate Research Vol. 2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/38/62</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
