<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/54</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T16:08:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Prevalence of Anaplasma (A.) Genus in Rhipicephalus sanguineus (L.) (Acari: Ixodidae) Found in Shelter</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cano, Frida Nohemi</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Animal shelters are known for being an excellent place for various diseases to be transmitted among dogs, since there is a large volume of animals enclosed in a relative small space. Rhipicephalus sanguineus (L.) (Acari: Ixodidae) commonly known as the brown dog tick is unusual among ticks, because it can complete its entire life cycle inside making it the perfect vector for diseases. In this study we looked at the prevalence of one of the main vector borne disease in the dog population of Texas, anaplasma. Three hundred and nine ticks used for the experiment were collected from six shelters around Texas. This ticks were identified to species. Three hundred and eight were identified to be Rhipicephalus sanguineus, only one Dermacentor Variabilis (S.) (Acari: Ixodidae)  was collected. DNA was extracted from 90 ticks; the DNA was analyzed using polymerase chain reactions (PCR). Positive samples were sent to a gene bank for sequencing.  Eleven samples came back as positive for Anaplasma genus. We concluded that the prevelansce of anaplasma might be much higher than previously expected and that more studies have to be conducted on the subject. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/54</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 2 (2015): Instars: A Journal of Undergraduate Research Vol. 2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/54/63</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
