<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/932</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Determining Which Household Chemical is Most Effective in Decomposing Raw Chicken Thighs Over a Two Week Period</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Eleanor Bond</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In crime scenes, humans will often choose chemicals to try and accelerate the process of decomposition. With this question posed, the purpose of this experiment is to determine which household chemicals are most effective in decomposing raw chicken thighs. In considering which chemicals to choose, three criteria were established. First, a wide range of acids and bases were selected to reflect the spectrum of the pH scale. Second, the chemicals must be easy to access or purchase without raising suspicion. Lastly, the household chemicals must be inexpensive to obtain. For the acids tested, 3% hydrogen peroxide, 5% vinegar, and Lysol toilet bowl cleaner were chosen. To test the basic efficacy, Clorox bleach, Drano, and dairy lime were selected. A single piece of raw, boneless chicken thigh was placed in a glass jar and then covered with the individual chemical. The duration of the entire experiment was fourteen days. To measure the changes in both the solution and chicken, pH paper was used to assess the chemical changes. Additionally, the physical changes of the meat were examined for decomposition. Data was collected on day one, seven and fourteen. The information collected was the pH levels of the meat and solution, odor, buoyancy, and consistency of the muscle fibers. After fourteen days, this data was analyzed to determine what was most effective. On the fourteenth day, it was concluded that the most effective household chemical was Lysol toilet bowl cleaner. This highly acidic solution lowered the pH of the meat the most, significantly degraded the consistency of the muscle fibers, and concealed the odor of decomposition the best. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/932</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/932/268</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Eleanor Bond</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
