<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/309</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-03-09T01:36:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparison of Culicidae Present in Phytotelmata versus Stream Pools at Springfield Station in Dominica, West Indies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomas, Anchal</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brundage, Adrienne</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wooley, James</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Mosquito borne diseases are proliferating all around the world. Mosquito habitats can be categorized into temporary and standing pools, both of which influence human health. To understand the extent of their presence in Dominica, a survey of mosquitoes was conducted by observing phytotelmata (plant-held water) and pools in streams present at the Archbold Tropical Research and Education Center (ATREC) in Dominica, West Indies from May 23rd, 2017 to June 14th, 2017. To test phytotelmata and pool stream habitats, samples were collected from different water holding plants and standing pools in various areas surrounding the station. The larvae obtained from these samples were then reared and identified. Fifteen mosquitoes were reared from pool streams, and 27 mosquitoes were reared from phytotelmata. The species Aedes busckii (Diptera: Culicidae) (Coquillet) were found to be the most common in phytotelmata, and Culex quinquefasciatus (Diptera: Culicidae) (Say) were found to be the most common in pool streams. Past research suggested that Aedes busckii were the only species found in phytotelmata. However, Culex inflictus (Diptera: Culicidae) (Theobald) was also found to inhabit water-holding plants. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/309</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/309/207</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
