<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/126</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T17:29:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Survey of Odontomachus (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) and General Observations of Nesting Preferences in the Commonwealth of Dominica in the West Indies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Graf, Andrew Jordan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Odontomachus spp. were collected from various locations across the Commonwealth of Dominicain the West Indies. Specimens were collected in nest series and information about their location, elevation, nesting substrate, and co-habitation with termitidae and other formicidae were recorded. Many colonies were found to be co-habitating in terrestrial termite mounds or rotting wood along with their termitidae inhabitants. No Odontomachus sp were found in elevations higher than 1686 ft above sea level. High resolution images of each species collected were recorded. Two species were found, most prominently Odontomachus bauri (Emery), and additionally in a single sample, Odontomachusruginodis (Smith). The specimens of O. ruginodis that were collected are new records for the Commonwealth of Dominica. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/126</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 3 (2017): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/126/77</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
