<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/557</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-03-09T01:35:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Attractiveness of Commercial Baits Toward Red Imported Fire Ants Solenopsis invicta (Hymenoptera: Formicidae)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leeke, Emily</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lesne, Pierre</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Behmer, Spencer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">From causing painful stings on animals and humans alike to damaging land, the Solenopsis invicta, or Red Imported Fire Ant, is an economic burden to the United States. Insecticidal baits are often used to control these pests, each containing their own proprietary coating. Discovering which formulation of bait is most attractive to fire ants would help inform consumers to select the proper bait for their personal fire ant control. After baiting ants following the method laid out in Kaspari et al. 2008 with six different baits, it was discovered that the most attractive bait attracting the largest percentage of ants was Advion with its lipid blend. Advion was significantly more attractive than the negative control of honey. However, the Advance 375 A protein blend was also significantly more attractive than honey. The success of the Advion bait in attracting a larger percentage of fire ants over the Advance 375 A bait may be due to seasonal timing as this experiment was done in early April. Fire ants may currently be choosing nutrition with a high content of stored energy. More research should be done to see if as fire ants prepare to reproduce in later spring, they may change their foraging bait preference to Advance 375 A’s protein blend in order to support their colony’s larval development with additional protein. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/557</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/557/245</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Emily Leeke, Spencer Behmer, Pierre Lesne</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
