<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/894</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Determining Hymenoptera Preference Pairing to Color and Odor in College Station, TX</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Benavidez, Bonnie</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Colette Daulton</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Caleb French</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anjel Helms</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One third of all food production is reliant on pollination, the transfer of pollen to allow for fertilization. For this process to occur, plants use visual and olfactory cues to attract a wide variety of pollinators. The persistent decline of pollinating insects has captured the attention of the public and has catalyzed the need for research focused on the affects that the overuse of pesticides, insecticides, and climate change has on pollinators. The interconnectedness of pollinators and food production has risen in prevalence, along with the increasing risks that threaten the agricultural and ecological sectors. The attraction to the combination of colors (blue and white) and essential oils (lavender and eucalyptus) were tested to determine which combined variables resulted in a higher capture of Hymenopterans, as the order is the third most diverse pollinator and is familiar to the public. The experiment occurred at an urban site to reflect the decreasing numbers of pollinators in cityscapes. In the isolation of color and essential oil, and the summation of all captured data, there was no significant difference in the attraction of Hymenopterans. With further research, this information has the potential to open the door for examining how Hymenopterans react to artificial scents and common colors, in both isolated and paired treatments.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/894</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/894/263</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Bonnie Benavidez, Colette Daulton, Caleb French, Dr. Anjel Helms</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
