<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/649</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of estrogen levels in women compared to men in memory recall</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Haley Russell</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In everyday court proceedings, eyewitness testimony has been considered an extremely important piece of evidence. However, despite its common usage in the court of law, it has been known to be unreliable and has led to wrongful convictions in the past. Understanding the significance of differences in the memory abilities from person to person is important when attempting to use testimony in court in hopes of reaching a guilty verdict. To better understand the accuracy of one’s memory, specifically the differences between a biological male and females’ memory, recall abilities between 15 male and 15 female participants were analyzed. While memory recall was the main focus of the study, the effects of a difference in estrogen levels was also looked at in order to determine whether or not there was a correlation between memory recall and estrogen levels in different witnesses. It was assumed that the females had a higher level of estrogen than the males and therefore the females were hypothesized to perform better on the questionnaire. A week after the initial questionnaire, the participants were asked to recall specific details from a scene and the correct number of answers from each group of respondents was recorded. No significant difference between the memory recall abilities of males and the memory recall abilities of females were found. With this, no definite conclusions about the effects of the presence of estrogen in different witnesses can be made, but larger work can be done in order to determine whether or not causation is present between the two variables.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/649</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/649/264</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Haley Russell</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
