<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/465</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-28T04:18:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Examining the Preference of Sodium Concentration in the Diets of Nasutitermes corniger (Blattodea:Termitidae)(Motschulsky)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fierro Morel, Emile</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sodium is an essential element for the nervous system of many animals, including termites. This experiment tested different sodium concentrations on rotting wood blocks and cellulose in a pure, powdered state.  Nasutitermes corniger termites were collected from a nearby colony. Thirty-eight colonoids were created, which consisted of 10 soldiers and 50 workers each. Each colonoid was kept in a Petri dish with a damp filter. For the first part of the experiment, Seventy-six blocks of wood were cut into pieces of similar mass and dipped into sodium concentrations ranging from 0-10% for 10 seconds. The blocks were placed 1cm apart on the arenas and the termites were left to roam for a certain amount of time. In the second part of the experiment, sodium concentrations ranging from 2-8% were made by mixing with pure, powdered cellulose. The arenas contained all four concentrations this time. It was observed that N. corniger termites do not have a clear sodium preference, however some trends were apparent in both experiments. Further experimentation would be needed to explore these trends.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/465</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 1 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/465/185</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Emile Fierro Morel</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
