<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/629</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluating General Public Knowledge of Ticks (Acari: Ixodidae) and Tick-Borne Diseases</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Woodruff, Elise</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Abstract: Tick-borne disease is an ever-present and ever-growing threat in the United States, with Lyme disease being the most commonly diagnosed vector borne disease in the country overall. Despite this threat, recent studies have reported broad knowledge deficits in regard to tick-borne disease prevention methods even in endemic areas and with high-risk groups including those regularly working outdoors in highly tick populated areas. This study aimed to assess the level of knowledge of the general public in terms of basic tick biology, tick-borne disease, and tick bite prevention methods through the use of an anonymous, internet-based survey spread through social media as well distributed at a local high school.&amp;nbsp; The results of this survey showed broad gaps in knowledge of the surveyed population in each of the three aforementioned areas, possibly signaling the need for disease-prevention based public outreach and informational campaigns in order to better protect against tick-borne disease.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/629</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/629/260</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Elise Woodruff</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
