<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/360</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-03-09T01:35:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effects of Sorghum Volatiles and Sugarcane Aphids on Harmonia axyridis (Pallas) (Coleoptera: Coccinellidae) Attraction to Plants</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Yanez, Apuleyo</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Abstract:Coccinella septempunctata and Harmonia axyridis are incredibly effective controls for insect pests in crops. We tested their ability to use olfactory cues to choose the plant with aphids on it. We used two strains of Sorghum bicolorone being the normal susceptible strain while the second was resistant to aphids. The tests conducted were ultimately to determine which strain of sorghum the ladybeetles would favor, and whether or not the ladybeetle would prefer the plants with aphids on them. When aphids were present, no significant difference between susceptible and resistant was found, but when there were no aphids the susceptible plant attracted more predators. This could suggest that there is some kind of chemical or volatile that the susceptible plant has that the susceptible plant does not. Further study of the volatiles that the two strains produce would be necessary as well as more replicants of the two strains with no aphids. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/360</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/360/246</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Apuleyo Yanez</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
