<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/709</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of varying freezing temperatures on kill times of Periplaneta americana (L.) (Blattodea: Blattidae)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Campbell, Nash</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Periplaneta americana (L.) (Blattodea: Blattidae), commonly known as the American Cockroach, is a common pest in human habitations and structures. Though not a major vector of any pathogens, P. americana is known to carry bacterial pathogens such as Salmonella spp. (Salmon), which can become a problem in poultry houses. Salmonella spp. bacteria is regularly present in the digestive tract of poultry, and when over abundant, it can become a problem when the meat is consumed by humans. With the presence of P. americana and other Blattodea species in poultry houses, it can become difficult to manage Salmonella spp. Managing pests in the poultry industry can be strenuous and expensive, as many pesticides can be harmful to the poultry if not properly applied. The aim of this experiment was to determine effective lethal freezing temperatures of P. americana so methods of eliminating the pest may be developed using cold temperatures. Using varying temperatures, P. americana specimens were freezed and death rates were monitored over specific time periods. While freezing the cockroaches below 0˚ C resulted in high mortalities, the intensity of the freeze appeared to be the major contributor to the rate at which the specimens were killed. With this information, future P. americana control methods can be set in place not only in poultry houses, but in any infested human structure.
Keywords: Periplaneta americana, salmonella, pest, freezing, exterminate</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/709</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/709/259</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Nash Campbell</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
