<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/559</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Observations of Sugar Preferences between Solenopsis invicta, Camponotus consobrinus, and Nylanderia fulva</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Miller, Taylor</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Solenopsis invicta, Camponotus consobrinus, and Nylanderia fulva are three ant species under the family Formicidae in the order Hymenoptera. Ants are known for their strong evolutionary success, for which carbohydrates take a big role in. For this reason, ants can be a big household pest; claiming sources of food where they can find it. Specimens were collected around the Texas A&amp;amp;M campus, kept alive and housed in an ant farm and their preferences in different sugar types were recorded. Results showed that Camponotus consobrinus preferred cane sugar, Nylanderia fulva preferred all three sugars almost equally, and Solenopsis invicta preferred brown sugar. Ants’ sugar preferences differed among different species; one of the species appeared to like all types of sugar presented to them. Our study provides further analysis of ants’ attraction to divergent sugar varieties based on their species.
Keywords: Sugar preference,&amp;nbsp; Solenopsis invicta, Nylanderia fulva, Camponotus consobrinus.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/559</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/559/284</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Taylor Miller</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
