<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/498</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-03-09T01:35:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Study on The Effects of Different Chemical based and Natural Pesticides on Gryllodes sigillatus</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Menchaca, Jacob</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Russell, Alashia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bazan, Brianna</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Monty</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Land, Kyleigh</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Crickets, although not known to be direct vectors for transmitting diseases, they are considered to be a nuisance species and can affect an individual's health indirectly.The cricket Gryllodes sigillatus, also commonly known as the tropical house cricket or as the decorated cricket, is in the order of Orthoptera and family Gryllidae. Much like the cockroach and the common house fly, Gryllodes sigillatus can be found in homes and as a result, can cause problems such as fabric damage, fabric staining, food contamination, and create incessant chirping. Gryllodes sigillatus was chosen as our experimental subject species because of its common distribution around the Southern part of the US border. Our experimental study provides information on the efficiency and effects of different chemically and natural based pesticides can have on the species Gryllodes sigillatus. Specimens were observed over a set time interval in three separate trials, followed by a discussion of the benefits of using natural pesticides instead of chemically based pesticides was made based on our data. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/498</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/498/188</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
