<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/298</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-11-06T22:28:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ecological Survey of Unknown Ladybug Species (Coleoptera: Coccinellidae) in Mineola, TX</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Renfro, Andrew David</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Ladybugs are commonly used as biological control agents against aphids, and typically not found to be invasive. However, the use of these insects might have had a negative effect by creating an invasive pest, Harmonia axyridis. It was hypothesized that the species observed in the area is H. axyridis because of the coloring and circumstances surrounding the collection. It was hypothesized that, at the time of the collection, around 200 ladybug carcasses could be found inside the building. Collection took place on Thursday, March 15, 2018 between the hours of 1:00 and 2:00 PM in Co Rd 3276, Mineola, TX (32.736248, -95.341007). Specimens were collected through careful handling with tweezers, and then placed into a single container. There was an actual value of 273 specimens inside the area. Using the accuracy formula, it was discovered that the estimated value was 73.260073% accurate. It was also hypothesized that all the collected organisms would be from the same species, however with the decay of the insects (greater than 3 weeks), it was difficult to determine, but the organisms presumably all belong to H. axyridis. All the ladybugs collected were found near doors, windowsills, or window panes. It was extremely rare to discover an insect in the middle of the surveyed region, dead or alive.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/298</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 5 (2019): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/298/140</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
