<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/201</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T17:29:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluating the effects of temperature on larval Calliphora vomitoria (Diptera: Calliphoridae) consumption</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Evans, Kadeja</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aaron, Kaleigh</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The blow flies (Diptera: Calliphoridae) are responsible for more cases of myiasis than any other arthropods. Several species, including Cochliomyia hominivorax and Cocholiomya macellaria, parasitize living organisms by feeding on healthy tissues. Medical professionals have taken advantage of myiatic flies, Lucillia sericata, through debridement or maggot therapy in patients with necrotic tissue. This experiment analyzes how temperature influences blue bottle fly, Calliphora vomitoria. consumption of beef liver. After rearing an egg mass into first larval instars, ten maggots each were placed into four containers. One container was exposed to a range of temperatures between 18°C and 25°C at varying intervals. The remaining three containers were placed into homemade incubators at constant temperatures: 21°C, 27°C and 33°C. Beef liver was placed into each container and weighed after each group pupation. The mass of liver consumed and the time until pupation was recorded. Three trials revealed as temperature increased, the average rate of consumption per larva also increased. The larval group maintained at 33°C had the highest consumption with the shortest feeding duration, while the group at 21°C had lower liver consumption in the longest feeding period. The research in this experiment was conducted to understand the optimal temperature at which larval consumption is maximized whether in clinical instances for debridement or in myiasis cases.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/201</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 3 (2017): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/201/95</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
