<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/92</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-31T20:40:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Comparative Study of Larval Culicid Species at Peach Creek Equestrian Center (College Station, TX)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Crawford, Brittany Addison</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It has long been noted that mosquitos pose a substantial threat to humans not only inthe United States, but also on an international land. Deemed the most dangerous animals in theworld, the family Culicidae (Diptera) are highly potent vectors of some of the world’s mostdeadly diseases including but not limited to Malaria, Chikungunya, Dengue Fever, and YellowFever. Given the overall danger associated with these animals, the study of their populations andthe epidemic potential that they pose is of the utmost importance in global public health. Thisstudy focused on establishing a relative population comparison of the bodies of water at PeachCreek Equestrian Center, a relatively isolated ranch south of College Station, TX, and found thatthe only species discovered in three bodies of water was Psorophora sp. (Diptera, Culicidae).Key words: vector, Culicidae, public health, survey, comparison</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-01-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/92</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 4 (2018): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/92/101</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
