<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/716</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Levels of Digestion-Protease Activity in the Alimentary Canal of Schistocera serialis (Orthoptera: Acrididae) (F.)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Burciaga, Megan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">


Locusts and grasshoppers (Orthoptera: Acrididae) are insect herbivores that are eliciting catastrophic affects to the agricultural industry and economy. The control of these pests with integrated pest management strategies and pesticides is costly worldwide at an average of $70.0 billion per year. As people adapt new ways to combat insects, plants are also coevolving. A natural defense mechanism that has been employed in plants is the production of protease inhibitors (PIs). These proteolytic enzymes are found in various parts of the plants and are produced as a response from insect attack. Proteases are also found in regulated concentrations in an insect’s alimentary canal during digestion. In a plant, PIs act as anti-metabolic proteins. When insects digest plants the PI’s defensive capabilities inhibit the regulation of proteases in an insect’s alimentary canal. As a result, negatively impacting the overall growth, development, and digestion of an insect because of the reduction of amino acids. This experiment was performed to lay the foundation of the extent of protease activity in each region of the alimentary canal (foregut, midgut, and hindgut) in Schistocera serialis. The methods to achieve this objective were six treatments of boiled and non-boiled regions to ascertain protease activity in each region of the alimentary canal. It was found that the non-boiled midgut has the highest levels of protease activity, while boiling the gut regions significantly decreases protease activity. This study addresses the need for a foundation of extent of protease activity in S. serialis; however, a number of questions regarding the diversity of proteases and utilization of knowledge towards decreasing crop loss using transgenic crops with higher levels of protease inhibitors remain to be addressed.


</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/716</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/716/278</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Megan Burciaga</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
