<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/125</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T17:29:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Longevity Comparison in Necrophagous Male Flies (Diptera:Calliphoridae) (Fabricus)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gosnell, Jakalynne Diahn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Abstract: Blowflies (Diptera: Calliphoridae) are a family of much importance to the fields of forensic and medical entomology. Blowflies can find decomposing flesh within minutes and are an important species used by forensic entomologists in determining a post-mortem interval (PMI). PMI may be used to estimate a time of death for a given individual and is a very common practice in the field of forensics. This study measured the differences in longevity between adult male Chrysoma rufifacies and Cochliomyia macellaria flies. Maggots were reared in a laboratory in order to properly measure their lifespan. A t-test was done to determine a p-value for the given data. It was found that C. macellaria adult male flies (M=27.7931; SD= 10.962) experience a greater longevity than Ch. rufifacies adult male flies (M=21; SD=12.8027). This information can be applicable in determining post-mortem intervals in future forensic entomology cases and for use in secondary myiasis in medical settings. Keywords: Cochliomyia macellaria, Chrysoma rufifaces, forensic entomology, Calliphoridae longevity, post-mortem interval (PMI)</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/125</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 3 (2017): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/125/90</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
