<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/153</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T17:29:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Household Methods for Controlling Ctenocephalides felis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Verne, Meghan L</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Fleas are arthropod ectoparasites dependent on a bloodmeal from a vertebrate host at each developmental stage for the completion of their life cycle. This flea feeding cycle impacts animal health by causing damage to hides, secondary infections, immune reactions and diseases caused by transmission of pathogens (Coles &amp;amp; Dryden, 2014). The species Ctenocephalides felis is the most commonly found in the household due to the flea favoring dogs and cats for blood meals. This leads to an infestation in the house and humans as hosts unless there is an exterminator intervention. This can be costly for the average household so this paper will investigate household methods for exterminating these pests. Room A was kept as the control. Room B was tested with Diatomaceous Earth. Room C was tested with Lemon Water Spray. Room D was tested with Dawn Soap and a desk lamp. Each experimental method was tested for a total of 6 days. Room D was the most effective test. Dawn soap and a desk lamp were very effective but future studies may consider how effective the desk lamp is with other household methods. These methods were tested twice in the same apartment during two separate episodes of flea infestation.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/153</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 3 (2017): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/153/99</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
