<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/13</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-08T21:24:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effect Ethyl Alcohol has on Insect Colonization/Decomposition of Exposed Chickens Reveals Postmortem Interval Estimations May Be Influenced</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dawson, Kris</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Evans, Rebecca</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Garmley, Lauren</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lowe, Kate</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pineda, Ozzy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Postmortem Interval Estimations are made using clues from the development of colonizing insects found on the individual. Insects are drawn to these bodies by chemical cues due to decomposition of the body. Many times in the forensics, the body has been burned, or in some way altered to make estimations difficult for investigators by altering the decomposition process, or effecting the colonization rate of insects to the body. To determine the effect of ethyl alcohol on insect colonization/decomposition, decomposing chickens that were previously soaked in 200 proof ethyl alcohol were compared to decomposing control chickens that were not soaked in alcohol. Insects in the orders Diptera and Coleoptera were  collected and identified. Results from our experiment were also compared to other groups performing the same experiment in order to find further similarities or differences.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-04-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/13</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 1 (2014): Instars: A Journal of Undergraduate Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/13/45</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
