<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/386</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-11-06T22:28:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Attractiveness of Solenopsis Ants (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) to Assorted Sugars and Oils</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Whitney, Stephen Roy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Fire ants (Solenopsis spp.) are bothersome insects to both humans and the environment alike. Due to their prevalence in areas near human habitation, we sought to determine a substance that the ants find attractive that could be used in future control methods. To answer our question, we designed a simple experiment in which Solenopsis sp. specimens were each given the opportunity to choose from a variety of sugars and oils that were presented on a piece of paper in front of them. It was determined that fire ants have a stronger attraction to substances higher in fatty acids, such as cooking oils, than carbohydrates. These results have shown that when devising a home remedy for controlling these insects, individuals would have the most success if they were to use an oil-based product in their control method.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/386</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 5 (2019): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/386/148</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
