<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/821</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Impact of Field of Study on Forensic Knowledge</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Marek, Olivia</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Abstract: Forensic science is a much-needed field to society, as forensic science provides the foundation for investigations from the crime scene to the laboratory. Often, forensic science is not widely taught to the students of America, leading to misunderstandings that are conveyed from fictional television. This study was conducted to attempt to see if the field of study of college students and college graduates affects their forensic knowledge. In this study, forensic knowledge will be defined as how many questions over general forensic science knowledge can be answered correctly. These findings can be applicable in the sense that they can be used to understand to what degree a person’s major impacts how much they are aware of the investigative processes and analysis of crime scenes and evidence. To answer this question, a survey was conducted, consisting of two preliminary questions, and ten knowledge-based questions. After all the responses were recorded, the results were analyzed and compared to find that although a student’s field of study may have some degree of impact on their forensic knowledge, it may not be the only variable that should be relied upon.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/821</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/821/273</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Olivia Marek</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
