<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/173</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T17:29:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Survey of Mosquito Species Inhabiting Bryan &amp; College Station, Texas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Powell, Mason</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Mosquitoes are members of the order Diptera and the family Culicidae. They have long been known as pesterous insects; however, their role as vectors has proven an even bigger nuisance to the human race. Mosquito-borne diseases are a serious threat to the health and well-being of all human beings. The recent emergence of serious diseases such as West Nile virus, yellow fever, malaria, and Zika virus have reinforced the importance of studying mosquitoes and their distribution across environments. Researchers have spent much time and money investigating the distribution of mosquitoes worldwide. While it is commonly understood that certain species are more prevalent in particular areas of the world, the distribution of mosquitoes within smaller communities of the United States, such as Bryan/College Station (BCS), is less studied and understood. The purpose of this survey was to gain a greater understanding of how environmental factors influence the prevalence and type of mosquitoes present in the Bryan/College Station vicinity. Mosquito larvae were collected from four different locations once a month from September to November, 2016. The larvae were identified using a wet mount slide. Additionally, some larvae were allowed to develop into mature adults, subsequently killed, and analyzed for identification. Environmental conditions were noted at each collection. Mosquitoes from the genera Aedes, Psorophora, and Culex were identified with Aedes being the most prevalent. Analysis of environmental conditions showed pH had a negligible effect on larval development while water and air temperature did indeed impact larvae numbers. Furthermore, mosquito numbers were greater in populated, brushy areas with standing water. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/173</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 3 (2017): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/173/86</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
