<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/118</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T17:29:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Population Assay of Tenebrio molitor (Linnaeus) (Coleoptera: Tenebrionidae): Growth and Development Analysis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hicks, Katina Anastasia</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This experiment focuses on the growth and population development of Tenebrio molitor (Coleoptera: Tenebrionidae).  The larvae are cylindrical and hard-bodied “false worms” called mealworms.  Due to the scavenger nature of this insect, they are typically found under stones, decaying logs, bark or on the ground. However, Tenebrio molitor can be purchased though many bait shops and markets and are a common food source for pets.  Measurements of the front of head capsule to the end of abdomen and body weight were taken from larvae, pupae, and adult stages. Data was imputed into a logarithmic program on Excel where the standard deviations, variance, range and averages were determined and compared.  It appears that variation in development of T. molitor occurs from the larval to pupal stage where most of the fatalities occurred.    </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/118</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 3 (2017): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/118/87</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
