<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/670</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Attraction of Drosophila melanogaster to Wine, Vinegar, and Soda</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Angela Lubrano</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Abstract: Drosophila melanogaster is a species of fly in the order Diptera and the family Drosophilidae. It is also known as the fruit fly and it is primarily attracted to fermenting fruit. It is a common pest that many people and places have to deal with. If one were to create a trap to reduce the amount of D. melanogaster in an area that was infested, it would be important to know what would work best as bait. This experiment tested and compared the ability of three different substances to attract D. melanogaster. The three substances were red wine, vinegar, and soda. The traps were made from plastic water bottles. The experiment was conducted in a wooded backyard where the traps were placed and stayed there over the course of two days. Results showed that red wine attracted the most D. melanogaster by far. Vinegar came in at second, and the soda proved to be least effective. All three of the traps also caught organisms that were not originally intended to be caught. Red wine was concluded to be the best substance out of the three to use in a homemade fly trap.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/670</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/670/282</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Angela Lubrano</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
