<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/570</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effect of Artificial Blood Meals on Culex quinquefasciatus Fecundity in Colony</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aguirre Cordero, Erik</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Artificial membrane feeding is critical in the maintenance of mosquito colonies. Feeding artificially is said to be as effective as live feeding and has replaced most types of live feeding in laboratories for years, however there is a lack of studies supporting this. Culex quinquefasciatus (Diptera:Culicidae) is often used for experiments due to its abundance and ability to vector many medically significant diseases. To study the difference in Culex quinquefasciatus fecundity between live feeding and artificial membrane feeding separate cohorts were used. A cohort for live feeding, one for artificial feeding, and one for exsanguinated blood feeding. The fecundity and fertility of each mosquito was observed in each cohort. In this study we found that live feeding resulting in the highest mean egg per raft ratio. This is possibly due to the chemical treatment of blood with the introduction of citrate to prevent clotting. Whether the reduction in egg production is due to the ingestion of chemical or the lack of natural clotting within the mosquito is unclear and would require further research.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/570</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/570/286</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Erik Aguirre Cordero</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
