<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/306</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-11-06T22:28:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Life Table of Psyllids (Hemiptera:Triozidae) on Tomato Leaves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Acevedo, Aurora</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bactericera cockerelli is a very destructive pest that transmits Candidatus Liberibacter solanacearum (Lso). An effective strategy does not exist to control the Candidatus Liberibacter species for plant protection. The management practices that do exist practice on limiting the spread of infection. When irradiation technology has been used, it has shown a great promise to disinfest pests. It is currently not clear how eBeam dosage impacts the psyllids life cycle. This experiment focuses on the life cycle of psyllids under laboratory conditions without eBeam treatment. It is meant to set the foundation for further research at Texas A&amp;amp;M University. Seeds were germinated and transplanted at the Texas A&amp;amp;M Institute for Plant Genomics and Biotechnology. Psyllids from a colony provided were placed on tomato leaves and the developmental times of 60 psyllids were documented. The average developmental time for an egg to become an adult was 21 days. The average developmental time for each instar stage was between 3 to 4 days. Further research will be conducted by Texas A&amp;amp;M University to evaluate the effects of eBeam irradiation at various doses on psyllid growth, developmental time and reproduction.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/306</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 5 (2019): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/306/142</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
