<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/456</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-03-09T01:35:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Survey of Acari Species and the found Prevalence of Medically Relevant Ixodes sp. in College Station, Texas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Henderson, Alyssa N</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brittany Gutierrez</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Austin Hurst</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kade Keener</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Christina Larrosa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nick Richter</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Eric Smith</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Audrey Stedman</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">
Within the Acari species, there are a number of specimens known to spread diseases of medical importance. Of the two most common tick spread diseases found in Texas, Lyme disease and Rocky Mountain Spotted Fever, Lyme disease, caused by Borrelia burgdorferi,  has a higher number of incidents and therefore is the focus of the survey. This disease is known to have detrimental effects on the nervous system and heart in humans. Two species are known for being prominent vectors of Lyme disease, Ixodes scapularis, and Ixodes pacificus. Of these two ticks, I. scapularis is a common tick found in Texas and is the primary tick to identify. A survey of ticks obtained from local animal shelters was performed and 29 species were identified. I. scapularis had the highest rate of identification. Due to the high amounts of I. scapularis in the survey, actions can be taken by the community to prevent future outbreaks of Lyme Disease in the College Station and Bryan areas.
Keywords: Ticks, Lyme disease, Ixodes scapularis, disease, vector, survey
</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/456</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/456/199</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
