<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/213</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-31T20:40:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Determining Species and Sex of Chrysomya rufifacies (Macquart) and Cochliomyia macellaria (Fabricius) (Diptera: Calliphoridae) Based on Pupae Weight Difference</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Krupa, Lauren Esther</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In both the medical and forensic fields, blow flies (Diptera: Calliphoridae) play an important role as decomposers of carrion. Chrysomya rufifacies (Macquart) (Diptera: Calliphoridae) and Cochliomyia macellaria (Fabricius) (Diptera: Calliphoridae)  have both been known to be some of the first insects present in the wild on carrion and can be used to determine the Post Mortem Interval (PMI) in certain cases. The two blow flies are similar in life style and appearance; however a certain size difference in pupae of females and males was noted. Being able to determine the sex and species from the weight of the larvae would allow for scientists to tell early on and not have to wait for them to emerge as adults for this information. This experiment set to test that there was a difference in the weight of the blow fly pupae based on sex and species. Maggots were collected from the wild and the second generation of those flies was used to weigh each species. There was found to be a significant difference (P value &amp;lt; 0.0001) in the weight of Chrysomya rufifacies male (0.043339 grams) and females (0.061941 grams) when compared to those of Cochliomyia macellaria male (0.006990366 grams) and females (0.042606 grams).Key words: Sex, Maggots, carrion, weight, pupae</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-01-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/213</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 4 (2018): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/213/108</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
