<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/224</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-11-06T22:28:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparison of the longevity of Cochliomyia macellaria (Fabricus) and Chrysomya rufifacies (Macquart) adult males (Diptera:Calliphoridae)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Davila, Erika Lauren</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brundage, Adrienne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en"> Abstract: Depending on the species, males or females tend to exhibit increased longevity based on heterogametic chromosomes. While differences in longevity between males and females of a species has been extensively studied, differences in longevity between males of the same family has been minimally investigated. Longevity is crucial in understanding an insect’s physiology; it can affect developmental times and other life history traits. Cochilomyia macellaria and Chrysomya rufifacies are two Calliphoridae species that are known to cause myiasis, which is detrimental to the livestock industry. By determining the longevity of the adult C. macellaria and Ch. rufifacies males, it is possible to use the data to predetermine future myiasis outbreaks and take preventative action. Wild maggots from both species were reared and emerging male longevity was recorded. Results show that male C. macellaria adults lived an average of 27.79 ± 10.96 days, significantly longer than Ch. rufifacies adult males that lived an average of 21 ± 12.80 days (p=0.021). It is possible that the difference in longevity is due to mating; Ch. rufifacies mate sooner than C. macellaria, due to differences in female developmental time and longevity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/224</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 5 (2019): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/224/130</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
