<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/625</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Metabolization of Different Sugars by Yeast(Saccharomycetales: Saccharomycetaceae)(1865 Luis Pasteur) using Fermentation and Cellular Respiration</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perez, Jarod</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stanley, Scott</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wilgers, Skylar </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cortez, Stacey </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Energy generation within plants is performed mainly by cellular respiration and fermentation. While cellular respiration is more efficient due to its electron transport chain use, its dependence on oxygen limits the environmental conditions this system can withstand. Conversely, fermentation can be utilized without oxygen, making it almost universally available within plants. Saccharomyces cerevisiae (1865 Luis Pasteur) can be tested within various environmental conditions, making it a good test subject within environmental conditions. S. cerevisiae was tested inside two environments, one that allowed the electron transport chain to be used and one inhibiting it, forcing the yeast to use fermentation. This tested the effectiveness of fermentation and cellular respiration and visualized how vast the differences between the efficiency of the processes were. Three different sugars were also tested, and it was found that the most effective energy generation occurred with glucose during cellular respiration.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/625</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/625/261</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Jarod Perez, Scott Stanley, Skylar  Wilgers, Stacey  Cortez</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
