<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/807</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Attraction of Solenopsis invicta (Buren) (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) to Linoleic Acid in Oil</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Denson, Andie</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lesne, Pierre</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Red imported Fire Ants (Solenopsis invicta) are well known pests that can lead to ecological destruction. An important industry regarding Red Imported Fire Ants (RIFA) is how to get rid of them—this includes baits. For RIFA ant baits it is important that fire ants need to have maximum attractivity to them, so the poison can eradicate the fire ant problem. Previous research has been conducted to see what is attractive to S. invicta and it appears that certain fatty acids are attractive to them. This study aims to examine different levels of attraction of S. invicta to a variety of oils with different fatty acid levels. It was expected that oils with higher levels of linoleic acid would be the most attractive to RIFA, as that seems to be one of the more nutritional oils for them. What was observed was that there was a higher attraction to macadamia nut oil, but only with a 90% confidence interval from the least attractive oil—pistachio nut oil. What may have happened in this experiment is that there was a higher attraction rate of oils with more intense aromas instead of attraction to the fatty acids themselves.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/807</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/807/254</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Andie Denson, Pierre Lesne</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
