<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/234</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-05-07T02:13:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effect of Treated Beef Liver on Blowfly Colonization</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson, Arie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Commonly known as the predominant insects responsible for the decomposition of human remains, blowfly larvae are of medical importance to forensic and medical entomologists. In order to perform an entomological survey about the effects on blowfly colonization time and delay composition, the use of treated and untreated beef liver were expended to attract blowflies. On April 14th, 2017 at 11:30am, six mason jars with sand, 3 containing beef liver soaked in vinegar and 3 containing untreated beef liver, were set up 1 meter away from each other in a secluded area of the woods. Protected from stray animals or scavengers, the jars were left undisturbed for five days for specimen collection and then, were extracted, killed, and ready to be identified. Out of the six mason jars, two of the three treated beef liver had higher amounts of blowfly specimens collected compared to treated jars. Based on the obtained results, the hypothesis was proven wrong and the beef liver treated with vinegar actually sped up the colonization of blowflies. However, it was suspected that several variables could have skewed the results such as the weather or placement of the mason jars. We see this through the  lack of larvae in one of the treated jars, the variation of beef liver texture, and the location of maggots found within the mason jars.  Although some specimens were unidentifiable due to the size of instar maggots, the most prevalent larvae collected was Lucilia coeruleiviridis. Overall, the results of this entomological survey displayed the different species of blowflies in the Bryan/College Station area specifically during the spring semester as well as showcased the effect of treated or untreated meat source on the collection of blowflies.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-05-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/234</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 4 (2018): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>en</dc:language>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
