<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/561</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Testing the Efficiency of Four Homemade Baits for Solenopsis invicta (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) (Buren)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Meagan Sheffield</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Both store-bought and homemade baits can be used to attract and kill ants. The efficiency of four homemade baits - peanut butter, grape jelly, powdered sugar, and dish soap - for attracting Solenopsis invicta (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) (Buren) were tested by mixing 1 tsp of baking soda and 1 tsp of each bait in four covered cups. The cups were placed on a mound in Flint, TX for 15 minutes before being placed in a plastic bag and stored for at least 24 hours. Ten identical trials were conducted. The dish soap mixture attracted the highest percentage of ants (53.36 percent ± 24.058 percent), followed by the peanut butter mixture (28.12 percent ± 26.02 percent), the grape jelly mixture (11.90 percent ± 9.398 percent), and then the sugar mixture (6.62 percent ± 7.475 percent). The dish soap mixture was the most efficient in attracting S. invicta although it does not contain sugar or protein, which have been proven to act as efficient ant bait. This result may be due to the paste’s ability to trap and suffocate the ants that interacted with it and its grapefruit scent.
Keywords: Solenopsis invicta, ant, bait, homemade</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/561</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/561/279</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Meagan Sheffield</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
