<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/329</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-11-06T22:28:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effect of Antibiotic Treatment in Agriculture Production on Fly (Diptera) Attraction</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vu, Keelen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The use of antibiotics in agricultural production has become a topic of growing concern, as these drugs have facilitated the growth of antibiotic resistant bacteria. Flies have a tendency to mechanically transmit these bacteria, causing potential health problems for humans. It is to our benefit to know the demographics of such flies in order to prevent contamination. Organic livestock is typically raised without antibiotics and has some recorded health benefits. It was hypothesized that organic raised chicken breast will attract more flies than non-organic raised chicken breast. Three of each type of chicken breast were placed outside for a week. Adult Diptera were collected, killed and identified. Phormia regina, Cochliomyia macellaria, Lucilia sericata and a Musca species were identified. There was not a statistically significant difference in the number of flies collected or species breakdown between the two chicken breast types. Many variables could have skewed the results. The null hypothesis was accepted that there was no direct correlation between fly attraction and raising of chicken breast, however it was concluded that further research should be conducted with greater control over the experiment for future investigation. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/329</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 5 (2019): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/329/144</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
