<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/683</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effect of Insect Feeding on Hard Tissue During Late-Stage Decomposition</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hupping, Rylee</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The study of how insect colonization affects the latter most stages of decomposition is vital to the progress of forensic studies as well as the applications of anthropology and entomology in a forensic context. In an effort to try and make progress in linking anthropology and entomology in an ap­plied forensics context, the experiment was performed and consisted of observing and analyzing decomposing hard tissue for potential physical evidence of insect feeding. Three trials consisting of three samples of mostly stripped beef rib were allowed to decompose for three weeks each. The ribs were not completely stripped in an effort to incentivize the insects in the surrounding environment to feed on the samples. Afterward, the samples were cleaned and stripped by breaking down the collagen in the connective tissues of the remaining meat through boiling the samples, and then were ana­lyzed under a dissection microscope. During analysis, each sample was individually compared to a control of the same type, and it was discovered that over 50% of the entire sample population of bones were found to have microscopic indentations that could not be accredited to environmental damage, production inconsistencies, or experimental error. The origins of the damage could not be attributed to any known variable in the experiment, but since there was proof of insect feeding on the samples the experiment proceeded under the assumption that the insects observed feeding on the samples were the origins of the damage. The conclusion drawn from the experiment is that insect damage from feeding can be imprinted on hard tissue for analysis during late stages of decomposition when hard tissue is more prevalent than soft tissue as a food source.
&amp;nbsp;
Key words: decomposition, entomology, anthropology, damage</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/683</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/683/280</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Rylee Hupping</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
