<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/27</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T16:08:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Survey of Mosquito Species in Brazos County and Other Areas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Crews, Emily</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Keiser, Amy</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Moncada, Kara</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sanchez, Angela</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Mosquitoes are arguably the most medically important insect in the world, vectoring numerous diseases to humans and animals alike. In order to adequately combat and control dangerous diseases, public health officials regularly observe and document the species composition of mosquito populations in any area also occupied by humans. Mosquito specimens were collected during the spring months of 2015 by the experimenters to determine which species were present in local Texas areas. Larvae were collected through use of a mosquito dipper and other various plastic containers, then reared in mosquito breeding containers (samples of larvae were preserved for identification). Regions surveyed were focused in the Bryan/College Station area, with several samples also collected in Round Rock, Texas near Austin, Humble, Texas and another located in De Kalb, Texas. Mosquitoes of the species Culex quinquefasciatus, Aedes canadensis, Anopheles albimanus, Aedes vexans, Aedes albopictus were collected in Brazos county. Culex quinquefasciatus was found to be present in Round Rock and Humble, Texas as well. Several mosquito species were consistently found in the various regions of Texas with a few exceptions.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/27</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 2 (2015): Instars: A Journal of Undergraduate Research Vol. 2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/27/60</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
