<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/135</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-06-12T17:29:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Investigating Native and Invasive Ant Communities in College Station, Texas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Caprio, Catherine Prince</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Patricio, Amber</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hong, Erin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Patel, Nidhi</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The purpose of this study was to examine the diversity of ant species and determine the prevalence of invasive and native ant species in College Station, Texas. Different types of bait were placed in various urban landscapes at regular time intervals for five weeks. Of the six ant species collected, the Red Imported Fire Ant (Solenopsis invicta) was the most common species in all areas except the residence halls. This is most likely because inhabited areas are frequently treated with insecticides to control fire ant populations. Lastly, areas with the highest amount of human activity exhibited the lowest species diversity as a result of the negative effects of urbanization. Among the two invasive ant species collected, the tawny crazy ant (Nylanderia fulva) was detected, which represents the first documented case of this invasive ant in Brazos County.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/135</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 3 (2017): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/135/79</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
