<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-08T21:24:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of 24-hour postmortem ethanol soaked chicken on insect succession</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Butler, Julie M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gaytan, Madison</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harrington, Bailey</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">King, Jenny L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Lindsey M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the field of forensic entomology, experts are most frequently called upon to determine a minimum postmortem interval (PMI) for victims of death investigations. Many factors have a repellent effect on arthropod attraction to carrion, affecting the PMI, and this study examined the effects of soaking remains in ethanol for 24 hours before the body was made available for colonization. Eight whole chicken carcasses were used in this experiment. Four were used as controls and four were experimental carcasses soaked in ethanol for 24 hours. All chickens were taken into the field and remained for 7 days in wire cages. Arthropod specimens were collected and identified. Sarcophagidae larvae were the most abundant on both the control and test chickens. Five families of beetles were collected from the control and test chickens. Adult fly populations couldn’t be distinguished between either the test or control chickens. No significant difference in insect succession between the control and experimental chicken was observed. However, there was a difference in gross decomposition between the control and experimental chickens. Further studies are needed to examine the behavior of adult flies with regard to colonization of ethanol-soaked chickens.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/8</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 1 (2014): Instars: A Journal of Undergraduate Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/8/43</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
