<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-08T21:24:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effects of Increasing Temperature on Solenopsis invicta (Hymenoptera:Formicidae)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bauer, Jacey</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This experiment focuses on the Solenopsis invicta’s ability to withstand increasing temperatures in a dry, arid environment and determining the highest temperature that it would be possible for them to survive without the protection of an underground mound. Forty organisms were collected and separated in half, one being the control group and the other being the test group. The test organisms were then placed into a commercial food dehydrator and temperature was gradually increased. The behaviors of the organisms were noted as each increase in temperature took place. The lowest temperature that a change was observed was at 115°F and the highest temperature found that a fire ant could withstand was 125°F. The majority of change occurred at 120°F. At this temperature, 90% of the test ants became motionless and died. These results demonstrate the importance of the complex nests that fire ants build underground in order to regulate their temperatures. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/3</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 1 (2014): Instars: A Journal of Undergraduate Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/3/27</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
