<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/796</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Presence or Absence of Insects on Decomposing Material with Scented Products</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dennis, Sydney</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Insects are a key component of the decomposition of organic material. Investigators will use the time of colonization of the insects to determine how long the human body has been exposed to the elements and the time between death and discovery of the corpse,or the postmortem interval. The postmortem interval can be a crucial part of solving a case. However, scented products can change how and what insects are attracted to. This is because the products could encourage the insects to delay colonization on a body. If colonization is delayed, it becomes harder for investigators to determine an accurate postmortem interval. In order to conduct this experiment, chicken thighs were used as a model organism with various body scented products and a control to figure out if insects would be attracted or deterred. It was noticed that not all of the decomposing material was inhabited by the end of the fifth day.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/796</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/796/274</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Sydney Dennis</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
