<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/297</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-11-06T22:28:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Foraging Behavior of Female Blow Flies (Diptera: Calliphoridae) Based on Visual Cues</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McFadden, Kiara</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hans, Krystal</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The attraction of blow flies to different resources can be affected by their ovarian development. For this study, the foraging behavior of the blow fly Calliphora terraenovae Macquart (Diptera: Calliphoridae) and attraction to visual cues mimicking flower colors were examined. Naïve blow flies that have not fed on protein and do not have eggs to lay should be attracted to flower colors that represent nectar resources, such as white, pink, yellow. Naïve male and female blow flies were put into experimental cages and exposed to seven flower water representing various colors for 24 h. After 24 h, the flies were removed and assorted by sex. Based on the results, both male and female flies preferred the color purple. Female flies preferred purple as well, but also showed preference for pink. By understanding the color preference of adult blow flies, forensic entomologists can further their understanding of attraction to various resources, whether for nutrients or as potential oviposition sites.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/297</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 5 (2019): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/297/156</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
