<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/915</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:FORS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ethnic Variations in Fingerprint Patterns: A Texas A&amp;M University Student Analysis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schuppe, Mailys</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study discusses the distribution of fingerprint patterns (loops, whorls, and arches) among four different ethnic groups: Hispanic, Black, Asian, and White, in a survey of 190 students at Texas A&amp;amp;M. 190 students were fingerprinted; the fingerprints were then analyzed for their fingerprint pattern and recorded. The data obtained from the percentage occurrence of fingerprint subtypes shows marked differences in the prevalence of patterns among the populations. Loops were found to be the predominant pattern in all groups; however, the frequency was different. Whites show the highest frequency of loops, 69.92%, while Asians have the least at 49.41%, indicating marked intergroup differences. While loops were less frequent in Asians, whorls were the most frequent compared to other ethnicities at 38.71%, and the least frequency is found among Whites at 23.82% (Chart 1). Arches have the greatest variability of frequency, being most evident in the Black population and least common in Whites. The subtype analysis showed that radial loops and plain whorls were highly frequent in all groups while the tented arch and accidental whorl were rare. These findings indicate that there is ethnic variability in dermatoglyphic traits, which may be genetically and evolutionarily influenced. However, more research should be conducted with a larger pool of participants to have a better, more accurate understanding of ethnicities in relation to fingerprint patterns.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/915</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/915/285</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Mailys Schuppe</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
