<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/773</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-19T02:09:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparative Analysis of Fragrances and Commercially Available Attractants to Insects</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elgohary, Georgia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elati, Anagha</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reynolds, Taylor</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en"> The attractiveness of different chemicals to insects is needed for developing effectivebaits for commercial traps. In addition, the use of personal fragrance could inadvertently increaseattractiveness to biting insects. Our objective was to evaluate the attractiveness of three differentpersonal fragrances and one commercial attractant for different insect orders in College Station,Texas. Traps captured a total of 1228 individual insects from eight different orders. The mostconsistent treatment in attractiveness was jasmine and the most commonly attracted insect orderwas Thysanoptera. We found that the mean abundance of most insect orders did not differ fromthe un-baited control group, indicating that the different baits did not significantly differ in theirattractiveness. This study helps identify baits for insect traps to increase effectiveness.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-10-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/773</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 8 No. 1 (2023): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/773/226</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Georgia Elgohary, Anagha Elati, Taylor Reynolds</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
