<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/305</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-11-06T22:28:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Survey of Insect Families Attracted to Carbon-Dioxide in Thomas Park and the Surrounding Area in College Station, Texas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rigby, Benjamin</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It is very important to be aware of the insects living in or around one’s home for many reasons. Insects can vector numerous diseases, damage structures and plants, and be pests. Knowing what insects are in certain areas can help aid in control and prevention methods. This experiment focused on surveying insect families attracted to carbon dioxide in and around Thomas Park in College Station, Texas. Three insect traps were made, using carbon dioxide producing-yeast as the attractant. The three traps captured 325 insects, a majority of them being vinegar flies. All three traps captured at least one fly from the family Calliphoridae and one from the family Muscidae. Trap 3 captured a beetle belonging to the family Bostrichidae. The flies captured were forensically important because they colonize remains soon after death. The beetle, known as a powderpost beetle, was significant because it was a wood-boring beetle that could cause structural wood damage. By knowing that these insects live in a certain location, proper control measures can be performed to effectively control the population.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/305</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 5 (2019): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/305/141</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
