<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/245</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-31T20:40:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparison of Attractant Type, Trap Size and Trap Color based on Number of Diptera Captured at a Livestock Facility</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">West, Elizabeth</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Biting and filth flies are typically present in large numbers at livestock facilities.  Using surveillance tools to monitor the species composition and abundance is a critical part of integrated pest management.  We evaluated a commercial funnel trap with different sugar bait attractants to evaluate the effectiveness at capturing these flies.  We selected the Texas A&amp;amp;M University Sheep Center as the location to perform the study.  Two different sugar baits were compared to determine which one was more effective at attracting flies.  Another variable that was tested was whether trap size and color affected the number of flies that were captured.  The specimens were collected, preserved, and counted, and the data was recorded.  Upon analyzing the data, it was established that the two sugar baits were not extremely different in their ability to attract flies.  There was however, a noticeable difference in the number of flies captured in the large versus small traps and the small dark versus small light traps.  The conclusions made from this study can be used by people who are looking to trap flies in a similar environment to the one tested. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-01-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/245</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 4 (2018): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/245/115</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
