<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/11</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-04-08T21:24:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Survey of Mosquito Populations in the Bryan-College Station Area</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Choi, Sarah</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Poulter, Katie</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ramirez, Amber</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomas, Zeb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Some species of mosquitos can be vectors of serious diseases that can not only cause death, but a significant amount of monetary lost. This survey was performed with the goal of discovering which species of mosquitoes are present in the Bryan-College Station area so that knowledge could be gained on potential disease vectors in the community. This survey was accomplished through frequent larvae sampling from pools of water in various locations. Samples of larvae were collected using plastic bottles and adults were collected using an insect net.  Larvae were reared into adults using a mosquito breeder. These adults were then placed into a kill jar to allow proper identification. Based on previous studies, it was expected that there would be a number of medically important mosquito species which vector common diseases that are prevalent in this part of the country. The conducted survey found two common genera from the collected larvae and adult mosquitoes: Aedes and Culex. Specifically, Aedes aegypti (L.) (Diptera: Culicidae) was found to be the most prominent species in the Bryan-College Station area. It is important to understand that our results could have been affected by the low temperatures and drought experienced this year.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/11</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 1 (2014): Instars: A Journal of Undergraduate Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/11/33</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
