<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/473</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-11-06T22:28:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Testing the Efficacy of Different Common Household as Baits on Diptera Using Baited Flytraps</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Suggs, Tatyanna Alexis</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There are many diseases and pathogens that can be transmitted by dipteran species. There is ample opportunity for fly pest species to do so because they can contaminate food and water sources. Scientist aim to reduce the and prevent the contact pest species have with places humans inhabit, however are not sure what the main attract is because pest flies can be found in a variety of environments. One of the most prevalent environments pest species are found are in homes. In this experiment, we investigated whether pest flies were more attracted to feces, fruit or meat. These three things can be found in the typical American home and distinguishing which one has more of an attract to pest flies can help deduce more ways to reduce their presence or even                                                            prevent it.  There is no difference in efficacy between the three different baits that were tested most likely because each bait can provide nutrition and a breeding site for dipteran species.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-11-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/473</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 5 (2019): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/473/154</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
