<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/887</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ecotone Effects on Arthropod Biodiversity in Texas Sorghum Field Edges and Within</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lam, Ivin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bradicich, Pius</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brewer, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Abstract: High levels of arthropod biodiversity are indicative of a healthy environment and bring valuable benefits to agroecosystems, providing diverse functions like pollination, decomposition, and predation of crop pests by natural enemies. The intensification of agricultural practices often changes the neighboring habitats, creating new man-made environments that alter arthropod biodiversity within and around agroecosystems. These man-made ecotones, ecosystems made of two or more bordering habitats, are of great importance to integrated pest management systems and conservation efforts as spatial control of pests has been underutilized and understudied in the agricultural space for years. To assess these differences in biodiversity within and around Texas sorghum fields, an arthropod biodiversity survey over a 5-week period was conducted. Overall, this study covered a total of thirty-three collections, sampling arthropods across Texas sorghum fields that shared a border with sorghum, cotton, or semi-natural land ecotones, extending from the edge of the field's border to 150 meters within the field. Collected specimens were identified to the family-level taxon, and statistical analysis was conducted to measure biodiversity. Field surveys revealed that sorghum fields bordering semi-natural, cotton, or sorghum ecotones exhibited no significant differences in biodiversity near the borders as a result of ecotonal differences. Yet, distance from ecotone edges may play a significant factor. Increasing our understanding of impacts related to spatial or ecotonal changes on biodiversity in Texas field crops, like sorghum, and the surrounding ecosystems may provide valuable information regarding environmental performance and pest monitoring for integrated pest management.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/887</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/887/265</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Ivin Lam, Pius Bradicich, Michael Brewer</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
