<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/653</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-19T02:09:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Survey of Effectiveness in Catching Pest Insects in Southeast Texas Using Various Homemade Traps</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pappolla, Sean</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The presence of pests in Southeast Texas is not uncommon given the primarilymarsh biome it encompasses. A result of this is the nuisance that is having many insectspresent near human habitations. A good portion of these insects tends to become pestsand interrupt everyday life and potentially cause disease. This study has the intent ofsearching for a reliable trap to exterminate these pests in the convenience of a residentialspace and its materials. Three different types of traps were used in this experiment: abowl filled with vinegar, plastic wrap, and side-door bottle trap. Each trap was studied forthree trials, with a total of nine traps set across three locations in Southeast Texas. Trapswere set for 24 hours each trial in a period from November 26 to November 29, 2021.There was a total of 111 insects caught, all in the order Diptera. Among this order, therewere three families present: 109 in Drosophilidae, one in Calliphoridae, and one inCulicidae. Insects higher in quantity and diversity found a significantly stronger attractionto and mortality rate with the vinegar bowl trap most likely due to its ability to drown thepests.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-10-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/653</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 8 No. 1 (2023): Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/653/210</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Sean Pappolla</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
