<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/551</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-07T20:50:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Investigation of Host Hormone Impact on Mosquito (Diptera: Culicidae) Feeding Preferences</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hassall, Andrew</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nicole Willison</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en"> Andrew Short</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sydney Mikes</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en"> Omar Khan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Carlos Koehl</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Abstract: Mosquitoes pose an immense threat in their capability to both locate and feed upon hosts. Though plenty is known about the methods used by these arthropods to seek out hosts, less is known regarding the impact each method has upon a successful host location. The degree of host-specificity between species is known to vary, and to what extent host-specific qualities affect this is not fully apparent. Specimens of medically important mosquito species known to inhabit Brazos County, Texas, including Aedes aegypti, Aedes triseriatus, Culex quinquefasciatus, and Psorophora columbiae were collected in the spring season of 2020. Samples were evaluated based upon apparent preferences for various simulated host signals, deer pheromone or sweaty clothes. The data obtained demonstrated preferences in-line with natural populations of Aedes aegypti and Psorophora columbiae, with other species lacking statistically significant results or sample sizes for proper analysis. Results provide an incentive for further ecological research into the impact of isolated host-seeking signals in initiating host-seeking behavior, as well as characteristics of said isolated signals that induce stages of behavior.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/551</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 9 No. 1 (2025): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/551/251</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Andrew Hassall, Nicole Willison,  Andrew Short, Sydney Mikes,  Omar Khan, Carlos Koehl</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
