<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/451</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-03-09T01:35:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>instars:ENTO</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Survey of the Culex quinquefasciatus (Diptera: Culicidae) Mosquito and the Transmission of West Nile Virus in Brazos County</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pickle, Kaylin </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Padilla, Kelbi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Badat, Sadiyya</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tellez, Kathleen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rico, Sarah</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Woods, Brian</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aguirre Cordero, Erik</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Arceneaux, Miles</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Localities in the College Station area of Texas were surveyed for Culicidae species to examine the prevalence of Culex quinquefasciatus. A recent outbreak of West Nile Virus (WNV) in a nearby suburb of Houston caused by salvarian transmission of Culex q. deems it a medically significant vector worthy of surveillance. Mosquito specimens were collected using Center of Disease Control (CDC) light traps in various recreational parks with proximity to water and moderate human activity, as is preferred by the organism. Collection procedures were implemented during warm, humid months due to mosquito populations peaking at this time. Through trapping, preservation, and identification with pictorial keys, the prevalence of Culicidae species was determined. It was found that while Culex q. poses health threats as a vector of WNV, Aedes aegypti is over three times more abundant in Brazos County. Thus, our research serves to reduce the risk associated with Culex q. and allows for future areas of surveillance that focus on a more widespread species in College Station and surrounding regions.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-01-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/451</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Instars: A Journal of Student Research; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2021): Instars: A Journal of Student Research </dc:source>
	<dc:source>2374-7595</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://instars-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/instars/article/view/451/202</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Instars: A Journal of Student Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
