<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1741</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T19:35:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Comparison of serological responses when modified-live infectious bovine rhinotracheitis virus vaccine, Mannheimia haemolytica bacterin-toxoid and Leptospira pomona bacterin are administered with needle-free versus conventional needle-based injection in Holstein dairy calves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hollis, Larry C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, John F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, Bradley J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kapil, Sanjay</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mosier, Derek A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle breeds</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immune response</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunization</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">live vaccines</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A total of 104, five- to ten-month old Holstein heifers and steers were blocked by age within sex-group, randomized to treatment and vaccinated with 5-way modified-live virus vaccine, Mannheimia haemolytica bacterin-toxoid and 5-way Leptospira bacterin utilizing either needle-free or conventional needle-and-syringe injection techniques. Blood samples were collected from all animals at the time of vaccination and 21 days later, and the serum analyzed for antibody titers to infectious bovine rhinotracheitis (IBR) virus as the indicator of serological response to the 5-way viral vaccine, Mannheimia haemolytica (MH) leukotoxin, and Leptospira pomona (LP) as the indicator of serological response to the 5-way Leptospira bacterin. On day 21 the serological response of heifers to the IBR fraction of the 5-way viral vaccine, MH bacterin and LP fraction of the 5-way Leptospira bacterin were not significantly different between routes of administration. On day 21 the serological response of steers to the IBR fraction of the 5-way viral vaccine and MH bacterin was significantly higher for the needle-free route of administration, while the serological response to the LP fraction was not significantly different between routes of administration.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2005-06-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1741</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol39no2p110-114</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 39, No. 2 (2005 June); 110-114</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1741/7702</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2005 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
