<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9018</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-02T14:54:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A comparison of two multivalent modified live viral/bacterial combination vaccines in feedlot calves at ultra-high risk of developing undifferentiated fever/bovine respiratory disease</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hunsaker, Breck D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McMullen, Christopher A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stamm, Courtney G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perrett, Tye</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hannon, Sherry J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bryant, Lonty K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Booker, Calvin W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">shipping fever</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunization</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Vaccine 1 (VAC1 group) and Vaccine 2 (VAC2 group) are com­mercially available vaccines labeled for the control of bovine respiratory disease (BRD) in beef cattle. There are limited data from large-scale commercial feedlot trials comparing VAC1 and VAC2 arrival processing vaccination pro­grams. The objective of this study was to evaluate the relative effects of VAC1 and VAC2 arrival processing vacci­nation programs on animal health, feedlot performance and carcass characteristic outcomes in feedlot calves at ultra-high risk of developing undifferentiated fever/BRD under large-scale commercial production conditions. Animals were randomly allocated at feedlot arrival to 1 of 2 experimental groups: VAC1 or VAC2.&amp;nbsp; Animals in the VAC1 group (6 multi-pen lots; 3,001 animals) received a bovine rhinotracheitis-virus diarrhea-parainfluenza 3-respiratory syncytial virus-Mannheimia hae­molytica-Pasteurella multocida vaccine per animal once at allocation. Animals in the VAC2 group (6 multi-pen lots; 3,005 animals) received a bovine rhinotracheitis-virus diarrhea-parainfluenza 3-respiratory syncytial virus vaccine with a Mannheimia haemolytica toxoid per animal once at allocation. Vaccines differed regarding viral strains, bacterial protection, means for providing bacterial immunity, and adjuvant use. Animals were housed by experi­mental group in commercial feedlot pens and followed from allocation until slaughter. Although histophilosis mortality was higher in the VAC1 group compared to the VAC2 group (P = 0.040), no statistical differences were detected in overall mor­tality or any of the other outcome variables (P ≥ 0.050). The relative cost effectiveness of each arrival processing vaccina­tion program in the study population is therefore dependent on relative program cost.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-06-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9018</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20249018</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2024); 23-33</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9018/8717</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
