<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2460</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T02:07:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Clinical and laboratory investigations on chronic bovine fluorosis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Metwalli, A. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">El-Gharieb, S. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ashry, K. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">blood chemistry</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical aspects</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fluorosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">haematology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pollution</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">symptoms</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">During summer 1995, a clinical picture of chronic bovine fluorosis was observed in Fowa villages (Kafr El-Sheikh Governorate) where many brick kilns were established. A total number of 26 cows (5-9 years) of native breed was investigated in the present study. Sixteen animals were collected from different places around the kilns, another 10 animals (control group) were chosen from places away from the brick kilns zone. The affected cows showed reduced appetite, loss in general body condition, lameness and dental lesions in the form of staining, mottling and blackish discoloration specially of the incisors teeth. Biochemical analysis of serum of affected cows revealed significantly decreased level of serum calcium and total protein, whereas serum alkaline phosphatase activity, fluoride content, urea, and creatinine were significantly increased as compared with control animals. Haematological examination of affected cows showed significantly decreased values of Hb and PCV. On the basis of laboratory and circumstantial evidence, the problem was suspected to be fluorosis, possibly due to environmental pollution with fluorine-bearing smoke arising from the large number of brick kilns.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1996-05-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2460</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1996no30p67-69</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 30 (1996 May); 67-69</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2460/2452</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1996 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
