<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1766</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T18:30:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Teat Dilators as Free Foreign Bodies in the Bovine Teat: Two Case Studies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Querengässer, Klaus</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Geishauser, Thomas</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Querengässer, Julia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bruckmaier, Rupert</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fehlings, Klaus</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wolf, Winfried</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">case reports</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">endoscopy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">foreign bodies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">inflammaiton</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk quality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">teats</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The objective of this study is to report two cases of foreign bodies in teats of cows with milk flow disorders. Foreign bodies and the causes of the milk flow disorders were diagnosed and treated by using teat endoscopy. In the first case, a teat dilator was found in the teat along with inflammation of the teat cistern lining. The milk flow disorder was caused by teat canal skin which had ruptured and inverted into the teat cistern. In the second case, a wax teat insert was found in the teat cistern. The milk flow disorder was caused by a narrowed inner opening of the teat canal. In both cases the milk from the affected quarters showed signs of subclinical mastitis. The foreign bodies were removed through the teat canal by using forceps. The causes of the milk flow disorders were treated surgically. Antibiotics were administered into the affected teats and a sterile silicone implant was inserted into the teat canal. The teat was bandaged and rested for several days. On re-examination four weeks later, milk flow and milk quality were significantly improved. Our findings indicate that the alterations in the teat canal area were the cause of the milk flow disorders rather than the foreign bodies. We conclude that in teats with milk flow disorders, a diagnosis should be made first and then a causal treatment initiated. Teat dilators and wax inserts without heads may slip into the teat and act as foreign bodies. Teat dilators may be deleterious to udder health.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1766</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol34no1p41-45</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 34, No. 1 (2000 January); 41-45</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1766/7826</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2000 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
