<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8544</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-03-01T02:21:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Survey of veterinary involvement in cattle health and production record-keeping on U.S. cow-calf operations</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jumper, W. Isaac</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Huston, Carla L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Willis, Robert L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, David R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">survey</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinarian</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cow-calf</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">VCPR</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The objective of this study was to identify factors associated with veterinary involvement in cattle health and production record (CHPR) management on U.S. cow-calf operations. We anonymously surveyed 14,294 cow-calf producers across the U.S. Multivariable logistic regression by manual forward variable selection was used to test demographic factors for association with veterinary involvement in CHPR management outcomes. A total of 3,741 (26%) responses were received, with 3,641 (97%) actively involved in cow-calf production. Of these, 2,216 of 3,486 (64%) said local veterinarians were their primary source of cattle health, treatment, and vaccination information. If available, 1,067 of 3,382 (32%) respondents would pay a veterinarian to analyze CHPR and provide management advice based on that information. Factors associated with willingness to pay a veterinarian for CHPR-keeping services include region (midwest: OR = 1.5; mountain: OR = 1.3; northeast: OR = 1.4; northern plains: OR = 1.8; southern plains: OR = 1.7; southeast: OR = 1.9; compared to west), cow-calf operation is not respondent’s primary income source (OR = 1.4; compared to being respondent’s primary income source), respondent records antibiotic treatments (OR = 1.4; compared to not recording antibiotic treatments), respondent education level (post-graduate or professional degree: OR = 1.4; some college up to completed Bachelor’s degree: OR = 1.1; compared to high-school diploma or less). A meaningful number of respondents were willing to pay a veterinarian for CHPR management services depending on region, income source, antibiotic record use and education level.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8544</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol56no2p2-37</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 56 No. 2 (2022); 29-37</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8544/8333</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
