<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2370</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T02:03:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Clinical, diagnostic and biochemical features of generalized gylcogenosis type II in brahman cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reichmann, K. G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Twist, J. O.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thistlethwaite, E. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Clinical, diagnostic and biochemical features of generalized glycogenosis are described in 96 Brahman- type calves. Typically the calves were presented when about 6 months of age, with ill-thrift and muscular weakness as the most common signs. Acidic a-glucosidase activity was reduced in peripheral blood lymphocytes and skeletal muscle. Muscle glycogen concentration was consistently higher in affected animals than in clinically normal cattle. Other observations in affected calves included elevation of serum aspartate aminotransferase and creatine kinase activities and excessive amounts of high molecular weight oligosaccharides in urine. Fine cytoplasmic vacuolation of neurones in the brain and spinal cord, skeletal muscle, myocardium and of Purkinje fibers were consistent histological observations. Periodic acid-Schiff staining revealed the presence of glycogen-like material in peripheral blood lymphocytes of all affected calves, indicating that this is a useful aid for the diagnosis of glycogenosis. While 3 of the 96 calves showed somewhat different clinical signs, the similarity of pathology and the biochemical and clinical evidence in the remainder suggested that, in these animals, the disease was expressed as a single syndrome.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1994-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2370</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1994no28p38-43</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 28 (1994 September); 38-43</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2370/2362</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1994 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
