<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8194</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-31T19:00:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Efficacy of a combination modified-live IBR-BVD-PI3-BRSV vaccine + Mannheimia haemolytica toxoid against challenge with virulent BVDV-1b and BVDV-2 viruses in young calves 60 days of age</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Masic, Aleksandar</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sobecki, Brian</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mahan, Suman</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brice, Chadwick</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mattern, Sally</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Peterson, Dennis</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Barret, Peter</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Daugherty, Colt</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Meinert, Todd</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Correas, Ignacio</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Moulin, Véronique</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BVDV-1</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BVDV-2</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BRD</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">MH toxoid</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">leukopenia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">viremia</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Efficacy of attenuated (att) bovine viral diarrhea virus (types 1 and 2) as antigen fractions in a modified-live multivalent vaccine were evaluated following single, subcutaneous (SC) administration and intranasal (IN) challenge 35 to 38 d after vaccination, with either virulent BVDV-1b (Study 1) or BVDV-2 (Study 2) viruses in young calves. A total of 80 BVDV-seronegative Holstein calves, 53 to 61 d of age at the time of vaccination, were used in 2 separate studies with 40 animals per study. In each study, calves were allocated to 1 of 2 treatment groups (20 animals per group) which received either a single dose of combination modified-live bovine rhinotracheitis (BHV-1)-bovine virus diarrhea-parainfluenza 3-respiratory syncytial virus vaccine + Mannheimia haemolytica toxoid, or corresponding placebo formulation without targeted test antigen fractions attBVDV-1a and attBVDV-2. In the respective studies, multivalent vaccine induced significantly higher virus neutralizing antibody responses and reduced incidence and duration of leukopenia and viremia in vaccinated animals compared to placebo-treated animals. Post-challenge leukopenia, a hallmark of BVDV infection, was observed in 75% and 100% of control calves compared to only 26.3% and 25% in vaccinated animals in Study 1 and Study 2, respectively (p=0.006; p=0.0001). In addition, duration of leukopenia was significantly shorter in vaccinates compared to placebo controls (p=0.0091 Study 1; p&amp;lt;0.0001 Study 2). Furthermore, 100% of placebo-treated calves in both studies were viremic compared to 57.9% (Study 1) and 25% (Study 2) of vaccinated animals, resulting in significant reduction of post-challenge viremia (p=0.0012, Study 1; p=0.0001, Study 2). The duration of viremia was significantly shorter (p&amp;lt;0.0001) in vaccinated groups compared to control calves in both studies. In conclusion, data from the current studies demonstrated vaccine efficacy in 60-day-old calves against BVDV-1b and BVDV-2 infection.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8194</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol55no1p1-12</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 55, No. 1 (2021); 1-12</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8194/8133</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
