<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1745</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T19:38:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Frequent changing and rinsing of drinking water buckets improved performance of hutch-reared Holstein calves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wiedmeier, R. D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Young, A. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hammon, D. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf feeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drinkers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drinking water</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hygiene</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">liveweight gain</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">washing</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There is often great variation in the cleanliness of drinking water provided to hutch-raised calves. Due to the relationship between dry matter intake and water intake, low water quality in the calf hutch could reduce feed intake and daily gain, and possibly affect health status of the calves. The objective of this study was to compare the performance of hutch-reared calves when drinking water containers were changed/rinsed with decreasing frequency. For three consecutive years, 24 Holstein bull calves (2-7 days of age) were purchased each year from a single commercial dairy. Calves were purchased in four sets of six calves each in September, December, March and June of each year. Calves remained in the hutches for 60 days, receiving milk replacer twice daily. A concentrate mix was available at all times. Of the six calves in each set, two had their drinking water buckets rinsed daily, two were rinsed at 7-day intervals and two at 14-day intervals. Average daily gain (ADG) of calves was measured during the 60-day period while in hutches, and through a subsequent 100 to 110-day post-weaning feeding period. The frequency of changing/rinsing drinking water buckets affected ADG of calves while in the hutches: daily, 1.55 lb (0.70 kg)/day; 7-day, 1.48 lb (0.67 kg)/day; 14-day, 1.40 lb (0.64 kg)/day. All means were different (P&amp;lt;0.05). These differences in ADG carried over through the post-weaning period: daily, 3.12 lb (1.42 kg)/day; 7-day, 3.01 lb (1.37 kg)/day; 14-day, 2.90 lb (1.32 kg)/day. The daily and 14-day treatments were different (P&amp;lt;0.05), while the 7-day treatment was intermediate. Calves assigned to the daily and 7-day changing/rinsing regimen required a similar number (1.25) of medical treatments while in the hutches (P&amp;gt;0.05). When drinking water buckets were changed/rinsed at 14-day intervals, calves required 1.75 medical treatments, an increase of 40%. Calves on the 14-day regimen were 2.48 (95% CI: range 1.32 to 4.68) times more likely (P&amp;lt;0.01) to receive more than one treatment, compared to calves on daily and 7-day changing/rinsing regimens. Thus, a seemingly minor management practice such as frequency of changing/rinsing drinking water buckets in calf hutches can have an impact on calf performance and health.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2006-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1745</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol40no1p1-6</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 40, No. 1 (2006 Spring); 1-6</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1745/7685</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2006 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
