<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8553</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-03-01T02:21:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Seroprevalence and molecular detection of Anaplasma marginale infected beef herds in Georgia, USA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jones, A. Lee</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Berghaus, Roy D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kalatari, Allen A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Credille, Brenton</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Naikare, Hemant K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heins, Bradley</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Saliki, JeremiahT.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wilkes, Rebecca P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Anaplasma marginale</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anaplasmosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Georgia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">seroprevalence</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The objective of the study was to conduct and compare serop­revalence and molecular detection of Anaplasma marginale-in­fected beef herds in Georgia, and to identify herd risk factors associated with A. marginale-positive herds. Herd informa­tion from the beef operations was collected from the sampled herds through a questionnaire to determine practices that may affect the risk of herd infections with A. marginale. Blood samples were collected from 1,059 adult beef cattle (≥ 2 years) from 33 herds. Overall, 8.12% of cattle and 42% of herds were cELISA antibody-positive. Seventy-seven percent of plasma samples from a subset of corresponding seropositive samples (n = 73) were PCR positive. All of the 406 seronegative samples were negative by PCR. There was almost perfect agreement by Cohen’s kappa statistics between PCR and cELISA (k = 0.85). Survey response rate was 100%. Surprisingly, 27% of the pro­ducer respondents had not heard of anaplasmosis. Survey also revealed that many producers had management procedures at their operations that could potentially cause mechanical transmission of A. marginale. About 55% of respondents did not always disin­fect tools between animals and 88% of the operations used the same needle to inject more than one animal. Over 80% of the producer respondents had brought in new cattle onto their op­erations in the last 3 years from the time of this study. Given the 8% seroprevalence in Georgia beef cattle and the reported survey findings from this study, educational programs on ef­fective preventive management practices to control bovine anaplasmosis is warranted.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8553</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol56no2p70-78</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 56 No. 2 (2022); 70-78</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8553/8337</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
