<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1281</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:02:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Use of milk progesterone testing for problem cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Varner, Mark A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">MPA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">progesterone</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">assay</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Knowledge of a cow’s ovarian status can be very useful in not only the daily reproductive management of dairy cows, but also in supplementing diagnosis of herd reproductive problems. Milk or blood progesterone levels can provide an accurate diagnosis of bovine ovarian status. Technology to measure progesterone levels in blood and milk has been available in this research laboratory for approximately 15 years. During this time, scientists have collected some of the background information necessary to use progesterone analysis for reproductive management of dairy cattle. A commercial laboratory to measure progesterone was initiated by the New York Dairy Herd Improvement Association, however, the laboratory has not analyzed enough samples to justify continuation of the progesterone analysis as was orginally intended. The primary problem, was that turn-around time for sample analysis was too long to provide results in a timely manner for action of a specific cow by a producer. Experience in New York demonstrated that a cow-side test was needed for progesterone.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1281</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no21p165-171</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 21 (1986 November); 165-171</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1281/1272</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
