<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2773</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T20:49:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Efficacy of a new navel dip to prevent umbilical infection in dairy calves.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Grover, Wayne M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Godden, Sandra</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neonate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">navel dip</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">umbilicus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">omphalitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bacterial diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy farms</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">disinfectants</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">iodine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pathogens</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A field study was conducted utilizing 495 newborn calves in 13 commercial Wisconsin dairy herds to evaluate the use of a new umbilical disinfectant dip (Navel Guard (NG), Sirius Chemical Group, McDonough, GA) to prevent umbilical infections (omphalitis) as compared to control groups (CG): (1) not dipping the umbilicus at birth (CGNodip; trial conducted in two herds), (2) dipping the umbilicus with 7% tincture of iodine (CG7TI; trial conducted in seven herds), or (3) dipping with solutions containing a low concentration (0.5 to 2%) of iodine (CGILow; trial conducted in four herds). In all three trials, newborn calves were alternately assigned (every other calf) to have their navel dipped with either NG or the control article (CGNodip, CG7TI or CGILow) as soon as possible after birth. A study technician evaluated each calf's navel once per week for the first three weeks of life by measuring the diameter of the umbilical stalk and determining whether a painful response was elicited upon palpation of the umbilicus. Results indicate that Navel Guard was more effective for reducing the incidence of umbilical infections in neonatal calves compared to calves not dipped shortly after birth. The risk for umbilical infection was numerically, but not statistically, reduced in calves when the umbilicus was dipped with Navel Guard as compared to calves for which the umbilicus was dipped with 7% tincture of iodine or solutions containing low concentrations of iodine (0.5 to 2.0%).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2010-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2773</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol45no1p70-77</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 45, No. 1 (2011 Spring); 70-77</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2773/2763</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2011 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
