<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9258</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-30T20:39:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of an automated on-farm device to identify groups of bacteria associated with clinical mastitis on a United States dairy farm</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Peña-Mosca, Felipe</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nydam, Daryl V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Caixeta, Luciano S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cuoto-Serrenho, Rita</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomas, Mark</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Saila, Susan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bork, Olaf</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stangaferro, Matias</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">udder health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antimicrobial stewardship</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">intramammary infection</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">&amp;nbsp;
Recent studies suggest that selectively treating non-severe clinical mastitis during lactation, guided by on-farm culture, can be prudent. However, on-farm culture presents logistical challenges. This study investigated Mastatest’s® (MT; Masta­plex, New Zealand) ability to identify broad groups of patho­gens in clinical mastitis milk samples compared to laboratory culture and matrix-assisted laser desorption ionization-time of flight mass spectrometry (LC+M) on one U.S. dairy farm. Milk samples from quarters with clinical mastitis were col­lected on a dairy farm located in Colorado (n = 162). The test’s ability to identify groups of pathogens was assessed against LC+M (reference method) using contingency tables. Test char­acteristics (sensitivity [Se], specificity [Sp], positive predictive value and negative predictive value) and their 95% confidence intervals were estimated. Agreement was assessed using the Kappa statistic. Prevalences (0.20-0.60) for Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacteria were used to estimate predictive values. Before analysis, contaminated or missing samples in either MT or LC+M were excluded (n = 36). Our findings indi­cated moderate to substantial agreement, with Kappa values ranging from 0.53 to 0.66. For Gram-positive pathogens, Se and Sp estimates, and their 95% confidence intervals were: Se: 0.83 (0.70, 0.92), Sp: 0.81 (0.70, 0.89), and for Gram-negative bac­teria (Se: 0.73 [0.50, 0.89], Sp: 0.93 [0.87, 0.97]). Negative predic­tive value remained above 0.70 across different prevalence sce­narios, particularly where values exceeded 0.90 for prevalences below 0.30. Our findings suggest MT is a suitable technology for on-farm detection of mastitis pathogens commonly identified on U.S. dairy farms in clinical mastitis milk samples.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9258</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20259258</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 59 No. 2 (2025): ONLINE FIRST; 26-31</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9258/8900</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
