<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/36</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T20:18:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Factors affecting the sale price of bulls consigned to a graded sale</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Irsik, Mark</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">House, Amanda R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shuffitt, Mark R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shearer, Jan R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Selection or replacement of a herd bull is an important decision for cow-calf producers. To justify the price paid for a bull, cattlemen may utilize several criteria. They must also determine if the specific selection criteria used add or detract from the value of a particular animal. The study reported here evaluated 13 years of data presented to bull buyers at a graded bull auction in Florida. Results of this study indicated that buyers placed significant emphasis on the following criteria: grade of bull, age, birth weight, sale weight, breed and year of sale. Buyers paid more for a bull evaluated as having superior phenotype and breeding potential. Younger bulls were preferred to older bulls, and bulls with increasing birth weights were discounted. While expected progeny differences (EPD) data are considered a useful selection tool, observations from this study suggest that progeny information had little or no effect on buying decisions, and thus the value of a particular bull. There was, however, a significant effect of breed on sale price: Angus bulls were the preferred breed and sold at a premium compared to other breeds consigned. Year of sale affected the price paid for a bull, with some years more significant than others. In general, producers at this sale did not discount or show prejudice to bulls brought from out-of-state.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2008-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/36</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol42no1p10-17</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 42, No. 1 (2008 Spring); 10-17</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/36/7667</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
