<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9261</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-06-09T16:35:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Utilization of point-of-care evaluation to determine prognosis in feedyard cattle with multiple previous respiratory disease treatments</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Feitoza, Luis F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">White, Brad J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Larson, Robert L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Spore, Tyler J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">chuteside diagnostics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feedlot cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">thoracic ultrasonography</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Determining prognosis to differentiate recoverable and non-recoverable cattle is a critical knowledge gap impacting ani­mal welfare and economic sustainability. Point-of-care (POC) diagnostics could provide prognostic insight. This study aims to determine potential associations between negative out­comes (mortality/culling) and POC evaluations of chronic respiratory cases. A cross-sectional study evaluated commer­cial beef feedyard cattle at their third or greater treatment for respiratory disease (n = 98, 799 ± 16 lb [362 ± 7 kg]). Post-evaluation outcomes were classified as did not finish (DNF) (DNF = mortality/culling) or recovered (still present in feeding system) 60-days post-enrollment. Captured POC parameters were: sex, days on feed, body weight, pulse oximetry, pulmonary auscultation score at cranio-ventral lobe/caudo-dorsal lobe, and targeted thoracic lung ultrasound imaging. Multivariate logistic regression was used to evalu­ate potential associations between DNF and POC parameters. Only ultrasound variables (B-line count, moth sign and B-line area) were significantly (P &amp;lt; 0.05) associated with DNF. Cases with B-line count ≥ 3 had higher probability of DNF (84% ± 5%) compared to cases with &amp;lt; 3 B-lines (34% ± 22%). Presence of moth sign was associated with higher DNF (78% ± 13%) com­pared to cases with no moth sign (43% ± 15%). Average B-line area was higher (18.7 ± 1.2 cm2) in DNF cases compared to recovered cases (9.6 ± 1.2 cm2). Strategic use of targeted tho­racic POC ultrasound has potential usefulness for determin­ing prognosis for chronically ill respiratory cases; offering valuable insights for treatment and management decisions in feedyard cattle health.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-06-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9261</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20259261</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 59 No. 2 (2025): ONLINE FIRST; 32-39</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9261/8901</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
