<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9299</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-02-19T17:34:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparison of the efficacy of pradofloxacin to florfenicol plus flunixin or tulathromycin in beef heifers challenged with Mannheimia haemolytica</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tessman, Ronald K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kayser, William C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cull, Charley A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lechtenberg, Kelly F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shankamurthy, N.C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rani, Shilpa</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pradofloxacin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">florfenicol</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">flunixin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tulathromycin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Mannheimia haemolytica</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The efficacy of pradofloxacin was compared to florfenicol plus flunixin or tulathromycin in beef heifers challenged with Mannheimia haemolytica. Ninety-five beef heifers were chal­lenged with M. haemolytica (60 mL inoculum with 5.35×106 CFU/mL) on study day (SD) -1. Seventy-four heifers with signs of bovine respiratory disease (BRD) were randomly allocated to one of 3 treatments. On SD 0, heifers in treatment 1 (n = 25) received 10 mg/kg pradofloxacin, heifers in treatment 2 (n = 25) received 40 mg florfenicol/kg and 2.2 mg flunixin/kg, and heifers in treatment 3 (n = 24) received 2.5 mg/kg tulath­romycin. All treatments were administered once by subcu­taneous route. Following the treatments, mortality, feeding behavior, BRD recurrence treatment and body weights were evaluated. During SDs 0-to14-day post-treatment, 4 heifers in pradofloxacin treatment, 9 heifers in florfenicol plus flunixin treatment and 7 heifers in tulathromycin treatment died or were euthanized due to BRD. Over the 60-days, BRD-related mortality was 10, 15 and 11 animals in the pradofloxacin, florfenicol plus flunixin, and tulathromycin treatments, re­spectively. Heifers in the pradofloxacin treatment had a lower respiratory score on SD 3. Additionally, the pradofloxacin-treated heifers showed significantly longer feeding duration on SDs 1 and 4 (versus florfenicol plus flunixin), significantly higher head down duration SDs 1 and 4 (versus florfenicol plus flunixin), significantly higher feeding frequency on SD 1, and significantly higher dry matter intake (DMI) on SD 1. In con­clusion, pradofloxacin had demonstrably beneficial clinical and feeding behavior outcomes in BRD compared to florfeni­col plus flunixin and tulathromycin.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-02-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9299</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20269299</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 60 No. 1 (2026): ONLINE FIRST; 86-94</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9299/8925</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
