<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1930</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T00:39:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comments on the eradication of bovine brucellosis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nicoletti, Paul</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bacterial diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">brucellosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Disease control</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Disease prevention</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">eradication</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">epidemiology</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Some have suggested that any disease which can be eliminated from a herd can also be eradicated from a region and a nation. However illogical this conclusion, it is safe to state that the opposite is true. To eradicate disease, when possible, is surely wiser and ultimately cheaper. But, to promise eradication and fail to accomplish it results in cynicism and backlash. The promises of an early end of human venereal disease failed to consider the effects of changing sexual mores, drug resistant microbes, and inadequate reporting. The promises of eradication of brucellosis also failed to consider many factors which influence persistence of the disease.
It is unfair to suggest that eradication of one disease can be equated with eradication of another or that comparisons can be made between one region or an entire country to others. Conditions, including the technology of diseases, are often vastly different and these will prevent achievement of goals. The nature of a disease must be known and the methods for its manipulation must be based upon all available facts such as transmission, reservoirs, vaccines, economics, etc. There are many negative aspects in brucellosis control and eradication and some of these are further examined in this paper.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1980-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1930</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1980no15p111-114</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 15 (1980 November); 111-114</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1930/1922</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1980 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
