<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2332</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:57:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of limit-fed growing programs on finishing performance and carcass traits of steers in a commercial feedlot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rakestraw, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lusby, K. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Edwards, A. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">slaughter</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">weaned calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">limit feeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">weight</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">growing programs</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Seven hundred and sixty two spring-born Limousin x Hereford-Angus calves (535 lb) from one Nebraska ranch were weaned and shipped to a commercial feedlot in the Texas panhandle. Steers were randomly allotted by limit-fed a ration containing 61 Mcal NEg/CWT of DM to gain 2.20 lbs/day; (2) limit-fed a ration containing 66 Mcal NEg/CWT to gain 2.20 lb/day; or (3) ad libitum a ration containing 61 Mcal NEg/CWT until weight reached 750 lbs. All pens were switched to full feeding of a ration containing 66 Mcal NEg/CWT when the calves averaged 750 lbs. The first pen was slaughtered when visual conditions indicated that the majority of that pen would attain choice grade. All other pens were then slaughtered to approximate equal days from the end of the growing period. Gains during the growing period were 2.36 and 2.37 lbs/day for Treatment 1 and 2, compared to 2.79 lb/day for full-fed calves. Cost of gain was lowest for Treatment 2 and 3 calves during the growing period. Daily gains during finishing to greater for Treatments 1 and 2 compared to Treatment 3. The number of days from the time calves weighed 750 lbs to slaughter was similar (122 days) for all treatments. The total feeding period was 11 days longer for limit-fed calves. Daily gains for the total trial were not different although feed intake tended to be lowest for limit-fed calves. Cost of gain tended to favor limit- fed calves. Slaughter weight and carcass weights tended to be increased but quality and yield grades were not different. This study shows that weaned calves can be successfully grown on a commercial scale with high concentrate, limit-fed rations. No management problems related to the limit feeding procedure were noted.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1991-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2332</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1991no26p64-67</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 26 (1991 September); 64-67</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2332/7869</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1991 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
