<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2918</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T19:51:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Efficacy of a new sustained-release intraruminal selenium bolus</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Renquist, B. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oltjen, J. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sween, M. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Flavell, D. K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Maas, C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">selenium</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">supplementation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">intraruminal boolus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">blood chemistry</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">body weight</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">efficacy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">heifers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mineral supplements</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Our objective was to test the efficacy of a new sustained-release selenium (Se) bolus versus negative and positive control beef cattle. Fifty-five English breed heifers (mean initial body weight 546ñ46 lb; 248ñ 21 kg) were randomly assigned to one of four treatment groups: one 120-day, sustained-release selenium (Se) bolus on day 0 (A-1X); one 120-day, sustained-release Se bolus on day 0 and a second bolus on day 121 (A-2X); one 365-day, sustained-release Se bolus on day 0 (B); and control (C), no supplemental Se. Heifers grazed Se-deficient native foothill range without any additional supplement. Body weights and blood samples were taken for Se analysis from animals in all four groups at days -28, 14, 28, 49, 63, 121, 183, 293 and 365. No evidence of excess Se intake was observed. Both blood and weight data were analyzed in a model with Se treatment as the main effect; a log transformation for blood Se was used to make variances across treatments similar. Blood Se concentrations were similar amongst treatment groups on day -28. However, on days 14, 28, 49, 63, 121, 183, 293 and 365, blood Se concentrations were higher for the three supplemented groups relative to the control group (P&amp;lt;0.0001). On day 121, Groups A-2X and B had higher blood Se levels than Group A-1X (P=0.0001 and 0.0046, respectively). At days 183 and 293, Group A-2X had the highest blood Se concentrations (231.1ñ22.7 and 133.4ñ13.4 ng/ml), with Groups B (136.8ñ23.0 and 75.8ñ17.9 ng/ml), A-1X (114.3ñ16 and 34.8ñ8.8 ng/ml), and C (21.26ñ2.8 and 15.53ñ2.7 ng/ml) having descending Se blood concentrations, respectively. On day 365, Groups A-2X and B had blood Se concentrations above the 50 ng/ml that is considered deficient. Groups A-1X, A-2X and B gained 25.1, 51.0 and 25.7 lb (11.4, 23.2 and 11.7 kg) more than the 219.6 lb (99.8 kg) gain of the control group (P&amp;lt;0.001). Selenium supplementation provided sufficient mineral to raise blood Se concentrations above deficient levels. When compared with a single 120-day bolus, the single 365-day bolus prevented blood Se concentrations from falling to deficient levels for a longer period of time.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-06-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2918</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol41no2p134-137</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 41, No. 2 (2007 Summer); 134-137</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2918/2908</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 The Bovine Practitioner</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
