<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1723</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T19:26:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Acute trichomoniasis and sub-optimal bull fertility in a cow/calf herd: An investigation and case management</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Barling, K. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Field, R. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Snowden, K. F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hoevers, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef herds</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">breeding season</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bulls</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">culling</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">disease control</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fertility</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">infections</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parasites</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parasitoses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pregnancy rate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">protozoal infections</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive performance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">trichomoniasis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A beef cow/calf ranch contacted the veterinary teaching hospital concerning low pregnancy rates. The 600-cow herd consisted of three breeding groups of females, with each group being exposed to multiple-sire bull batteries for 90 days (April-June). Each breeding group was palpated for pregnancy approximately 60 days following bull removal from the cows. Pregnancy rates in the groups were 60, 25 and 41%. No abortions had been observed by management during or following the breeding season. Initial work-up found that each group of cows was in adequate body condition for reproduction. A high percentage of the ranch's bull population was positive for culture and polymerase chain reaction for Tritrichomonas foetus. In addition, a high percentage of the bull population failed to pass a breeding soundness examination. Treatment recommendations included culling the entire bull population and replacing it solely with virgin bulls that had passed a breeding soundness examination. Simultaneously, we recommended administration of a T. foetus vaccine to all females, followed by a vaccine booster dose 30 days later. All non-pregnant females were to be placed in separate breeding groups and exposed to the new bull population for 60 days (Dec-Jan). Palpation of non-pregnant females was to be performed 60 days following bull removal. The ranch followed these treatment recommendations. Following bull removal 60-day pregnancy rates were 95%. All replacement bulls passed a breeding soundness examination and were negative for T. foetus by polymerase chain reaction following exposure to the non-pregnant females. Ninety-eight percent of pregnant cows from the original bull exposure (April-June) delivered term calves.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2005-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1723</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol39no1p1-5</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 39, No. 1 (2005 February); 1-5</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1723/7706</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2005 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
