<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2295</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:55:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Dairy practitioners' opportunity to improve the cow's environment</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jones, Gordon A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cattle housing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Nutrition</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Performance is the new standard that dairy farms and dairy practitioners are being judged by. Everyday, a dairy practitioner has opportunities to view subpar performance of both the dairy livestock and the total system (housing, ventilation, feeding, cattle handling, etc.). Cow performance increases as the environment becomes more cow friendly. Many times, the environment may be healthy enough to keep the cow healthy, but not friendly enough to increase performance. Taking these opportunities and giving leadership to the dairy farm is rewarding to both the veterinarian and the dairyman.
There are four major reasons for improving the environment. First, we can improve the animal's health, both clinically and subclinically. Healthy animals are needed to perform optimally but they are not necessarily profitable animals unless managed profitably. Second, we can improve and measure the improvement of the animal's performance, i.e., pounds of milk per cow per day, rate of gain, reproductive efficiency and labor efficiency. Third, we can improve the operator's health and safety. The last reason is that we can improve the building's health and longevity.
Presented at the Dairy Herd Health Programming Conference, College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Minnesota, St. Paul, Minnesota, June 6-7, 1990</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1990-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2295</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no25p71-72</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 25 (1990 September); 71-72</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2295/2287</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1990 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
