<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1650</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T18:47:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Growth performance of cattle following percutaneous liver biopsy utilizing a Schackelford-Courtney biopsy instrument</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rogers, Glenn M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Capucille, Dawn J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Poore, Matthew H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Maas, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smallwood, James E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biopsy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnostic techniques</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feed conversion efficiency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feed intake</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">growth</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">liver</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Percutaneous liver biopsy has been utilized routinely in cattle as a diagnostic and research tool. However, there is little information on the effect on post-procedural performance. This paper describes a modified technique utilizing a Schackelford-Courtney bovine liver biopsy instrument, which generally obviates the need for multiple entries. Two trials were performed to evaluate post-procedural growth performance. In Trial 1, performed on finishing cattle, average daily gain (ADG) from the date the procedures (liver biopsy, ruminocentesis, orogastric intubation) were performed through the end of the 120-day finishing period was not different (p&amp;gt;0.25). However, calves that underwent the procedures had lower ADG, dry matter intake (DMI) and gain-to-feed ratio (G:F) (p&amp;lt;0.01) at Day 7 than calves that did not undergo the procedures. In Trial 2, a 112-day pasture study using stocker heifers, there were no significant differences at any weigh day (7, 28, 56, 84, 112) between liver-biopsied and non-biopsied groups. Results of the second trial suggest that differences seen in Trial 1 at Day 7 could have been related to other procedures performed concurrently (ruminocentesis, orogastric intubation), rather than the liver biopsy itself. In both studies, percutaneous liver biopsy was a relatively safe and effective procedure with minimal complications.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2001-06-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1650</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol35no2p177-184</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 35, No. 2 (2001 June); 177-184</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1650/7811</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2001 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
