<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2921</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T19:51:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of short-term exposure of feeder cattle to calves persistently infected with bovine viral diarrhea virus</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stevens, Elliot T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomson, Daniel U.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Loneragan, Guy H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lindberg, Nels</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BVDV</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">persistent infection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">morbidity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">carcass composition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">carcass quality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical aspects</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">heifers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">risk factors</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">steers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">viral diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Research using 2,954 auction-derived feeder steers and heifers was conducted at a single commercial feedlot in Kansas to determine the effects of testing for cattle persistently infected (PI) with bovine viral diarrhea virus (BVDV) at 10-14 days-on-feed (DOF), and removing them at 13-18 DOF. After removal of test-positive animals, the effect of the short-term exposure (STE) to PI cattle on health, performance and carcass characteristics was determined. The percentage of calves exhibiting signs of illness was increased (P&amp;lt;0.01) in cattle with STE to PI-BVDV. Cattle with no exposure (NE) to PI-BVDV calves had a morbidity rate of 18.8%, while a 29.6% morbidity rate was observed in pens of calves with STE to a PI-BVDV calf. Characterization of the temporal pen morbidity rate of STE and NE calves revealed that 31.7% of all STE and 15.3% of NE illness occurred in the first seven DOF. Additionally, the incidence of cattle treated for bovine respiratory disease in STE calves was 2.17 (95% CI 1.73 to 2.72) initial treatments per 1,000 head-days at risk, whereas the incidence of treatment of calves in NE pens was 1.28 (95% CI 0.98 to 1.68) initial treatments per 1,000 head-days at risk. Short-term exposure to PI-BVDV calves had no effect on retreatment rate, death loss, or performance. There was no evidence of a BVD-PI exposure X sex interaction (P=0.62) for carcasses that graded USDA Choice or better, but there was a main effect of sex (P&amp;lt;0.01). There was evidence of a BVD-PI exposure X sex interaction for Yield Grade 2 or greater carcasses (P=0.03). In this study, testing at 10-14 DOF was too late in the feeding period to eliminate the initial morbidity spike that occurred during 0-7 DOF, and the subsequent morbidity differences between calves with STE or NE to PI calves.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-06-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2921</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol41no2p151-155</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 41, No. 2 (2007 Summer); 151-155</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2921/2911</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 The Bovine Practitioner</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
