<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1297</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:08:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Practice development in the late 80's and the veterinarian's role: disease specialist or health specialist?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Neubauer, Gary D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Veterinary practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Profitable livestock production and the veterinarian’s role. Will this be a challenge or an opportunity? Ask yourself—am I a necessary evil or a partner in profits? Practice development in the future will rely heavily on the expanded role of the veterinarian as a health specialist and not just as a disease specialist. The veterinarian’s image needs to be reviewed as a part of profits not losses of the livestock enterprise. Finally, the veterinarian’s role as a herd health specialist needs to be looked on as: 1) a leader who is knowledgeable and respected, 2) as a partner who is trusted and reliable, and 3) as a business manager who is profit oriented.
A successful health specialist will be one who can utilize this knowledge of medicine and production and effectively communicate these ideas in such a way that the client understands them, accepts them, and implements them to the fullest extent toward efficient, profitable production.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1987-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1297</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no22p16-17</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 22 (1987 November); 16-17</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1297/1291</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1987 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
