<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/176</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T20:18:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Comparison of two Mannheimia haemolytica Immunization Programs in Feedlot Calves at High Risk of Developing Undifferentiated Fever/Bovine Respiratory Disease</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perrett, Tye</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wildman, Brian K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abutarbush, Sameeh M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pittman, Tom J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jones, Corey R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pollock, Colleen M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schunicht, Oliver C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Guichon, P. Timothy</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jim, G. Kee</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Booker, Calvin W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feedlot</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A field study was conducted to compare the relative effect of a Mannheimia haemolytica toxoid (Presponse® SQ, Wyeth Animal Health, Division of Wyeth Canada, Guelph, Ontario) and a Mannheimia haemolyticaPasteurella multocida bacterin~toxoid (Pulmo-guard™ PHM-1, Boehringer Ingelheim (Canada) Ltd., Burlington, Ontario). Upon arrival at the feedlot, 5,128 animals were enrolled in the study and randomly assigned to two experimental groups. Animals in the first group received Presponse® SQ (PSQ), while animals in the second group received Pulmo-guard™ PHM-1 (PHM-1). Animals in each experimental group were housed in separate pens with 10 pens per experimental group. With respect to morbidity, the first undifferentiated fever relapse, overall chronicity and overall wastage rates were significantly (P&amp;lt;0.05) lower in the PSQ group as compared to the PHM-1 group. There were no significant (P~0.05) differences in any of the other morbidity or mortality outcome variables between the experimental groups. In addition, there were no significant (P~0.05) differences in average daily gain or the dry matter intake-to-gain ratio between groups. The PSQ group had a higher proportion of carcasses grading YG Canada 3 (P&amp;lt;0.05) than the PHM-1 group. In the economic analysis, there was an advantage of $4.06 CDN/animal in the PSQ group. Based on these results, it is more cost-effective to use PSQ than PHM-1 in feedlot calves at high risk of developing bovine respiratory disease in western Canada.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2008-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/176</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol42no1p64-75</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 42, No. 1 (2008 Spring); 64-75</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/176/170</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2008 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
