<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9263</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-07-04T13:30:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of 3-, 6- and 9-day post-treatment intervals following pradofloxacin for treatment of bovine respiratory disease in stocker cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heinen, Lilli</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lubbers, Brian V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tessman, Ronald K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Amachawadi, Raghavendra G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">White, Brad J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antimicrobial</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BRD</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pradofloxacin</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Pradofloxacin is a fluroquinolone antimicrobial approved for treatment of bovine respiratory disease (BRD) in cattle in the United States. The primary objective of this study was to compare different post-treatment intervals (PTI) follow足ing therapy with pradofloxacin on first treatment success and case fatality in stocker cattle naturally affected with BRD. The days-to-death (DTD) following enrollment was evaluated as a secondary outcome. Cattle at 5 commercial stocker operations were identified with BRD by site personnel and were random足ized in a 1:1:1 ratio to 3-, 6- or 9-day PTI within each cohort. Following treatment with pradofloxacin, cattle were followed for 45 days to monitor health outcomes. First treatment suc足cess was defined as no additional treatment for BRD and no mortality. Case fatality was defined as death due to any cause. Generalized linear mixed models were used for statistical analysis. Weight at treatment and rectal temperature were not different between PTI groups. First treatment success (P = 0.51) and case fatality (P = 0.52) were not different among PTI treatment groups. DTD was not different between PTI treatment groups (P = 0.20). These results will assist with de足termining optimal use of pradofloxacin in stocker cattle.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-07-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9263</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20259263</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 59 No. 2 (2025): ONLINE FIRST; 47-52</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9263/8903</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
