<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8229</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-01-20T03:02:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparison of frontal-sinus and poll shot locations as  secondary methods for euthanizing dairy cattle with a  penetrating captive bolt gun</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Robbins, Jesse A. </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Williams, Rachel</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Derscheid, Rachel J. </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boyum, Brett</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Spangler, Conrad</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">euthanasia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anatomical landmarks</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal well-being</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">captive bolt gun</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">death</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">humane</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Humane euthanasia is a crucial component of dairy farm animal welfare programs. When using either a gunshot or captive bolt, the frontal-sinus area is well established as the primary shot location, but a secondary shot is often used as well. The objective of this study was to evaluate the efficacy of 2 different secondary shot locations. Cattle from a commercial dairy operation (n = 44) were randomly assigned to receive a secondary shot in the frontal-sinus or poll location and clinical signs of consciousness were assessed. A subsample of adult cattle heads (n = 6) were also evaluated to assess the extent of trauma. With the exception of heartbeat, all signs of sensibility were absent immediately following the first frontal-sinus shot and remained absent until confirmation of death, regardless of treatment (P &amp;gt; 0.05). Relatively fewer animals shot in the poll location had a heartbeat 5 min after being shot (P = 0.03). Pathology results on the subsample of adult cattle showed poll shots rarely penetrated beyond the cerebrum and only 1 of 6 animals had a severed brainstem. We conclude the frontal-sinus and poll locations are similarly effective secondary shot locations, and brainstem damage may not be necessary for irreversible insensibility and death.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8229</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol55no2p115-119</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 55 No. 2 (2021); 115-119</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8229/8153</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
