<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1335</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:08:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Case Report: Surgical correction of jejunal obstruction by ductus deferens (gut tie).</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weaver, A. David</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Case reports</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Digestive system diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Intestines</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Jejunum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Obstruction</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Surgery</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In a review of 129 cases of pelvic hernia due to this cause encountered over a period of 30 years, the majority were right-sided and were corrected by rectal manipulation and rupture of the occluding band. Laparotomy, however has been performed since 1813 and has been claimed to be the preferable method, in particular during the later years of the nineteenth century.
The condition of “gut tie” is described in detail including left flank laparotomy for section of the intra-abdominal strangulating cord by a bistoury.
This form of incarceration appears to be much less common today. In 100 cattle with intestinal obstruction Pearson found that the etiology involved inflammatory lesions caused by traction castration or traumatic lesions of the parietal peritoneum in only four cattle. Adhesions were not present in this current case. Similar obstructions of jejunoileal segments have been caused by a persistent hepatic round ligament, para-ovarian bands and vitello-umbilical bands or by adventitious fibroserosal cords. Differential diagnosis from such abdominal bands was impossible in this case but in retrospect might have been suspected since this particular band is more caudal than other forms reported in the past twenty years. It is doubtful whether it could have been ruptured by digital manipulation per rectum and such manipulation would also have been unnecessarily hazardous to the steer.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1987-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1335</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no22p168-169</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 22 (1987 November); 168-169</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1335/1329</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1987 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
