<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9296</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-02-07T16:12:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:DSCR</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Intestinal entrapment by ductus deferens remnant causing small intestinal obstruction in a steer</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Garcia, Jessica D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Miniard, Lyndsee</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Veerasammy, Brittany</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Neal, Casey E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mulon, Pierre-Yves</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">steer</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">acute abdomen</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">incarceration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">laparoscopy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">spermatic cord remnant</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">gut tie</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This report describes the successful treatment of a small in­testinal incarceration around the right ductus deferens and ileal impaction in a 9-month-old Jersey steer which was cor­rected in two sequential surgeries; exploratory laparotomy followed by standing laparoscopy with local anesthesia. The patient presented for a 3-day history of mild intermittent colic unresponsive to medical management on the farm. At pre­sentation, the steer was systemically stable other than a mild tachycardia and tachypnea attributed to pain along with in­termittent mild to moderate colic signs including stretching of the abdomen, extension of the neck, and flank watching. Transabdominal ultrasonography revealed ileus and distend­ed small intestine. Based on these findings, an exploratory laparotomy was pursued. A small intestinal incarceration due to an unidentified thin band was noted in the right caudal ab­domen. The incarceration was manually reduced, while the small intestines proximal to the strangulation were impacted necessitating an enterotomy. Following recovery from the laparotomy, a standing right flank laparoscopy was performed to identify the structure responsible for the incarceration: the right ductus deferens was transected to prevent future com­plications. The patient recovered uneventfully and was dis­charged. Previous reports of small intestinal strangulating le­sions in steers caused by spermatic cord remnants have been described with variable prognoses while the present case led to a favorable outcome for survival. Laparoscopic identifica­tion and division have not been previously described as a sur­gical option for resolution of remnant cords and may offer a new route of non-invasive correction if the anomaly cannot be safely transected blindly.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-02-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">250</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9296</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20269296</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 60 No. 1 (2026): ONLINE FIRST; 75-79</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9296/8922</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
