<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8810</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-03T23:13:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A survey of Mississippi cow-calf producers regarding factors associated with veterinarians performing bull breeding soundness evaluations and/or pregnancy diagnosis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gunderson, Todd G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jumper, W. Isaac</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">King, E. Heath</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Huston, Carla L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, David R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive efficiency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">producer survey</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Reproductive efficiency is a major driver of profitability in cow-calf herds, yet many beef producers do not hire veterinar­ians to perform services intended to improve reproductive ef­ficiency such as bull breeding soundness evaluation (BSE) or pregnancy diagnosis. The objective of this study was to deter­mine reasons Mississippi cow-calf producers do or do not hire veterinarians to perform these services. Anonymous surveys were mailed to 1,500 randomly selected members of the Missis­sippi Cattlemen’s Association. Multivariable logistic regression was used to test respondent characteristics for association with outcome variables (e.g., respondents hire a veterinarian for BSEs and/or pregnancy diagnosis). Of 414 returned surveys, 397 (96%) qualified for analysis for an overall response rate of 26%. Of respondents that answered the respective ques­tions, 155/386 (40%) hire a veterinarian for BSEs, and 103/392 (26%) hire a veterinarian for pregnancy diagnosis. Of 396 re­spondents, 229 (58%) indicated they had some form of a defined breeding season. The most common reasons for not hiring a veterinarian were lack of time/help (82/202, 41%) for BSEs and cost (91/248, 37%) for pregnancy diagnosis. On in­ferential analysis, the factors positively associated with hiring a veterinarian for BSEs were having a defined breeding season (OR = 6.8, 95% C.I. = 4.1-11.1) and raising seedstock cattle (OR = 1.7, 95%C.I. = 1.0-13.3). The only factor positively associ­ated with hiring a veterinarian for pregnancy diagnosis was having a defined breeding season (OR = 4.2, 95%C.I. = 2.5-7.3). Management style and operation type influenced producers hiring a veterinarian for BSEs and pregnancy diagnosis.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-02-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8810</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol58no1p41-50</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 58 No. 1 (2024); 41-50</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/8810/8538</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
