<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1702</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T19:11:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">An Evaluation of a treatment protocol for intramammary infections in early postpartum dairy cows based on a positive California Mastitis Test result</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wallace, J.A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stipetic, K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schukken, Y. H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingwell, R. T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baillargeon, P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bacic, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leslie, K. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">analytical methods</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">California mastitis test</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">control programmes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnostic techniques</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">disease control</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">disease prevention</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mammary gland diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mammary glands</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">postpartum period</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">somatic cell count</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Recent studies have evaluated the use of the California Mastitis Test (CMT) in early postpartum cows to identify intramammary infections (IMI). Whether the CMT is used to identify cows for culture or for herd-level udder health monitoring, many producers are in a dilemma when faced with a positive CMT result. The purpose of the study was to evaluate the effectiveness of an intramammary treatment protocol based on a positive CMT result within the first three days of calving. In addition, the effect of early intramammary antibiotic therapy on cure rates, linear somatic cell score (LS) and milk production for the first three Dairy Herd Improvement (DHI) tests postcalving were assessed. A total of 1861 quarters, representing 561 cows from 24 commercial herds, were enrolled. All quarters from each cow were tested by the dairy producer using the CMT, and sampled aseptically for milk bacteriology between calving and three days-in-milk (DIM). Cows with a positive CMT (n=180) were randomly assigned to receive either intramammary (IMM) cephapirin sodium, or no treatment. A CMT with any reaction was considered positive. All CMT-positive cows were sampled for bacteriological culture between 10-16 DIM to determine cure of infections. Cure rates were evaluated using data from 138 treated and 117 control quarters. Cure rates for all major pathogens for the treated and control group were 84.6 and 71.7%, respectively. This difference was not statistically significant. However, cure rates for environmental streptococcal infections for the treated and control group, 89.4 and 70.82%, respectively, were statistically different (P=0.05). Cows that recovered from infection with a major pathogen had a decrease in linear score. As LS decreased, milk production increased. When milk production was evaluated, it was demonstrated that as the CMT score increased, cows had a 2.1-kg decrease in milk production per test date. The antibiotic treatment groups were not significantly different for LS or milk production by the third test date. In conclusion, this fresh cow protocol was most effective to reduce IMI due to environmental streptococci and reduce LS. Therefore, blanket therapy of all CMT-positive cows may not be justified. Udder health status and predominant mastitis pathogen within the herd need to be considered when developing treatment protocols.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2004-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1702</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol38no1p72-78</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 38, No. 1 (2004 February); 72-78</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1702/7736</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2004 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
