<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9035</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-02T14:36:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:DSCR</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Case Report: Investigating an outbreak of tremorgenic mycotoxicosis in beef cows on pasture in Mississippi due to ergot (Claviceps paspali) infection in Dallisgrass (Paspalum dilatatum)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jumper, W. Isaac</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brown, Clare C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lee, Stephen T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cook, Daniel</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stilwell, Justin M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harvey, Kelsey M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ataxia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">plant toxicity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">staggers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tremors</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">&amp;nbsp;
The Mississippi State University College of Veterinary Medi­cine Ambulatory Service examined a 3-year-old Charolais-cross cow on October 19, 2023, for lateral recumbency, inabil­ity to rise and generalized tremors. Within 4 hours following initial case discovery, 20 additional cases were discovered in 2 adjacent pastures, including one mortality. Clinical signs ranged in severity from mild tremors to severe ataxia, hy­perexcitability, aggression, lateral recumbency and death. All affected cows had calved in the spring of 2023, and all 2023 spring calves were weaned 3 days prior on October 16. Overnight on October 16-17, one group of cows pushed down a fence, and 32 cows entered a pasture adjacent to their weaned calves. Following discovery of cases on October 19, all cattle were removed from the affected pasture and grass hay was provided immediately. Necropsy of 2 affected animals as well as serum chemistries of 5 affected cows revealed non-specific findings. However, abundant dallisgrass (Paspalum dilatatum) with obvious Claviceps paspali infection was present on the pasture that the cattle entered overnight on October 16-17. High-performance liquid chromatography-mass spectrom­etry (HPLC-MS) analysis of samples collected from C. paspali infected pasture as well as rumen and abomasum contents collected at necropsy revealed several tremorgenic indole di­terpene alkaloids. Additionally, DNA metabarcoding of rumen contents and forage samples confirmed the ingestion of dallis­grass infected with C. paspali. Upon recheck on October 20, all previously affected cows appeared to be recovering, and com­plete resolution of clinical signs had occurred by October 23.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-08-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">250</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9035</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20249035</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2024); 59-68</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9035/8721</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
