<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2471</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T00:44:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Screening tests for abnormal milk and physical examination of the udder</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heider, Lawrence E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk test</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">abnormalities</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">infection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">udder</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Many tests have been described for use in detecting abnormal milk. These include: black plate or strip cup, catalase test, (modified) Whiteside test, serum albumin, milk chloride, electrical conductivity, California Mastitis Test (CMT), Wisconsin Mastitis Test (WMT), Direct Microscopic Somatic Cell Count (DMSCC) and Electronic Somatic Cell Counts (ESCC). In summary, the black plate is still a useful tool for the examination of lactating cows to detect clinical mastitis.
The CMT Test is a useful cowside test for detecting subclinical infections.
ESCC provides useful information for assessing the prevalence of subclinical infection and for regular evaluation of mastitis control practices.
Examination of the udder may be indicated. Udder palpation is not as important in the current scheme of management of cows as it may have been in the past but could still provide useful additional indications for culling decisions.
Teat end lesions may be reduced by avoiding chemical irritation and faulty machine function. However, teat end appearance may be related to high production and, depending on degree, is not always an indication of unusual trauma.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1983-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2471</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1983no18p7-12</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 18 (1983 November); 7-12</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2471/2463</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1983 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
