<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1325</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:08:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Plasma transfusions in failure of colostral immunoglobulin transfer (1)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson, K. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hunt, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fleming, S. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">blood</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Blood plasma</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Blood transfusion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Colostral immunity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Immunity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">plasma</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Partial or complete failure of colostral immunoglobulin transfer (FCIT) is frequently encountered in neonatal calves and is associated with increased morbidity and mortality. Therapy for FCIT and associated diseases may include administration of antimicrobials, fluids, various supportive measures and attempts to restore protective levels of circulating immunoglobulins (Ig). Because FCIT is frequently encountered after gut closure to absorption of exogenous Ig, administration of Ig in plasma or whole blood has been used to restore protective levels of Ig. Recommendations for plasma administration to neonatal calves are empirical and have been based upon practices commonly used in neonatal foals. A commonly recommended dose is administration of plasma at 20ml/kg body weight.
In the present study, plasma administration was studied in newborn calves with FCIT. The purposes of the study were: 1.) To determine if administration of plasma at 20ml/kg would produce protective levels of circulating Ig in calves with FCIT; and 2.) To compare levels of circulating Ig in calves administered plasma IP once, IV once, and IV twice with 7 days between dosing. In addition, calves with FCIT and administered plasma were compared to calves receiving colostrum.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1987-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1325</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no22p129-130</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 22 (1987 November); 129-130</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1325/1319</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1987 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
