<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/351</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T20:38:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Characterization of Specific Passive Immunity Stimulated by Vaccination of Beef Cows Grazing Native Range with E. coli 0157:H7-SRP®</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wileman, B. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomson, D. U.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Olson, KC</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pacheco, L. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jaeger, J. R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Burkhardt, D. T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sandstorm, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Emery, D. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">E.coli O157:H7</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">SRP</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">passive immunity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food safety</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A total of 20 four-year-old, mixed breed cows were selected from the Kansas State University commercial cow-calf herd for this study. Cows were assigned randomly to one of two treatments: placebo, or E. coli O157:H7 SRP® (Epitopix LLC, Wilmar, MN) vaccination prior to calving. Serum total protein (TP) and serum Escherichia coli O157:H7 SRP® antibody levels (SRP) were measured pre-suckle and at set intervals post-suckle in calves. All 20 cows were negative for fecal shedding of E. coli O157:H7 throughout the study. Vaccination of cows had no effect on calf serum TP level (P &amp;gt; 0.05) compared to controls, however, length of time post-birth had a significant effect on calf serum TP levels (P &amp;lt; 0.001). Failure of passive transfer was recognized as early as six hours post-birth. A vaccine treatment by time post-birth interaction was observed for calf serum SRP® antibody levels (P &amp;lt; 0.01). Calves born to dams vaccinated with E. coli O157:H7 SRP® vaccine had elevated serum SRP antibody titers over time compared to placebo vaccinated calves. This study demonstrated that successful E.coli O157:H7 SRP® antibody passive transfer can occur in beef calves under natural range conditions. This could be the first step toward understanding life cycle immunization strategies against E. coli O157:H7 in cattle, and its effects on shedding of the organism by the animal at the time of harvest.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2010-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/351</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol44no1p12-16</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 44, No. 1 (2010 Spring); 12-16</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/351/347</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2010 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
