<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2919</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T19:51:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of frequent functional foot trimming on the incidence of lameness in lactating dairy cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, B. I.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kristula, M. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">frequent functional foot trimming</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sole ulcer</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lameness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">epidemiology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">foot diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hooves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">incidence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lactation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A 36-month field trial was conducted to determine the effect of frequent functional foot trimming on lameness. Six hundred and thirty-eight (638) lactating dairy cattle in a southwestern Pennsylvania commercial herd were subjected to functional foot trimming either once a year (control group - CG) or three times a year (foot treatment group - FTG). FTG cattle were trimmed as a group in May, September and January; CG cattle were trimmed at dry-off. All cattle were managed the same during the trial period. The overall reduction in all foot lameness by treatment was 27% when controlling for a previous history of lameness and lactation number, but results were not significant (P=0.15). Cows in the FTG group were 52% less likely to develop a sole ulcer compared to CG cows (P=0.05). Overall, cows with a previous history of lameness were 6.4 times more likely to become lame and 3.1 times more likely to develop a sole ulcer. There was no difference in risk of being culled between FTG and CG cows. In addition, there was no difference in lameness for first-lactation heifers (prospective heifers) assigned to either the FTG or CG after the study began, suggesting that more research is needed to establish the benefit of a single functional foot trimming compared to an untreated control group in first-lactation heifers. Although results from this study and others suggest a reduction in lameness for cows trimmed more frequently than once a year, further studies with larger numbers of cows from multiple herds are needed to make definitive conclusions regarding the overall benefit of frequent functional foot trimming.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-06-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2919</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol41no2p138-145</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 41, No. 2 (2007 Summer); 138-145</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2919/2909</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 The Bovine Practitioner</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
