<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9289</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-12-29T19:28:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A comparison of tildipirosin to tulathromycin as the first treatment for naturally occurring bovine respiratory disease using a 3-day posttreatment moratorium</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hagenmaier, Jacob A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Terrell, Shane P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lukasiewicz, Kip. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomson, Daniel U.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bryant, Lonty K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feedlot</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tildipirosin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tulathromycin</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Macrolide antibiotics are commonly selected for treatment of bovine respiratory disease (BRD) in conventional feedlot production systems. A randomized complete block design study was used to evaluate the relative efficacy of tildipirosin (TILD) and tulathromycin (TULA) for first treatment of natu­rally occurring cases across 4 commercial feedlots in central Nebraska. A total of 940 beef steers and heifers (668 ± 136 lbs) were enrolled in the study during a 5-month period beginning September of 2019. Cattle diagnosed with BRD and satisfying enrollment criteria were assigned to treatment using a lot-level randomization. Data were analyzed using linear mixed models and generalized linear mixed models. Enrollment body weight, rectal temperature and days-on-feed were simi­lar for cattle regardless of assigned BRD treatment (P ≥ 0.1373). There was no difference in BRD first treatment success (P = 0.9866) or subsequent treatment success (P ≥ 0.6404) between the antibiotics. Case fatality and railer rate also did not differ (P ≥ 0.7924) between TILD and TULA cattle. Carcass data were obtained from the abattoir on a subset of cattle (n = 531), and no characteristics were different between treatments (P ≥ 0.5139). The results of this study suggest similar efficacy of tulathromycin and tildipirosin for first treatment of naturally occurring bovine respiratory disease in commercial cattle.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-12-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9289</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20269289</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 60 No. 1 (2026): ONLINE FIRST; 48-53</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9289/8918</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
