<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9460</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-05-19T17:22:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A randomized trial comparing the effectiveness of tulathromycin, tulathromycin + ketoprofen, and tildipirosin for treatment of naturally occurring bovine respiratory disease in feedlot cattle that did not receive metaphylaxis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McAtee, Taylor B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bryant, Lonty K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Spore, Tyler J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Renter, David G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="es">`</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">macrolide</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Arovyn</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Draxxin KP</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Zuprevo</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Our objective was to compare the relative effectiveness of three macrolide antimicrobials for the initial treatment of bo­vine respiratory disease (BRD) in medium-risk feedlot steers and heifers that did not receive metaphylaxis. Steers and heif­ers (n = 704; 734 ± 111 lb [333 ± 50 kg]) were enrolled at a com­mercial Kansas feedlot. Animals were eligible for inclusion if they exhibited clinical signs of BRD from natural exposure and had not previously received any antimicrobial treatment, including metaphylaxis, at the feedlot. At the time of first BRD diagnosis, individual animals were randomly allocated to be administered treatment with either tulathromycin, tulathro­mycin + ketoprofen, or tildipirosin. General and generalized linear mixed models, accounting for time and lot, were used for statistical analyses. At enrollment, initial body weight (P = 0.40), rectal temperature (P = 0.50), and days on feed (P = 0.24) did not differ significantly between treatments. There was no evidence of differences in any morbidity outcome during the first 60 days after enrollment, the first 100 days after enroll­ment, or through closeout (P ≥ 0.14). Likewise, there was no evidence of differences in any mortality outcome across these same evaluation periods (P ≥ 0.41). Treatment success, defined as animals that were not retreated and did not die, ranged from 74.46% to 75.45% through closeout (P = 0.96). In medium-risk feedlot cattle managed without on-arrival metaphylaxis, no differences in morbidity or mortality outcomes were ob­served among the three macrolide treatments – tulathromy­cin, tulathromycin + ketoprofen, or tildipirosin.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9460</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20269460</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 60 No. 2 (2026): Online First; 41-52</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9460/9065</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
