<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1241</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:02:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Field studies of protective shelters for beef calves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Olson, David P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">environment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cold exposure</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">death</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">shelters</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nutrition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">survival</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">For the past 8 years, research scientists at the University of Idaho have conducted a series of controlled experiments designed to determine the effects of cold exposure on young calves. This work stemmed, in part, from field observations suggesting an association between exposure of calves to cold temperatures and excessive moisture under field conditions and incidence of the ‘weak calf syndrome’. Results of the experiments indicated that young calves are highly susceptible to the effects of cold exposure and that this stressor may be a direct or indirect cause of death of these animals. Life-threatening changes observed in severely cold stressed calves include subnormal body temperature, decreased concentration of blood glucose, decreased total number of leukocytes in blood, temporary failure of calves to absorb colostral immunoglobulins, and decreased aortic blood pressure and heart rate. Respiratory failure is the usual cause of death of severely cold stressed calves. Other changes commonly observed in cold-exposed young calves include intensive shivering, physical weakness, depression, reluctance to nurse, changes in concentration of blood constituents other than glucose, and extensive hemorrhage and straw-colored edema beneath the skin of the extremities.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1241</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no21p19-22</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 21 (1986 November); 19-22</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1241/1232</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
