<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/193</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T21:12:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of outcomes in beef cattle comparing preventive health protocols utilizing viral respiratory vaccines</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tripp, Holt M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Step, D. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Krehbiel, Clinton R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Moberly, Heather K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Malayer, Jerry R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">virus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccines</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Vaccination to reduce the occurrence of bovine respiratory disease is a commonly performed preventive health measure employed by veterinarians and beef cattle producers. Despite its widespread acceptance, evidence relating health and performance outcomes of receiving and feedlot cattle to vaccination for viral components of the bovine respiratory disease complex remains to be completely established. PubMed, CAB Abstracts, and The Bovine Practitioner were searched for peer-reviewed journal articles reporting field trials of viral respiratory vaccines utilizing naturally occurring disease models published in English between 1982 and 2012. Antigens of interest for this systematic review included bovine herpesvirus-1, parainfluenzavirus type 3, bovine viral diarrhea virus types 1 and 2, bovine respiratory syncytial virus, and bovine coronavirus. Search results were also reviewed for manuscripts reporting the effects of timing on viral respiratory vaccine efficacy in receiving and feedlot cattle. Studies were included in this review only if they reported clinically relevant outcomes, which were defined as morbidity, mortality, rates of chronic illness, lung lesions identified at necropsy or harvest, and performance parameters including average daily gain and feed-to-gain ratios.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2013-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/193</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol47no1p54-64</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 47, No. 1 (2013 Spring); 54-64</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/193/202</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2013 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
