<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2578</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T00:23:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Water Buffalo: Domestic Animal of the Future</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cockrill, W. Ross</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">buffaloes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">meat productin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk production</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The water buffalo (Bubalus bubalis) is a neglected bovine animal with a notable and so far unexploited potential, especially for meat and milk production. World buffalo stocks, which at present total 150 million in some 40 countries, are increasing steadily.
&amp;nbsp;It is important that national stocks should be upgraded by selective breeding allied to improved management and nutrition but, from the standpoint of increased production and the full realization of potential, it is equally important that crossbreeding should be carried out extensively especially in association with schemes to increase and improve buffalo meat production.
Meat from buffaloes which are reared and fed for early slaughter is of excellent quality. Because the buffalo is a superb converter, meat can be produced at lower cost than with cattle and without the need for expensive fodders and concentrates.
There is growing interest, in both the advanced and the developing countries, in the full exploitation of the domestic water buffalo, as is shown by the expanding international trade in breeding stock and the establishment of many new herds in countries where the buffalo is a newcomer. The upsurge of international interest and activity is not yet shared by the United States, though the future for this attractive, tractable, and productive animal is one of undoubted and outstanding promise.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1977-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2578</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1977no12p92-98</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 12 (1977 November); 92-98</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2578/2570</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1977 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
