<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1591</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T02:45:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Efficacy of Serpens spp bacterin combined with topical administration of lincomycin hydrochloride for treatment of papillomatous digital dermatitis (footwarts) in cows on a dairy in California</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Berry, Steven L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Graham, Thomas W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mongini, Andrea</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Arana, Marit</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dermatitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">foot diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunization</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lincomycin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">skin diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lincosamide antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The objective of this prospective, randomized field trial was to determine if a Serpens spp bacterin had a therapeutic effect on cows with active lesions of papillomatous digital dermatitis (PDD) before or in combination with treatment with topical lincomycin HCl on a California dairy. Fifty-nine lactating cows with active, painful PDD were randomly assigned to control (not vaccinated) and vaccinated groups. Lesions of the rear feet were evaluated for pain response, color, size, and lesion scores at each of the examinations. Cows in the vaccinated group were vaccinated 3 times with a Serpens spp bacterin (days 1, 14, 43). All cows were restrained on a hydraulic tilt table at approximately day 30 and, after examination, all lesions were treated with a slurry containing 3.2 g of lincomycin mixed with 3 ml of deionized water. The slurry was applied to cotton gauze and held in place with an elastic bandage. Bandages were allowed to wear off. Lesions were re-examined while cows were locked in stanchions at approximately days 50 and 70 and while restrained on the hydraulic tilt table on approximately day 110. Lesions improved on all cows during the course of the trial. Lesion and size scores were improved for control and vaccinated cows on days 50, 70, and 110. Pain response and color scores improved on days 50 and 70 but showed evidence of recurrence or recrudescence by day 110. There were no significant differences in evaluated scores between control and vaccinated cows at any of the examination times. When affected cows were re-examined at day 110, recurrence or recrudescence of lesions was evident in 41% of the control cows and 45% of the vaccinated cows. Vaccination of PDD affected cows with Serpens spp bacterin had no apparent effect on clinical outcome.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1999-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1591</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol33no1p6-11</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 33, No. 1 (1999 January); 6-11</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1591/1584</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1999 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
