<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1306</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:08:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bovine herd health programmes : state of the art and science</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Radostits, Otto M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Computers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Veterinary services</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">DISEASE CONTROL</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine veterinary practice has changed and continues to change from emphasis on the diagnosis and treatment of the individual animal to increased emphasis on the health and production of the herd. However, herd health service is not yet a major component of most bovine practices. The knowledge and skills are available for the veterinarian to provide varying levels of planned animal health and production management. The factors which have impeded the delivery of a totally integrated herd health service to cattle producers include those related to the desire of the farmer to adopt a regularly scheduled herd health service, the economic viability of the herd, the market price for beef and milk, the enthusiasm and competence of the veterinarian and, the data recording system. The widespread use of the veterinarian in a herd health program will depend on the development of species-industry veterinary specialists. Veterinarians must show integrated animal health and production management service. Computers allow the collection and analysis of the animal health and production data required to identify problem areas and to make intelligent decisions about changes in management.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1987-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1306</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no22p46-54</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 22 (1987 November); 46-54</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1306/1300</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1987 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
