<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9459</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-05-18T17:39:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of the shed and spread of infectious bovine rhinotracheitis, parainfluenza-3 and bovine respiratory syncytial virus in young calves post-intranasal vaccination</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bromm, Jenna J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cull, Charley A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lechtenberg, Kelly F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Singu, Vijay K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Seagren, Jon E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Amachawadi, Raghavendra G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Swafford, William S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Braun, Douglas A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BRSV</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">IBR</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">PI3</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Histophilus somni</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">intranasal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neonatal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Intranasal vaccines are critical for early prevention of re­spiratory diseases in neonatal calves; however, concerns remain regarding potential transmission of vaccine virus strains to unvaccinated commingled animals, particularly in high-stress environments where vaccination history may be unknown. This study evaluated the presence, duration and shedding of infectious bovine rhinotracheitis (IBR), parainflu­enza virus type 3 (PI3), and bovine respiratory syncytial virus (BRSV) in nasal secretions of intranasally vaccinated calves and transmission to commingled unvaccinated controls. Three commercially available intranasal vaccines, Inforce 3® (Zoetis), Nasalgen® 3-PMH (Merck), and PrimeLine® IN5 (Huvepharma), were evaluated. Holstein-cross, mixed-sex, colostrum-deprived calves, seronegative and PCR-negative for IBR, PI3 and BRSV, were enrolled. Blood samples were col­lected on days 0 and 21 to measure antibody titers using viral serum neutralization assays. Nasal swabs were collected daily from days 0 to 21 and analyzed by PCR for IBR, PI3 and BRSV. Nasal swabs were also tested for Histophilus somni by PCR to assess prevalence. Calves were randomly assigned to 4 groups housed in separate biosafety level 2 rooms. Each vaccine group contained commingled, inoculated and non-inoculated calves. A fourth sentinel group was monitored for wild-type virus or biosecurity breaches. Intranasal vaccination resulted in detectable virus in nasal secretions and transmission to commingled non-inoculated calves. Seroconversion in inocu­lated and non-inoculated calves confirmed vaccine virus shed­ding and pen-level spread. These findings demonstrate that intranasal vaccine strains can complicate diagnostic interpre­tation during respiratory disease investigations, underscoring the importance of vaccination history when distinguishing vaccine-derived from wild-type viruses in clinical and research settings.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9459</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20269459</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 60 No. 2 (2026): Online First; 32-40</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9459/9064</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
