<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2261</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:41:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Assessment of sodium deficiency and polyuria/polydipsia in dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Olson, W. G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Link, K. R. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Otterby, D. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stevens, J. B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">deficiency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Minerals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Nutrient deficiencies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">polyuria</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Sodium</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Thirst</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Urination disorders</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sodium (Na) deficiency was observed as a cause of decreased production and associated with polyuria/polydipsia (PU/PD) in a herd of dairy cows. Subsequent investigations revealed other herds experiencing milk loss due to Na deficiency, however PU/PD was not observed in all cases. To further study Na deficiency and diagnostic tests to confirm a diagnosis of NaCl deficiency, sixteen mid-to-late lactation dairy cows were divided into 2 groups for a 30 day Na depletion study. The control group (C) received 0.75% NaCl in their concentrate while the deficient group (E) was fed a ration without supplemental Na. There was a significant difference in production decline (9.5% vs. 29.3%) between C (25.1 to 22.7 kg) and E (18.8 to 13.3 kg). A significant difference in urine Na was observed between C vs. E (29.7 to 21.4 vs. 43.4 to 1.8 mEq/L) and in faecal excretion of Na (FENa) of C vs. E (0.357 to 0.205 vs. 0.329 to 0.016%). A significant decline in serum K was demonstrated between C vs. E (4.43 to 4.61 to 1.8 mEq/l, P&amp;lt;0.01), while FEK increased (39.27 to 36.68 vs. 39.47 to 50.78%). There were no significant differences observed in serum Na or other serum parameters between groups. The diagnostic values of FENa and urine Na determinations was very high. A significant difference between control and depleted animals in both determinations was observed in both experimental and field conditions. Therefore the simple determination of urinary Na concentration in a herd of lactating dairy cows can be used to diagnose Na deficiency. Sampling of 5 high producing cows could be recommended since they would be at greatest risk of deficiency in borderline salt supplementation situations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1989-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2261</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no24p128-133</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 24 (1989 November); 128-133</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2261/2253</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1989 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
