<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2475</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T00:44:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Changing patterns of nutritional myodegeneration (white muscle disease) in cattle in Great Britain</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bradley, R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson, P. H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wilesmith, J. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Muscular dystrophy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Great Britain</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">UK</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diet</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Analysis of data accumulated between 1975-1980 from a computer bank of diagnoses of cattle disease occurring on farms in Great Britain, and from pathological and biochemical examinations revealed nutritional myodegeneration to be the most frequently reported and probably the most economically important myopathy. Reported disease incidence increased between 1976 and 1979. The increase in incidence was relatively greater in yearlings and adults than in calves in which the disease predominates. In calves 3 clinical syndromes (dyspnoea; locomotor and postural disorders; sudden death) were recognized. The presenting signs in yearlings were locomotor or postural disorders; in cows they resembled milk fever. In weaned calves and yearlings disease risk increased in the spring and was frequently associated with turnout to pasture in adverse weather. The commonest environmental associations with the disease are dietary deficiencies of selenium, vitamin E or both, coupled with cold, wet and windy weather, sudden increased exercise, and in cows, bad management and parturition. Changing methods of feeding, increases in herd size and increased awareness are possible reasons for the increased incidence. Risk of the disease developing can be reduced by Se supplementation.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1983-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2475</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1983no18p30-32</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 18 (1983 November); 30-32</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2475/2467</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1983 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
