<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1743</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-30T19:35:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Survey of the relationship between management practices and risk of acute interstitial pneumonia at US feedlots</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Woolums, Amelia R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Loneragan, Guy H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hawkins, Larry L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Williams, Shamita M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal husbandry</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feedlots</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">morbidity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mortality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pneumonia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">risk</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Acute interstitial pneumonia (AIP) is a recognized cause of feedlot morbidity and mortality, but the cause is unknown. Management practices have been suggested to contribute to the pathogenesis of AIP, but little supportive data exists. A cross-sectional survey of US feedlots evaluated the relationship between management practices and subjective and objective measures of AIP risk. Of 65 respondents, 75.4% recognized AIP as a cause of morbidity or mortality in their feedlot. Managers reported that 80.5% of AIP deaths occurred in cattle on feed over 60 days, 62% of AIP deaths occurred in the summer and 62.2% of AIP deaths were heifers. Thirty-three feedlots reported the percent of placements that died of AIP, which ranged from 0.001-0.75%. Feedlots in northern states were less likely to report AIP as a cause of morbidity/mortality, while larger feedlots and feedlots placing higher proportions of yearlings more often recognized AIP as a cause of morbidity/mortality. Although heifers were recognized to account for 62% of AIP deaths, feedlots placing a large proportion of heifers were not more likely to recognize AIP as a cause of morbidity/mortality than feedlots placing a small proportion of heifers. Feedlots that vaccinated over 95% of cattle for Mannheimia haemolytica/Pasteurella multocida were less likely to recognize AIP as a cause of morbidity/mortality than feedlots who vaccinated less than 95% of cattle for these pathogens. The percent of cattle dying of AIP in feedlots that vaccinated over 95% of cattle for Mannheimia/Pasteurella was 0.06%, compared to 0.14% for feedlots vaccinating less than 95% of cattle for these pathogens. Although these data must be interpreted in light of the limitations of a survey as a data collection device, results suggest the impact of feedlot location and size, animal gender and vaccination strategy merit further scrutiny in research to determine the cause of feedlot AIP.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2005-06-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1743</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol39no2p125-133</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 39, No. 2 (2005 June); 125-133</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1743/7704</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2005 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
