<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1599</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T02:45:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Association between selected metabolic parameters and left displaced abomasum in dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Geishauser, T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leslie, K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Duffield, T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Edge, V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">3-hydroxybutyric acid</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">abomasum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">aspartate aminotransferase</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">blood chemistry</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">enzymes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parturition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">risk factors</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The association between selected metabolic parameters and subsequent left displaced abomasum (LDA) diagnosis in dairy cows was investigated in 44 LDA cows sampled in the third week before calving (a.p.), which was at a median of 34 days before LDA diagnosis; 36 LDA cows were sampled in the first week after calving (p.p.), which was at a median of 14 days before; and 28 LDA cows were sampled in the second week p.p., which was at a median of 9 days before LDA diagnosis were used. Each case was matched to 3 controls by herd and calving date. Data were available from a large field study. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) activity, the concentrations of beta-hydroxybutyrate (BHB), glucose, calcium and urea in blood, and the body condition score (BCS) were monitored. Logistic regression was used to analyse the association between these parameters and subsequent LDA, adjusting for the effects of parity and pretreatment. A separate model was used for each sampling week and each parameter. In the third week a.p., none of the parameters were significantly associated with LDA. AST and BHB sampled in the first week p.p. and in the second week p.p. were significantly associated with LDA diagnosis. The higher the AST and BHB the higher the odds of being diagnosed subsequently with LDA. The lower glucose and Ca in the second week p.p. the higher the odds of subsequent LDA diagnosis. Urea and BCS were not significantly associated with LDA in any of the weeks examined. It is concluded that AST and BHB in the first and second week p.p. might be used as tests for developing LDA.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1999-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1599</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol33no1p63-66</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 33, No. 1 (1999 January); 63-66</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1599/1592</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1999 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
