<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9500</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-13T19:03:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of six commercial test strips for measuring nitrate in cattle drinking water</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hirsch, Brittany A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hanthorn, Christy J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Charnas, Savannah R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sanderson, Mike W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Temaat, Matt</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fritz, Scott A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nitrate toxicoses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drinking water</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">colorimetric strip testing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">screening test</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Nitrate toxicosis from contaminated drinking water is a com­mon cause of acute death in cattle. The objective of this study was to determine if commercially available semi-quantitative colorimetric test strips designed for human drinking water can be used as a screening test to identify elevated nitrate con­centrations in cattle drinking water. Six test strip brands were used to measure nitrate concentrations in water samples with known values. Sample concentrations were prepared and veri­fied via ion chromatography. Ten volunteers were instructed to test water samples and record nitrate levels according to the test strip manufacturer’s instructions. There was no sig­nificant effect of evaluator or evaluator sex. Results were di­chotomized where targeted nitrate concentrations ≥ 100 ppm were considered positive and &amp;lt; 100 ppm negative, resulting in a 50% proportion of positive samples. Sensitivities of the tests ranged from 22.5% to 97.5%. Two brands resulted in few false negatives when screening water samples with sensitivities of 97.5% and 90%, two brands resulted in a moderate number of false negatives with sensitivities of 77.5% and 72.5%, and two brands resulted in numerous false negatives with sensi­tivities of 47.5% and 22.5%. These findings suggest that while some commercially available test strips can be an effective and economical option for producers and veterinarians to utilize for screening water sources for nitrate contamination, others may pose a risk of underestimating harmful nitrate levels. Water samples with nitrate concentrations reaching or exceeding 100 ppm on test strips should undergo confirmatory testing via quantitative analysis.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9500</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20269500</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 60 No. 2 (2026): Online First; 53-59</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9500/9100</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
