<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9291</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-01-11T17:29:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of a novel method of castration for calves: A pilot study</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schumacher, Jacob J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bortoluzzi, Eduarda M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cull, Charley A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Coetzee, Johann F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">castration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pain</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">banding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Physical castration of male calves is a standard management practice that causes pain. ClipFitter is a novel castration clip that combines the attributes of Burdizzo and band castration, which could reduce failures and improve welfare, respec­tively. This randomized, blinded, controlled pilot study aimed to determine the viability of the ClipFitter in cattle and its ef­fects on pain and welfare. Twelve intact male beef-dairy cross calves weighing 184 ± 1.8 lb (83.8 ± 0.8 kg) were assigned to 1 of 3 treatment groups: castration with ClipFitter (CLIP; n = 4), castration with rubber ring band (BAND; n = 4), or no castra­tion (SHAM; n = 4). Calves’ plasma cortisol, Substance P, lie/ stand behavior and infrared thermography were assessed at multiple timepoints. Infrared thermography images of the scrotum showed a treatment by time interaction, with calves in the CLIP group exhibiting significantly lower scrotal tem­perature than calves in the SHAM group at 7 d post-castration (P &amp;lt; 0.05). Lying and standing outcomes were not significantly different between CLIP and BAND groups (P &amp;gt; 0.05). There were no significant differences in plasma cortisol or Sub­stance P concentrations between treatments (P &amp;gt; 0.05). The decreased scrotal temperatures observed in the CLIP group at d 7 suggests a decrease in blood flow to the testicles, therefore implying that the ClipFitter device could potentially be a vi­able method of castration for cattle. The welfare implications of the ClipFitter device in cattle require further evaluation.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-01-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9291</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20269291</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 60 No. 1 (2026): ONLINE FIRST; 59-66</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9291/8920</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
