<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2230</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T00:56:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Aspects of treatment of severe claw diseases in a large animal practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Surborg, H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">FOOT DISEASES</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Lameness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Local anaesthesia</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper reports on causes of lameness in cattle due to severe claw disease, on methods of restraint and anesthesia for their treatment and on the treatment itself in a large animal practice. Intravenous anesthesia can easily be carried out on the raised leg of the sedated animal. In the case of phalangeal joint involvment, puncture of these joints will give information about subsequent treatment. A wooden block attached to the unaffected claw will give relief to the treated one.
About 90% of all cause of lameness in cattle derive from the claw area. Hoof diseases are still an important economical factor in raising cattle and quite often they are the cause for selling these animals. Amstutz(1974) estimated the economic loss due to lameness of dairy-cows in the USA at $150. In most cases the patient is not presented for veterinary treatment until the animal is extremely lame. The milk yield is already reduced significantly and the patient has rapidly lost weight and the general state of health is affected.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2230</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1984no19p227-229</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 19 (1984 November); 227-229</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2230/2222</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
