<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1411</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:13:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Comparison of fenprostalene and oxytetracycline as treatment for retained fetal membranes in dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Callahan, C. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Horstman, L. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Frank, D. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Fenprostalene</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Oxytetracycline</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Placental retention</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Puerperal disorders</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Synthetic prostaglandins</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Retained fetal membranes (RFM) is a common postpartum disorder of the reproductive system of dairy cows. The incidence, etiology, consequences, treatment and prevention of RFM have been thoroughly discussed. Agreement on the best way to manage and treat RFM is not unanimous. Management and treatment schemes are numerous, and there are proponents of each. Regimes of therapy include no treatment, intrauterine antibacterials, systemic antibacterials, uterine contractants, manual removal, no manual removal and various combinations. At the present time the most widely used treatment for RFM is probably intrauterine tetracycline with or without manual removal of the membranes; however, there is an apparent trend away from manual removal. The ideal therapy for RFM would be non-irritating to the endometrium, non-depressing to the uterine defense mechanism, prevent the development of metritis and promote uterine tone and contractions to discourage the accumulation of fluid. To achieve these desired effects, it would appear that both the proper antibacterials and uterine contractants would be needed. Thus far, the various treatments employed have not consistently brought about the desired results.
Fenprostalene, an analogue of prostaglandin F2 alpha, has recently been advocated as a treatment for RFM. At least 3 reports indicate the beneficial effects of fenprostalene as therapy for RFM in dairy cows. In another trial, however, there was no benefit.
The purpose of this study was to compare fenprostalene and oxytetracycline for the treatment of RFM noting in particular the effect on body temperature, days to expulsion, incidence of postpartum metritis and subsequent fertility.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1411</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no23p21-23</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 23 (1988 November); 21-23</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1411/1405</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
