<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1538</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T02:17:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Understanding cow behavior</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roberts, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal behaviour</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">behaviour</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk production</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milking</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stray voltage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Understanding cow behavior, and behavioral responses to stress of any origin, is important when attempting to interpret the effects of stray voltage on a dairy farm. Some behaviors can become detrimental to health and production even if the cause of the behavior change does not directly result in damage. The essential message to understand is that the behaviors commonly considered as indications of stray voltage are general behavior responses. These changes should not be considered specific to stray voltage. This is particularly relevant in cases where stray voltage is resolved, but abnormal behaviors do not decrease.
Abnormal or undesired animal behaviors usually have their origins in the very basic psychological makeup of an animal. The performance of the animal behaviors commonly associated with the occurrence of stray voltageare generalized behavioral expressions that are likely to come from a variety of electrical and non-electrical stresses. Behaviors such as lapping at the water cup, weight shifting, tail switching, nose pressing, kicking,self destructive heifer syndrome, and a general unthriftiness or apathy in the herd may be perceived asbeing caused by stray voltage. Certainly some of these behaviors are increased by stray voltage, but their origin can also be from non-electrical stresses.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1997-05-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1538</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol1997no31.2p104-107</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 31.2 (1997 May); 104-107</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/1538/1531</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1997 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
