<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9058</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-02-04T16:58:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluating a selective therapy approach to antimicrobial treatment of high-risk calves at arrival to a male dairy calf rearing facility on future health, growth and antimicrobial use: A group randomized controlled trial</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">von Konigslow, Taika E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Renaud, David L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Duffield, Todd F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Winder, Charlotte B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kelgon, David F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antimicrobial use</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">risk assessment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">arrival strategies</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">&amp;nbsp;
The objective of this group randomized controlled trial was to compare a selective therapy strategy to a conventional group antimicrobial strategy at the time of arrival on mortality, mor­bidity, average daily gain and antimicrobial use. Data were collected from 1,032 calves in 19 rooms over an 84-day study period between January 15 and August 7, 2018. All calves were randomly assigned to rooms and subject to a standardized screening risk assessment upon arrival at the facility. Rooms were randomly assigned to receive either conventional group oral antimicrobials; or, selective therapy based on risk assign­ment (long-acting parenteral antimicrobials, oral electrolytes, or both). Cox proportional hazards models were built for calf health outcomes, while mixed linear regression models were constructed for calf growth and antimicrobial use outcomes. There was no difference between interventions for morbid­ity over the entire study period. However, lightweight calves assigned to the conventional group antimicrobial therapy had higher total and group treatment incidence. Calves assigned to the selective therapy strategy that had rectal temperatures be­low 103.1 °F (39.5 °C) at the time of arrival were more likely to be treated with antimicrobials. The selective therapy strategy had an increased hazard of mortality. Growth was lower in calves assigned to the selective therapy strategy in the winter as com­pared to calves assigned to conventional group metaphylaxis. This study demonstrates that a selective therapy strategy at the time of arrival may not be appropriate for all facilities or in all seasons despite the overall reduction in antimicrobial use.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-01-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9058</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20259058</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 59 No. 1 (2025): ONLINE FIRST; 40-54</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9058/8733</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
