<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2296</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-28T01:55:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Corynebacterium pseudotuberculosis associated skin disease of Holstein cattle in the San Joaquin Valley, California</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson, M. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lean, I. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Blanchard, P. C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bacterial diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Drug therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Histology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Skin diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Symptoms</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The role of Corynebacterium pseudotuberculosis in diseases of sheep and goats, particularly caseous lymphadenitis, is well recognized. However, there are few reports in the North American literature of Corynebacterium pseudotuberculosis causing diseases of cattle. There is a case report of Corynebacterium pseudotuberculosis associated with otitis media in feedlot cattle but there are no reports of its association with skin disease of cattle. By contrast, the Egyptian literature contains many case reports of an "oedematous skin" disease which occurs primarily in buffalo, but which has also been reported in cattle. Edematous skin disease is associated with C. pseudotuberculosis.
In this report the clinical findings are described for a herd that was affected by an outbreak of severe skin disease associated with Corynebacterium pseudotuberculosis. Pathology, microbiology and treatment of this condition are discussed. Herd outbreaks of this condition appear to be not uncommon in the San Joaquin Valley based on records of the California Veterinary Diagnostic Laboratory System at Tulare (CVDLS) which record seven additional herd outbreaks since 1987. Herd outbreaks are characterized by the sudden onset of skin lesions in a number of animals. All outbreaks have occurred between October and February. The condition is severe and results in losses due to culling, treatment costs and problems with milking parlor cleanliness and disinfection.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1990-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2296</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bovine-vol0no25p73-75</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; No. 25 (1990 September); 73-75</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/2296/2288</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1990 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
