<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9254</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-11-06T15:38:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>bovine:DSCR</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Morphokinetic features of the bovine embryo may be associated with lethal chondrodysplasia condition</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wells, Cara</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hayden, Cameron</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rea, MIchael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Killingsworth, Russell</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine lethal chondrodysplasia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine embryo transfer</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">embryo morphokinetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This case report details the identification of lethal chondro­dysplasia (LCD) in a Holstein embryo following embryo trans­fer and initial normal development during pregnancy. Lethal chondrodysplasia is a genetic disorder characterized by se­vere skeletal deformities during the developing pregnancy, leading to detrimental live-calf outcomes and cow-calf wel­fare. In this study, an in vitro produced (IVP) Holstein embryo was classified stage 7, quality grade 2, by an experienced bo­vine embryologist and was transferred to a recipient Holstein heifer. A video of this embryo was recorded with a View 4k camera attached to a Nikon SMZ 1270 microscope before load­ing and transferring. The recipient showed normal pregnancy progression, but resulted in abortion near ~180 days post em­bryo transfer. Post-abortion examination revealed severe skel­etal deformities consistent with LCD. Upon analysis, embryo morphokinetics which evaluates developmental patterns and cellular activity from the embryo video showed normal activ­ity levels, but higher variability and standard deviation in the LCD-affected embryo. This case underscores the limitations of initial embryo evaluations and highlights the potential of advanced embryo analysis technologies, such as computer vi­sion morphokinetic assessment, to detect genetic abnormali­ties earlier and improve breeding programs’ accuracy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">250</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9254</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/bpj20259254</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Bovine Practitioner; Vol. 59 No. 2 (2025); 10-16</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0524-1685</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/bovine/article/view/9254/8898</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
