<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/58</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-04-06T22:14:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>regsci:ED</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">What is in the Product and How to Measure It?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dai, Susie Y.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Label claim, as its name implies, assures consumers that the claims printed on the label of a regulated product accurately represent the product within. Ruth et al. reports in “Consistency of label claims of internet-purchased hemp oil and cannabis products as determined using IMS and LC-MS: a market survey” of a qualitative and quantitative study of 23 hemp oil products using two advanced instrument methods: an ion mobility mass spectrometry method and a liquid chromatography high-resolution mass spectrometry method. Cannabis products have become a hotly debated topic due to recent legislative changes. Although several cannabinoid compounds are designated as Schedule I controlled substances by the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (USDEA), many state legislatures have legalized marijuana for medical use, recreational use, or both. Schedule I controlled substances are defined by DEA as “drugs with no currently accepted medical use and a high potential for abuse. Schedule I drugs are the most dangerous drugs of all the drug schedules with potentially severe psychological or physical dependence” (USDEA). Regardless of state-level legislation and on-going debate in state legislature, science-driven research forms the background needed by the general public, public health officials, and policy makers to make informed decisions about cannabis products and marijuana. Particularly important from a public health perspective are methods to assess cannabis product content and safety. Ruth et al. found that some commercial products were not consistent with the label claim, foreshadowing future regulatory challenges of the cannabis industry, such as denoting compounds to be sought in testing, testing methods, and the implementation of quality control and quality assurance.https://doi.org/10.21423/jrs-v04n03pi (DOI assigned 5/31/2019)</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Office of the Texas State Chemist</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/regsci/article/view/58</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/JRS-V04N03PI</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Regulatory Science; Vol. 4 No. 3 (2016); i-ii</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2377-3537</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/regsci/article/view/58/40</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
