<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/149</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-05-08T20:20:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>regsci:SA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Regulatory policies for heavy metals in spices – a New York approach</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ishida, Maria L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Greene, Virginia </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">King, Thomas</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sheridan, Robert</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Luker, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oglesby, Debra  V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Trodden, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Greenberg, Jon</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">spices, regulation, action level, heavy metals, lead, arsenic, cadmium</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Food contamination and adulteration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Risk analysis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Evaluation of regulatory practices and improvement</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets (NYSAGM) Division of Food Safety and Inspection (NYSAGM-FSI), observed high levels of heavy metals in spices through its routine food surveillance program. There are no federal action levels for heavy metals in spices. In consultation with the NYSAGM Food Laboratory (NYSAGM-FL) and using results from a devised targeted sampling plan, NYSAGM-FSI instituted a State Class II action level of 1 ppm for Pb, arsenic (As) and cadmium (Cd) and a State Class I action level of 25 ppm for Pb in spices. In 2018, NYSAGM and the New York State Department of Health’s Bureau of Toxic Substance Assessment (NYSDOH-BTSA) created the Center of Excellence on Food Research to determine actionable limits of contaminants commonly found in spices, particularly heavy metals. NYSDOH-BTSA performed an assessment of relevant literature published and derived health-based guidance values for As, Cd, chromium (Cr), and Pb in spices. Consequently, NYSAGM lowered the State’s Class II action levels for Pb, As and Cd in spices by a factor of almost 5 times and is the first State in the nation to establish action levels for heavy metals in spices providing better protection to New York State consumers.
https://doi.org/10.21423/jrs-v10i1ishida</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Office of the Texas State Chemist</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/regsci/article/view/149</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/JRS-V10I1ISHIDA</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Regulatory Science; Vol. 10 No. 1 (2022); 1-12</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2377-3537</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/regsci/article/view/149/256</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 Maria L. Ishida, Virginia  Greene, Thomas King, Robert Sheridan, John Luker, Debra  V. Oglesby, Jennifer Trodden, Jon Greenberg</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
