<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/305</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-10-06T19:46:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>regsci:RA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Regulatory and Global Challenges in the Approval, Accessibility, and Monitoring of mRNA Vaccines Post COVID-19: A Review</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shukla, Dr. Drashti</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vora, Dr.Kunal </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">COVID-19   ,                         Regulatory bodies     ,                        mRNA Vaccines </dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">:    COVID-19                            Regulatory bodies                             mRNA Vaccines </dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">An important advancement in vaccine technology was made possible by the COVID-19 pandemic, which sped up the creation and regulatory licensing of mRNA vaccines. The regulatory obstacles faced in the post-pandemic era during the approval, monitoring, and post-market surveillance of mRNA vaccines are examined in this paper. Emergency usage permits allowed for quick implementation, but long-term safety, public confidence, and worldwide accessibility are still major issues. To strike a balance between quick approvals and thorough safety evaluations, regulatory bodies including the FDA, EMA, and WHO have modified their frameworks. Despite persistent under reporting and inconsistent data, post- market surveillance systems such as VAERS and EudraVigilance have been crucial in detecting adverse occurrences. In order to guarantee fair vaccine access, expedite approval procedures, and fortify pharmacovigilance infrastructure, the a assessment also examines the necessity of international regulatory harmonization. Regulatory futures approaches must integrate real-time data monitoring, adaptive approval pathways, and international cooperation to enhance preparedness for future pandemics while maintaining public confidence in vaccine safety and efficacy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Office of the Texas State Chemist</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/regsci/article/view/305</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/JRS.REGSCI.131305</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Regulatory Science; Vol. 13 No. 1 (2025)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2377-3537</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://regsci-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/regsci/article/view/305/343</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Dr. Drashti Shukla, Dr.Kunal  Vora</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
