<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:dlrpj-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/33</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-09-23T08:58:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>dlrpj:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">There is No Monster Outside: It's A Virus! (German Version)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Iris, Von</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ebener, Richard</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Irby, Beverly</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lara-Alecio, Rafael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">AbdelRahman, Nahed</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tong, Fuhui</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schiller, Pam</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">



We wrote this book for children who are hearing the news about COVID-19 and who may be experiencing fears. Personally, we have heard children’s dreams that include mean people who take them away from their families, strange things that have happened to their classrooms, friends who are going away, or monsters that are coming after them. All of these types of fears have been expressed in dreams or daydreams of children we know. This book is dedicated to our hope of tomorrow-- the children around the world-- and to their families and caregivers who are supporting them. Our desire is that this book will be a comfort for children and will give them a sense of security in these uncertain times. This book is published in several languages to serve a need during this coronavirus pandemic. The book, free of charge, is supported by the Center for Research and Development in Dual Language and Literacy Acquisition, Department of Educational Psychology, College of Education and Human Development at Texas A&amp;amp;M University.



</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-09-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://dlrpj-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/dlrpj/article/view/33</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/dlrpj-v4.a33</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Dual Language Research and Practice Journal; Vol. 4 No. 1 (2020): There Is No Monster Outside: It's a Virus!; 1-14</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2375-2777</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2375-2777</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://dlrpj-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/dlrpj/article/view/33/22</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Dual Language Research and Practice Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
