<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/172</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-05-29T19:21:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:ARTICLES</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Future-Proofing Forensic Science Education: Enhancing Student Experience Through Course Redesign and Industry-Driven Learning</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Seale, Hannah </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nurse, Beth </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fall, Lewis</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">student engagement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Forensic education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">curriculum design</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study addresses the challenge of disengagement and career uncertainty among final-year BSc Forensic Investigation Undergraduate students by redesigning a key module at the University of South Wales. Traditional, theory-heavy curricula often fail to bridge the gap between academic learning and professional practice, leading to low student motivation. To combat this, a new module was co-created with student input and delivered by a diverse network of external forensic professionals. The module aimed to increase student engagement, provide insight into diverse career pathways, and connect theoretical knowledge to real-world application. A questionnaire, adapted from the Student Engagement in Schools Questionnaire was administered to 39 final-year students to evaluate their perceptions of the redesigned module. The results showed a strong positive response for cognitive, emotional, and behavioral engagement, with students reporting increased motivation and confidence in their career aspirations. Most respondents also felt the module was highly relevant to current forensic practices, however, respondents did not feel motivated to attend all sessions, and perceptions of a sense of belonging within the learning community were low. The findings indicate that an expert-led, career-focused approach can enhance student engagement and curriculum relevance. This model offers a framework for forensic and investigative education by connecting theory with authentic professional practice. Future module iterations will focus on enhancing peer connections and providing greater insight into industry challenges to further support students as they transition from academia to their careers.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/172</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 8 No. 1 (2026): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/172/134</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 Hannah Seale, Beth Nurse, Lewis Fall</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
