<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/127</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-06T22:12:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:HLAB</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Authentic Assessment: Using Authentic Assessment to Foster and Improve Learning Through a Mock Crime Scene Final Exam in a High School and College Level Forensic Science Course</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubins, Scott</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">authentic assessment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mock crime scene</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">experiential learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">forensic science</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">high school</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article demonstrates how authentic assessment has a positive effect on student learning in a high school and college level forensic science course and fosters learning through a mock crime scene final exam. After completing multiple units throughout the course, including crime scene analysis, recognition and preservation of evidence, physical and trace evidence, DNA, fingerprints, firearms, fire investigation, photography, death investigation, documentation and the concept of teamwork, the students have gained a thorough understanding for successfully completing the crime scene final exam. For the students’ final exam, multiple mock crime scenes (one per student group, there can be 5-8 groups depending on the number of students per year), based upon real crimes, are set up in a wooded area (FIGURE 1) in close proximity to campus and students are provided with the necessary equipment to process the scene they are assigned. Each scene is supervised and evaluated by a uniformed member of the New Rochelle Police Department. After processing the crime scene, students work in the “lab” (the classroom) to evaluate their evidence. Approximately five days later, students present their cases in the mock “courtroom” (the classroom) including photos, rationale for how the scene was processed, any work requested from the lab and any subsequent findings. Police officers who evaluated the students during the crime scene processing also attended the “courtroom” part of the final. Each student presentation is evaluated for accuracy, proper procedure, integrity of the crime scene and the evidence collected as well as the students’ overall understanding of what they have learned throughout the year.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-12-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/127</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2024): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/127/107</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Scott Rubins</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
