<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/138</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-06-06T19:42:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:ARTICLES</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Comparative Study of Self-Confidence and Future Outlook among Forensic Science Students</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bechard, Cameron</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Castillo, Abigail</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Legron-Rodriguez, Tamra</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lapeyrouse, Nicole</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">forensic science students</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">self-confidence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">future outlook</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Self-confidence has been positively associated with various facets of accomplishment in academics, such as academic performance, persistence, and future employability of graduated students. In this mixed-methods study, forensic science students' self-confidence and future confidence levels at different points in their undergraduate degrees are measured and compared. Independent T-tests are utilized to compare the self-confidence and future confidence levels of forensic science students at the beginning of their forensic science degrees and forensic science students in the last year of their forensic science degrees. Additionally, open-response questions were analyzed using thematic analysis to gain further insight into the current confidence levels of forensic science students and where these students derive their confidence in themselves and their confidence in their futures as professional forensic scientists. The results show that forensic science students in the final year of their degree are reporting lower self-confidence levels and lower confidence in their futures as forensic science professionals. Further insight into students’ perceptions of their confidence levels reveals that students in the first and final years of their forensic science degrees derive their confidence in contrasting ways that may be linked to their views regarding their future employability in the field. This paper highlights how the next class of future forensic science professionals are concerned about their employability and ability to support themselves, and the potential link to lower confidence levels in both themselves and their futures as forensic science professionals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/138</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 7 No. 1 (2025): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/138/117</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Cameron Bechard, Abigail Castillo, Tamra Legron-Rodriguez, Ph.D., Nicole Lapeyrouse Ph.D. </dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
