<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/178</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-05-29T19:21:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:ARTICLES</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">When the Items Fail the Test: Prevalence of Item-writing Flaws in Multiple-choice Questions used in Introductory Forensic Science Courses</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rios, Gabrielle </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Khogali, Fatima</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Legron-Rodriguez, Tamra</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Assessment Validity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Assessment Quality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Question Design</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Faculty Development</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Forensic Science Education</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Multiple-choice questions (MCQs) are widely used in undergraduate education because they allowinstructors to efficiently assess students’ comprehension, support consistent exam structure, and identify areas that may require instructional or curricular adjustments. However, the quality of MCQs can be compromised by item writing flaws (IWFs), which reduce the reliability and validity of assessments. This study systematically examined the presence of IWFs in MCQs using the Item Writing Flaws Evaluation Instrument (IWFEI). Examples of IWFs include incomplete question stems, ambiguous wording, and inconsistent answer-choice formats. A content analysis was conducted on 337 instructor-generated MCQs and 569 publisher-generated MCQs from introductory forensic science courses. Across both sources, Criterion 7 (items lacking a complete stem) of the IWFEI emerged as the most frequently observed IWF. Overall, 47% of publisher-generated items and 68% of instructor-generated items contained at least one IWF. These findings highlight the importance of critically evaluating MCQs in undergraduate forensic science education to ensure accurate measurement of student learning. The study offers a practical framework for improving assessment design by identifying common IWFs and provides recommendations for instructors.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/178</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 8 No. 1 (2026): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/178/135</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 Gabrielle Rios, Fatima Khogali, Tamra Legron-Rodriguez</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
