<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/130</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-06-06T19:42:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:ARTICLES</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Grossed out to Engrossed: Experiential Learning Shifts Student Attitudes on Forensic Entomology</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cooper, Vanessa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brauer, Jonathan R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hans, Krystal</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">CSI effect</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">active learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">forensic science</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">experiential learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">education</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Students enrolled in forensic science programs at universities likely have preconceived ideas about crime investigations and protocols due to the influence of television shows, movies, or social media. A forensic field that is often overlooked is forensic entomology. Forensically relevant insects are sometimes a component of crime scene investigations, and most students have not had an opportunity to learn about them in an academic setting. Forensic Investigation (FI) at Purdue University includes a laboratory component and is one of the core courses required to obtain a minor in Forensic Sciences while Investigating Forensic Science (IFS) is lecture-only and not required to obtain the minor. Surveys inquiring about comfort levels with areas of forensic entomology, greatest challenges during the semester, and topics of most and least interest were distributed to FI students in Fall 2022 and 2023 semesters before and after any laboratory activities took place. Surveys were also distributed to IFS students, which learned about this topic through lecture and video. There was a significant positive change in comfort levels with forensic entomology after all laboratory activities in FI while there was no significant change in IFS student comfort levels. These results demonstrate the value of including forensic teaching models in the classroom and the impact of active learning in forensic science education. Experiential learning activities in forensic science education promote student engagement and can increase comfort levels around unfamiliar topics.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-06-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/130</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 7 No. 1 (2025): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/130/120</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Vanessa Cooper, B.Sc., AFBE-T, Jonathan R. Brauer, Ph.D., Krystal Hans, Ph.D., M-ABFE</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
