<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/132</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-06T22:11:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:ARTICLES</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Advancing Forensics Pedagogy: A Pathway to Quality Matters Course Certification</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heston, Amy J. </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Forensics pedogogy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">quality matters</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">assessment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">student success</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">course design</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study represents a multiyear investigation into the development and evolution of Walsh University's first forensic science course, Introduction to Forensic Science (NS 114). From the initial planning and first offering in 2007 to its current form, the course has undergone significant transformations to enhance student engagement, critical thinking, and application of forensic science concepts to real-world situations. Initially offered as a face-to-face course, NS 114 transitioned to an online format in 2014 to accommodate a wide range of student schedules and incorporated emerging technologies. This transition involved restructuring assessments, implementing problem-based learning through forensic reflections, and aligning content to Quality Matters (QM) standards for course design. Key innovations include the development of the new pedagogical models: 10 Print Card of Fingerprints of Student Success and Student Reflection Formulator. Collectively, these models were designed to guide instructors in creating effective learning experiences and aligning course content with learning outcomes. These initiatives have led to significant improvements in student engagement and achievement of learning outcomes, as evidenced by assessment of student performance. The study highlights the importance of continuous improvement in course design, the effectiveness of problem-based learning in forensic science education, and the value of aligning course content with national standards for quality assurance. Strategies and tools developed through this process have potential applications across various disciplines and educational settings, thereby offering pedagogical approaches for enhancing student success in the online forensic science courses and beyond.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-12-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/132</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2024): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/132/113</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Amy J.  Heston</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
