<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/116</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-06T22:12:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:CLAB</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Morphoscopic Examination to Estimate Sex in Forensic Anthropology: An Approach in Laboratory Teaching</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zhang, Min</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Emmanuel Atta-Obeng</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">morphoscopic examination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sex estimation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sexually dimorphic traits</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Skectchfab</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Morphoscopic examination is an important task in forensic anthropology sex estimation. Sexually dimorphic traits on skeletal structures are studied to complete this task. How to locate, observe, and compare the sexually dimorphic traits in males and females is critical in forensic anthropology teaching. The existing teaching modalities, facilities, and access to teaching sources of forensic anthropology courses vary among institutions. This article introduces a straightforward approach to morphoscopic examination based on Klales et al. and Walker ’s methods in teaching. Sexually dimorphic traits identification on the anatomical skull and pelvic models and comparison on the computer assisted 3D skull and pelvic models are included in this approach. The teaching purposes include locating and identifying the sexually dimorphic traits on the skull and pelvic anatomical models and comparing the differences of sexually dimorphic traits via computer assisted 3D skull and pelvic models. The proposed approa ch aims to serve the morphoscopic examination sex estimation laboratory teaching purposes under various teaching modalities with appropriate considerations .</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-12-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/116</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2024): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/116/111</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Min Zhang, Emmanuel Atta-Obeng</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
