<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/174</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-05-29T19:21:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:ARTICLES</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Modular Course in Art Forgery: Interdisciplinary Approaches in Forensic Science Education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bedijn, Rebecca</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Andrews, Zachary</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">art crime</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">authentication</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">connoisseurship</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">investigation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">curriculum</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In recent decades, criminal activity in the art world has been on the rise, with increasing attention from both the professional and academic world. The interdisciplinary nature of art crimes provides a unique background for the teaching of investigative techniques. Art forgery investigations in particular utilize techniques used in other forensic disciplines, but it receives little attention in the higher education sphere. This manuscript presents a semester-long, modular course designed to bridge the gap between traditional connoisseurship and scientific techniques in art forgery investigations. The course covers foundational knowledge of the art market and art crimes, provenance and stylistic analysis, forensic and material science techniques, legal and ethical considerations, and a culminating mock case study. Students will learn about visual, chemical and dating methods (including spectroscopy, chromatography, spectrometry, and microscopy) as well as provenance research and legal frameworks. The course is designed to be accessible and open to students from a variety of backgrounds. The pedagogy behind the course focuses on active, constructive, and case-based learning. Additionally, suggestions are provided for modular expansion, based on the resources available to an institution. This course offers a novel educational approach to art forgery by framing it within forensic science, providing students with skills applicable to real-world investigations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/174</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 8 No. 1 (2026): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/174/136</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 Rebecca Bedijn, Zachary Andrews</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
