<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/117</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-06T22:12:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:CLAB</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Utilization of the ‘World of Guns’ in Firearms Examination Courses</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Spaulding, Jamie S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">firearms examination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">game-based learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">student engagement</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Delivery of a comprehensive firearm and toolmark examination course is often challenging because few universities are able to maintain extensive reference collections such as those found in crime laboratories. These reference collections are essential to understanding the functionalities of various firearms and in the developmental training of apprentice/entry level firearm and toolmark examiners. Several sections of the Association of Firearm and Toolmark Examiners (AFTE) Training Manual and the National Firearms Examiner Academy (NFEA) curriculum, including numerous training exercises are dedicated to field stripping, disassembly, and assembly of firearms to develop a comprehensive understanding of their operation. To overcome a limited reference collection, a major assignment utilizing the ‘World of Guns: Gun Disassembly’ was integrated into an undergraduate course to enhance student learning, provide active learning opportunities for students, and align the course with several learning outcomes of the AFTE Training Manual and the NFEA. Students were expected to 1) use the game to field strip, disassemble, and reassemble a series of assigned firearms and 2) draft a paragraph description of the firearm and the mechanism by which it operates. The integration of the game resulted in improved exam scores on questions about firearm mechanism recognition and student understanding of how markings are transferred to evidential samples. Furthermore, the application demonstrates the effectiveness of game- based learning in a forensic science course.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-12-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/117</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2024): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/117/110</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Jamie S. Spaulding</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
