<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/128</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-06T22:11:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jfse:ARTICLES</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Impact of Attendance on Academic Performance in Forensic Science Undergraduate Programs: A Cohort Analysis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Preece, Daniel</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Forensic science</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Attendance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Engagement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Grades</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Attainment</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Attendance in educational settings has long been regarded as a crucial factor influencing student performance and outcomes. In the field of forensic science, where both theoretical knowledge and practical skills are essential, regular attendance in lectures, laboratories, and tutorials may have a significant impact on students' academic success. Previous research has indicated a positive correlation between attendance and grades across various disciplines; however, there is a need for discipline-specific studies to understand the nuances and specific requirements of different fields of study. This study investigates the relationship between attendance and academic performance in forensic science undergraduate cohorts during the 2023/2024 academic year. Attendance records and final grades for first, second, and third-year students were analyzed to determine how attendance impacts students' academic outcomes. Using regression analysis and Pearson correlation coefficients, the study reveals significant positive correlations between attendance and grades in several modules across all three years. First-year modules exhibited strong correlations, with most showing significant relationships (r ranging from 0.6768 to 0.9573, p &amp;lt; 0.05). Second-year data also indicated significant correlations in many modules, though with some variability (r up to 0.9773, p &amp;lt; 0.05). The third-year results demonstrated significant correlations in selected modules, but also instances of non-significant correlations, highlighting a shift in the factors influencing academic performance as students’ progress. These findings underscore the critical role of attendance in academic success and suggest that targeted educational strategies to improve attendance could enhance student outcomes in forensic science programs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">The Council of Forensic Science Education</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-12-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/128</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">The Journal of Forensic Science Education; Vol. 6 No. 2 (2024): Journal of Forensic Science Education</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2641-8533</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jfse-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jfse/article/view/128/108</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Daniel Preece</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
