<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7201</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-06-04T15:25:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Assessing Awareness and Use of Library Services within Chinese Partner Academic Programs: A Case Study Developing and Analyzing Bilingual Surveys</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wade, MaryAlice</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">VanDyne, Heather</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nickerson, Claire</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Landis, Cynthia</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A library at a regional comprehensive university created a Global Access Committee to provide support for students and faculty at international partner campuses in China. In 2022, the Committee sent out a survey to these students and faculty to assess their awareness of and satisfaction with library resources and services. The survey received responses from 302 students and 12 faculty members. Students reported high awareness and use of online library resources, instructional materials such as guides and tutorials, and the library’s Ask-A-Librarian service. However, there was a discrepancy between students’ self-reported usage and usage statistics collected by the library. The responses may also have been influenced by cultural differences and by the translation of the questions and responses into and out of Mandarin Chinese. However, the library was able to make positive changes based on the survey results.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7201</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 15 No. 1 (2025)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7201/6174</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
