<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7216</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-01-12T20:53:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Coffee with Calantha: Measuring the Impact of a Discussion-Based Series for Graduate Students</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tillotson, Calantha</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Amy Snyder</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en"> Matthew Delgado</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Julia Noll</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In order to serve the needs of Information Sciences graduate students at the University of Tennessee Knoxville (UTK), a collaboration between the subject librarian and the student chapter leaders of the American Library Association and Special Libraries Association was established. Through this relationship, the two parties crafted a synchronous event series called “Coffee with Calantha” (CwC) that centers around career readiness. Participants of multiple sessions responded to a survey concerning the efficacy of the series in preparing them for post-graduation employment and building community while still in graduate school. Data collected through this survey revealed how participating in these events benefited attendees' preparation to enter the field of librarianship and ability to network with their peers and practicing professionals. Additional emerging themes included the supportive dialogue and differing perspectives present throughout the discussions and the specific needs of distance learners in the educational process.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Association for Information Science and Technology</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-11-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7216</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship; Vol. 15 No. 2 (2025)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7216/6178</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Calantha Tillotson, Amy Snyder,  Matthew Delgado, Julia Noll</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
