<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7195</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-11-24T15:20:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Study of the Coverage of Open Educational Resources (OER)  Through Websites of Colleges and Universities in Connecticut</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brown, Mary</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hak Joon Kim</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Notwithstanding reports of increased awareness and use of Open Educational Resources (OER) in higher education, the literature notes that awareness and use of and institutional support for OER remain major challenges to campuses seeking to reduce student cost burden and support access to materials. OER also support faculty who desire to move beyond the traditional textbooks in order to increase their students’ engagement and thereby access to learning, to support pedagogical changes they are making that enhance student learning, and to give faculty greater control over their courses. The university website, as a public-facing vehicle to aid students, parents, alumni, faculty, the community, and interested others in being aware, among other things, of the resources available, is examined for findable support for OER. The purpose of this study is to show, through examination of their websites, a snapshot of the response of Connecticut universities and colleges to OER. Through an examination of these websites, we gage the ability to connect with information related to OER through the university website.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-11-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7195</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 15 No. 2 (2025)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7195/6180</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Mary Brown, Hak Joon Kim</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
