<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1463</identifier>
				<datestamp>2011-06-23T18:21:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">‘Where to start?’: Considerations for faculty and librarians in delivering information literacy instruction for graduate students.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harkins, Mary Jane</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rodrigues, Denyse B</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Orlov, Stanislav</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">information literacy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">graduate students</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">librarian faculty collaborations</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It is often assumed that incoming graduate students are information literate, yet many of them lack the skills needed to effectively organize and critically evaluate research. Supporting students in acquiring information literacy skills is a critical role for universities, as it improves the quality of student research and enhances their opportunities for lifelong learning. The literature in this area has focused on the partnership between librarians and course instructors, which has been shown to produce the most effective library instruction: however, additional research is needed concerning the collaborative approach to teaching information literacy to graduate students. The current study used action research to gather information on students’ perceptions of a blend of two methods of library instruction, a web-based tutorial and an in-class library instruction session. While few students indicated engagement with the online tutorial, most students appreciated the in-class session. Recommendations for information literacy instruction and further research are included.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-05-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">action research</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/1463</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 1 No. 1 (2011); 28-50</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/1463/1852</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
