<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7229</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-05-26T12:18:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:PRACTICE</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Expanding Library Information Access for Alaska's Rural and Indigenous Students</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brookes Boyd, Genova</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article details the impactful collaboration between the University of Alaska Fairbanks (UAF) Rasmuson Library and the Rural Alaska Honors Institute (RAHI). RAHI empowers rural and Alaska Native high school students by offering college credits and a university experience. The adapted LS101 course not only teaches essential information literacy skills but also positions the library as a welcoming and supportive space.
The program prioritizes building student rapport, cultural support, and fostering ownership of the library through active learning and strategic use of various library spaces. Librarians are deeply involved in student support, from selection of students for the program, to providing academic and well-being assistance. This approach has led to positive student feedback and high completion rates. The collaboration offers a powerful model for engaging underserved students, showing that successful initiatives for Indigenous populations must involve authentic, sustained partnerships with Native and rural stakeholders.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Association for Information Science and Technology</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-05-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">In Practice</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7229</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship; Vol. 16 No. 1 (2026)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7229/6185</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 Genova Brookes Boyd</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
