<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6990</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-01T23:19:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">23 Things Revisited: Participant perceptions of a staff development program over a year later</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Neilson, Christine</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sofoifa, Jamie</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sarjeant-Jenkins, Rachel</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">staff training</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">professional development</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">web technologies</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">23 Things programs have been used around the world to help educate library workers about web 2.0 applications. This paper describes the results of two feedback surveys for a 23 Things program that was offered to library employees at the University of Saskatchewan: the first survey, conducted at the time of program completion, and a follow up survey, conducted a year and a half later to assess whether participants were applying what they learned in the program, and if so, how.  Generally speaking, respondents indicated that the program was beneficial, and all but 3 of the respondents from the second survey had applied some of what they learned through the program, either personally or professionally.  Despite being an independent learning activity, social aspects that arose organically as participants worked their way through the program seemed to be valued by program participants as much as the newly acquired knowledge from the lessons. The semi-facilitated format, in addition to the flexibility of completing the lessons at a convenient time and place, was key to the program’s success. Organizations that wish to transition long-time employees from the print-based working world to the digital world should consider making 23 Things style learning opportunities a regular part of their staff development activities.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-11-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/6990</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 5 No. 2 (2015); 32-59</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/6990/6094</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
