<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7004</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-01T23:19:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Review and Weeding of a Reference Collection: A case study</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mueller, Susan Marie</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Reference</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">weeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">core titles</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">literature review</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The author’s library weeded its paper-based reference collection. Some of the titles in the collection were out of date because the most recent edition was in the e-book format and available online. Other titles were simply outdated, irrelevant or in poor physical condition. In addition, the collection took up prime space on the main floor. The library used three criteria to assess the collection: age, currency of content and inclusion on a core title list. The criteria were not determined initially, but rather through trial and error. When completed, the print-based reference collection was considerably smaller and moved to a different location. When viewed in retrospect, the weeding process lacked one standard criterion. No one did a literature search. Though there was no compelling reason to do a search after the fact, the collection development librarian wanted to know if this would have made a difference in the process.  The literature search revealed some interesting information about weeding. This included the fact that weeding of a reference collection is a topic frequently not covered in the literature, as well as the fact that a core title list is rarely used.  It also revealed that the creation of a reference collection development policy and a weeding policy would have made the process simpler.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-11-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">case study</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7004</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 5 No. 2 (2015); 60-76</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7004/6095</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
