<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7213</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-06-04T15:25:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:PRACTICE</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">What Should We Do Next? Designing an Innovation Portfolio for Academic Libraries</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mathews, Brian</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Innovation is essential for academic libraries navigating the complexities of a rapidly evolving knowledge ecosystem. This article explores how structured frameworks, such as the Innovation Matrix and the Three Horizons framework, can guide libraries in strategically aligning their efforts with institutional goals while balancing immediate needs with long-term aspirations. By shifting the focus from reactive decision-making to intentional problem framing, libraries can prioritize opportunities that deliver meaningful outcomes for their communities. Additionally, the 70-20-10 rule for resource allocation provides a practical approach to balancing core services, exploratory initiatives, and visionary projects. Through this multidimensional strategy, libraries can foster a culture of thoughtful innovation, adapt to emerging challenges, and position themselves as leaders in shaping the future of higher education. The article emphasizes the importance of aligning goals with actions, cultivating agility, and embedding innovation as a core practice to ensure relevance, creativity, and impact in a changing academic landscape.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-06-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">In Practice</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7213</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 15 No. 1 (2025)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7213/6170</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
