<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7164</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-05-20T20:57:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Putting the Puzzle Together:   Creating a Library Orientation Escape Room for University Freshmen</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Giles, Kelly</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sullivan, Brian</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">At James Madison University, many first-year students enroll in a general education course that requires them to participate in campus events. James Madison University Libraries offers special information literacy sessions as part of this program, but developing an engaging session that is not tied to a research assignment or academic major can be challenging. A team of librarians and staff collaborated on creating an escape room that would teach freshmen about James Madison University Libraries spaces, collections, and services. In this case study, we describe the development process from identifying learning objectives through playtesting to the successful implementation of the escape room as a library orientation activity. We discuss some principles of good escape room design taken from the literature as well as observations and lessons learned from our experiences.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-05-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7164</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 13 No. 1 (2023)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7164/6155</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
