<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7063</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-10-09T23:39:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Employers Needs Versus Student Skillsets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hahn, Susan E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pedersen, Jocelyn</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Media</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">education and instruction</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">training</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">e-learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">and information literacy</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper is a review of the skills employers seeks in new graduates and the skillsets new graduates have to offer. Employers report they want to hire people with solid soft skills, research, critical thinking and problem-solving skills (Stewart, Wall, Marciniec, 2016).  The question is:  Does the literature support recent graduates’ media education and training in research, critical thinking and problem-solving skills?  This paper will examine literature to determine whether there is a disparity between employers’ needs and the abilities of recent graduates who have grown up in an e-learning environment, and if so, where those disparities exist. Synthesizing this information has broad implications for future research into how universities can best educate and prepare students for success after graduation. Certainly, today’s undergraduate students are computer and Internet savvy, can they apply critical thinking skills to the vast amount information available to determine reliable sources?  When using Google, can students identify a credible source, determine fake news from real, identify native advertising from editorial content, or learn to take researched information in, digest it, and apply it to real-world applications? This paper sets the stage for future research into the above questions and beyond. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-10-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7063</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 10 No. 1 (2020); 38-53</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7063/6136</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
