<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7224</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-01-12T20:53:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:PRACTICE</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From Conferences to Conventions: Taking Copyright Education to New Venues</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Finlay, Stephen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Soto Luna, Isabel</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Many academic libraries lack a librarian with a JD to serve as a dedicated expert on copyright issues. Even among law librarians, only 30% hold a law degree (AALL, 2023). However, librarians can develop the necessary expertise in copyright matters—such as Fair Use, authors’ rights agreements, open access, and open education—through literature, conferences, and online certifications.
As co-authors, we fall into this latter category. We began collaborating in Fall 2021, initially focusing on faculty workshops and presentations on copyright and Creative Commons. Our shared interests led us to explore alternative ways to deliver copyright education. This article describes our efforts to bring copyright education to an unconventional setting for academic librarians: pop culture conventions.
With the support of our institution’s leadership, we developed a presentation designed to establish a foundation in copyright knowledge, then expand to issues relevant to creators. This meant trading in traditional faculty workshop settings for convention halls filled with attendees dressed as their favorite comic book, superhero, and fantasy characters. In this article, we outline our process, share lessons learned, and discuss the professional value of stepping outside one’s comfort zone.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Association for Information Science and Technology</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-11-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">In Practice</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7224</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship; Vol. 15 No. 2 (2025)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7224/6177</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Stephen Finlay, Isabel Soto Luna</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
