<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7203</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-03T16:37:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:PRACTICE</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Thinking Around the Box: using complementary innovation for designing programs and nurturing community</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mathews, Brian</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This essay explores a nuanced approach to innovation, challenging the traditional emphasis on either disruptive "outside the box" thinking or incremental improvements within established frameworks. Drawing inspiration from David Robertson's concept of "complementary innovation," the essay proposes a third way—thinking around the box—that libraries can apply to program and service development. By focusing on the creation of integrated, user-centered service portfolios, libraries can enhance the user experience while fostering community engagement. Through case studies and practical examples, the essay illustrates how this approach not only strengthens services but also nurtures human connections, addressing broader societal challenges such as isolation and disconnection. By adopting complementary innovation, libraries can become vital hubs for knowledge, creativity, and social interaction, contributing to a more connected and resilient future for their communities.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-12-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">In Practice</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7203</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 14 No. 2 (2024)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7203/6165</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
