<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7190</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-03T16:37:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Conducting an Environmental Scan of Scholarly Communication Programs at The Ohio State University Libraries</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Meetz, Johanna</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article discusses the process of conducting an environmental scan after a reorganization of the Publishing and Repository Services Unit at The Ohio State University Libraries. The scan focused on the institutional repository and publishing programs and was intended to give colleagues post-reorganization context and information about our work. The methods used, including stakeholder interviews of library and university staff as well as a review of peer institution websites are examined. The conclusions and recommendations from the document as well as the lessons learned are also detailed. Lastly, the role the scan has continued to play in strategic planning as well as its long-term value is discussed.
Keywords: environmental scan, institutional repository, library publishing, reorganization</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-12-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7190</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 14 No. 2 (2024)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7190/6166</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
