<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7193</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-12-03T16:37:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>pal:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cancelling the ‘Big Deal’ at a Public University: A Discussion of STEM Faculty Perceptions of Cancellation and Post-Cancellation Usage Data</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McCormick, Amanda</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rowley, Erin</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article discusses how faculty, staff, and students at the University at Buffalo (UB), a public Carnegie R1 university, were impacted by the cancellation of the Elsevier ScienceDirect Big Deal package. After the cancellation, UB participated in a multi-site study which included interviewing faculty about the effect of the cancellation on their research and teaching. In general, the faculty were supportive of the cancellation. There was frustration expressed with the current structure of the publishing industry, particularly with the exorbitant pricing of journal subscriptions. Later analysis of usage data at UB post-cancellation was conducted; unsurprisingly, the data showed a decrease in usage on the ScienceDirect platform and increase in requests for unavailable articles. Although the cancellation of the ScienceDirect Big Deal package had a direct impact on UB, the initial outcome was not exceedingly harmful and could be addressed through mitigating measures such as the quick fulfilment of requests for unavailable articles.
Keywords: Big Deal; collection development; STEM faculty</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">SLA: Special Libraries Association</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-12-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7193</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division; Vol. 14 No. 2 (2024)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1947-0037</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://pal-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/pal/article/view/7193/6167</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Practical Academic Librarianship: The International Journal of the SLA Academic Division</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
