<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12641</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:11:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">TSUNAMI RUN-UP CONSIDERING TIME VARIATION OF DENSITY OF INUNDATION WATER</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Matsutomi, Hideo</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Arikawa, Taro</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Aiming for the advancement of tsunami load, historical and/or prospective tsunami scale evaluations, practical empirical formulas for evaluating friction factor K of inundation flow and density ρ of inundation water over a movable bed, which can be applied to a tsunami run-up theory, are proposed using experimental data whose amount (range) is increased (expanded) by carrying out additional experiments on ρ and run-up of inundation flow with sediment, and verification data of the above theory under a uniformly sloping movable bed condition are provided. Series solutions with a higher universality to the run-up of tsunami inundation flow with sediment over a uniformly sloping movable bed, in which both K and ρ depend on time, are derived under the conditions depending on an incident bore height h1 at shoreline (or an initial stored water depth), bed slope i, median particle diameter d50 of initial bed material, and examples of the solutions are shown. The solutions are applicable to the case that ρ is independent on time, i.e., the case of inundation flow without sediment over a movable bed or fixed bed. Including the case of inundation flow without sediment, validity of one of the solutions is also verified through a comparison with the verification data on run-up distance.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12641</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.papers.2</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; papers.2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12641/11914</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Hideo Matsutomi, Taro Arikawa</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
