<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3559</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T23:06:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">LONG-TERM EXPERIENCE WITH THE USE OF SYNTHETIC FILTER FABRICS IN COASTAL ENGINEERING</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heerten, Georg</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">filter fabric</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">synthetic fabric</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Various types of synthetic filter fabrics are available for geotechnical applications. Especially in the field of coastal engineering a lot of experiences are generally known. Unfortunately technical recommendations and testing regulations for specific implimentations of geotextiles are not generally available and some actual examples of damage of coastal structures urgently require investigations on long-term resistance. A research program oriented towards the development of guidelines for testing geotextiles, the development of filtration rules and the clarification of long-term resistance of fabrics was carried out. This paper deals with testing procedures associatied with the estimation of the opening size and the permeability to water of fabrics. Results of investigations on long-term resistance are described and filtration rules for selecting a fabric according to the special requirements of the application are given.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1980-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3559</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v17.130</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 17 (1980): Proceedings of 17th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 1980.; 130</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3559/3241</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
