<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3371</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T00:11:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DISTRIBUTION OF SAND TRANSPORT RATE ACROSS A SURF ZONE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Swaragi, Toru</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Deguchi, Ichiro</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sediment transport</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">surf zone</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">transport rate</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The distributions of longshore and on-offshore sediment transport rates in a surf zone were measured by an apparatus which was able to separately record both components of the sediment transport rate,, The characteristics of their distributions were discussed from the bottom shear stresses which were measured by the shear meter under the same wave conditions as the laboratory experiment of the sediment transport. The maximum bottom shear stress took place at the depth between the breaking depth of waves and the depth where the velocity of the longshore current showed a maximum. On the other hand, the maximum on-offshore and longshore sediment transport rates occured at the depth slightly shallower than the depth where the maximum bottom shear stress took place. What's more, the longshore sediment transport rates were represented by the longshore current velocity and the bottom shear stress generated by waves and the longshore current. However, the distribution of the on-offshore sediment transport rates showed more complicated profile than that of the longshore sediment transport rates because there were no eminent unidirectional flow in the direction normal to the shore line. Therefore, the on-offshore sediment transport rates could not be formulated by the bottom shear stresses.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3371</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v16.95</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 16 (1978): Proceedings of 16th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Hamburg, Germany, 1978.; 95</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3371/3051</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
