<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3909</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T21:01:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DUCK82 - A COASTAL STORM PROCESSES EXPERIMENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mason, Curtis</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sallenger, Asbury H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Holman, Robert A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Birkemeier, William A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">DUCK82</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">storm processes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">storm experiment</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In recent years, several field experiments have been conducted to define nearshore processes and sediment transport patterns under "normal" wave and wind conditions. Large arrays of wave and current measuring sensors, combined with bathymetric surveys, have provided preliminary evidence of complex relationships between forcing processes and sediment response. To date, however, lack of both rugged instrumentation and a means to survey nearshore areas during high wave conditions have precluded measurements of storm-related nearshore processes. To document the response of a typical East Coast site to extratropical storms (northeasters), a cooperative experiment known as DUCK- 82, was conducted in October, 1982 at the Field Research Facility (FRF) of the U. S. Army Engineer Waterways Experiment Station, Coastal Engineering Research Center, Vicksburg, Miss. Participating in the experiment were investigators from the FRF, the 0. S. Geological Survey, Oregon State University, and the University of Washington. Newly developed sensors and equipment were deployed which, for the first time, allowed a comprehensive analysis of the processes affecting the magnitude and time scale of short-term nearshore response.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3909</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v19.128</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 19 (1984): Proceedings of 19th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Houston, Texas, 1984.; 128</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3909/3592</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
