<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14488</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T10:32:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SALT MARSH AND EXTREME CONDITIONS: A LARGE SCALE EXPERIMENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Antonini, Alessandro</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dermentzoglou, Dimitrios</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Muller, Jos</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tissier, Marion</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Breteler, Mark Klein</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Willemsen, Pim</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mason, Victoria</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bouma, Tjeerd</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vouziouris, Akis</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buring, Paul</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hofland, Bas</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Borsje, Bas</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In densely populated coastal regions across the globe, hard sea defenses have been widely used to guarantee the safety of the population and exposed assets. However, the efficacy of these hard structures has come under scrutiny in recent times due to the expected impacts of climate change and the claimed inappropriate behavior due to their static nature. In 1925, A.G. Verhoeven (Verhoeven, 1938) introduced the concept of man-made salt marshes for land reclamation purpose. He transplanted around 40,000 Spartina Townsendii plants from their native southern UK habitat to Zeeland, the coastal southernmost region of the Netherlands. In doing so, Verhoeven inadvertently played a pioneering role in the early development of the 'Building with Nature' concept. Since then, several decades of dedicated research showed the potential use of salt marshes as low environmental impact structures (Maza et al., 2015) as an opportunity to be quantitatively investigated, Willemsen et al., 2020, Vuik et al. 2019, Borsje et al., 2011; Gedan et al., 2010; Costanza et al., 1997; Chapman VJ., 1974. Nevertheless, a comprehensive understanding of wave attenuation by salt marsh and its survivability remains limited, with only a few experimental studies addressing this topic under mild hydrodynamic conditions (Ghodoosipour et al., 2022; Maza et al., 2015; Möller et al., 2014). As a result of this knowledge gap, salt marshes have been excluded from technical consideration within coastal flood protection systems and the underlying risk quantification, thereby allowing for speculative claims regarding their efficacy in mitigating coastal flooding, both in the Netherlands and internationally. This contribution aims to present the first worldwide large-scale test dedicated to quantitatively describe the response and survivability of a salt marsh under extreme hydrodynamic conditions while also providing a complete overview of the complex background activities required for such a unique experiment.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14488</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.165</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.165</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14488/13760</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Alessandro Antonini, Dimitrios Dermentzoglou, Jos Muller, Marion Tissier, Mark Klein Breteler, Pim Willemsen, Victoria Mason, Tjeerd Bouma, Akis Vouziouris, Paul Buring, Bas Hofland, Bas Borsje</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
