<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2544</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T04:30:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">CUFF DRAINAGE AND BEACH DISTRIBUTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fryde, W.T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cliff drainage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beach distribution</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The works described m this paper are part of a large Coast Protection scheme recently completed at Clacton-on- Sea, Essex, England. The paper is m two parts, the first describing cliff drainage and the second dealing with beach distribution. The method of drainage departs from the usual one of surface rubble drains and comprises a system of auger bored vertical and inclined drains. This method of drainage does not depend on the slope of the cliff face, its most important feature being that it makes it possible to dram the water away from within the cliffs. The second section describes the effect of large impermeable groynes on beach distribution as experienced at Clacton and the remedial works carried out, including tipping of imported material to improve the beach levels, and the results achieved. Both sections of the paper refer to the specific problems encountered on the Clacton frontage and the methods adopted to deal with them. The solutions found could be applied to other frontages but thorough investigations would be necessary beforehand due to the very varying nature between one frontage and another.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1968-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2544</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v11.41</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 11 (1968): Proceedings of 11th Conference on Coastal Engineering, London, United Kingdom, 1968.; 41</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2544/2209</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
