<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10341</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE ROLE OF GEOTEXTILE TUBE AS LOW-CRESTED BREAKWATERS IN RESTORING SEVERE BEACH EROSION PROBLEM AT PEBUAHAN BEACH IN BALI ISLAND</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sulaiman, Dede</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hidayat, Hendra</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Pebuahan Beach in Jembrana Regency, Bali has experienced severe beach erosion since the construction of the Nusantara Pengambengan fishing port, 10 km east of Pebuahan. Efforts to countermeasure the coastal problem has been carried out by many local residents, but failed due to strong longshore drift. Through a collaboration between the Research Center for Water Resources, the Bali Penida River Basin, and PT. Geotechnical Systemindo, the implementation of low-crested breakwaters (LCB) or PEGAR, made of Woven Geotextile Tubes was initiated. Four woven geotextile tubes C12.9 m with length varied from 20 m to 25 m were installed to form LCB with the length of 60 m, at distance to the coast of 50 m. The monitoring of shoreline changes was conducted over the 3 months after its installation, which shows the formation of a new shoreline with the amount of deposited sand of 185.8 m3. The breaking wave on LCB crest results in successfully controlling the longshore current, hence the longshore drift settles behind the LCB to form a new coastline. It is expected this field study can be treated as an additional input to improve LCB Guideline and to expand LCB effectiveness scope not only apply to shallow wave conditions and beaches such as on North coast of Java, but also can be applied more universally to a deeper coastal waters with high wave conditions.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/AFzvkvYY2Do</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10341</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.papers.53</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; papers.53</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10341/9627</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Dede Sulaiman, Hendra Hidayat</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
