<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/13979</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EROSION PROCESS OF A CLAY REVETMENT WITH GRASS COVER ON COASTAL FLOOD DEFENCES BASED ON LARGE SCALE PHYSICAL MODEL TESTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bergeijk, Vera van</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zwanenburg, Suzanna</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nieuwenhuis, Jan-Willem</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jong, Kees de</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Meer, Martin van der</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Halter, Werner</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buring, Paul</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Breteler, Mark Klein</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Clay and grass are natural building materials for flood defences that has been used in the Netherlands for centuries. However, the erosion process of the clay layer under wave loads is not well understood and is therefore usually not included in design and safety assessment methods in the Netherlands. Full scale physical model tests have been performed in the Delta Flume – the large scale wave flume at Deltares - with an undisturbed layer of clay and grass from sea dikes. Three measurement campaigns have been performed with 9 clay types and different geometries: slope steepness between 1:4 – 1:7 with and without a berm. The erosion process on the outer slope by wave impacts has been studied for significant wave heights up to 2 m and varying water levels. The results show that the erosion process of the clay revetment after erosion of the grass cover consists of two phases. During the first phase, the erosion mainly develops in depth. This erosion process shows a fast increase in erosion depth with a relatively small increase in eroded volume as the additional strength of the grass cover roots in this upper clay layer slows the growth of the erosion hole towards the dike crest. At a depth of around 50 cm, the grass cover roots have negligible influence on the erosion process allowing the erosion hole to grow faster towards the crest. A cliff is formed in the erosion hole and the second phase starts. During the second phase, the waves impact on the cliff resulting in cliff erosion and migration of the cliff towards the crest. The results of the physical model tests can be used to determine the erodibility of the different clay types and to develop formulas for the design and assessment of coastal flood defences built with local and natural materials.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13979</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.papers.28</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; papers.28</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13979/13251</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Vera van Bergeijk, Suzanna Zwanenburg, Jan-Willem Nieuwenhuis, Kees de Jong, Martin van der Meer, Werner Halter, Paul Buring, Mark Klein Breteler</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
