<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2163</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T06:15:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE USE OF RADAR IN HYDRODYNAMIC SURVEYING</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oudshoorn, H.M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">radar</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hydrodynamic surveying</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">radio</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Rotterdam</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">During several kinds of surveys at sea or in the wide estuaries in the South West of the Netherlands the location of moving objects presents a problem. When studying the various systems of radio location it appeared that radar, an instrument which gives a birds eye view of a fairly extensive area, could be a useful aid in solving this problem. Especially when it was shown that with the newly developed short-wave radar sets wave crests were clearly visible on the radar screen, it was considered worth while to carry out some tests to see whether radar would really be useful for surveying purposes * In 1958 the Rijkswaterstaat hired an 8 mm radar set for a trial period. The tests were carried out at the mouth of the entrance channel to the Rotterdam harbour, the Rotterdam Waterway. During these tests it became evident that radar could solve several problems and that valuable information about wave patterns could be gathered with this instrument. The set was bought and then used to determine 1. flow patterns 2. wave patterns 3. the behaviour of ships in fairways. In paragraphs 2 and 3 some basic principles of radar are discussed in order to establish the special requirements the radar equipment must satisfy for this particular purpose, [l] In paragraphs ^-7 the methods of observation and the results obtained for the purposes mentioned above are discussed and some practical examples given.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1960-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2163</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v7.4</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 7 (1960): Proceedings of 7th Conference on Coastal Engineering, The Hague, The Netherlands, 1960.; 4</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2163/1857</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
