<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14018</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">STUDY OF SEDIMENTATION PROBLEM AT KIASHAHR FISHERY PORT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Javanmard, Zahra</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Soltanpour, Mohsen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shibayama, Tomoya</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ranji, Zahra</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study investigates the significant sedimentation issues observed at Kiashahr Fishery Port in the southern Caspian Sea. Utilizing satellite imagery, hydrographic maps, and numerical modeling, this research examines the impact of port design and environmental factors on sediment accumulation. Despite the initial positioning of the jetties within the surf zone, the study reveals that changes in the dynamic Sefidroud Delta have intensified longshore sediment transport towards the port. Furthermore, the extension of the main breakwater, intended to enhance updrift sediment trapping, inadvertently induced a circulation current behind the secondary breakwater, leading to increased downdrift sediment transport toward the port. This, combined with the bypassing of littoral drift in front of the main breakwater, resulted in substantial sediment accumulation at the port entrance from both updrift and downdrift directions. The findings highlight the critical importance of considering both local hydrodynamics and proper layout design in the planning and construction of coastal structures, particularly for small fishery ports.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14018</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.papers.67</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; papers.67</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14018/13290</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Zahra Javanmard, Mohsen Soltanpour, Tomoya Shibayama, Zahra Ranji</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
