<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3179</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T01:12:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">WAVE ACTION ON LARGE OFF-SHORE STRUCTURES</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Apelt, C.J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Macknight, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">offshore structures</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">offshore waves</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The paper describes investigations carried out in order to design for the wave action, both wave force and scour, on large off-shore berthing structures sited approximately 1.3 miles (2.1 km) off-shore near Hay Point, North Queensland, in 56 feet (17 m) of water at low tide, the tidal range being 20 feet (6 m). The region is a cyclone area and the structures must be capable of withstanding attack from maximum predicted waves with period of 8.25 seconds and amplitude of 24 feet (7.3 m). The main units in the berthing structures are concrete caissons sunk on to the ocean bed and the largest of these have plan dimensions of approximately 150 feet (46.7 m) by 135 feet (41.4 m) with four columns approximately 40 feet (12.2 m) square projecting through the water surface. No theoretical method available at the time of the investigation was capable of accurate calculation of wave forces on these structures. A scale model was tested to obtain wave forces and the paper compares results from the model with those of numerical methods and discusses the application of the results to the design functions. Scour effects were also modelled and the results used as the basis for design of scour protection.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1976-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3179</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v15.129</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 15 (1976): Proceedings of 15th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1976.; 129</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3179/2843</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
