<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2206</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T05:59:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MODERN DESIGN AND CONSTRUCTION OF DAMS AND DIKES BUILT WITH THE USE OF ASPHALT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Van Asberk, Baron W.F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dam</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dike</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">construction of dams/dikes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">asphalt</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In recent years quite a number of important coast protection and harbour construction works in Europe, in the U.S.A. and in Japan have been built or strengthened with the use of asphalt according to established methods of construction in various countries. These works have proved to be not only technically sound and durable but also economical in initial capital investment as well as in maintenance costs. Moreover, as the results obtained have been very encouraging, new outlets and methods of construction with asphalt are being sought, and systematically investigated and developed to cover a wider field of application for coast protection and harbour construction works. Although there are many purposes and means of applying asphalt constructions for these works, the author has limited the scope of his paper to describe in particular the fundamental problems related to the hydraulic and asphalt-technical aspects of building dams and dikes of sand according to the hydraulic fill process, covered and protected by a two course hot-mix asphalt revetment or layer. Assuming a general knowledge of the various facets of hydraulic dam and dike constructions and of asphalt construction methods the author deals with essential items concerning the hydraulic and strength design of asphalt revetments for dikes and dams and describes certain details of construction that require particular attention and perhaps further investigation as experience has proved.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1960-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2206</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v7.47</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 7 (1960): Proceedings of 7th Conference on Coastal Engineering, The Hague, The Netherlands, 1960.; 47</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2206/1900</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
