<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10405</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Plenary</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DEVELOPMENT OF A NEARSHORE EXTREME EVENTS RECONNAISSANCE COMMUNITY</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Raubenheimer, Britt</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Extreme events have significant impacts on the nearshore water-land system - where ocean, sound, and estuary processes interact with the nearby land - that pose high risk to society. Observations before, during, and after these events are critical to improve understanding of the interactions and feedbacks among the natural and built environments during major storms, and the corresponding human actions and reactions. The goal of the Nearshore Extreme Events Reconnaissance (NEER) Association is to organize and coordinate a national network of scientists spanning many disciplines to perform rapid, pre-and post-event site characterization, to deploy instruments to observe event processes, and to gather virtual data about the event and provide support to field teams. This presentation provides information about NEER's motivation, event-response and coordination activities, data-distribution plans, and lessons learned to date. Funding for NEER is provided by the U.S. National Science Foundation Coastlines and People Program.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/9I9Z3OLGszU</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10405</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.keynote.12</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; keynote.12</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Britt Raubenheimer</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
