<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3545</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T23:10:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">FULL SCALE TRAILS OF DOLOSSE TO DESTRUCTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Burcharth, Hans F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dolos</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">destruction of dolos</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">destruction tests</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It is well known that the relative dynamic strength of unreinforced slender concrete units decreases as the size increases. Big units can resist relatively smaller movements than small units. When model tests of cover layer stability are performed the determination of the damage criterion that should be adopted must therefore be based on knowledge of the dynamic strength of the corresponding prototype units. With the purpose of establishing a relation between the size and the dynamic strength of unreinforced units some full scale tests to destruction of 1.5 and 5.4 t units were performed. The set up and the procedure of the tests which simulates the impact from rocking of the units and from concrete pieces that are thrown against the units are designed to make a comparison between the behaviour of units of different sizes possible. The test method is described and proposed as a standard method. The theoretical expression for the dynamic strength is compared with the test results and it is shown that if the units are allowed to move there is an upper limit for the size of unreinforced units where a balance between the hydraulic stability of the cover layer and the strength of the units exists. Different ways of improving the strength of the units are discussed on the basis of the results from tests with different types of concrete. The tests included an investigation of the influence of reinforcement, and of different types of concrete and surface cracks on the performance of the units.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1980-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3545</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v17.117</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 17 (1980): Proceedings of 17th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 1980.; 117</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3545/3227</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
