<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/938</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T07:26:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:ICCE</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EROSION AND CORROSION ON MARINE STRUCTURES, ELWOOD, CALIFORNIA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schaufele, H. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">corrosion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">erosion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">piles</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sheet piles</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The sole purpose of this paper is to present to the public more than twenty years' experience acquired in designing for, and eventually combating, the unusual forces of nature acting on marine structures in exposed waters. The structural design will naturally be determined by the use the project is called upon to serve and the standards of the designer. This particular phase of the overall picture, with the aid of available meteorological and oceanographical data for a specific area offers no particular difficulty in structural design. The subject matter presented herein refers to observations made among the various pier and oil well foundations constructed in the Elwood Field, California, during the interval between 1929 and 1935, and major maintenance problems to date. Where protective measures made at the time of installation are explained, they refer to our own specific works, while the general observations in the field are confined to no one particular structure or type of design.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1950-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/938</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v1.35</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 1 (1950): Proceedings of First Conference on Coastal Engineering, Long Beach, California, October, 1950.; 35</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/938/035_Schaufele</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
