<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6608</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-04T03:12:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Waves</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ON THE INFLUENCE OF BREAKING WAVE LOCAL GEOMETRY ON IMPULSIVE LOADS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abadie, Stephane Marc</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mokrani, Cyril</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave impact</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">impulsive loads</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pressure peaks</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">numerical modeling</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Navier-Stokes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Volume of Fluid.</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In this paper, we study the wave impact process with a multi-fluid Navier-Stokes model (THETIS). Preliminary simulations have been conducted, first on a plunging wave generated by unstable Stokes initial condition, and second, involving a dam breaking bore impact. In both cases, a convergence study shows pressure peak results instability when using different meshes. This is due to the incapacity of the model to ensure, after a certain time of computation,  the exact same surface profile at impact when simulating a specific case with different meshes. This instable numerical behavior is somehow similar to peak pressure instabilities observed in experiments. This similarity shows the critical role played by local free surface shape at impact on impulsive loads.  When initializing  the model with a specific interface right at impact, convergence is observed and the pressure peaks are correctly assessed by the code for moderate intensity impact. However, further improvements are still needed especially  regarding the interface tracking technique to simulate the most violent impacts involving the weaker dead rise angles. The paper also encourages us to use numerical simulations preferably to study impact flow at local scale.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2012-10-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/6608</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v33.waves.61</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 33 (2012): Proceedings of 33rd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Santander, Spain, 2012; waves.61</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/6608/pdf_597</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
