<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14047</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">PROTOTYPING AN ENGINEERED ALGAE FIELD TO ATTENUATE LONG SWELLS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hurtado, Felipe</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Toledo, Jean Pierre</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">López, Jesús</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zamora, Víctor</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Magnere, Milton</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bruna, Alexandra</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pérez, Jorge</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Córdova, Pablo</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Correa, Sebastián</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Winckler, Patricio</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sea level rise, increased storminess and land changes due to plate tectonics threaten South America’s western coasts with flooding, beach erosion and infrastructure damage. The significant amount of coastal systems exposed to such hazards in the region has motivated the design, construction and monitoring of a new prototype of engineered algae field (EAF), aimed to attenuate waves and reduce erosion, a widespread impact in Chilean coasts (Martínez et al. 2021). The EAF will be deployed by mid-2024 in a management and exploitation area of benthic resources (AMERB) located in Maitencillo (32.64°S,71.44°W), Chile. With this applied research project, we aim to fill a gap in a research topic where literature is focused on relatively stable coasts, shallow waters and mild wave climates which substantially differ from the highly energetic wave conditions and relatively deep shores found in subduction zones. The study aims to assess the technical feasibility of the EAF using local kelp species on the project site, and if proved successful, to scale up the solution. The design process considers a combination of numerical and physical models to assess the performance of the EAF. Once deployed, a monitoring scheme will include measuring its hydraulic efficiency, structural stability and algae growth rate for one year. The project is funded by ANID’s agency under grant FONDEF ID23I10078.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14047</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.4</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.4</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14047/13319</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Felipe Hurtado, Jean Pierre Toledo, Jesús López, Víctor Zamora, Milton Magnere, Alexandra Bruna, Jorge Pérez, Pablo Córdova, Sebastián Correa, Patricio Winckler</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
