<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12951</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:14:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ASSESSMENT OF COASTAL DAMAGE FOR THE COOLING WATER INTAKE STRUCTURE OF A COAL-FIRED POWER PLANT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dita, Andrei Raphael P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cruz, Eric C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Santos, Jose Carlo Eric L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Last October 2020, a strong tropical cyclone with international name Molave (local name: Quinta) caused widespread damage to agricultural and infrastructure sectors in the Philippines. Among those affected is a coalfired power plant located within the vicinity of Tayabas Bay. The velocity cap at the head of the cooling water intake structure of the power plant was found washed ashore in the morning of October 26, 2020 (PH time) after the onslaught of Typhoon Molave. Underwater site investigations post-typhoon revealed that the walls and other components of the intake structure were damaged as well. The intake structure head was initially built at seabed depths of 9m below Mean Tide Level (MTL), while the velocity cap was topped at 6m below MTL. This paper presents the forensic analysis and coastal damage assessment methodology carried out to identify the nearshore hydrodynamic conditions during the passage of potentially critical typhoons throughout the useful life of the intake structure (2017 to 2020).             </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12951</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.structures.95</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; structures.95</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12951/12224</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Andrei Raphael P. Dita, Eric C. Cruz, Jose Carlo Eric L. Santos</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
