<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1118</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-04T04:12:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">WAVE OVERTOPPING AND RUBBLE MOUND STABILITY UNDER COMBINED LOADING OF WAVES AND CURRENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Eslami A., Sepehr</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Van Gent, Marcel R.A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">physical model tests</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">rock slopes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">breakwaters</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">overtopping</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stability</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">waves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">current</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Coastal structures such as breakwaters are usually studied under wave loading only. However, at several locations also a current is present. For instance, breakwaters along intake and outfall channels of power plants and desalination plants, or structures in regions with important tidal currents, experience wave loading that can be affected by currents. Nevertheless, wave overtopping and rubble mound stability are usually studied under wave loading only; the effects of waves on wave overtopping and rock slope stability have been summarised in many empirical design formulae. None of the existing empirical relations account for the effects of currents on the wave loading and consequently on wave overtopping and rock slope stability. The effects of wave-current interaction on wave overtopping and rubble mound stability has not been quantified, other than that for mild currents these processes are dominated by waves. Therefore, the present study is focussed on wave loading in combination with a strong current. This study is based on physical model tests in a wave-current basin. The results show to what extent wave overtopping and rubble mound stability are affected by wave loading in combination with a current. Wave overtopping and the damage to rock slopes generally reduce due to the presence of a current compared to the situation without a current.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1118</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v32.structures.12</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 32 (2010): Proceedings of 32nd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Shanghai, China, 2010.; structures.12</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1118/pdf_204</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
