<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14043</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">NUMERICAL STUDY OF THE EFFECT OF SHIPPING CONTAINER STORAGE YARD LAYOUTS ON THEIR TRANSPORT IN EXTREME HYDRODYNAMIC EVENTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ruffini, Gioele</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Briganti, Riccardo</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stolle, Jacob</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Girolamo, Paolo De</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Extreme hydrodynamic events, such as those driven by tsunamis, most notably in Tohoku, Japan 2011 (Mori et al., 2011) and in Indonesia 2004 and 2018 (Sassa et al., 2019), have shown the need to consider debris for an accurate hazard assessment. Three main processes are relevant in this context: (I) debris transport and dispersion (Naito et al. 2014), (II) debris impact on coastal structures and infrastructures (Stolle et al., 2018, De Iasio et al., 2023) and (III) debris damming (Mauti et al., 2020). For (II) and (III), multiple design guidelines for structures, such as the FEMA P646 (FEMA, 2012) and American Society for Civil Engineers design codes (ASCE, 2016), were developed. (I) is mainly addressed either by simple empirical laws or by laboratory experiments. Numerical simulations of debris transport are still challenging in realistic conditions (Koh et al. 2023). Simple empirical rules describe debris lateral dispersion defined by a spreading area ±22.5° from the initial position (Naito et al. 2014), and by a dispersion law depending on the number of debris transported (Nistor et al., 2017). Harbours and nearby areas are exposed to container transport hazard (Naito et al. 2014., Koh et al. 2023). This makes understanding the role of tsunamis impact angle and storage yard layout on the movement of shipping containers particularly important. While dispersion at city scale can be simulated with depth integrated models (Koh et al. (2023), the analysis of the pick-up stage and near field transport requires modelling of the six degrees of freedom of the waterborne debris. Due to their nature, Lagrangian numerical models have been used to simulate these problems. More specifically Smoothed Particles Hydrodynamics (SPH) models coupled with the Multiphysics model CHRONO have recently demonstrated their capability in accurately simulating these type of phenomena (Ruffini et al., 2021, 2023). Using this numerical approach, this study aims to provide insight into the role of the initial debris layout in the hazard generated by their mobilisation, focusing on shipping containers in harbours.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14043</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.2</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14043/13315</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Gioele Ruffini, Riccardo Briganti, Jacob Stolle, Paolo De Girolamo</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
