<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4631</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T16:54:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A NUMERICAL MODEL FOR SAND TRANSPORT UNDER COMPOUND WAVES</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sato, Shinji</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mitsunobu, Norihiko</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">numerical model</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sediment transport</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">compound waves</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In order to understand sediment transport around various maritime structures, it is essential to elucidate the mechanism of sand transport under compound waves. Although numerous studies have been carried out on sand transport, most of them have been concentrated to the sand movement mechanism under one-component wave. Laboratory experiments and numerical modeling of sand movement under compound waves are required for better understanding sand transport due to three-dimensional waves. The objectives of the present study are to describe sand transport mechanism under three-dimensional compound waves through laboratory experiments and to develop a numerical model to estimate the net sand transport rate under compound waves. As a simple example of compound wave field, we selected the wave field in front of a breakwater with obliquely incident waves. This is because under such conditions the water particle near the bottom moves in various orbits, from linear to elliptic or circular orbit, so that they cover a wide range of conditions encountered in general compound wave conditions.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1990-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4631</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v22.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 22 (1990): Proceedings of 22nd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Delft, The Netherlands, 1990.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4631/4312</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
