<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14025</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ROLE OF WAVE-INDUCED OSILLATORY MOTIONS IN DEVELOPPMENT OF SANDY- MUDDY TRANSITIONAL BEACHES ON SOUTH CHINA COASTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Li, Yuan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zhang, Chi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zhao, Shaohua</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Qi, Hongshuai</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sandy-muddy transitional beaches (SMT-Beaches) consist of an upper sand shoreface and a lower mudflat, connected by a distinct sand-mud transition (SMT) boundary. The formation and development of SMT-Beaches require unique geological and dynamical conditions. Therefore, SMT-Beaches receive less attention compared with sandy beaches or sand-gravel mixed beaches. SMT-Beaches are mainly supplied with the sediments originating from e.g., river mouths, and the mud finally deposits on the intertidal or subtidal zone (Anthony and Dolique, 2004). The position of SMT boundary depends on the hydrodynamically controlled non-deposition of mud and the intensity of the mud supply. On SMT-Beaches, the exchange of sediments between the upper beachface and the lower shoreface is still unclear. Unlike pure sandy beaches with sufficiently in- depth studies, it is found that the exchange between the upper and lower shoreface is dominated by waves (Anthony and Aagaard, 2020), e.g., sandbar offshore migration transporting sediments from the upper shoreface to the lower shoreface under energetic wave conditions (Li et al., 2021), and onshore migration and wielding of sandbars transporting sediments from the lower shoreface to upper shoreface under mild wave conditions. So far, studies on sediment transport on SMT-Beaches are just starting up (Guo et al., 2021). More attention needs to be paid to the hydrodynamically-controlled mud deposition, to get comprehensive insights on the formation of the SMT- Boundary.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14025</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.sediment.2</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; sediment.2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14025/13297</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Yuan Li, Chi Zhang, Shaohua Zhao, Hongshuai Qi</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
