<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1357</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-04T03:48:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BARRIER ISLAND RESTORATION FOR STORM DAMAGE REDUCTION: WILLAPA BAY, WASHINGTON, USA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Michalsen, David R</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Babcock, Steven D</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lin, Lihwa</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">extreme water levels</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">barrier island restoration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">flood risk</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave modeling</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Seattle District has completed a feasibility study and determined barrier island restoration to be the most appropriate long-term coastal flood and storm damage reduction measure for the Shoalwater Indian Reservation.   Over the last century, Cape Shoalwater has receded more than 2.8 miles.  By 1990, the Shoalwater Reservation's only remaining protection from storm wave attack was a series of barrier islands fronting Tokeland Peninsula.  Extreme water levels coincident with strong winter storms have historically inundated this low lying topography and are responsible for the erosion and overwash of the protective barrier island known as Graveyard Spit.  Here a simple risk assessment tool is presented for identifying flood risk to the Shoalwater Reservation infrastructure.  Statistical analysis of extreme water levels and numerical modeling is utilized to determine the extent of inundation.  From the analysis it was determined 54% of the inventoried infrastructure is at risk during a storm event equivalent to the observed event on March 3, 1999.  With the barrier island restoration it was found that this risk is reduced to 7%.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1357</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v32.management.32</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 32 (2010): Proceedings of 32nd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Shanghai, China, 2010.; management.32</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1357/pdf_334</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
