<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14607</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T07:37:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">URBAN-INTEGRATED STRATEGIES FOR CLIMATE CHANGE ADAPTATION AT COASTAL COMMUNITIES</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lara, Javier</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Eulate, Maria Alvarez de</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lucio, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fernandez, Alberto</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Losada, Inigo</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Coastal regions are increasingly vulnerable to the impacts of climate change, with rising sea levels and a surge in extreme weather events, a trend reinforced by the latest climate projections (IPCC, 2023). In pursuit of sustainable development and heightened resilience, a novel methodology is proposed within the LIFE-Garachico project in Tenerife, Spain. This approach revolves around designing adaptation measures considering the evolving perception and acceptable risk levels of the population. These adaptations must align with risk reduction principles following IPCC guidelines, recognizing the dynamic relationships between current, future, perceived, and acceptable flood risks. Simultaneously, they acknowledge that complete prevention of coastal flooding is impossible, necessitating that Macaronesia's coastal communities learn to coexist with such events. This comprehensive methodology seeks public engagement through information campaigns and stakeholder involvement at local and regional levels to ensure that adaptation measures are effective, integrated in the urban landscape and embraced by the community.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14607</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.191</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.191</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14607/13879</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Javier Lara, Maria Alvarez de Eulate, David Lucio, Alberto Fernandez, Inigo Losada</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
