<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3555</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T23:07:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SITING AND DESIGN CRITERIA OF DOCK STRUCTURES IN THE MARSHALL ISLANDS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Noble, R.M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leslie, K.C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">O'Day, D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Marshal Islands</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">design criteria</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dock siting</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dock</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the summer of 1978, a siting/design investigation for dock structures (Marshall Islands Dock Project) was conducted at 15 atolls within the Marshall Islands group (see Figure 1). The Marshall Islands are within the U.S. Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands (TTPI), located in the North Pacific. The Marshall Islands Dock Project is part of the Capital Improvements Program currently underway in the Marshalls. The program, aimed towards making the Marshall Islands more selfsufficient in preparation for their independence in 1981, includes the construction of low cost dock structures for use by the design vessels described in this paper to load/unload agricultural products, supplies, and passengers. This study did not include the feasibility of this approach versus other alternative loading/unloading approaches. This investigation included site selection, development of design criteria, and the design and alignment schemes for 12 new dock structures. In addition, design criteria and plans were developed for the upgrading of three existing dock structures. The site selection was performed using a multidisciplinary approach which considered environmental, sociological, and archaeological impacts, in addition to the usual technical site selection. This paper only discusses the technical considerations to site selection. Overall responsibility for the project was assumed by the Pacific Ocean Division of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers on behalf of the Government of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. Our work was performed for Alfred A. Yee &amp; Associates, Inc., the structural engineer and prime contractor for the project, and in collaboration with R. M. Towill Corporation.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1980-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v17.126</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 17 (1980): Proceedings of 17th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 1980.; 126</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3555/3236</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
