<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7657</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T04:16:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Posters</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BACK-SILTING CAUSES UNDER NORMAL ENVIRONMENTS OF THE UPPER SECTION OF DEEP-WATER CHANNEL IN YANGTZE ESTUARY, CHINA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Li, Xiaoxiao</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zhao, Xiaodong</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dou, Xiping</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In this paper, the deep-water channel back-silting causes in the South Channel-Yuanyuansha section will be discussed by analyzing field data and physical and numerical simulation results. According to the field data, the causes were sought from the points of channel-silting characteristics, changes of flow, sediment and salinity environments and variation of riverbed. Sediment-character basic test and sediment-transport physical test were carried out for sediment-transport rules in the South Channel-Yuanyuansha section. The causes are also studied from the aspect of waterway deepening by numerical simulation. The following are the main causes: 1) sediment supply for South Channel-Yuanyuansha section from the upstream increases; 2) water with high sediment concentration flowing over the south training jetty to Yuanyuansha section offers a suspended sediment source; 3) waterway deepens in South Channel-Yuanyuansha section; 4) silting duration in Yuanyuansha section increases after the three-phase silting reduction engineering.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/7657</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v34.posters.33</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 34 (2014): Proceedings of 34th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Seoul, Korea, 2014; posters.33</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/7657/pdf_850</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
