<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14651</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T08:14:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">RUN-UP AT RUBBLE MOUND BREAKWATERS WITH SUBMERGED BERM: AN EXPERIMENTAL STUDY</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Celli, Daniele</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Castellino, Myrta</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pasquali, Davide</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nucci, Carmine Di</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Girolamo, Paolo De</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Risio, Marcello Di</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the recent years, the effects of climate change are becoming increasingly evident (e.g., Naughten et al., 2023; Pörtner et al., 2022). Sea level rise, change in the intensity of storm surge, and wave heights are typical consequences of climate change in the coastal environment (e.g., Toimil et al., 2020). Therefore, coastal structures deployed to protect coastlines and harbors from wave action, may become ineffective due to the potential increase of wave loads, run-up, and overtopping phenomena (e.g., Galiatsatou et al., 2018). Indeed, several adaptation measures for existing coastal structures have been proposed (e.g., Burcharth et al., 2014). Past research studies illustrated how the deployment of a berm in the seaward side of conventional rubble mound breakwaters can significantly improve the performance of the structure. (e.g. Van Gent, 2013; Celli et al., 2018; Celli et al., 2021). Basically, the presence of a berm enhances the wave energy dissipation at the toe of the armor layer. Besides the stability of the structure, this could be effective in the reduction of wave run-up, and overtopping phenomena, potentially. To investigate the role of the submerged berm on the wave run-up phenomenon, a series of 2D experimental tests is being carried out at the Environmental and Maritime Hydraulic Laboratory (LIam) of the University of L'Aquila.      </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14651</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.structures.105</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; structures.105</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14651/13923</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Daniele Celli, Myrta Castellino, Davide Pasquali, Carmine Di Nucci, Paolo De Girolamo, Marcello Di Risio</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
