<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12974</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:14:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">APPLICABILITY OF ATMOSPHERIC REANALYSIS DATA FOR THE REPRODUCTION OF TYPHOON-INDUCED STORM SURGE IN JAPAN</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Amunugama, Mangala</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ono, Nobuyuki</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Suzuyama, Katsuyuki</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ogata, Takehiko</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The accurate estimation of a typhoon is a key to improving the reproducibility of typhoon-induced storm surges. The grid point value (GPV) data of Local Forecasting Model (LFM), which are provided by the Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA), are shown to be the most accurate data to simulate typhoons in and around Japan. However, due to the limitations of LFM data (limited spatial and temporal coverage), the atmospheric reanalysis data, which are available for the global domain covering a long period, are commonly used in practical applications. According to previous researchers, it is expected to give a better representation of typhoons in terms of structure and intensity with reanalysis datasets although they are in too coarse resolutions to capture the internal dynamics (Malakar et al., 2020), and the reproducibility of typhoons with different reanalysis datasets varies over different oceanic basins (Schenkel and Hart, 2012). Hence, this paper analyses the two major atmospheric reanalysis datasets together with LFM dataset, and confirms their applicability to reproduce typhoon-induced storm surges in Japan.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12974</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.management.16</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; management.16</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12974/12247</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Mangala Amunugama, Nobuyuki Ono, Katsuyuki Suzuyama, Takehiko Ogata</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
