<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10197</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DUNE EROSION AND SAND BAR MIGRATION DURING A STORM EVENT: LARGE-SCALE WAVE FLUME TEST AND NUMERICAL SIMULATION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shin, Sungwon</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kim, Jichang</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Yoo, Jeseon</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Do, Kideok</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chang, Tae Soo</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kim, Jinah</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The coastal sand dune is an important natural coastal protection system in the nearshore region from storm wave damage. USACE (2013) introduced coastal dune as Nature and Nature-Based Feature for coastal resilience. Therefore, accurately predicting the dune erosion and sediment transport is very important not only to protect the coastal community from the extreme wave but also to provide design guideline for restoration. However, the ability to accurately predict the coastal dune morphodynamics has not been enough improved. The main objective of this study is to investigate erosion and deposition mechanisms of dune and sand bar by obtaining the synoptic data set of movable bed experiment during the entire storm event. Using the experimental data, this study tried to verify the numerical model (XBeachX). Moreover, box cores were used to track the storm history in surf and swash zone.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/E-Itkn36rLQ</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10197</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.sediment.34</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; sediment.34</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10197/9483</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Sungwon Shin, Jichang Kim, Jeseon Yoo, Kideok Do, Tae Soo Chang, Jinah Kim</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
