<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10126</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">CRITERIA FOR IMPLEMENTATION OF GREEN INFRASTRUCTURE IN COASTAL AREAS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chavez, Valeria</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lithgow,  Debora</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Silva, Rodolfo</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Unlike traditional infrastructure, which only takes into account socio-economic and political factors, or ecological restoration which focuses on the recovery of ecosystem health, resistance and resilience, green infrastructure has multifunctional goals, determined by the ecological and socioeconomic conditions of each, specific site (Silva et al., 2017). Connectivity, multifunctionality, integration and a multiscale approach are the key concepts in green infrastructure projects. Coastal green infrastructure projects include broad and contrasting aspects such as: 1. Recovery of the structure and functionality of natural ecosystems, 2. Creation of artificial ecosystems, 3. Engineering structures that depend on the functioning of the surrounding ecosystems, 4. Traditional engineering projects, adapted to reduce their environmental impact and, 5. Corrective actions applied to structures and land uses which damage the environment and threaten socio-economic aspects.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/76S-SfbIM4Y</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10126</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.management.17</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; management.17</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10126/9412</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Valeria Chavez,  Debora Lithgow, Rodolfo Silva</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
