<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14026</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">COST-EFFECTIVE SHOALING REDUCTION ALTERNATIVES FOR A NAVIGATION CHANNEL NEAR AN INLET</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kabiling, Michael B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Intracoastal Waterway (IWW) near Bakers Haulover Inlet in Miami, Florida passes 0.64 km west of the inlet. Wave- and tide-generated currents entrain and transport some of the littoral sediments through the inlet and the rest to downdrift nearshore areas. These currents can move sediments inshore until flow velocities decrease below a critical value, at which point sediments fall out of suspension and can form shoals in the IWW and surrounding areas. A Florida Department of Environmental Protection study (FDEP, 2021) estimates a total net transport into the inlet of approximately 46,410 m3/yr for 2007 – 2016. A review of U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE) data of IWW maintenance dredging events near Bakers Haulover Inlet from 1969 to 2017 shows shoaling volumes total 314,754 m3. Of this total volume, at least 71percent was dredged between 1969 and 1998 from within the 1.77-km portion of Cut-DA9 adjacent to Haulover Sandbar (North Flood Shoal) and South Flood Shoal. Thus, this portion of the IWW Cut-DA9 is vulnerable to large shoaling and historically required dredging on average once every 4 – 5 years to maintain the authorized IWW navigation depth of 3.05 m below mean lower low water.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14026</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.sediment.3</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; sediment.3</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14026/13298</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Michael B. Kabiling</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
