<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14198</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:32:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">STORM IMPACT ON BEACH NOURISHMENT MORPHOLOGY IN A SHALLOW BAY</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Adell, Anna</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Luetzenburg, Gregor</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kroon, Aart</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Almström, Björn</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hallin, Caroline</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Designing coastal protection solutions that combines hard and soft techniques can be an appropriate measure to reduce wave impact on structures (Steetzel et al., 2017). The elevated bed level in front of the hard protection dissipates energy and thereby limits wave runup and overtopping. This can increase the expected lifetime of the protection while also limiting the design dimensions and hence be a cost-effective alternative. In addition, the implementation of soft coastal protection measures in combination with hard structures can provide possible additional recreational and environmental functions. A beach nourishment was conducted in front of the rock revetment with the objectives to reduce wave overtopping onto the adjacent road and to restore the beach for recreation (Baden and Aarosiin-Hansen, 2017). Field measurements and observations, combined with numerical modelling has been conducted with the aim to monitor the morphological evolution of the nourishment and adjacent coastlines in order to assess the performance of the protection.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14198</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.sediment.34</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; sediment.34</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14198/13470</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Anna Adell, Gregor Luetzenburg, Aart Kroon, Björn Almström, Caroline Hallin</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
