<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14293</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:11:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Waves</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">TYPHOON-INDUCED EFFECTS ON WAVE EVOLUTION ACORSS COASTAL WETLANDS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zhao, Ying</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Peng, Zhong</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Coastal wetlands play a pivotal role in providing a natural shield against the relentless forces of wave energy and storm surges. Previous research, as demonstrated by Zhao et al. (2023), underscores the substantial impact that mudflats and saltmarsh areas can exert on the intricate process of wave evolution. Their ability to absorb, deflect, and dissipate wave energy makes coastal wetlands a vital component of the coastal landscape. Understanding the intricate dynamics of how waves transform and evolve as they interact with these ecosystems holds great significance. Such knowledge empowers us to comprehensively assess the effectiveness of coastal wetlands in mitigating flood risks, curbing erosion, and facilitating the movement of sediments within coastal environments. Furthermore, we witness the emergence of large and potent waves induced by typhoons can dramatically impact coastal regions. These typhoon-induced waves have the potential to trigger significant changes in wave distribution, alter the profiles of significant wave height, and reshape wave spectrums (Collins et al. 2018) along the coast. However, our understanding of how typhoons precisely influence the evolution of waves across coastal wetlands remains incomplete. As such, this study investigates the typhoon-induced effects on wave evolution at coastal wetlands, deepening our comprehension of wave evolution within these ecosystems. This research will not only aid in bolstering our coastal defences but also contribute to the broader field of coastal science and resilience.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14293</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.waves.51</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; waves.51</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14293/13565</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Ying Zhao, Zhong Peng</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
