<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5004</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T14:47:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DEVELOPMENT OF A PARTIALLY THREE-DIMENSIONAL MODEL FOR SHIP MOTION IN A HARBOR WITH ARBITRARY BATHYMETRY</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ohyama, Takumi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tsuchida, Mitsuru</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">3D bathymetry</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">3D model</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ship motion</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A numerical method has been developed for the analysis of ship motions in a harbor with arbitrary bathymetry. A BEM-based 3-D model, applied partially to a near-field surrounding a ship, is combined with a FEM-based 2-D model, utilized in the remainder of harbor domain. This combination may achieve an efficient computation of the ship motions with taking into account of wave deformation in a harbor. Preliminary examinations have been performed to investigate appropriate location of a matching boundary where these two models are coupled. It is found that, for reliable prediction, (2 ~ 3)ft (h: water depth) is required for the distance between the matching boundary and a body. The numerical results of added mass and damping coefficients for a rectangular floating body in a rectangular basin are then compared with those obtained from a conventional numerical model. Favorable agreement between the results verifies the present numerical method. Ship motions in a harbor with slowly varying depth are also demonstrated.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1994-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5004</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v24.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 24 (1994): Proceedings of 24th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Kobe, Japan, 1994.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5004/4684</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
