<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8689</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-23T01:34:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A LATTICE BOLTZMANN APPROACH FOR THREE-DIMENSIONAL TSUNAMI SIMULATION BASED ON THE PLIC-VOF METHOD</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sato, Kenta</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Koshimura, Shunichi</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Free surface flow problems occur in numerous disaster simulations, such as tsunamis inland penetration in urban area. Simulation models for these problems have to be non-hydrostatic and three-dimensional because of the strong non-linearity and higher-order physical phenomena. Despite all the progress in the modern computational fluid dynamics, such simulations still present formidable challenges both from numerical and computational cost point of view. The lattice Boltzmann method (LBM) has been attracting attention as an alternative fluid simulation tool to overcome the problems. In current study, LBM for three-dimensional tsunami simulations is developed which are coupled with the piecewise linear interface calculation with the Volume of Fluid (VOF) approach. This model is for an efficient three-dimensional tsunami simulation by a one-fluid formulation, where the lattice Boltzmann equation is assigned to solve for a single virtual fluid. Various benchmark problems are also carried out to validate the utility of the proposed models in term of coastal engineering.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8689</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36.papers.90</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36 (2018): Proceedings of 36th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Baltimore, Maryland, 2018; papers.90</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8689/7493</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8689/8071</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
