<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14023</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">CONDITION CHARACTERISATION OF COASTAL INFRASTRUCTURE USING EXPERIMENTAL MODAL ANALYSIS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">O’Shea, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Flynn, William</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Soumille, Lison</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sharvin, Rory</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">O’Donavan, Darragh</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As coastal infrastructure built in the mid and late 20th century reaches the end of original design life span, assessing the structural condition of these assets is becoming critical. In an age of sustainability where remediation rather than replacement is now the preferred strategy due to lower carbon footprint, condition analysis enhances the remediation potential of such marine structures. Understanding the residual functional capacity of coastal structures such as jetties, dolphins and piers can enable asset managers make informed decisions on when and what form of intervention is required to extend their operational life. This work aims to characterize the condition of aging and potentially damaged coastal infrastructure utilizing experimental modal analysis similar work has looked previously at breakwaters (Lee et al., 2018). The study examines 3 typical structures including a gravity based reinforced concrete (RC) pier, a suspended mooring dolphin on concrete piles, and an RC jetty supported on steel piles.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14023</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.structures.1</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; structures.1</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14023/13295</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Michael O’Shea, William Flynn, Lison Soumille, Rory Sharvin, Darragh O’Donavan</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
