<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2497</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T04:46:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">STUDY ON BOTTOM WATER INTAKE FOR CONDENSER COOLING SYSTEM OF POWER STATION SITED ON A BAY</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Senshu, Shin-ichi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wada, Akira</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bottom water intake</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">condenser cooling</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">power station</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This report concerns study on a method of taking the cold water from bottom layer with relation to the design of the intake structure of cooling water for the power station sited on a bay. The quantity of cooling water used for condenser system increases year by year along with the construction of thermal power stations of large capacity. If the bottom sea water of low temperature is taken into the condenser cooling system, remarkable saving of fuel expenses can be expected due to the improvement of heat efficiency of turbine. Especially, in case that the location of intake structure of cooling water is chosen at the interior of the reclaimed land or the bay, it is absolutely necessary to take the colder water from the lower layer of the sea, in order to prevent taking hot water over the sea basin where the water temperature of the surface layer is raised by the evacuation of heat of released industrial water. Various hydraulic problems concerning thermal density flow phenomena were examined aiming to obtain the design method of the most effective intake works of cooling water, and the authors proposed a curtain-wall type intake structure. Some results of analysis are described in this paper.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1966-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2497</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v10.83</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 10 (1966): Proceedings of 10th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Tokyo, Japan, 1966.; 83</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2497/2162</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
