<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2283</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T05:42:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DESIGN OF DEEP DRAFT NAVIGATION CHANNEL FROM GULF OF MEXICO INTO MATAGORDA BAY, TEXAS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weiser, E.A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Armstrong, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Matagorda Bay</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">navigation channel design</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">deep draft</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It was in July 1956 when the senior writer of this paper was requested to prepare a program for investigations and studies required in connection with the proposed deep-draft channel from the Gulf of Mexico to Point Comfort. During 1938 to 19^0, the senior writer had attempted to analyze the available field and model study data which were then available on Galveston Bay in the hope of thus being able to reduce the shoaling in the various deep draft channels in Galveston Bay. In 19^0, the senior writer had been in charge of two field parties one of which measured the flow of water in the Colorado River and the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway near their crossing near Matagorda, Texas. A peak discharge of about 80,000 cubic feet per second was measured in the Colorado River at the Palacios Road bridge, about 15 miles upstream from its mouth during this period. At that time there were no locks nor gates in the Intracoastal Waterway adjacent to the Colorado River. It was found then that about one third of this peak river discharge flowed southwest through the Intracoastal Waterway. On the basis of the above experience and the information obtained from a review of the Matagorda Ship Channel, Texas, project report (l) and other literature, then, available (2) thru (5) a program was formulated in June 1958 and submitted to the Division Engineer in Dallas with the request that the Office of the Chief of Engineers, the Southwestern Division Engineer Office, the Beach Erosion Board and the Committee on Tidal Hydraulics review the program.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1962-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2283</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v8.34</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 8 (1962): Proceedings of 8th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Mexico City, Mexico, 1962.; 34</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2283/1974</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
