<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3482</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T23:31:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">PHYSICAL PROCESSES AND SEDIMENT FLUX THROUGH REEF-LAGOON SYSTEMS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roberts, Harry H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sediment flux</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reef</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lagoon</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reef-lagoon system</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Studies of physical processes in reef-lagoon systems continue to emphasize the importance of waves and wave-induced currents at the reef crest as agents of sediment transport to backreef environments. These across-the-reef currents are also largely responsible for driving backreef lagoon circulation. Rapid energy transformations associated with the process of wave breaking at the reef crest are responsible for strong reef-normal surge currents. Estimates of energy loss, as determined by wave height changes caused by wave breaking, can be as high as 70-80%' for discontinuous reefs and &gt;90% for continuous examples. The amount of energy loss is related to depth of water over the reef crest, a function of reef topography and tidal regime. Low-tide conditions promote the greatest incident wave modification and attenuation as a result of increased breaking-wave intensity. Under trade-wind conditions found in the Caribbean, surge currents of 50-80 cm/sec for durations of 2-6 sec are common in a low to moderate wave-energy setting (4-6 sec input waves, 40- 50 cm average heights). Sediments through the sand sizes up to pebbles are easily transported lagoonward by these periodic bursts of energy. Flow in shallow backreef lagoons (generally </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1980-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3482</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v17.58</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 17 (1980): Proceedings of 17th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 1980.; 58</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3482/3162</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
