<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10124</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">CALIFORNIA'S EFFORTS AT DEVELOPING COMMUNITY LEVEL TOOLS FOR ADDRESSING FUTURE IMPACTS RELATED TO SEA LEVEL RISE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ewing, Lesley</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sea level rise poses many daunting challenges that are economic, technical, ecological, social, scientific, cultural, governmental and legal. There have been enormous efforts to study historic sea level conditions, to analyze the main factors that have modified historic sea levels, to predict future sea levels at global, regional and local scales, to anticipate time periods for changes to flood frequency and erosion rates. While each of these efforts improves our understanding of possible future sea level rise the changes that might happen along the coast as a result, they also increase community uncertainty about what this will mean to their efforts to undertake long-term land use planning, to develop capital improvement plans for infrastructure and for future shore protection and recreational opportunities provided by existing beaches. The proposed presentation will discuss the various guidance reports that have been prepared by the California Coastal Commission staff to assist local governments in identifying and planning for sea level rise vulnerabilities. The presentation will also address many of the options that California communities are considering for sea level rise adaptation.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/-hXO0r79NKk</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10124</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.management.19</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; management.19</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10124/9410</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Lesley Ewing</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
