<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7175</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T05:11:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MODELING WAVE DAMPING AND SEDIMENT TRANSPORT WITHIN A PATCH OF VEGETATION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ma, Gangfeng</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">NHWAVE</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vegetated flow</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sediment transport</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nearshore sediment flux</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Vegetation canopies control mean and turbulent flow structures as well as suspended sediment processes in the coastal wetlands. In this study, a three-dimensional hydrodynamic and sediment transport model is developed for studying flow/wave-vegetation-sediment interactions. The model is based on the non-hydrostatic model NHWAVE. The vege- tation effects on turbulent flow are accounted for by introducing additional formulations associated with vegetation- induced drag and turbulence production in the governing equations. The sediment concentration is obtained by solving the advection-diffusion equation with sediment exchange at the bed. The turbulent flow and suspended sediment are simulated in a coupled manner. The model is validated against the laboratory measurements of partially vegetated open channel flows. It is shown that the model can well predict the vegetation effects on the flow field. The model is then employed to study nearshore sediment suspension influenced by a patch of vegetation, which is located in the surf zone. The turbulence generated by wave breaking is greatly damped by the vegetation patch, resulting in considerably less sediment pickup from the bottom in the surf zone. Within the vegetation patch, most suspended sediments are restricted in a thin layer near the bottom. The net sediment transport is in the shoreward direction, in contrast to the seaward net transport of sediments in the unvegetated surf zone.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/7175</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v34.sediment.17</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 34 (2014): Proceedings of 34th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Seoul, Korea, 2014; sediment.17</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/7175/pdf_470</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
