<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3595</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T22:53:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EXPERIMENTAL STUDY OF THE BUOYANT SURFACE JET WITH THE PRESENCE OF BOTTOM BOUNDARY AND CROSS CURRENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Safaie, B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cross current</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">experimental study</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">buoyant jet</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">jet</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">surface jet</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bottom boundary</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The problem of buoyant surface jet (BSJ) is relevant from the practical standpoint to the discharge of cooling water of power plants into the receiving water bodies. The buoyant surface jet has extensively been studied by numerous investigators both theoretically and experimentally. Most studies have been concerned with the problems of BSJ discharged horizontally into a surface of a deep ambient water with or without cross current. From a practical standpoint, however, the design engineers are often confronted with the design of thermal outfalls in the coastal regions which are frequently shallow and have the boundary effects. Few investigators have studied the problem of BSJ discharged horizontally over slopping bottom into quiescent receiving water (1), (2), (4), (5), (6), and (7). However, no information on the foregoing problem with moving ambient water is available. The purpose of this paper is (a) to present the experimental results of BSJ which is discharged over slopping bottom into moving ambient water, and (b) to see the degree of error which is introduced by applying the deep water integral models to the case of a buoyant surface jet with a bottom boundary.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1980-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3595</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v17.166</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 17 (1980): Proceedings of 17th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 1980.; 166</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3595/3277</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
