<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14044</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Waves</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">PROTECTING VALLETTA’S GRAND HARBOUR AGAINST ADVERSE WAVE CONDITIONS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mazas, Franck</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Farrugia, Christopher</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Valletta’s Grand Harbour is a natural shelter that has been home to a variety of activities for many centuries. The protection of Grand Harbour against waves is mainly ensured by a system of two breakwaters at its entrance, built during the British era at the beginning of the 20th century. However, due to Malta’s central position in the Mediterranean basin, the site is exposed to waves from multiple directions. The most common conditions are waves from the NW (majjistrale), which play a key role in the port’s operating conditions. The NE (gregale) and E sectors, to which the harbour is more directly exposed, are less frequent, but they include the most severe storms (up to 7 - 8 m of Hs). Recent storms in February 2019 (NE sector) and February 2023 (E sector) caused significant damage in the port, highlighting the need for enhanced protection. Infrastructure Malta therefore wishes to improve the operational and extreme wave conditions in the Grand Harbour and commissioned ARTELIA to carry out several studies to characterize the wave conditions in external approaches and inside the harbour, define a protection scenario, assess the hydraulic efficiency of the different structures and test them in ARTELIA’s hydraulic laboratory.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14044</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.waves.8</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; waves.8</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14044/13316</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Franck Mazas, Christopher Farrugia</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
