<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14194</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:31:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SEDIMENT DISTRIBUTION IN AN UNMAINTAINED COASTAL BRUSHWOOD GROYNE FIELD</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bischoff, Christina</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bunzel, Dorothea</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Paul, Maike</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To adapt coastlines and their management to future sea level scenarios, resilient foreshores are a key element of coastal protection. Within the borders of constructed brushwood groynes, calmed hydrodynamic conditions allow suspended sediments to settle (von Lieberman et al. 1998; Siemes et al. 2020). The resulting vertical land growth enables the establishment of different salt marsh succession stages. As a result, a semi-natural salt marsh ecosystem is formed that contributes to a spatial expansion of the foreshore: a nature-based solution for supporting coastal protection is constructed. However, little is known about the spatial distribution of sediments and vegetation and the interaction-based biogeomorphological processes operating in groyne fields, although this is crucial for the successful development of effective and future-oriented management strategies. Further, maintaining brushwood groynes is costly and time-consuming, although the effects have not yet been assessed. In order to successfully implement the aspects of economic efficiency and ecological enhancement in the planning and maintenance of groyne structures, it requires (i) an improved understanding of the impact of the interaction between hydro-, morpho-, and vegetation dynamics on the effectiveness of groyne fields, and (ii) an active involvement of local coastal protection authorities, enabling the transfer of knowledge between science and practice for the optimization of coastal protection.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14194</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.sediment.32</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; sediment.32</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14194/13466</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Christina Bischoff, Dorothea Bunzel, Maike Paul</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
