<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2366</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T05:28:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SAND LOSSES FROM A COAST BY WIND ACTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, J.W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kadib, A.A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sand loss by wind</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">littoral drift</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sand supplied to a coast by streams, cliff erosion, and other sources generally is moved in one particular direction along the shoreline as a littoral drift by the prevailing wave conditions in the area (3). When this drift encounters a partial obstruction, such as a prominent natural headland or a major engineering structure, a condition is realized which is conducive to sediment deposition. Such littoral compartments eventually become filled and some sand is carried past the obstruction. If the topography back of the area of deposition is relatively low and the prevailing winds are onshore, considerable quantities of sand may be moved inland to create a dune system. This loss of material from the coast may affect the stability of the downcoast shoreline. A measure of the annual loss of sand from a particular section of coast by wind action is necessary in many instances. A method of estimating this loss of sand involves the use of a suitable transport equation along with a knowledge of the sand characteristics and the duration and velocity of the wind in the area under study.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1964-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2366</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v9.24</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 9 (1964): Proceedings of 9th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Lisbon, Portugal, 1964.; 24</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2366/2043</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
