<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14450</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T10:41:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Swash</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE TURBULENCE LENGTH SCALES OF SWASH FLOWS GENERATED BY SOLITARY WAVES ON A PLANAR SLOPE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sou, In Mei</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wang, Jinghua</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wu, Yun-Ta</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Liu, Philip L-F</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Measurements of spatial structures in swash flows are important for development and verification of turbulence models and for the understanding of the fundamental characteristics of turbulence. To accurately calculate the full turbulent energy spatial spectra to examine the energy of the different turbulent energy length scales, the velocity vector field must cover a large spatial extent to include the large-scale energy and must have a fine enough spatial resolution of the order of the Kolmogorov length scale (Pope 2000). This study investigates the turbulent kinetic energy length scales of swash flows generated by six solitary waves on a planar slope in the laboratory. The larger turbulent length scales are resolved with the direct spatial spectrum method using the spatial data obtained by particle image velocimetry (PIV). As the spatial resolution of the velocity field is not fine enough in the PIV measurements, the smaller scales are resolved by the continuous wavelet transform using the temporal data at a fixed-point measurement. We will examine the validity for applying the Taylor frozen hypothesis to the swash flows.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14450</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.currents.27</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; currents.27</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14450/13722</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 In Mei Sou, Jinghua Wang, Yun-Ta Wu, Philip L-F Liu</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
