<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2751</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T03:46:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">PERIOD BY THE WAVE-GROUP METHOD</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Warren C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">period</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave group</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The wave-group period, T , is obtained by a eimple manual procedure from the periodic wave groupff'and sequences that appear in strip-chart records. A dozen or more values are commonly derived from a 20-minute record. When plotted as a time-series, T values form patterns that represent individual wave trains, each generated by a synoptic weather event. Swell trains and wind-wave trains can be distinguished by their characteristic period distributions. For swell trains, the mean wave-group frequency, f , obtained from the best-fit line to the time-series plot of f_ values (reciprocal T values), is equivalent to the frequency of maximum energy density, fm, obtained from spectral analysis. The distance and time of origin for a swell train can be determined from the time rate of change of f,,, and with the use of weather maps the generating area can be identified and the deep-water arrival direction of the swell train at the wave gage determined. The zero-line crossing period, T , represents an integration of the waves from all wave trains present and has no synoptic significance.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2751</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v13.8</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 13 (1972): Proceedings of 13th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Vancouver, Canada, 1972.; 8</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2751/2415</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
