<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4579</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T17:12:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BEACH AND DUNE NOURISHMENT IN THE NETHERLANDS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roelse, Piet</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beach nourishment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dune nourishment</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the Netherlands up to the fifties of this century, dike and groyne building were the most important coastal defence measures. Because of the increased awareness of the importance of the sandy coast the demand for a more environmentally friendly coastal protection measure increased. However, artificial beach nourishment was very expensive. In the past two decades the costs of nourishment have decreased as a result of technical developments in the dredging industry, and erosion control by means of sandfills has become in general cheaper than the construction of groynes and dikes. In that period also large volumes of sand have become available from harbour extension and maintenance dredging. These have been the conditions that led to a new coastal defence method. Up till now nearly 50 beach nourishment projects have been carried out, with a total amount of 60 million m . This paper provides a review of the projects carried out in the last 4 decades, with a description of the most important aspects.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1990-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4579</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v22.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 22 (1990): Proceedings of 22nd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Delft, The Netherlands, 1990.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4579/4260</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
