<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/13984</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BACTON SANDSCAPING: QUANTIFIED BENEFITS 4 YEARS AFTER CONSTRUCTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Borsje, Ruben</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Flikweert, Jaap</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Price, Caroline</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Everington, Nick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Bacton Sandscaping Scheme was constructed in August 2019 at the Norfolk coastline to protect the Bacton Gas Terminal from severe damages due to cliff erosion, while reinstating the beach for the neighbouring villages. It was designed to deliver a wide range of outcomes, but the business case mainly relied on the benefits in terms of prevented damages due to coastal flooding and erosion as a result of storm events. The sources of potential damages are the cliff erosion at the terminal, flooding due to overtopping of the seawall at the villages of Bacton and Walcott, and failure of the seawall resulting in coastal erosion at these villages. No damages have occurred since the implementation of the scheme so the generated benefits are equal to the damages that would have occurred if the scheme had not been in place. This paper reports on a study to quantify these actually occurred benefits, utilising pragmatic methods and hindcast data. This results in approximately £3.1M of damages due to flooding and erosion having been prevented in the first 4 years since the scheme was constructed.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13984</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.papers.33</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; papers.33</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13984/13256</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Ruben Borsje, Jaap Flikweert, Caroline Price, Nick Everington</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
