<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2843</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T03:13:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MATHEMATICAL MODELING OF LARGE OBJECTS IN SHALLOW WATER WAVES AND UNIFORM CURRENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wang, Hsiang</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mathematical model</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">shallow water</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">uniform current</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A mathematical model is presented which portrays the physical system of a large axially symmetric structure in a flow field of finite water depth, large amplitude wave and strong current. The flow field, which enters as the input, is derived from a velocity potential similar to that of the cnoidal wave of Keulegan and Patterson. The inclusion of a uniform velocity in the derivation of velocity potential results in a cross interference term in addition to the well known Doppler shift effect. The numerical results are compared with experiments on a bridge pier (Ref. 6) which is partially cylindrical with base diameter equivalent to 100 feet in prototype; close to the surface, where the wave action is greatest it is conical. These results are also compared with theoretical calculations based on linear wave theory and fifth-order wave theory. It is concluded that the results based on the modified cnoidal wave theory come closest to the experimental value.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2843</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v13.96</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 13 (1972): Proceedings of 13th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Vancouver, Canada, 1972.; 96</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2843/2507</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
