<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/13960</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BEACH NOURISHMENT AND SEDIMENT MANAGEMENT FRAMEWORK FOR HATTERAS ISLAND, NORTH CAROLINA, USA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kaczkowski, Haiqing Liu</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kaczkowski, Stephen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hatteras Island features 85 kilometers (km) of developed and undeveloped shoreline and the beaches exhibit a range of conditions from accreting segments to retreating ones. NC Highway 12 (NC 12) is the only north-south highway along Hatteras Island and serves as the primary route for local access, emergency response, and connectivity to state and federal facilities. NC 12 at Hatteras Island has suffered repeated damage from erosion and dune breaches over the past thirty years. To address these challenges, the National Park Service (NPS), in collaboration with state and federal agencies, developed a sediment management framework (Framework) in 2022. This Framework outlines anticipated methods, locations, and frequencies for sediment management actions over the next 20 years, with beach nourishment as one of the main engineering solutions. By adopting this comprehensive approach, the Framework allows for the cumulative impacts of multiple sediment management actions to be considered, enhancing resilience to climate change effects. Following the Framework’s guidelines, the first two beach nourishment projects were completed in Avon and Buxton in summer 2022, targeting the most vulnerable sections of the island. These efforts followed an earlier nourishment project in Buxton in 2017-2018. Collectively, these projects have placed approximately 3.692 million m3 (4.8 million cubic yards) of beach-quality sand along an 8.7-km stretch of oceanfront, at a total construction cost of over $48 million to the local government – Dare County. These nourishment efforts have significantly reinforced the island’s shoreline, enabling it to withstand multiple hurricanes and storms without major damage to NC 12 or oceanfront properties since their completion.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13960</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.papers.9</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; papers.9</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13960/13232</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Haiqing Liu Kaczkowski, Stephen Kaczkowski</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
