<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8224</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-22T13:59:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Swash</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">LABORATORY EXPERIMENTS OF BICHROMATIC WAVE GROUPS PROPAGATION ON A GENTLE SLOPE BEACH PROFILE AND ENERGY TRANSFER TO LOW AND HIGH FREQUENCY COMPONENTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Padilla, Enrique M</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Alsina, Jose M</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Grouping waves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bandwidth</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Energy transfer</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This work presents a first analysis of experimental data studying the influence of the frequency bandwidth on the
propagation of bichromatic wave groups over a constant 1:100 beach slope. The use of a large spatial cross-shore resolution
and Bi-Spectral analysis techniques allows the identification of nonlinear energy transfers along the propagation
of wave groups. During wave-group shoaling, nonlinear coupling between the primary wave frequencies results in a
larger growth of superharmonics for narrow-banded wave conditions, increasing the skewness of the wave and leading
to eventual instabilities and earlier high frequency (hf) wave breaking compared to the broad-banded wave condition.
Regarding the growth of low frequency (lf) component, the data analysis has shown a larger growth of the incident
bound long wave (IBLW) for broad-banded wave conditions. It is generally assumed that the transferred energy from
the primary wave components to subharmonics does not affect the short wave energy budget. Here, the opposite is
hypothesised, and a larger growth of the IBLW for broad-banded wave conditions is accompanied of a larger reduction
of the primary wave components, a reduced growth of hf components and, consequently, a reduction in the growth
of hf wave asymmetry during wave group shoaling. Conversely for narrow-banded wave conditions, a reduced IBLW
growth is associated with a larger growth of hf wave asymmetry. After hf wave breaking, within the low frequency
domain (lf), the IBLW decays slightly for narrow-banded conditions, consistent with a reduction in radiation stress
forcing. This involves a nonlinear energy transfer from the wave group frequency back to hf components. The remaining
lf energy, Outgoing Free Long Wave (OFLW), reflects back at the shoreline. However, for broad-banded wave
conditions, strong dissipation and minimal reflection of lf components occurs close to the shoreline, which might be
caused by lf wave breaking.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8224</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v35.currents.6</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 35 (2016): Proceedings of 35th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Antalya, Turkey, 2016; currents.6</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8224/pdf</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
