<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14649</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T08:16:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DESIGN AND MANAGEMENT OF NATURAL AND NATURE BASED FEATURES
CASE STUDIES IN SOUTHWEST FLORIDA, USA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dabees, Mohamed</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Natural disasters and coastal storms present an increasing threat for public safety and property damage in coastal communities. Climate and weather-related natural disasters have been on the rise in intensities and frequency over the past decades. The geography and exposure of the State of Florida to coastal storms necessitates development of coastal resiliency plans to manage and reduce the risk of flooding and damage due to coastal storms. Southwest Florida in particular, experienced increased frequency and intensity of tropical storms with multiple major hurricanes impacting the region over the past few decades. Recently, Hurricane Ian caused major catastrophic damages to the region in 2022 and Hurricane Idalia impacted the coastal areas with storm surge and waves as it passed through the Gulf of Mexico in 2023. This paper will discuss two examples of NNBF in Southwest Florida, their responses to tropical storms and the management efforts to maintain those features. Examples include Clam Bay Natural Resources Protection Area (NRPA) in Naples and The Tigertail Lagoon/ Sand Dollar Island Ecosystem in Marco Island (Dabees et al 2022).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14649</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.207</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.207</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14649/13921</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Mohamed Dabees</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
