<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14042</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">FLOATING CITIES FOR CLIMATE CHANGE ADAPTATION: EXPLORING MOTION PERCEPTION THRESHOLDS VIA IMMERSIVE VIRTUAL REALITY</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wang, Shengzhe</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Han, Bing</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sea level rise due to climate change is predicted to consume 1.79 million km2 of land alongside the displacement of 187 million people by the 22nd century (Bamber et al. 2019). In response, both the United Nations Human Settlements Program (UN-Habitat) and the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) have advocated for the development of floating cities as a sustainable solution towards climate resilience and adaptation. However, large-scale floating structures for permanent human habitation have not advanced beyond architectural speculation with no guidelines to inform their design. Unlike traditional land-based buildings, no attempts have been made to investigate their habitability (i.e., human comfort) under low-frequency oscillations induced by wind and waves. This work employs immersive virtual reality (VR) to ascertain motion perception thresholds across all six degrees of freedom (DOF) for a hypothetical floating structure situated in Auckland, New Zealand. Through this process, we aim to establish VR as an invaluable tool for the exploration of immersive visual stimuli to motion perception and comfort criteria within complex floating environments.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14042</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.1</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.1</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14042/13314</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Shengzhe Wang, Bing Han</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
