<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4946</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T15:06:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A SPECTRAL MODEL FOR WAVES IN THE NEAR SHORE ZONE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ris, R.C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Holthuijsen, L.H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Booij, N.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">spectral model</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nearshore zone</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The present paper describes the second phase in the development of a fully spectral wave model for the near shore zone (SWAN). Third-generation formulations of wave generation by wind, dissipation due to whitecapping and quadruplet wave-wave interactions are added to the processes of (refractive) propagation, bottom friction and depth-induced wave breaking that were implemented in the first phase (Holthuijsen et al., 1993). The performance and the behaviour of the SWAN model are shown in two observed cases in which waves are regenerated by the wind after a considerable decrease due to shallow water effects. In the case of the Haringvliet (a closed branch of the Rhine estuary, the Netherlands) reasonable results in terms of significant wave heights were obtained. In the case of Saginaw Bay (Lake Huron, USA), the SWAN model underestimates the significant wave height deep inside the bay (as did two other models). Due to the absence of triad wave-wave interactions in the model the mean period is not properly shifted to the higher frequencies in shallow water. Adding these triads is planned for the next phase of developing the SWAN model.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1994-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4946</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v24.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 24 (1994): Proceedings of 24th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Kobe, Japan, 1994.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4946/4626</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
