<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2821</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T03:21:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NILE DELTA C0ASTA1 PROTECTIOH PROJECT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mobarak, Ismail E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Nile Delta</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">coastal protection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Nile River</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Nile Delta Coast on the Mediterranean Sea was formed through many centuries. The two existing main branches of the River Nile, i.e. Rosetta and Damietta, succeeded over the ages in forming two peninsulas or protrusions in the sea. By the end of the 19th century erosion started at several important points of the coast, causing damages to the national economy, either directly or indirectly. This erosion has increased tremendously during the last decade. Several field and laboratory studies were carried out during the last few years, concentrating on the severely attacked areas, such as Ras-EL-Bar, Burullas, Rosetta,Maadia. Based on the quick field and laboratory studies, remedial constructions are designed for the locations of severe erosion* Groins for Ras-El-Bar with artificial sand feeding and stone pitching and a wall for the Damietta estuary. A large groin for Burullos outlet which developed some advantageous changes even before finishing its execution,, and sea wall for Maadia. All the above projects are discussed and explained. A long term study project was started early in 1971 to collect the data necessary for a better understanding of the problem. The aims of this project are as follows: (1) To determine the historical formation of the Delta and forecasting future changes ; (2) Study the Meteorology and the Hydrodynamics of the area ; hindcasting and starting a new forecasting technique for them; (3) Planning and design of protective constructions for the coast is to be gained. All the above will be based on an extensive field data collection programme, mathematical models and hydraulic scale models. 1409</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2821</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v13.74</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 13 (1972): Proceedings of 13th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Vancouver, Canada, 1972.; 74</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2821/2485</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
