<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10338</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MATAGORDA SHIP CHANNEL AND ITS ENTRANCE'S NAVIGATION EFFICIENCY AND SAFETY IMPROVEMENT VIA ADCIRC AND CMS MODEL SIMULATION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lin, Lihwa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Demirbilek, Zeki</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shih, Tzenge-Huey</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The present study investigated alternatives including deepening/widening of Matagorda Ship Channel in the south central coast of Texas to improve navigation safety through entrance inlet channel by using ADCIRC and CMS numerical models. The alternatives modify bayside channel depths from 38 ft to 50 ft, referenced to Mean Lower Low Water (MLLW), and widths from 200 ft to 600 ft, and deepen the entrance channel from 38 ft to 55 ft MLLW and widen the channel from 300 ft to 600 ft. The alternatives include seven new dredged material placement areas along the ship channel. Model results show the proposed ship channel dimensions will slightly increase flow efficiency and current magnitude in Matagorda Bay. Current velocities in and around ship channel tend to increase with alternatives, large river input and future sea level rise in the region. However, the current effect becomes more pronounced during tropical storms.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/YAugdJe9dIw</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10338</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.papers.56</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; papers.56</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10338/9624</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Lihwa Lin, Zeki Demirbilek, Tzenge-Huey Shih</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
