<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8325</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-23T01:34:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A CLASSIFICATION METHOD FOR THE PRESENCE OF TIDAL SAND WAVES AND MAINTENANCE DREDGING DESIGN</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">de Koning, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">de Vries, Jaap van Thiel</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Borsje, Bas</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The study into sand wave dynamics in South Channel commenced after large dune forms were observed in monitoring campaigns following the channel deepening project of the Port of Melbourne. The project involved deepening of the harbor berths and channels, but more importantly, it involved the deepening of South Channel in Port Phillip Bay. South Channel, the main shipping channel, crosses the bay over ≈20km. The growth of bedforms at various locations in South Channel now threatens to impede marine traffic. The dimensions and migration rate of the bedforms in the channel are remarkable, especially in the harsh flow conditions in the narrow channel. Therefore, the bedforms in South Channel cannot be given an obvious classification. In this paper it is shown that the bedforms in South Channel can be classified as a tidal sand wave type with a method that requires only insight in water depth, tidal flow velocity and grain size. Tidal sand waves are large-scale bedforms generated by recirculating flow cells that drive sediment to the top of a crest and are commonly observed on shallow coastal seas such as the North Sea. The bedform concern in the channel illustrates the necessity of an evaluation of the present, and alternative, channel maintenance strategies. A numerical model in Delft3D software is applied, along with a probabilistic calculation that combines insights from the simulations and survey data, to assess different maintenance strategies.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8325</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36.papers.48</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36 (2018): Proceedings of 36th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Baltimore, Maryland, 2018; papers.48</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8325/7133</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8325/7805</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
