<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3260</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T00:43:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">WAVE CLIMATE IN SOME ZONES OFF THE BRAZILIAN COAST</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Homsi, Alberto</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave climate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Brazilian coast</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">METEOROLOGICAL FEATURES - The Brazilian coast could be considered a calm area not affected by violent tropical storms. The major meteorological factor in Brazil is the South Atlantic anticyclone, almost permanent, which causes periodical northward heading of cold fronts. A slightly reduced energy and frequency of storms could be observed going up from South coast toward North and could reach the major part of Northeast region. As a general condition the average monthly frequency of cold fronts passing along the Brazilian coast is higher during the winter - five per month with an average duration of 3 days, decreasing to 2 per month during summer with an average duration of 5 days. During winter high waves could occur between Santos and Macae caused by a depression near the Rio de Janeiro as the cold front stays at North, before the cold front goes down to South. Fig. l shows the average flow pattern across Brazil for summer and winter periods and a six days cold front advancing toward North, going into as far as to tropical latitudes during winter time. The daily tracks of the winter cyclones appear on this figure; they do not get beyond latitudes of 40 South.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3260</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v16.5</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 16 (1978): Proceedings of 16th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Hamburg, Germany, 1978.; 5</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3260/2924</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
