<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/13081</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:15:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BEHAVIOR OF VARIABLE DENSITY MUNITIONS UNDER DAM BREAK FORCING</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Idowu, Temitope</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gangadharan, Manoj</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chapman, Emily</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Puleo, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stolle, Jacob</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bang, Damien Pham van</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Munitions or Unexploded Ordnance (UXO) are ammunitions belonging to a larger family of explosives from past military activities. Sea disposal of munitions was a common practice from the late 1800s to 1970 when international conventions put an end to the practice. The exact quantity of munitions dumped into the Oceans globally is unknown due to sparse documentation but conservative estimates of known records stand at 1.6 million tons (Wilkinson, 2017). After decades underwater, some munitions have resurfaced in the nearshore, presumably washed onshore or exhumed by high-energy wave action. Extreme events could be major causes of migration and exposure of UXO in the nearshore. The quantification of variable density munitions behavior in the swash zone remains poorly understood. Biofouling, encrustation, and corrosion can alter the density of the underwater munitions, which consequently impacts the behavior of the munitions in the swash zone. Hence, this experimental study aimed to quantify the behavior of variable density munitions in the swash zone under dam-break scenarios. The findings of the study create more insights into the behavior of variable density munitions in the swash zone and can also serve as validation data for probabilistic models on munitions behavior in the swash zone under extreme events.     </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13081</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.management.123</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; management.123</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13081/12354</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Temitope Idowu, Manoj Gangadharan, Emily Chapman, Jack Puleo, Jacob Stolle, Damien Pham van Bang</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
