<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4293</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T18:49:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">STUDY OF SHELF WAVES VS SAND DRIFT IN NW COAST OF TAIWAN</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hou, Ho-Shong</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Taiwan</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">shelf waves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sand drift</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">For the planning and design of harbor and coastal Engineering, most important affected factors are waves and Littoral drift. This research deals with analysis of the measured waves and the budget of the beach material whether it is deposited or scoured in the North-western coast of Taiwan; and the relationship between wave energy and littoral transport rate. For processing this research the field Survey wave measurement, sand sampling, and echo sounding is necessitated. The objective of this research is to establish the model of waves and littoral transport budget. Therefore, the results of this research are planned to submit to the planning and design of harbor and coastal engineering works of the Taiwan west sandy coast. The main contains of this research are consisted of (1) Analysis, observations and investigations of the field oceanographic data, winds, waves, coastal geomorphology and littoral drift of the North-western coast of Taiwan. (2) Analysis of the shelf waves from the actual measured wave records. (3) Research of the wave decaying process of the continental shelf waves. (4) Statistical research of the measured waves and establishment of the practical model of the relationship between the shelf wave energy and the littoral transport rate in the north-west coast of Taiwan.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4293</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v21.86</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 21 (1988): Proceedings of 21st Conference on Coastal Engineering, Torremolinos, Spain, 1988.; 86</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4293/3974</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
