<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/994</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-04T04:02:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">COMPARISON OF STORM SURGE DISASTERS IN ASIA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shibayama, Tomoya</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Storm Surge</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Myanmar</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bangladesh</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Field surveys were performed in the southwest of Bangladesh after cyclone Sidr in 2007 and in Yangon River Basin after Cyclone Nargis in Myanmar in 2008 in order to learn lessons out of severe disasters due to cyclones. Spatial distributions of inundation heights were measured around the most damaged areas.  Both Bangladesh and Myanmar were severely damaged, but the preparedness against storm surge and the experiences were different. The resultant total losses in these two countries were significantly different.  In Bangladesh, many people witnessed that storm surges inundated with bore-like waves. Counter measured against storm surges should account for the physical mechanisms for the development of such bore-like waves and possible damages due to such waves. Embankment showed significant roles to minimize the damage. Development of riverbanks especially around the river mouth is one of most essential counter-measures to be carried out in Bangladesh. Shelter functioned well to save significant number of lives in Bangladesh.  But in Myanmar, there were few experiences on storm surge and no countermeasures such as shelters.  These differences results the difference of losses.  They were 4,232 including deaths and unknowns in Bangladesh but 138,373 in Myanmar.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-01-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/994</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v32.management.18</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 32 (2010): Proceedings of 32nd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Shanghai, China, 2010.; management.18</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/994/pdf_267</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/994/7679</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
