<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3687</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T22:21:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DESIGN AND CALIBRATION OF FALSE BAY SEDIMENT MODEL</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schoonees, J.S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Moller, J.P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">False Bay</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bay</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sediment model</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">model calibration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">model design</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">False Bay is situated near Cape Town in the Republic of South Africa. The National Research Institute for Oceanology (NRIO) of the Council for Scientific and Industrial Research (CSIR) was commissioned to undertake studies on a recreational scheme in the Strandfontein area of False Bay. A tidal pool was built as phase 1 of this project. Phase 2 is a bathing improvement scheme (see Figures 1 and 2). The aim of the bathing improvement scheme which consists of a number of structures, is to provide bathing facilities for the Mitchell's Plain community. At present the major part of the coast is rather unsafe for bathing mainly because of very steep beach profiles. Conditions were laid down to ensure safe bathing, e.g. a uniform flat beach slope and the absence of rock and rip currents. Further requirements were that a safe bathing beach must be formed soon after completion of the structures and that the adjacent coastline must not be adversely affected in the long term. This paper deals with the design and calibration of a sediment model which was chosen to evaluate and optimise the design of the proposed T-groyne and the system of detached breakwaters shown in Figure 3.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1982-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3687</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v18.72</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 18 (1982): Proceedings of 18th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Cape Town, South Africa, 1982.; 72</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3687/3370</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
