<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1351</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-04T03:49:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Swash</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">OSCILLATIONS OF SEMI-ENCLOSED WATER BODY INDUCED BY HURRICANES</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tan, Paul Yuan-Hung</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lee, Jiin-Jen</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">oscillation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hurricane</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">depth-averaged</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">non-linear shallow-water equations</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">finite-volume method</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">risk-based design &amp; analysis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The primary focus of this research is to study the oscillations of semi-enclosed water body induced by hurricanes.  The physical mechanisms of the wind-induced oscillation (storm surge) in a semi-enclosed water body are analyzed by the depth-averaged, non-linear shallow-water equations.  The numerical model using the finite-volume method (FVM) to solve the depth-averaged, non-linear shallow-water equations is developed and the present model is verified by the intensive field data reported by IPET.  The present model is further applied to the investigation of the oscillations (storm surges) in Lake Pontchartrain induced by the winds generated by four synthetic hurricanes within the time-span of 00:00 UTC August 29 to 00:00 UTC August 30, 2005: 1.Hurricane Katrina tracking on its original route, 2.Hurricane Katrina tracking 36 km west of its original route, 3.Hurricane Katrina tracking 72 km west of its original route, and 4.Hurricane Katrina tracking on its original route with reduced forward speeds.  The major application of the present model is to assist the design of the water-front structure surrounding the semi-enclosed water body that has been influenced by the oscillations induced by hurricanes.  The numerical simulations generated by the present model can help the planners to determine a better strategy of the hurricane protection systems surrounding the communities of the semi-enclosed water body.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-02-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/vnd.ms-powerpoint</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1351</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v32.currents.41</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 32 (2010): Proceedings of 32nd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Shanghai, China, 2010.; currents.41</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1351/pdf_331</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1351/7693</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
