<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/13953</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DISASTER PREVENTION FUNCTION OF NOURISHED BEACH DURING 50 YEARS UNDER CONDITIONS OF SEA LEVEL RISE AND LAND SUBSIDENCE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kuriyama, Yoshiaki</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hayashi, Hiroyuki</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Yamagata, Souichi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shimizu, Toshihiro</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Katano, Akiyoshi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mori, Haruo</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ogawa, Shusei</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The disaster prevension function is oen of the key functions that sandy beaches offer. This study investiagted whether a nourided beach at the Niigata West Coast in Japan, which previously suffered severe beach erosion, can maintain its disaster prevention function for a 50-year period under conditions of sea level rise and land subsidence. At the study beach, which is now surrounded by submerged breakwaters and groins, beach nourishment was implemented from 1994 to 2000. This study defined the disaster prevention function as the ability to prevent the wave runup height induced by the design wave from exceeding the level of the road located immediately landward of the beach at the high high water level. The critical beach width, which is the minimum width required to satisfy the criterion for the disaster prevention function, was determined by estimating wave runup heights on several assumed eroded breach profiles and by evaluating the estimated wave runup heights exceed the road level. Future shoreline change was predicted using a numerical model under a sea level rise of 4.1 mm/year, which is the value for the RCP2.6 scenario, and a land subsidence of 7.0 mm/year. The comparison between the prediction results and the critical beach width confirmed that the disaster prevention function at the study beach is expected to remain effective for the next 50 years starting from 2019 even under conditions of sea level rise and land subsidence.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13953</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.papers.2</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; papers.2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13953/13225</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Yoshiaki Kuriyama, Hiroyuki Hayashi, Souichi Yamagata, Toshihiro Shimizu, Akiyoshi Katano, Haruo Mori, Shusei Ogawa</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
