<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14199</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T10:40:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">NUMERICAL STUDY ON THE INFLUENCE OF COASTAL FOREDUNES ON STORM- INDUCED EROSION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schweiger, Constantin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mehrtens, Björn</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bölker, Thea</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lojek, Oliver</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ahrenbeck, Lukas</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schürenkamp, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Goseberg, Nils</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the context of nature-based solutions, there is a growing interest in considering the benefits of ecosystem services towards sustainable coastal protection measures (Sutton- Grier et al. 2015). Coastal dunes serve as a natural barrier at sandy coastlines. While higher elevated dunes protect the adjacent hinterland from flooding during severe storm surges (e.g. Figlus 2022), coastal foredunes can act as a first buffer zone during storm surges by enhancing near- shore wave breaking-induced energy dissipation as a result of the deposition of eroded sand in the foreshore bathymetry (Temmerman et al. 2013). The Eiderstedt peninsula in Northern Germany harbors a complex beach- dune system that, among others, consists of an up to 2 km wide beach, an elongated foredune of varying height and an established secondary dune (Mehrtens et al. 2023). Previous large-scale experiments focused on the influence of a foredune on the erosion volumes of a secondary dune during varying storm conditions following the regimes as described by Sallenger (2000). Results showed a reduction of wave-induced erosion at the secondary dune independently of both the hydrodynamic conditions and the foredune configuration with respect to volume and location. However, due to the natural time limitation in laboratory studies, additional data is beneficial in order to evaluate the protection potential of coastal foredunes more general.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14199</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.sediment.35</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; sediment.35</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14199/13471</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Constantin Schweiger, Björn Mehrtens, Thea Bölker, Oliver Lojek, Lukas Ahrenbeck, David Schürenkamp, Nils Goseberg</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
