<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4933</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T15:11:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">PRESENT SITUATION OF SEA-SAND MINING IN KYUSHU ISLAND, JAPAN AND ITS INFLUENCE ON COASTAL ENVIRONMENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hashida, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Matsunaga, N.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Komatsu, T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sand mining</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Kyushu Island</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The sea-sand mining has been carried out in the coast of western part of Japan since the early 1970's. Mined sea-sand is mainly used as fine aggregate of concrete structures. Mining a large amount of sea-sand near the coast induces the possibility of beach erosion and devastation of fishing grounds. In order to evaluate its influence on coastal environment, the present situation of sea-sand mining has been investigated in seven prefectures of Kyushu Island in Japan. The sea-sand mining in Kyushu Island is classified into two types. One is the mining in the sea areas where sea-sand reserves are limited. In these areas, the compatibility between the sea-sand mining and the protection of coastal environment will become very important in future. The other is the type that sea-sand has been supplied constantly from rivers or other sea areas. In this case, it will be the most important to keep the balance between the amount of mined sea-sand and that of supplied one.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4933</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v23.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 23 (1992): Proceedings of 23rd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Venice, Italy, 1992.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4933/4613</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
