<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4671</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T16:40:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BERM BREAKWATER CONTAMINATION STUDY SERGIPE MARINE TERMINAL, BRAZIL</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fournier, Charles P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sayao, Otavio J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Caldas, Felipe</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">case study</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">breakwater</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">berm breakwater</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">contamination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Sergipe Marine Terminal</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A physical modelling programme was undertaken to investigate the contamination of a berm breakwater armour stone layer with fines. For construction purposes, it became necessary to significantly increase the berm breakwater core crest width (construction roadway) beyond the design value. Thus, contamination of the armour material by fines, much beyond the specified tolerance, immediately adjacent to the core section resulted. As the original design did not consider the influence of this contamination on the armouring stability, the present modelling study was carried out, in response to the above construction limitation. The implications of a contaminated berm armour section was investigated. The results showed that for a high crested breakwater structure, the contamination of the armouring close to the core did not influence the breakwater stability and, profile reshaping was virtually the same for the contaminated and the original structure. This is due to the fact that the contaminated section was not placed in the active berm area. However, for a low crested structure, the contaminated section was less stable that the uncontaminated counterpart, due to the increased volume of water which overtopped the structure resulting in back slope instability.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1990-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4671</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v22.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 22 (1990): Proceedings of 22nd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Delft, The Netherlands, 1990.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4671/4352</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
