<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12790</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:13:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EFFECTS OF SHELLS ON AEOLIAN SEDIMENT TRANSPORT ON A NATURAL BEACH</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Strypsteen, Glenn</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rauwoens, Pieter</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Studying aeolian sediment transport in coastal areas is challenging. Therefore, a location with a small number of supply-limiting elements (e.g., shells, moisture and vegetation) and a long fetch length is frequently chosen to allow for a better comparison of predicted and observed transport rates (Strypsteen et al., 2021). Many natural beaches, however, contain an abundance of shells and shell fragments/hash due to pounding and fracturing in the surf zone and literature on this topic is rather scarce. Direct field studies on the impact of shells on aeolian sediment transport rates have been limited. This study reports on a two-day measurement campaign on the upper beach of Koksijde, Belgium, where data on aeolian transport rates, mass flux profiles, surface moisture, wind conditions, and grain size distributions were collected. The goal of the experiment was to measure aeolian sand transport on the upper beach as input for dune growth and to find out how a shell pavement affected these transport rates during a strong, oblique onshore wind.           </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12790</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.sediment.16</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; sediment.16</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12790/12063</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Glenn Strypsteen, Pieter Rauwoens</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
