<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5476</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T12:08:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SMALL-SCALE MORPHOLOGY RELATED TO WAVE AND CURRENT PARAMETERS OVER A BARRED BEACH</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Faria, A.F. Garcez</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thornton, E.B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stanton, T.P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">barred beach</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beach morphology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave parameter</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">current parameter</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Small-scale morphology (&lt; 5 m horizontal wavelength) was measured by combining CRAB surveys with bed elevations acquired from a 1 MHZ sonic altimeter mounted on the CRAB during the DUCK94 experiment in October 1994. Bedform plan views were recorded simultaneously using a 500 KHz side-scan sonar mounted on the CRAB. Waves and currents were measured at the same time. Three cases are examined in detail: mild waves and weak longshore currents resulting in wave ripples throughout the study area; narrow-band, normally incident waves with a strong rip current resulting in a planar bed except in the throat of the rip where megaripples were measured; and storm waves with strong longshore currents resulting in lunate and straight-crested mega-ripples in the trough of the barred beach. During these strong current days, bed shear stresses calculated from logarithmic velocity profiles are equated to a quadratic bottom shear stress formulation. The associated bed shear stress coefficients vary by more than an order of magnitude across the surf zone (0.0006- 0.012). Bottom roughness was obtained by calculating the wavenumber spectra of the bed. The bed shear stress coefficients are positively correlated with bottom roughness (linear correlation coefficient, 0.68). A higher linear correlation coefficient (0.80) is obtained by subtracting skin friction from the total bed shear stress.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1996-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5476</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v25.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 25 (1996): Proceedings of 25th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Orlando, Florida, 1996.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5476/5152</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
