<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14307</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:11:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">STORM CLUSTER IDENTIFICATION AND IMPACTS FOR SHORELINE RESILIENCE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Moritz, Heidi Pfeiffer</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Moritz, Hans</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jensen, Robert</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hall, Candice</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The USACE recognizes resilience as a fundamental and important characteristic of its systems and operations. (USACE, 2020) Increasing attention is being focused on understanding the effects of extratropical storms and storm clustering (Wadey, 2023). These effects will take on particular significance in regions with higher rates of sea level change. The development of a foundational understanding of the spatial and temporal characteristics of storm clusters may be found to be essential to a more comprehensive description of nonstationary hazards and risks. USACE mission areas that may be sensitive to sea level change, storm power, and threshold exceedance include Coastal Storm Risk Management (CSRM), Flood Risk Management (FRM), Navigation, Water Supply, Recreation, Environmental Restoration, and Disaster Response. The approach to the identification and evaluation of storm cluster potential impacts will analyze the range and significance of storm cluster definitions, storm and storm cluster duration and power, exceedance of wave height threshold, influence of wave direction, and water level realization and development over the storm cluster.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14307</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.107</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.107</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14307/13579</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Heidi Pfeiffer Moritz, Hans Moritz, Robert Jensen, Candice Hall</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
