<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14455</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:44:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">USING STILLING WAVE BASIN FOR ADAPTATION MEASURES TO SEA LEVEL RISE IN COASTAL AREAS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bahadiroglu, Nisa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kisacik, Dogan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cappietti, Lorenzo</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">İzmir, a coastal city in Turkiye, has rapidly expanded due to economic growth and urban development centered around Izmir Bay. However, haphazard growth and inadequate infrastructure have left the region vulnerable to natural disasters, particularly with the increasing risk of sea level rise caused by global warming. This situation could lead to severe coastal flooding, erosion, and damage to important structures and properties. In the inner bay of Izmir, the current coastal protection structures, including vertical and armoured rubble mound sloping structures, may not be sufficient to withstand the challenges posed by climate change (Kisacik, 2022). This study underlines the importance of implementing resilient adaptation measures in the low-lying and coastal areas of Izmir Bay in response to the urgency of the situation. Increasing the crest height of current flood defense structures is a common method for reducing wave overtopping; however, its applicability in densely populated coastal areas is limited by negative social acceptance. As an alternative solution, this research focuses on developing the Stilling Wave Basin (SWB) crest modification approach. The study focuses on the experimental modeling of the SWB approach, demonstrating its potential efficiency in reducing wave overtopping to tolerable levels. The findings of this study contribute to the expanding body of knowledge about coastal resilience strategies, especially in the urbanized coastal regions susceptible to sea level rise caused by climate change.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14455</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.structures.74</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; structures.74</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14455/13727</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Nisa Bahadiroglu, Dogan Kisacik, Lorenzo Cappietti</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
