<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3509</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T23:21:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A SEDIMENT TRAPPING EXPERIMENT AT SANTA CRUZ, CA.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Seymour, R.J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Domurat, G.W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pirie, D.M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sediment trapping</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Santa Cruz</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tapping experiment</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Santa Cruz Harbor is located on the northern coast of Monterey Bay, California, approximately 104 kilometers south of San Francisco and 22 kilometers north of Moss Landing, as shown in Figures 1 and 2. Harbor construction was authorized by Congress under the Rivers and Harbors Act of 195S, which provided for a harbor to accommodate light-draft vessels in Woods Lagoon at the eastern boundary of Santa Cruz. The authorized improvements included two rubblemound jetties 360 meters long and 243 meters long, on the west and east sides of an entrance channel, respectively - an entrance channel approximately 270 meters long, 30 meters wide and 6 meters deep, reducing to 45 meters in depth at the same width for an additional HI meters - an inner channel, 240 meters long, 45 meters wide, 45 meters deep, reducing to 3 meters in depth at the same width for an additional 100 meters - a'turning basin approximately 90 meters long, 75 meters wide, and 3 meters deep, and a sand-bypassing plan. Figure 3 shows the project features. The armor units of the seaward side of the west jetty are 28-ton quadripods. The west jetty also has a concrete cap extending to elevation +4. 8 meters MLLW. Construction of the harbor was initiated in February of 1962 with the dredging of Woods Lagoon and the start of work on the west jetty. The west jetty was completed in February 1963. Then work began on the east jetty, and it was completed in April 1963. The entrance channel was dredged to the project dimensions in the summer of 1963. Construction of Santa Cruz Harbor was completed in November 1963, with the exception of the sand-bypassing plant. Construction of the sand-bypassing plant was deferred until the littoral drift rate could be more accurately determined.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1980-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3509</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v17.84</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 17 (1980): Proceedings of 17th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 1980.; 84</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3509/3189</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
