<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12814</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:13:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">FIELD STUDY FOR WIND-BLOWN SAND ON THE SWASH ZONE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Katano, Akiyoshi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Arikawa, Taro</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Niigata West Coast faces the Sea of Japan and Sado Island is located approximately 45 km to the west from there (Fig.1). This coast has suffered severe erosion since the early 1950s. Hiyoriyamahama beach where is a part of the Coast is a highly erosive beach. For the protection of the beach erosion, the combined shore protection system with the jetty, submerged wide breakwater and beach nourishment have been constructed at the beach. There, strong winds from NW to WNW blow in the winter season and nourished sand has been blown off from the beach. For the prevention of blown off nourished sands from the beach, an attempt to develop an integrate system for controlling the wind-blown sand combined with sand fences, a green belt (an artificial low dune) and a vacancy space (road) has been made. To examine the function of the integrate system under development, extensive field surveys for beach topographical changes, wave runup on the swash zone, wind at the site, waves have been conducted. The purpose of this paper is to describe the field measurement results.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12814</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.sediment.40</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; sediment.40</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12814/12087</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Akiyoshi Katano, Taro Arikawa</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
