<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2642</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T04:28:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">PREDICTION CURVES FOR WAVES NEAR THE SOURCE OF AN IMPULSE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Miller, Robert L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">prediction curve</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">impulse</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The general problem of single-impulse induced waves has been under experimental investigation by the author for several years The present paper is confined to a presentation of the wave modes which are to be expected for various permutations of displacement velocity and displacement length at the impulse source Other portions of the study will be published elsewhere It is clear that a number of geometric arrangements in the laboratory may be made to generate impulse waves, for example, sudden upthrust or downdrop of a block on the tank bottom analagous to block faulting on the sea-floor in nature, or a hinged flap moving on the bottom analagous to the undulatory bottom motion which may occur during seismic disturbances on the sea floor However, it is my opinion that the impulse generator which is most simple and most easily related to contemporary generalized theory, is a single piston thrust at one end of the wave tank which pushes the fluid down channel (See Figure 1) As an additional simplification, the investigation is carried out for the flat bottom, fixed depth case, relegating the effect of varying depth to a later study.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1970-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2642</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v12.37</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 12 (1970): Proceedings of 12th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Washington, D.C., 1970.; 37</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2642/2306</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
