<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4165</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T19:33:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">CRITICAL RUN-UP HEIGHT ON THE SEA WALL</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Seyama, Akira</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kimura, Akira</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sea wall</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">run up</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">critical height</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study aims at clarifying the difference between irregular and periodic wave run-ups on a slope or a sea wall. Since hydraulic phenomena on a slope are the induced result of an interaction between a running up wave and a back-wash. The run-up height, therefore, has to be investigated in terms of a back-wash properties in addition to run-up wave properties. The experiments which are so designed that waves can run up on a slope without meeting back-wash, were conducted to evaluate the back-wash effects. The relative run-up heights K /HQ of periodic waves in these experiments reached up to about two times as high as those of periodic waves which have the same steepnesses. The run-up heights of irregular waves on a slope were also investigated experimentally. There are no clear relations between R_/HQ and HQ/LQ as those for periodic waves ordinary observed, and they distributed widely. The upper-most value of RJ-/HQ in the distribution for any HQ/LQ was almost equal to the value in the above experiment. The uppermost (critical) relative run-up heights RJ-/HQ for the given HQ/LQ and slope may exist. The differences between the critical and ordinary run-up height of periodic waves on the sea wall were also experimentally investigated. The difference is prominent when a sea wall is set onshore from the shore-line. It reaches up to about 4 times when a sea wall is set a little on-shore from the shore line. Some statistical discussion on the probability of the situation in which the critical run-up may be brought about is given at the last part.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4165</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v20.164</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 20 (1986): Proceedings of 20th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Taipei, Taiwan, 1986.; 164</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4165/3846</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
