<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12929</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-03T03:09:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">HOW MUCH LONGER CAN AN OLD SEAWALL LAST? DESIGN, CONSTRUCTION AND MAINTENANCE LESSONS TAUGHT BY NORTH CRONULLA’S PRINCE STREET SEAWALL</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Turnbull, Adrian</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sellers, Erin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cai, Patrick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Within the traditional lands of the Dharawal people, the headlands, beaches and sandy dunes of Gunnamatta / Cronulla are long recognised as important regional environmental, social and economic assets. With early settlers holding large tracts of land, once connected to Sutherland by a steam train from 1911, the seaside holiday village of Cronulla was quickly subdivided and became a permanent town, with increasingly expensive infrastructure built along the foreshore. The sandy beach and dunes of North Cronulla, where the main settlement was established, has a well-documented history of being impacted by coastal erosion events over the past 100 years. Modification of the foreshore started around 1919, using dune sand to infill the low-lying swamp in the hind-dune, creating more ‘useable’ land. The recommendations and forward plan to prolong the life of the Prince Street Seabee seawall will be the subject of this presentation.              </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-10-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12929</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.structures.73</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; structures.73</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12929/12202</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Adrian Turnbull, Erin Sellers, Patrick Cai</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
