<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10226</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">GUIDELINES FOR DESIGNING SAND NOURISHMENT ON LOW TO VERY EXPOSED COASTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Karlsson, Henrik Vinge</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Larsen, Britt Gadesboll</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sorensen, Per</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Danish law establishes a common right of passage on foot along the Danish shoreline, even though beaches are often privately owned. The law also states that coastal protection must not hinder this. Therefore, sand nourishment should be part of every coastal protection scheme against erosion. Sand nourishments can be designed in numerous ways depending on their objectives. As part of the European Interreg project, Building With Nature (BWN), guidelines will be developed by the Danish Coastal Authority (DCA) in end-2020. This abstract presents these guidelines with special focus on the coasts of Denmark. Special emphasis will be on insight into the natural variation of the coasts, as this is vital both when designing effective coastal protection schemes and when evaluating the impact of the nourishment. In this project, the pathway along which sediment is being transported spans from offshore at the outer bar to the coastal cliff. The aim is to be able to determine the along- and cross-shore paths, along which the nourishment sand is transported, the diffusion velocity of the nourishment and the impact on the surrounding coasts. Based on the results of the multiple analysis, the primary objective is to produce guidelines on how to use sand nourishment to counteract erosion in a sustainable and socioeconomic way.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/nIrFFmH98V8</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10226</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.sediment.5</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; sediment.5</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10226/9512</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Henrik Vinge Karlsson, Britt Gadesboll Larsen, Per Sorensen</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
