<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2209</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T05:58:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SHORELINE ADVANCEMENT BY SEA WALL AND GROYNES AT COCHIN</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hiranandani, M.G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gole, C.V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">shore advancement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">groin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cochin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">shoreline protection</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the paper "Some coastal engineering problems in India" presented at the Vlth Conference on Coastal Engineering, a mention has been made about experimental protective measures consisting of one mile long sea wall and groynes adopted for giving protection to the coast near Cochin. The protective works mentioned in the above paper are now in operation for the last five years. As there are no major rivers there is very little littoral drift along this coast. The material eroded from the coast forms the main source of littoral transport. The data regarding high water and low water marks along the coast have been recorded, and statistically analysed to assess the efficiency of these measures in respect of shoreline advancement. Results are discussed in the paper. Some experiments have also been carried out in the prototype for a sea wall with bituminous grouting. Behaviour of this type of sea wall has also been discussed in the paper. Since the construction of the experimental measures, protective measures in the shape of either sea wall or sea walls with groynes have been further extended to a 10 mile long reach of the coast. The results of these new works, experiments carried out in a model for evolving the design of protective measures and model limitations have also been included. Fig. 1 shows the plan of the sea wall and groynes in one mile experimental reach.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1960-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2209</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v7.50</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 7 (1960): Proceedings of 7th Conference on Coastal Engineering, The Hague, The Netherlands, 1960.; 50</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2209/1903</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
