<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4054</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T20:11:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">IRREGULAR WAVE TRANSFORMATION AFFECTED BY OPPOSING CURRENTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sakai, Shigeki</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hiyamizu, Kouestu</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Saeki, Hiroshi</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">irregular wave</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave transformation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">current</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">opposing current</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Transformation of irregular waves affected by opposing currents on a sloping sea bed was discussed, experimentally and theoretically. It was found that representative values of wave height, such as a significant wave height, are larger before breaking and the wave height decaying occurs more promptly in a surf zone as opposing currents become dominant, and that characteristics of a irregular wave transformation are determined by the dimensionless unit width discharge q* and the deep water wave steepness. This means that the effects of opposing currents on irregular wave transformation are qualitatively identical to that on the regular waves. A transformation model of irregular waves affected by opposing currents was presented. In the model, formulations for a regular wave transformation, in which the effects of opposing currents were taken into account, were applied to individual waves defined by zero-down" cross-method from irregular wave profiles. Comparisons between experimental results and the prediction by the model showed that the present model gives a good explanation for wave height distributions and the experimental finding that the surf zone is moved offshore by opposing currents.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4054</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v20.53</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 20 (1986): Proceedings of 20th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Taipei, Taiwan, 1986.; 53</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4054/3736</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
