<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/13029</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:15:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EXPERIMENTAL ANALYSIS OF HYBRID SOLUTIONS FOR COASTAL PROTECTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Maza, Maria</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rold치n, Mariana</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lara, Javier L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Losada, I침igo J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Among the newest strategies are nature-based solutions based on coastal ecosystems (Spalding et al., 2014; Jongman 2018). Such solutions have several co-benefits, such as habitat creation, increased water quality or carbon sequestration. However, these solutions may not be effective on their own in high-risk areas or in areas where there is not enough space for their implementation. In these cases, the union of conventional engineering with these nature-based solutions, the so-called hybrid solutions, can represent an optimal solution that provides the necessary risk reduction while reporting the cobenefits associated with natural solutions (Sutton-Grier et al., 2015; Vuik et al., 2016). This makes hybrid solutions a highly attractive option in which there is a growing interest. However, their relatively novel character, the few real cases implemented and the need for a strong integration of knowledge linking different disciplines pose a series of gaps in knowledge. To this end, an experimental campaign is proposed to study different typologies of hybrid solutions. The interaction between the ecosystem and the hard structure is studied to better understand the coastal protection service provided by the joint solution. To compare the performance of the different hybrid solutions, wave run-up over the rigid structure is analyzed and it is compared to the run-up obtained for the traditional rigid solution.      </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13029</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.management.71</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; management.71</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/13029/12302</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Maria Maza, Mariana Rold치n, Javier L. Lara, I침igo J. Losada</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
