<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2807</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T03:26:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MOVABLE-BED MODEL STUDIES OF PERCHED BEACH CONCEPT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chatham, C.B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">moveable bed</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">model study</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">perched beach</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hydraulic model studies were conducted to aid in ascertaining the technical feasibility and optimum design factors of the perched beach concept. Among these were two-dimensional, movable-bed studies to determine an estimate of the amount of sand which would be lost seaward over the submerged toe structure by normal and storm wave action, the optimum elevation of the submerged toe structure, and the length of a stone blanket required to reduce seaward migration of sand to a minimum. The model beach was subjected to test waves until equilibrium was reached for a wide range of wave conditions for both the existing beach and the perched beach. Test results indicate that (a) little or no beachfill material will be lost seaward of the toe structure for normal wave conditions but the larger storm waves may cause erosion of the perched beach, (b) the installation of a stone blanket shoreward of the toe structure will reduce the amount of beach erosion, (c) if the beach fill is extended a sufficient distance seaward, the toe structure serves no useful purpose, and (d) a three-dimensional movable-bed model study is feasible and is necessary to determine the final design features of a perched beach.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2807</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v13.60</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 13 (1972): Proceedings of 13th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Vancouver, Canada, 1972.; 60</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2807/2471</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
