<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3036</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T02:03:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">FINITE ELEMENT MODEL OF TWO LAYER COASTAL CIRCULATION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wang, John D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Connor, Jerome J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">finite element</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">circulation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">two dimensional circulation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A set of "averaged partial differential equations for the circulation in a two layered coastal water is established by assuming each layer to be vertically homogeneous and by performing a vertical integration over the layer thicknesses. Since the phenomena to be investigated typically consist of long waves such as a tidal wave, the hydrostatic pressure assumption is also introduced. The finite element method is employed to transform the partial differential equations to a discrete system of ordinary differential equations which are solved using an implicit time stepping method similar to the trapezoidal rule, but with the variables (elevation and flows) staggered in time. A linear stability analysis shows the initial value problem to be unconditionally stable. In practice, instability due to boundary conditions and non-linearity sets in. Comparisons between computed and analytical solutions for simple cases give good agreement. The tidal excitation of Massachusetts Bay, represented as a rectangular basin with opening on one side is presented as an illustrative example.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1974-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3036</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v14.141</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 14 (1974): Proceedings of 14th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Copenhagen, Denmark, 1974.; 141</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3036/2701</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
