<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14419</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:45:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A COMPREHENSIVE ONE-LINE MODEL FOR SHORELINE EVOLUTION ESTIMATION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Scipione, Francesca</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Castellino, Myrta</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Girolamo, Paolo De</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Risio, Marcello Di</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The prediction of sandy shoreline evolution, over both short/medium- and long-term temporal scales for small and large spatial scales, remains a challenge for coastal researchers and engineers. Basically, the configuration of sandy beaches, which are characterized by high complexity, are influenced by waves-sediment interaction. Coastal zones, which have a significant environmental, tourist, and economic value, are constantly exposed to natural (e.g., waves, tides, climate change) and human (e.g., over-exploitation by the construction of railways, roads, and private buildings close to the beach) pressures. One- line models, with a particular focus on the study of curved shorelines, and the development of coastal shoreline features, such as spits, cups, and rhythmic shoreline undulations (Ashton and Murray, 2006a, b; Kaergaard and Fredsoe, 2013a; Hurst et al., 2015; Robinet et al., 2018, 2020) have been developed. Other one-line models (Vitousek et al., 2017; Antolinez et al., 2019) have explored the impact of the cross-shore sediment transport on long- term shoreline dynamics, accounting not only for river inputs, beach nourishments, sand-bypassing (Pelnard- Considère, 1956), but also cross-shore transport due to wave action (Yates et al., 2009) and water level variation due to sea level rise (Bruun,1962), storm surge, and monthly sea level anomalies. In this context, the work described hereinafter is aimed to provide the scientific and technical communities with a comprehensive one-line tool, covering hydrodynamics and morphodynamics processes.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14419</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.133</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.133</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14419/13691</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Francesca Scipione, Myrta Castellino, Paolo De Girolamo, Marcello Di Risio</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
