<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10352</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">RECOVERY OF SANDY BEACH AFTER TYPHOON WAVES - CASE STUDY ON CHIGASAKI COAST</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ishikawa, Toshinori</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Uda, Takaaki</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hosokawa, Jun-ichi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">San-nami, Toshiro</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Beach topography quickly changes in response to the action of storm waves, resulting in erosion of the foreshore with accretion under a calm wave condition after a storm. These seasonal beach changes may occur on beaches with protective measures or artificial beaches produced by beach nourishment. On these beaches, the shore protection function of a sandy beach is reduced when a trough is formed immediately offshore of the shoreline and the foreshore slope increases, indicating the importance of the study on topographic changes. Moreover, the time required for a beach recovery in response to wave conditions has not been sufficiently studied, along with the 3-D topographic changes associated with beach cycles. In this study, we aim to investigate these issues using the Narrow Multi-Beam survey data, wave data, and seabed materials data, taking the Chigasaki coast as an example. It was found that a seabed shallower than 2 and 3 m depths was eroded by rapid offshore sand transport during a storm event with the deposition of sand in a zone between 3 and 5 m depths, and then the beach recovered within 1-2 years after the storm. It was also confirmed that a bar and trough disappeared in 1-2 months under the conditions of HE = 0.5 m, TE = 8 s, and H/L = 0.005 when the crown depth of the bar was smaller than approximately 2 m. Thus, the topography after the storm waves recovers within several months or 1-2 years depending on wave conditions and the crown depth of the bar.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/W_P_3p_xd8U</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10352</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.papers.42</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; papers.42</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10352/9638</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Toshinori Ishikawa, Takaaki Uda, Jun-ichi Hosokawa, Toshiro San-nami</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
