<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14704</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T10:33:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">LESSONS LEARNT ON THE DESIGN OF A DYNAMIC COBBLE REVETMENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mauti, Gabriella</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Camarena, Amaury</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Coastal hazards are becoming increasingly prevalent with rising sea levels and severe storm events regularly occurring. As a result, there has been a growing need for long-term and resilient coastal protection solutions that also provide co-benefits such as social value, ecological benefits, and adaptability. In response to this, alternative coastal stabilization solutions are being implemented rather than the typical traditional coastal infrastructure, particularly nature-based solutions (NBS). Dynamic cobble revetments reduce erosion and coastal- driven flooding, by reducing wave runup and overtopping, which subsequently protects the shoreline and any landward infrastructure. In addition, cobble revetments are particularly adaptable as they reshape during storm events and self-maintain their elevation relative to extreme water levels (Bayle et al. 2020). Examples of successful cobble/ gravel revetments include projects at Flathead Lake, Montana, USA (Lorang, 1991), Yaquina Bay, Oregon, USA (Allan et al., 2012), amongst several others (Bayle et al., 2020). This study includes the design and implementation of a coastal protection solution for 500 m of shoreline along a roadway that is undergoing erosion and flooding.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14704</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.structures.120</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; structures.120</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14704/13976</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Gabriella Mauti, Amaury Camarena</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
