<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8848</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-23T01:34:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">NUMERICAL ANALYSIS OF INTERLOCKING CAISSON BREAKWATER USING MODULAR SYSTEM</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Song, Sunghoon</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Park, Minsu</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">You, Youngjun</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jeong, Younju</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hwang, Yoonkoog</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Breakwaters have been severely damaged quite often since they are directly exposed to large waves. And damage level of breakwaters has been scaled up because of abnormal global climate changes. In particular, according to the report of caisson breakwater damages in Japan(Takayama, 2002), it was found that damages caused by caisson sliding, account for more than 70% of breakwater failure modes. So, the design criteria for new breakwaters is being intensified to cope with abnormal global climate changes and unusual waves. In the case of a long structure, the wave force is reduced due to the phase difference in oblique waves. Therefore, if a caisson is made as long as possible, the stability of breakwaters could be ensured even if unusual high waves occur. Recently, interlocking caisson systems, which are to form a long caisson by interlocking individual caissons with each other, have been much attention to enhance the structural stability of conventional caisson breakwaters. In the present study, a modular caisson was proposed that can improve structural stability and workability by using the shear-key interlocking system; and the wave force reduction effects of the modular caisson breakwater were evaluated by numerical analysis method.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8848</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36.structures.20</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36 (2018): Proceedings of 36th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Baltimore, Maryland, 2018; structures.20</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8848/7648</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
