<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4876</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T15:30:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A FEASIBILITY STUDY OF A PERCHED BEACH CONCEPT IN THE NETHERLANDS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">de Ruig, Joost H.M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roelse, Piet</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Netherlands</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">perched beach</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feasibility study</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The present Dutch coastal defence policy is aimed at a full compensation of shoreline retreat, mostly by means of beach nourishment. For some parts of the coast with a small dune ridge attacked by severe erosion, a so-called 'seaward coastal defence strategy' might be more profitable. According to this stra-tegy, measures will be taken to influence the morphological system in such a way that erosion is prevented, which will result in a stable or even progressive coastline. An analytical policy design was chosen at the onset of the study. A number of seaward coastal defence measures will be tested following a series of selected criteria, such as effects on morphological, financial and construction aspects as well as effects on recreation and ecology. The study works from 'coarse' (entire province of Zeeland, SW-Netherlands; different coastal defence alternatives) to 'fine' (selected location; preferred coastal defence alternative). This has resulted in conclusions and recommendations with regard to the feasibility of a pilot project with a perched beach in the 'Cadzand' area.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4876</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v23.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 23 (1992): Proceedings of 23rd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Venice, Italy, 1992.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4876/4557</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
