<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14001</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">OPTIMAL LAYOUT OF LIMESTONE SUBSTRATES FOR OYSTER BEDS AS NATURE- BASED SOLUTIONS FOR COASTAL MANAGEMENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Archetti, Renata</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buccino, Mariano</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Casadei, Isabella</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gaeta, M. Gabriella</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tuozzo, Sara</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ponti, Massimo</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper presents a preliminary design for beach restoration using nature-based solutions (NBS) in the northern Adriatic Sea, specifically between the Bevano and Fiumi Uniti rivers in Ravenna, Italy. The project leverages the high potential of sabellariid worm and oyster reefs, supported by numerical modeling results. The area, characterized by existing populations of native sabellariid worms, is ideal for species settlement. The proposed intervention involves constructing a submerged Basal Limestone Reef (BLR) offshore, which aims to stabilize sand, mitigate flooding from storm surges, and enhance biodiversity. The BLR will be created using limestone boulders retained in metallic cages and will be strategically placed to create optimal initial conditions for oysters and sabellariid worms settlement. The hydrodynamic characteristics of the BLR, particularly its wave transmission performance, were assessed through numerical simulations, indicating minimal diffractive phenomena due to its submerged nature. The findings contribute to understanding the effectiveness of artificial reefs in coastal habitat protection and resilience.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14001</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.papers.50</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; papers.50</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14001/13273</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Renata Archetti, Mariano Buccino, Isabella Casadei, M. Gabriella Gaeta, Sara Tuozzo, Massimo Ponti</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
