<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2883</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T02:58:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">TIDAL HYDRAULICS IN THE CANO MACAREO</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zagustin, Konstantin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Masch, Frank D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brandes, Robert J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tidal hydraulics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cano Macareo</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Investigations have been undertaken to predict the tidal amplitudes and current patterns at the mouth of the Cano Macareo in Venezuela to the Atlantic Ocean. These studies were undertaken as part of a more comprehensive feasibility study sponsored by the Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana for location and orientation of a 60-foot deep navigation channel and for the design of related channel appurtenances. In the analysis, three simulation methods were employed conjunctively. These included oneand two-dimensional mathematical models and an electro analogical model. Model results have been supplemented with prototype data and other information based on field observations. Analyses provided for determination of tidal hydraulics, first, to establish baseline conditions as they presently exist, and second, to evaluate the effects of various proposed channel alignments. The twodimensional mathematical model and the electro analogical model both provided for inclusion of a pronounced longshore sea current which plays an important role in determining current patterns at the mouth of the Macareo. In addition, the use of a berm to modify the sea current in the vicinity of the channel entrance was investigated.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2883</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v13.136</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 13 (1972): Proceedings of 13th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Vancouver, Canada, 1972.; 136</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2883/2547</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
