<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5331</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T12:56:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">POTENTIAL USES FOR THE RAPIDLY INSTALLED BREAKWATER SYSTEM</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fowler, Jimmy</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Resio, Donald</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Briggs, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pollock, Cheryl</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">breakwater</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">rapid install</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">breakwater system</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Engineers and scientists at the U.S. Army Engineer Waterways Experiment Station (WES) are developing a Rapidly Installed Breakwater (RIB) System specifically designed to address problems associated with the military's efforts to offload ships during Logistics Over The Shore (LOTS) operations. Problems arise with these operations when seas become energetic and limit capabilities of crane operators and stevedore crews. The RIB System is designed to solve this problem by creating a 'pool' of calmer water where these operations occur so that crews can continue to function. A series of small-scale laboratory experiments conducted in 1995 and 1996 at WES's facilities in Vicksburg, Miss., and at the O. H. Hinsdale Wave Research Laboratory at Oregon State University in Corvallis, laid the groundwork for the RIB System development and yielded an optimum RIB System configuration known as the "Double Delta". Laboratory results, obtained with the Double Delta configuration, showed that wave heights could be reduced by more than 80 percent. During the spring and summer of 1996, a mid-scale RIB System successfully demonstrated its capabilities during a field deployment, with wave height reduction on the order of 75 percent. Based on these results, it is believed that the RIB System will be integrated into the Army's LOTS asset inventory and become a key part of the solution to the military's LOTS problems.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1996-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5331</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v25.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 25 (1996): Proceedings of 25th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Orlando, Florida, 1996.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5331/5009</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
