<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3348</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T00:14:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">UNDULATED BOTTOM PROFILES AND ONSHORE-OFFSHORE TRANSPORT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Manhohar, Madhav</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bottom profile</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">crossshore transport</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Underwater bars, the characteristic features of oceans and lakes occur singly or in a series along the coast. Nearest bar to the shore, namely the break-point bar moves shoreward in summer, joins the coast and is replaced by another bar in its original place. The other seaward bars are storm bars, more or less permanent though they may shift slightly in orientation, position and shape depending upon the wave climate and state of the coastal processes. With the sediment and bottom profiles changing constantly with differing wave characteristics and beach exposure, a rigorous mathematical analysis for long range variability of profiles and therefore coastal processes in not possible. Therefore, the concept of medium depth and steepness characteristics is introduced to distinguish the profiles and their major dimensions. Onshore-offshore sediment motion is sometimes far in excess of longshore transport mostly confined in the breaker zone. When submarine bars are present, such motion is considerable mainly as a result of the hydrodynamic reaction between the rotating eddies generated over the bars and the bar surface. By means of dimensional analysis, it is possible to relate the quantity of onshore-offshore motion to the bar dimensions, wave period, water depth and transport direction by profile steepness characteristics. The above two concepts are then applied to the Nile Delta coastal processes with satisfactory results.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3348</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v16.86</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 16 (1978): Proceedings of 16th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Hamburg, Germany, 1978.; 86</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3348/3017</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
