<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14267</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:11:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Swash</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">PREDICTION OF WAVE RUN-UP AFFECTED BY DUNE SCARP: A LARGE-SCALE TWO- DIMENSIONAL MOVABLE BED EXPERIMENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lee, Eunju</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dang, Hai Van</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shin, Sungwon</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Yoo, Jeseon</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Park, Hyoungsu</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Korean beaches have suffered erosion due to coastal development. Recently, the South Korean government has initiated efforts to restore the dune system for a beach on the west coast of Korea. Coastal sand dunes serve as natural barriers against extreme waves caused by climate change and rising sea levels. To design effective artificial sand dunes, understanding the erosion and restoration mechanisms of coastal dunes is crucial. Hence, the COastal sand Dune Experiment in Korea (CODEK), a large-scale two-dimensional movable bed experiment, was conducted to investigate these mechanisms. This study focuses on observing wave run-up affected by dune erosion, particularly the dune scarp during a storm. Wave run-up is a vital parameter for assessing the vulnerability of coastal beaches, dune systems, and structures to dynamic wave action. The aim of this study is to analyze the wave run-up on the dune scarp based on experimental results and propose ways to enhance prediction accuracy using an existing empirical formula.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14267</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.currents.18</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; currents.18</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14267/13539</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Eunju Lee, Hai Van Dang, Sungwon Shin, Jeseon Yoo, Hyoungsu Park</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
