<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10119</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">TAILORING THE MARINE DESIGN FOR THE BRISBANE INTERNATIONAL CRUISE TERMINAL TO CATER FOR MEGA-SHIPS AND CHALLENGING CONSTRAINTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Burley, Peter Kastrup: Michael Kelleher: Daniel</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Port of Brisbane (PBPL) is developing the new AUD$177 million Brisbane International Cruise Terminal (BICT) located at Luggage Point at the mouth of the Brisbane River. The project has successfully progressed through the detailed design phase, and construction is currently underway. BICT will be the first purpose-built megacruise ship terminal in Australia when it opens in 2020. It will cater for cruise vessels of all sizes including the world's largest ocean-going ships and will function as both a base port and port of call facility. The planning and design of an international cruise terminal requires a fully integrated multi-disciplinary approach. There are a number of inter-dependencies from different disciplines based on a number of variables. This presentation will explore how the terminal masterplan was developed to address the key site constraints and how significant challenges for the marine design were overcome.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/qIC3aL0FqYg</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10119</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.management.24</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; management.24</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10119/9405</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Peter Kastrup: Michael Kelleher: Daniel Burley</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
