<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10408</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:foreword</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">FOREWORD: Proceedings of the virtual International Conference</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lynett, Patrick J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The virtual International Conference on Coastal Engineering (vICCE) was held online from October 6th-9th, 2020.  This was a most unusual ICCE, organized over a few short months in response to the required postponement of ICCE 2020 in Sydney to 2022.  The vICCE program was planned on a 24-hour schedule, so that presenters from across the globe might participate in their local time zones.  Over 3,500 people registered for the vICCE to discuss research and applications in coastal engineering. This Proceedings contains 311 papers from the virtual International Conference on Coastal Engineering.  The papers and presentations contained in this Proceedings cover a wide range of topics including waves; swash, nearshore currents, and long waves; coastal management, risk, and environmental restoration; sediment transport and morphology; and coastal structures.  The “Papers” sections includes full length Proceedings papers, covering a broad range of topics including theory, numerical and physical modeling, field measurements, case studies, design, and management.  The other sections include abstract and recorded presentation links, as presented at the conference. These submissions provide engineers, scientists, and planners state-of-the-art information on coastal engineering and coastal processes.  The authors have provided state-of-the-art contributions, and this volume could not be produced without their commitment to solving coastal engineering challenges.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10408</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.foreword.1</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; foreword.1</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10408/9680</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Patrick J. Lynett</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
