<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12994</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:14:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">HIGHWAYS IN THE COASTAL ENVIRONMENT: NEW USA GUIDANCE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Douglass, Scott</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Krolak, Joseph</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Webb, Bret</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There are over 60,000 miles (100,000 km) of coastal highways in the United States (US) that are occasionally exposed to coastal waves and water levels. Wise stewardship calls for the integration of coastal engineering principles and practices in the planning and design of these roads and bridges to make them more resilient. A new, 3rd, edition of the primary guidance document Hydraulic Engineering Circular No. 25 (HEC-25), entitled “Highways in the Coastal Environment” was recently released by the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA). It provides guidance on a range of issues for the design, planning and operation of coastal highways. This manual should help those with little experience in coastal engineering to understand and, as appropriate, to apply scientific methods and engineering approaches that are unique to the coast. For experienced coastal engineers, this manual should serve as a reference document in providing specific highway-oriented assistance and consultation for FHWA and state Department of Transportation projects.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12994</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.management.36</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; management.36</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12994/12267</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Scott Douglass, Joseph Krolak, Bret Webb</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
