<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14088</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Waves</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">RECENT ADVANCES OF LBM FOR TSUNAMI MODELLINGS: AN ENHANCEMENT OF IMPACT PRESSURE CALCULATION BY FOURTH-ORDER CUMULANT MODEL</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sato, Kenta</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Koshimura, Shunichi</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Tsunamis, though infrequent, wield devastating power upon coastal regions, necessitating accurate simulation techniques to comprehend their impact and enhance disaster preparedness. Despite the significant advancements in modern computational fluid dynamics, these simulations continue to pose considerable challenges, encompassing numerical intricacies and substantial computational expenses. In the context of this issue, the lattice Boltzmann method (LBM) has garnered attention for its ability to perform high-performance simulations of large-scale tsunamis due to its remarkable computational efficiency. In recent years, there have been reported instances of utilising the LBM for tsunami simulations, and its application is poised to increase further in the forthcoming research. In this study, we present the recent advances of the LBM for tsunami modelling, especially in the non-hydrostatic three- dimensional free surface flow model and discuss future development. We will demonstrate an enhancement of tsunami impact pressure simulations using the fourth- order cumulant model (Geier et al. 2017).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14088</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.waves.16</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; waves.16</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14088/13360</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Kenta Sato, Shunichi Koshimura</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
