<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2454</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T05:02:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DEPOSITIONAL BEHAVIOR OF FINE SEDIMENT IN A TURBULENT FLUID MOTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Partheniadis, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kennedy, John F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fine sediment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">turbulent fluid</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">depositional behavior</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">An experimental investigation, utilizing an apparatus consisting of a counterrotating annular channel and ring, of the depositional characteristics of fine, cohesive sediment revealed that after an initial period of rapid deposition, the sediment concentration approaches asymptotically an equilibrium value. The ratio of this equilibrium concentration to the initial concentration is nearly independent of initial concentration and for a given sediment and environment depends only on the flow conditions. For the three water depths investigated, the ratio of equilibrium to initial concentration was found to he a single function of an average shear stress around the channel-section perimeter. A comparison of the size distributions of the parent material with the material retained in suspension when equilibrium was achieved indicated that the greatest losses occur in the clay-size fractions, suggesting that the deposition is controlled predominantly by flocculation, and that the strength and size of the floes exert a stronger influence on the deposition than does the particle weight. A silty-clay sediment with a mean particle diameter of 0.0009 mm was used in all experiments.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1966-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2454</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v10.40</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 10 (1966): Proceedings of 10th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Tokyo, Japan, 1966.; 40</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2454/2119</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
