<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3197</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T01:06:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">LARGE SCALE MODEL TESTS OF PLACED STONE BREAKWATERS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sollitt, Charles K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Debok, Donald H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">model test</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">large scale model</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stone breakwater</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">breakwater</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Large scale model studies reveal that Reynolds scaling can affect the apparent stability and wave modifying properties of layered breakwater structures. Results of a study for a breakwater configuration designed to protect offshore power and port facilities in water depths to 60 feet are presented and discussed. The armor layer of this structure is formed from quarried rock of irregular rectangular parallelepiped shape, individually placed perpendicular to 1:2 seaward slope and crest. The resulting armor layer is relatively smooth, densely packed and very stable. Model studies of similar configurations were studied at 1:10, 1:20 and 1:100 scale ratios. Stability, runup, rundown and reflection were measured for a variety of water depths, wave heights and periods. Analysis of the large scale test results establish that the placed stone armor is approximately as stable as dolos armor units. Runup, rundown and reflection respond similar to rough, impermeable slopes. Comparison of large and small scale results demonstrate that relative increases in drag forces at lower Reynolds numbers decrease stability and runup in small scale models.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1976-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3197</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v15.147</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 15 (1976): Proceedings of 15th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1976.; 147</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3197/2861</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
