<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14030</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ADAPTION OF ESTUARINE WATERWAY INFRASTRUCTURE TO MITIGATE THE EFFECT OF LONG-PERIOD SHIP-INDUCED WAVES</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dempwolff, Leon-Carlos</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Windt, Christian</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Melling, Gregor</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bihs, Hans</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Holzwarth, Ingrid</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Goseberg, Nils</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In narrow maritime channels frequented by large vessels, particularly in estuaries serving as entryways to seaports, the impact of waves generated by ships has grown increasingly significant. This is mainly due to the continuous enlargement of vessels in operation. Of notable importance is the potential for increasing damage associated with the extended wavelength of the long-period primary wave system, which distinguishes it from natural hydrodynamic forces (Dempwolff et al., 2022a). Due to this unique characteristics of ship- induced primary waves, the damage mechanisms acting on the estuarine infrastructure can be specific to long- period ship-induced waves (Dempwolff et al., 2023b). Examples of civil works being deteriorated by primary waves are rock groins which are overtopped during ship passages. This leads to a displacement of the armour layer near the groin root. Consequently, this study aims to explore possible mitigation strategies that can be employed to reduce the loads on estuarine groins.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14030</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.structures.4</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; structures.4</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14030/13302</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Leon-Carlos Dempwolff, Christian Windt, Gregor Melling, Hans Bihs, Ingrid Holzwarth, Nils Goseberg</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
