<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10147</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">LOADING AND STRUCTURAL RESPONSE OF DEVELOPED SHORELINES UNDER WAVES, SURGE, AND TSUNAMI OVERLAND FLOW HAZARDS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lomonaco, Pedro</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Barbosa, Andre</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cox, Dan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, Tori</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Keen, Adam</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kennedy, Andrew</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lynett, Patrick</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Barra, Joaquin Moris</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Park, Hyoungsu</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shin, Sungwon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Inundation from storms like Hurricanes Katrina and Sandy, and the 2011 East Japan tsunami, have caused catastrophic damage to coastal communities. Prediction of surge, wave, and tsunami flow transformation over the built and natural environment is essential in determining survival and failure of near-coast structures. However, unlike earthquake and wind hazards, overland flow event loading and damage often vary strongly at a parcel scale in built-up coastal regions due to the influence of nearby structures and vegetation on hydrodynamic transformation. Additionally, overland flow hydrodynamics and loading are presently treated using a variety of simplified methods (e.g. bare earth method) which introduce significant uncertainty and/or bias. This study describes an extensive series of large-scale experiments to create a comprehensive dataset of detailed hydrodynamics and forces on an array of coastal structures (representing buildings of a community on a barrier island) subject to the variability of storm waves, surge, and tsunami, incorporating the effect of overland flow, 3D flow alteration due to near-structure shielding, vegetation, waterborne debris, and building damage.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/EDLiEK6b64E</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10147</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.structures.36</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; structures.36</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10147/9433</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Pedro Lomonaco, Andre Barbosa, Dan Cox, Tori Johnson, Adam Keen, Andrew Kennedy, Patrick Lynett, Joaquin Moris Barra, Hyoungsu Park, Sungwon Shin</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
