<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14208</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:32:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MODELLING THE EFFECT OF SALT MARSHES FOR COASTAL PROTECTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dissanayake, Pushpa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oberrecht, Dennis</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wurpts, Andreas</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Salt marshes are populated in the East Frisian Wadden Sea behind the barrier islands and in the foreland areas, functioning as a coastal protection measure and carbon sink, and enhancing biodiversity and ecology. Increased understanding of the interactions of salt marshes with hydro-morpho-dynamics supports to use them as a nature-based-solution (NBS) for the coastal protection. The main objective of this study within the framework of the EU REST-COAST project is to quantify the role of salt marshes in wave attenuation and mitigation of coastal erosion for different present and future scenarios, and to increase awareness of policy/coastal managers using salt marsh as a potential NBS for coastal protection. This investigation is being carried out using the exemplary salt marsh community in Ley Bay, which has dimensions of about 5 km × 5 km, and is located in the tidal basin behind Borkum and Juist barrier islands, adjacent to the Ems-Dollard estuary. The salt marsh community covers about 1⁄3 of the bay area lying around +2 m NN attached to the foreland dyke (Fig. 1b and c: green-polygon). The study area is characterised by semi-diurnal meso-tides (mean tidal range ~2.5 m) and high waves (Hs) from the N-W sector reaching up to about 6 m (at 20 m depth) (Herman et al., 2009).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14208</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.64</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.64</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14208/13480</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Pushpa Dissanayake, Dennis Oberrecht, Andreas Wurpts</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
