<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1128</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-10-04T04:38:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">LABORATORY EXPERIMENT ON CROSS-SHORE BARRIER SPIT EVOLUTION BY STORM DYNAMICS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Xuan Tinh, Nguyen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Larson, Magnus</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Donnelly, Chantal</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tanaka, Hitoshi</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Storm</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Barrier evolution</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">experiment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">overwash</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">washover</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">analytical model</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Every year there are many severe storms occurring around the world, in general, and in Japan, in particular. The occurrence of storms is expected to increase because of the global warming effects. An increasing wave height together with a rising mean water level during a storm create a high possibility for waves to overtop the beach crest causing a lot of sediment to be eroded to offshore areas or deposited in the inland direction. The study of the barrier island response to storms has therefore become very important in terms of sediment transport and beach morphology change, as well as damage to nearshore structures due to runup overwash and inundation overwash. However, changes in the beach profile and prevailing sediment transport mechanisms during a real event are difficult to obtain. Thus, laboratory studies are necessary to conduct. This study presents a laboratory experiment on the impact of storms on a sandy barrier islands. The main aim is to investigate the entire barrier island (or sand spit) response due to storm conditions considering the increase in water level due to storm surge. Also, further development of an analytical model for barrier profile change caused by runup overwash is presented and obtained results overall captured order-of-magnitude barrier face retreat and volume changes after the storm.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-01-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1128</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v32.sediment.32</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 32 (2010): Proceedings of 32nd Conference on Coastal Engineering, Shanghai, China, 2010.; sediment.32</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1128/pdf_37</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/1128/7689</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
