<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14181</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:31:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">INVESTIGATION OF EROSION MANAGEMENT ALTERNATIVES BY AREA-BASED ANALYSIS METHOD</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Manno, Giorgio</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Re, Carlo Lo</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nardone, Gabriele</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ciraolo, Giuseppe</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Coastlines are in a perpetual state of transformation, undergoing continuous modifications as a result of natural processes, such as erosion and accretion, driven by the forces of waves, currents, and tides (Davidson, 2021). These alterations hold significant implications across various scientific domains. Precisely determining the position of shorelines is of paramount importance for effective coastal management and the investigation of morphodynamics. A comprehensive grasp of shoreline evolution is crucial for the analysis of erosion patterns (Bergillos et al., 2017) and for evaluating the effects of coastal structures, nourishment practices, and energy farms. As human activities and coastal developments surge, there is a growing need for specialized studies on shoreline stability (Manno et al., 2017; Molina et al., 2020). While natural shoreline shifts persist, coastal development often necessitates structural interventions. Intense storms, flooding, erosive processes, and rising sea levels heighten coastal risks, which are shaped by both local and regional factors. This research represents a preliminary study that utilized an aerial-based approach for shoreline change analysis to evaluate the rates of coastal transformation.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14181</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.56</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.56</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14181/13453</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Giorgio Manno, Carlo Lo Re, Gabriele Nardone, Giuseppe Ciraolo</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
