<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14206</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:32:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">HAIFA BREAKWATER RETROFIT DESIGN</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bayram, Atilla</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Paparis, Bill</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ostrovsky, Daniela</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Haifa Port is Israel’s largest commercial port and is a vital gateway for international trade and commerce. The Existing Main Breakwater (“EMBW”) is comprised of two parts: the original breakwater that was built in the 1930s (“British MBW”) and an extension that was built in the 1980s (“Carmel MBW”). This breakwater section has deteriorated over the years and is subject to regular overtopping during storm events. In addition the stone used for the British MBW has deteriorated and neither the British MBW nor Carmel MBW were designed to resist current wave or seismic loading. Furthermore, the frequency and intensity of large storms are increasing, and therefore, and this coupled with the deterioration to date results in repairs being required on a more frequently basis. IPC retained HPA Engineers, P.C. (HPA) to carry out the planning and design of the retrofit alternatives for both breakwaters. The main objective of this study was to develop various retrofit options for 12.5-yr, 25-yr, and 50-yr design life, considering conventional rock armor and concrete armor units. The three design life alternatives were evaluated by considering six key factors: life-cycle cost, seismic resistance, effect on Navy and other harborside operations, environmental issues, sustainability, and construction schedule.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14206</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.structures.33</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; structures.33</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14206/13478</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Atilla Bayram, Bill Paparis, Daniela Ostrovsky</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
