<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5470</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T12:10:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">INTERACTION OF THE COLORADO RIVER PROJECT, TEXAS, WITH LONGSHORE SEDIMENT TRANSPORT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heilman, Daniel J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Edge, Billy L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Colorado River</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">longshore transport</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sediment transport</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In 1985, a weir jetty system was constructed at the mouth of the, Colorado River, Texas, and river discharge was diverted from this mouth in 1992. An evaluation of project impacts on longshore sediment transport was performed to determine the effectiveness of the project at preserving an open, navigable channel while preventing excessive erosion along adjacent beaches. This evaluation included both physical and numerical analysis of pre- and post-project conditions at the Colorado River mouth. Analysis of site data revealed that under the dredging and mechanical bypassing schedule followed during the first 8 years after jetty construction, the project resulted in significant trapping and sorting of sediment transported alongshore. Numerical modeling of the design maintenance dredging plan confirmed the plan to be sufficient for achieving project objectives. However, the entrance channel has continued to shoal considerably more rapidly than was anticipated during the project design.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1996-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5470</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v25.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 25 (1996): Proceedings of 25th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Orlando, Florida, 1996.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5470/5146</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
