<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2433</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-17T05:09:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">FIELD OBSERVATIONS OF WAVE PRESSURE, WAVE RUN-UP, AND OSCILLATION OF BREAKWATER</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Muraki, Yoshio</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave pressure</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave run-up</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">breakwater oscillation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">When a strong progressive wave collide against a shore structure, run-up and reflection of the wave take place on the front surface of the structure. At the same time, the structure is subjected to wave pressure resulting its oscillation or sometimes its sliding when the wave pressure is very large. Studies concerning such wave phenomena related to structures have been conducted by numerous scientists and engineers in many laboratories. While only a few investigations in the field have been made on these phenomena. At the same time it is noted that very few investigations have been carried out on the oscillation of breakwater caused by wave forces. The author performed some field observations on the wave pressure, wave run-up, and oscillation of breakwater at Haboro Harbor m Hokkaido, Japan, from 1957 to i960 (Refs. 1,2 and 3). In this paper the main results obtained from these observations such as the frequency of occurrence of shock pressure, the relationships among the run-up height, wave pressure and incident wave height, and the rocking phenomenon of the breakwater caused by wave pressure are summarized.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1966-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2433</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v10.19</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 10 (1966): Proceedings of 10th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Tokyo, Japan, 1966.; 19</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/2433/2099</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
