<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4094</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T19:58:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EVALUATION OF INCIDENT WAVE ENERGY IN FLUME TEST</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kit, Eliezer</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gottlieb, Oded</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rosen, Dov S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">flume test</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave energy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">incident wave</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">energy evaluation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A two dimensional model study, carried out for a structure in a flume using irregular waves, presents the problem of determining the relationship between the total incident wave energy attacking the structure and its response to that attack (displacements, forces, etc.) in various sea states, The total incident wave energy can be evaluated indirectly only, because the wave energy measured in the flume contains an extent of residual wave energy in addition to that generated by the wave machine. This residual energy consists of the re-reflected wave energy from the paddle of the wave machine, assuming the existence of quasi-stationary wave conditions in the flume. A method originally presented by Gravesen et al. (1974), was applied in this study to evaluate the total incident wave energy. In view of the results obtained by this method, a physically more sound refinement is proposed for the evaluation of the total incident wave energy (and characteristic wave height). Results of model tests were analyzed by the CAMERI refinement and compared with the Gravesen method and with a cross-spectral least squares method, separating incident and reflected wave spectra from wave spectra measured in the flume, Good agreement was found between the results obtained employing the CAMERI refinement and the cross-spectral least squares method, Advantages and drawbacks of these methods are indicated,</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4094</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v20.93</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 20 (1986): Proceedings of 20th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Taipei, Taiwan, 1986.; 93</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/4094/3776</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
