<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7585</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-20T04:23:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">COASTAL RISKS, NATURE-BASED DEFENSES AND THE ECONOMICS OF  ADAPTATION: AN APPLICATION IN THE GULF OF MEXICO, USA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reguero, Borja G</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bresch, David N</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Beck, Mike</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Calil, Juliano</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Meliane, Imen</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Economics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Climate Adaptation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Risk</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Nature based Defenses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Ecosystem Based Adaptation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The need to reduce risks  from coastal storms and climate change in coastal areas has given rise to efforts to make greater use of integrated ecosystem-based approaches. Assessment of  the  role and cost efficiency of adaptation measures  is increasingly demanded.  Applying  the Economics of Climate Adaptation framework in the US Gulf Coast, we compare nature-based defenses, artificial defenses, and policy measures for adaptation and risk reduction and quantify their costs and benefits under a variety of economic growth and climate change scenarios. Our analyses are spatially explicit and all models, tools and information are open source.  The  framework  includes (i)  a probabilistic assessment of hazards,  (ii) estimation of damages and (iii) assessment of adaptation and  risk reduction measures. We  perform  sensitivity analyses to understand the  parameters  that created the most variation in risk assessment and most influenced estimates of cost effectiveness. We  find  that  high rates of economic growth  and coastal development  are  likely to create  greater  risks in the near term than climate change, due to the increase in exposed assets. Nature-based solutions such as oyster  reef and marsh restoration are particularly cost effective, but their cost-effectiveness is highly dependent on where these measures are used. As decision-makers look for the most cost effective group of measures for adaptation and risk reduction, these approaches and results should be particularly useful for informing management priorities.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/7585</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v34.management.25</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 34 (2014): Proceedings of 34th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Seoul, Korea, 2014; management.25</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/7585/pdf_828</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
