<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12954</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:14:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EXPERIMENTAL EVALUATION OF THE PERFORMANCE OF A HYBRID ARTIFICIAL CORAL REEF WITH BRAIN AND STAGHORN CORALS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ghiasian, Mohammad</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tan, Peisen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Unsworth, Joseph</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baker, Andrew</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lirman, Diego</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Haus, Brian</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rhode-Barbarigos, Landolf</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Considering that more than 40 percent of the world's population resides within 100 km of coastal areas [WRI, 2007], the protection of coastal communities is critical. Coral reefs provide a large variety of ecosystem services from fishing, recreation and tourism to coastal flood risk reduction to nearby populations. They act as a green, self-building and self-repairing breakwaters dissipating wave energy through wave breaking and bed friction [Beck, 2018]. However, coral reefs are not typically accounted for as a coastal infrastructure as their effects are not easy to quantify [Ferrario, 2014] as their interaction with waves depends on multiple parameters including the variable morphologies of the organisms that form the reef. In this study, the wave energy dissipation of a scaled reef model with two coral species (staghorn and brain corals) of variable cover was evaluated through a series of laboratory experiments at the University of Miami SUrge STructure Atmosphere INteraction (SUSTAIN) Facility, a wind/wave tank with hurricane capabilities. A scaled coral reef model was tested under the direct impact of swell and hurricane generated waves considering Froude similarity with a prototype reef in South Florida.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12954</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.structures.98</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; structures.98</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12954/12227</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Mohammad Ghiasian, Peisen Tan, Joseph Unsworth, Andrew Baker, Diego Lirman, Brian Haus, Landolf Rhode-Barbarigos</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
