<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14080</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">HOLISTIC COASTAL RESILIENCY IN THE GALVESTON BAY AREA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Maglio, Coraggio</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Figlus, Jens</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Williams, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Houston-Galveston area is conceptualizing some of the largest flood defense systems on the planet. The Coastal Texas Study and the Harris County Flood Control District’s proposed tunneling program are both estimated to be in the +$30 billion, first cost, range. Solutions of this large a scale are desperately needed, and we are at the point where we have the political resolve and now need to obtain the financial investment to construct “Texas sized” coastal resilience solutions prior to another devastating event. Advancing the science and keeping these needed projects in the forefront is critical to implementing these projects and protecting those that have less resources and typically live in more vulnerable areas, while also preserving the environment for future generations. In our view, coastal flood risk reduction and equity across resiliency efforts are inherently tied to improved sediment management and other practices plus innovations that can adapt to changing climate threats. Here, we explore a focused series of demonstration projects combined with technical research and development to grow scientific knowledge, awareness, community support, and lower coastal risk by aiding the implementation of billions of dollars in investment already studied and recommended for design and construction. Below is a subset of the existing or ongoing Coastal Storm Surge and Resiliency Studies in the region.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14080</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.15</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.15</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14080/13352</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Coraggio Maglio, Jens Figlus, Tony Williams</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
