<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8274</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-22T13:59:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A CASE-STUDY OF RUBBLE-MOUND BREAKWATERS STABILITY  AGAINST MAKRAN SUBDUCTION ZONE TSUNAMIS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Banijamali, Babak</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Alviri, Amirhamed</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rastgoftar, Ehsan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Soltanpour, Mohsen</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Makran Subduction Zone</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Tsunami</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Rubble-Mound Breakwater</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A case-study pertaining to a number of existing breakwaters located on northern coastlines of the Gulf of Oman, directly facing the Makran Subduction Zone (MSZ) sets the context in order to elucidate the adopted methodologies for both Probabilistic Tsunamis Hazard Analysis (PTHA) as well as investigating breakwater stability in the event of a major tsunami. MSZ stretches from west to east for over 900 (km), affecting the coastlines of Iran, Pakistan, India, Oman and UAE as a potential source of tsunami hazard. According to historical data, the last reported MSZ generated tsunami which was triggered by the 1945CE earthquake of 8.1 (Mw) magnitude caused  human fatality figures of up to almost 4,000, in addition to major structural devastation in its wake. Of particular interest, is the fate of existing breakwaters along the northern shorelines of the Gulf of Oman whose design criteria did not initially incorporate tsunami-related considerations, providing impetus for the modeling, design &amp; analysis efforts presented in this article to serve the two-fold objective of assessing the need for strengthening existing structures, which are virtually all of the rubble-mound type, as well as deriving suitable design criteria for new breakwaters in the MSZ related tsunami affected region of Iran, earmarked for significant new developments.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8274</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v35.structures.44</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 35 (2016): Proceedings of 35th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Antalya, Turkey, 2016; structures.44</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8274/pdf</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
