<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10388</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-03T02:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SPECTRAL ANALYSIS OF STORM-INDUCED WAVES BY CYCLONE ASHOBAA IN ARABIAN SEA AND GULF OF OMAN</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ranji, Zahra</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Soltanpour, Mohsen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shibayama, Tomoya</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Extensive field measurements along the north coast of the Gulf of Oman are analyzed to study the spectral characteristics of the generated waves of Ashobaa along the path of cyclone. The data showed a maximum significant wave height of about 3.2 meters on Iranian coasts. MLMST algorithm was used to process the directional wave. The measured wave spectra were bimodal (or trimodal) when the cyclone was far from the measuring stations. Approaching closer to the stations, the waves turned to unimodal spectra, with the highest measured wave energies at the time of minimum distance between the cyclone eye and the stations. Wave spectrum became bimodal again at the time of landfall, including the local seas and swell waves of the cyclone. After dissipation of the cyclone, swell waves dominate resulting in unimodal wave spectra. Study of 2D wave spectra reveals that minimum values of directional spreading correspond to peak frequencies.Recorded Presentation from the vICCE (YouTube Link): https://youtu.be/k9Bs4TebgdE</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10388</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36v.papers.6</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36v (2020): Proceedings of virtual Conference on Coastal Engineering, 2020; papers.6</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/10388/9674</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 Zahra Ranji, Mohsen Soltanpour, Tomoya Shibayama</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
