<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8384</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-23T01:34:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Swash</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">VALIDATION OF INTEGRATED COASTAL PROCESS MODEL FOR SIMULATING WAVE-CURRENT-VEGETATION INTERACTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ding, Yan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rosati, Julie D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Vegetation plays an important role in reducing wetland and coastal erosion. It is well-known that vegetation in coastal regions acts as a buffer to reduce wave impact and wave setup, as waves are deformed and energy of waves is attenuated through vegetation zones. Modeling wave deformation and transformation through vegetation zones can quantify wave attenuation effects as a function of vegetation properties, improve our understanding of physical processes, and eventually provide an effective assessment tool for management, control, and design of vegetation zones and wetlands. Wave attenuation effects have been studied for several decades. In addition to physical modeling and field observation, two types of mathematical approaches for modeling effects of vegetation on waves can be identified, i.e., phase resolving wave model and phase-averaged wave model. The former directly simulates dynamic wave shape deformations through a vegetation field by solving the time-dependent fluid flow governing equations. The latter directly computes wave spectral variations in space and time by using a time-averaged wave energy equation. Although a phase-resolving model can give detailed wave phase information as waves propagate through vegetation zones, it needs extensive computing efforts to solve dynamic fluid flow problems.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8384</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36.currents.73</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36 (2018): Proceedings of 36th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Baltimore, Maryland, 2018; currents.73</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8384/7192</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
