<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5428</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T12:24:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BEACH MAINTENANCE STRATEGIES, A COMPARISON FOR A RECREATIONAL BEACH</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pluijm, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kant, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nolten, R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">de Looff, A.P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beach maintenance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">recreational beach</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper describes the morphological and economical evaluation ofthe beach nourishment maintenance strategy of an eroding recreational beach at the Dutch coast. In addition to the results of this evaluation two alternative strategies were analysed. In order to assess the economical feasibility of the alternatives appeared to be essential to estimate the morphological effectiveness of the alternative strategies. Therefore, an extensive numerical modelling scheme was set up. The numerical modelling played a key role in the understanding of the existing morphological system and subsequently in the assessment of the effectiveness of the alternatives on a long term basis. The morphological effectiveness of the alternatives, being offshore breakwaters and a 450 m long groin, was calculated in terms of reduction of required beach nourishments. The objective of the study was not only to find an optimal coastal morphology strategy but also to find the best strategy which combines a sound beach protection with effects valuable for the specific recreational function of the beach, including an effective way to deal with eventual lee-side erosion. Possibilities were studied to shift the erosion to the dune area in the north which would allow a more flexible and dynamic way of maintenance.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1996-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5428</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v25.%p</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 25 (1996): Proceedings of 25th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Orlando, Florida, 1996.</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/5428/5104</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
