<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8598</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-23T01:34:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">NORTH BRETON ISLAND RESTORATION, DESIGNING TO INCREASE A BARRIER ISLAND'S HABITAT AND LONGEVITY</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Utku, Murat</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Emmanuel, Gary B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Poff, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The product and purpose of a well-planned program of investigation and design will be realized later this year when restoration construction begins on North Breton Island. North Breton Island is the southern-most of a chain of barrier islands forming the Chandeleur Islands. The barrier island formation lies within the Mississippi River delta plain system approximately 62 miles southeast from the metropolitan city of New Orleans, LA. Under the authority of the Natural Resource Damage Assessment (NRDA) process, NRDA Trustees selected enhancement of North Breton Island as part of the 2014 Deepwater Horizon NRDA Phase III Early Restoration Plan to help restore injuries to natural resources (Trustees, 2014). The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) is the lead implementing agency for this Project. The Project includes restoring the barrier shoreline along the entire length of North Breton Island through beach, dune, and marsh fill placement utilizing an offshore sand source in the Borrow Area located approximately 3.3 nautical miles (NM) east of the Restoration Area in the Gulf of Mexico.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8598</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36.risk.4</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36 (2018): Proceedings of 36th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Baltimore, Maryland, 2018; risk.4</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8598/7402</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8598/8001</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
