<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12881</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:14:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EROSION MITIGATION DESIGN IN THE ARCTIC CONSIDERING CLIMATE CHANGE IMPACTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Scott, Fred</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Duckett, Fiona</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Arenson, Lukas</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Klengenberg, Charles</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elias, Erwin</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Hamlet of Tuktoyaktuk is a low-lying peninsula in the Arctic on the Beaufort Sea that is vulnerable to coastal erosion and intermittent flooding. Most residences and buildings located near the coast have been relocated; those remaining are currently at risk of damage or destruction during storm events. In the longer term, cultural sites such as the graveyard are also at risk. Nearby Tuktoyaktuk Island, a beach/bluff system which shelters Tuktoyaktuk Harbour from waves, is eroding and if not protected may be gone by 2050. Baird was retained by the Hamlet of Tuktoyaktuk and Inuvialuit Regional Corporation (IRC) to assess erosion mitigation alternatives and select/implement a preferred design to protect the Hamlet and Island, which comprise a total shoreline length of approximately 2 km. Baird developed three design alternatives for shoreline protection, including articulated concrete block mattress (ACBM), concrete slab, and quarried armour stone revetments. The selected design is comprised of a quarried armour stone revetment along the entirety of the exposed shoreline of Tuktoyaktuk Island and the majority of the Tuktoyaktuk Hamlet shoreline.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12881</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.structures.25</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; structures.25</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12881/12154</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Fred Scott, Fiona Duckett, Lukas Arenson, Charles Klengenberg, Erwin Elias</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
