<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8369</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-23T01:34:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Papers</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DEFORMATION OF COASTAL PROFILE DURING DIFFERENT STORM PHASES</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Korzinin, Dmitry</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shtremel, Margarita</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The aim of the work is to describe the mechanisms controlling the sediment transportation at different stages of the storm cycle including three main phases, namely development, stabilization and attenuation. The resulting morphological effect of the considered storm depends presumably not only on its strength, but also on the relative duration of the destructive and recovery phases. Two full-scale experiments conducted on the Bulgarian coast in 2016 and 2018 provided materials on the shore profile dynamics under conditions of storm waves. It proved that the profile deformations usually considered to be seasonal may happen in the course of a single extreme event of once a year frequency. Field experiment data analysis proved the concept that long mild waves move sediments onshore (cause accumulative profile) and short steep waves create erosional profile with sandbar. In studied case waves steeper than 0.02 create sandbars and milder than 0.02 - transport sandbars onshore. It was observed that in some cases accumulative phase corresponds to decrease of the peak period while mean period stays unchanged, which indicates narrowing of the wave spectrum.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8369</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36.papers.43</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36 (2018): Proceedings of 36th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Baltimore, Maryland, 2018; papers.43</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8369/7177</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
