<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8824</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-06-23T01:34:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Waves</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ANALYSIS OF HIGH FREQUENCY BREAKING WAVES AND LOW FREQUENCY SURGES GENERATED IN HARBORS DUE TO PASSAGE OF DEEP-DRAFT TANKERS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Agarwal, Arpit</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fenical, Scott</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McElhinney, Kirsten</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Carangelo, Paul</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Krams, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Cline's Point Marina, located in Port Aransas, TX, has been experiencing detrimental conditions near the marina's entrance and within the marina itself during the passage of deep-draft ship traffic. The wave activity is primarily generated by pressure field effects from large, laden outbound vessels in Corpus Christi Ship Channel (CCSC). The basin was originally protected by an approximately 180 ft. long breakwater constructed in 1976 on the west side of the entrance which by 1980 has deteriorated and partially failed to 120 ft. long breakwater and continued deteriorating over time, reaching its approximate 60 ft. long current condition by 2003. The deterioration of this breakwater has reportedly resulted in enhanced penetration of deep-draft vessel wave activity into the marina (Figure 1). Mott MacDonald (MM) evaluated the mechanisms by which waves are generated in the navigation channel, transform, and enter the harbor, quantified the level of protection afforded by past and present entrance breakwater configuration(s), and developed conceptual alternatives for improving conditions inside the marina.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8824</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v36.waves.27</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 36 (2018): Proceedings of 36th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Baltimore, Maryland, 2018; waves.27</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8824/7624</dc:relation>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/8824/8163</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Coastal Engineering Proceedings</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
