<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14482</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T07:30:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">INTEGRATED FRAMEWORK FOR COASTAL ZONE HEALTH INDEX AND VULNERABILITY ASSESSMENT</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cabrera, Jonathan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lee, Han Soo</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jeong, Jae-Soon</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aljber, Morhaf</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The coastal zone is the environment that connects terrestrial and marine environments. (Cabrera and Lee, 2022). It has been estimated that 23percent of the world's population lives within 100 km of the coastal regions (Small and Nicholls, 2003). Coastal zones offer a variety of significant ecological, social, and economic benefits. It is a dynamic and diverse environment. It supports various human activities, such as fishing, tourism, and transportation, and is home to a wide range of plant and animal species. However, there are several issues that coastal areas must contend with, such as pollution, climate change, and overdevelopment. The health and integrity of coastal ecosystems, as well as the communities and industries that depend on them, could be seriously harmed by these threats. It is crucial to routinely evaluate the health and well-being of these environments to address these issues and guarantee the long-term viability of coastal zones. The goal of this study is to identify any issues or problems that may be affecting the health and integrity of the coastal zone environment.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14482</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.management.163</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; management.163</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14482/13754</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Jonathan Cabrera, Han Soo Lee, Jae-Soon Jeong, Morhaf Aljber</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
