<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/12959</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-09-01T15:14:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A PATH TOWARDS HOLISTIC COASTAL ZONE MANAGEMENT IN TEXAS LEVERAGING SIGNIFICANT INVESTMENTS IN DATA COLLECTION, PLANNING, AND IMPLEMENTATION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Maglio, Coraggio</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Green, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Frenzel, Kevin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Williams, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kartman, Carla</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brooks, Kelly</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McCutcheon, Melissa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oyer, Joshua</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Payne,  Tyler</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Burkes-Copes, Kelly</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kerr, Patrick Corbitt</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Das, Himangshu</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thies, Jason</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mallindine, Jessica</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Figlus, Jens</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Goff, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Gulf of Mexico shorelines of Texas are in a largely regressive state due to an amalgamation of factors including but not limited to: sea level rise, subsidence, littoral drift, and riverine supply disruptions. In some areas the erosion rate is several meters annually, leading to significant loss of coastal barrier island area. The bulk of the coastal barrier systems in Texas is undeveloped. However, barrier island loss is no longer able to go unnoticed as there is ever-growing recognition of their intrinsic value to coastal habitat and economies and their role in coastal storm resilience. Projects with significant merit and sediment needs are being identified for funding, which could result in a firstcome- first-serve extraction of the easily available and less costly sediment resources. Without proper management, the complexity and cost of future projects will naturally escalate, leading to a reduction in investments due to lower returns. The following questions need to be addressed: how can lower returns be avoided to incentivize investment and maximize coastal restoration efforts in Texas? And what can be done to galvanize support for beneficial use (BU) placement of beach-quality dredge material to minimize its removal from the littoral system? What can be done now to inform and leverage the existing and future knowledge so that management decisions lead to better outcomes for the environment and Texas constituents? A well thought out and executed plan maximizing returns and coastal resilience will enable other regions to more easily replicate the success.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-09-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12959</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v37.management.1</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 37 (2022): Proceedings of 37th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Sydney, Australia, 2022; management.1</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/12959/12232</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Coraggio Maglio, David Green, Kevin Frenzel, Tony Williams, Carla Kartman, Kelly Brooks, Melissa McCutcheon, Joshua Oyer,  Tyler Payne, Kelly Burkes-Copes, Patrick Corbitt Kerr, Himangshu Das, Jason Thies, Jessica Mallindine, Jens Figlus, John Goff</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
