<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14068</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Structures</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EXPERIMENTAL STUDY OF THE EFFECT OF VEGETATION ON WAVE OVERTOPPING UNDER STRONG WINDS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aoki, Yudai</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sasaki, Kosuke</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nakamura, Ryota</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ishibashi, Kunihiko</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Yamamoto, Katsuhiro</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Coastal structures at ports and coastlines in Japan are usually built with concrete. These grey infrastructures can increase the concentrations of greenhouse gases and lead to the global warming. In recent years, a changing climate as a result of global warming potentially leads to unexpected coastal hazards. For example, on 9th September 2019, one of the most severe typhoon Faxai made landfall in Japan's Kanto region, causing widespread and severe damage. On Fukuura coast located on the western side of Tokyo Bay, the typhoon Faxai caused the collapse of seawalls due to high waves and flooding to the hinter- land due to overtopping waves. Therefore, in recent years, new disaster management measures in coastal areas have been required in addition to grey infrastructure, and green infrastructure become alternatives. For instance, mangroves have the potential to attenuate wave intensity due to their shape characteristics (Quartel et al., 2007). In addition, Dong et al. (2020) show the effect of placing veg- etation in front of seawalls in an experiment under wind- less conditions. Their result shows higher vegetation density could lead to lower the wave overtopping discharge. However, there are few studies that have examined the effects of vegetation on wave overtopping during storms (Vuik et al., 2016). Therefore, in this study, we focused on studying wave overtopping under strong winds against vertical seawalls, investigated the effects of vegetation on wave overtopping rate, and verified the effectiveness of green infrastructure.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14068</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.structures.12</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; structures.12</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14068/13340</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Yudai Aoki, Kosuke Sasaki, Ryota Nakamura, Kunihiko Ishibashi, Katsuhiro Yamamoto</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
