<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14122</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T06:12:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Sediment</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MECHANISMS OF SEDIMENT TRANSPORT AND SEAWATER EXCHANGE IN THE KARAVASTA LAGOON, ALBANIA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tsujio, Daiki</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Asano, Koji</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hoxha, Sajmir</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Karavasta Lagoon is located at the coastal extending between Shkumbini and Semani Rivers, in the center part of the Albanian Adriatic coast in Republic of Albania (see Figure 1). The lagoon is one of the Ramsar sites and the largest area (4300 ha) with the largest fishing catch in the country. The environments around the lagoon have been significantly changed after the 1950s due to increased needs for agricultural land. The reclamation network was built with drainage in two large canals: Terbuf and Myzeqe. Moreover, the mining activities upstream of Shkumbini River, deforestation and freshwater extraction in east of the Karavasta etc. could affect the delta environment. The Karavasta has three channels connected with the Godulla Lagoon, the west side of Karavasta. Although the northern channel was directly connected to the Adriatic Sea in the past, the channel was blocked due to sedimentation. The only one channel of Godulla lagoon, which location is changing, is directly connected to the sea. In this situation, local fishermen concerned that the degradation of the lagoon eco-system was causing a decline in fishery resources. The sediment transport in this area is relatively drastic and might affect the seawater exchange to diverse eco- system in the lagoon. This study aims at understanding the mechanisms of sediment transport and seawater exchange in the Karavasta Lagoon to conserve this natural landscape.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14122</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.sediment.15</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; sediment.15</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14122/13394</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Daiki Tsujio, Koji Asano, Sajmir Hoxha</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
