<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3794</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-19T21:43:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:old_proceedings</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">NUMERICAL SIMULATION OF STORM SURGES INDUCED BY TROPICAL STORMS IMPINGING ON THE BANGLADESH COAST</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dube, S.K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sinha, P.C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roy, G.D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">surge</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">numerical simulation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tropical storm</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bangladesh</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the present paper a vertically integrated coastal zone numerical model has been described for the simulation of the surges generated by the tropical storms striking the Bangladesh coast. The model is fully nonlinear and uses a conditionally stable explicit finite- difference scheme for solving the relevant equations of motion. In this model the analysis area extends from 87°E to 93°E along the south coast of Bangladesh and there are three open-sea boundaries situated along 87°E, 93°E and 19°N. The model utilises a curvilinear boundary treatment to represent the coastline and uses a non-uniform off-shore grid spacing adjacent to the coastal boundary. This allows an increased resolution near the Bangladesh coast. Using a forcing wind-stress distribution representative of the 1970 Chittagong cyclone, we compare the model predicted surges with the observed sea-surface elevations along the Bangladesh coast. The predicted peak surge elevation above mean sea level compares well with the observed values at Chittagong port. A comparison of the results has also been made with those obtained from the corresponding model having uniform off-shore grid spacing.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-01-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3794</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v19.13</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 19 (1984): Proceedings of 19th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Houston, Texas, 1984.; 13</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/3794/3477</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
