<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/14517</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-29T10:41:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Waves</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MODELING WIND WAVE DEVELOPMENT BASED ON PHASE-RESOLVING WAVE MODEL AND ITS APPLICATION TO TYPHOON JEBI in 2018</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sato, Shoko</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Miyashita, Takuya</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shimura, Tomoya</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mori, Nobuhito</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lynett, Patrick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The extreme wave hazards caused by typhoons in bays are increasing. An accurate deformation evaluation of typhoon-induced high waves in coastal regions is critical to mitigate disasters. High wave deformation is an intermediate phenomenon rarely modeled by current wave models, the phase-resolving and spectral wave models. This study aims to develop a phase-resolving wave model that considers the development of wind waves in shallow water under strong wind conditions. A wind-wave growth term, which includes the local wave deformation, is introduced into the phase-resolving wave model. XBeach (Roelvink et al.(2009)), an open-source model based on the nonlinear shallow water equation with non-hydrostatic pressure, is used for the numerical calculation. The wind wave growth term is parameterized, and the new momentum expression for wave development is verified through sensitivity experiments. The proposed model simulates the overtopping volume under the calculation condition of typhoon Jebi in 2018.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-05-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14517</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v38.waves.80</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 38 (2024): Proceedings of 38th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Rome, Italy, 2024; waves.80</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/14517/13789</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Shoko Sato, Takuya Miyashita, Tomoya Shimura, Nobuhito Mori, Patrick Lynett</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
