<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7455</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-05-02T05:36:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>icce:Management</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ATTENUATION OF SOLITARY WAVE BY PARAMETERIZED FLEXIBLE MANGROVE MODELS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Strusinska-Correia, Agnieszka</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Husrin, Semeidi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oumeraci, Hocine</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mangroves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parameterization method</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">solitary wave</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wave attenuation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">laboratory experiments</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The systematic laboratory investigation on tsunami attenuation by flexible mangrove models was performed in order to improve the knowledge on tsunami-coastal forest interaction. A sophisticated parameterization method, based on structural and bio-mechanical properties of a mature mangrove (Rhizophora sp.), was developed for the construction of the mangrove models under assumption of stiff and flexible structure. The forest model examined in the laboratory experiments consisted of the selected flexible mangrove models, arranged in different configurations, which was impacted by a tsunami-like solitary wave of varying height, propagating in different water depths. Based on the envelopes of max. wave height and wave forces induced on single tree models, wave evolution modes were determined to identify the source of wave attenuation. The results indicate the dependence of wave transmission on
the observed wave evolution modes and relative forest width: the highest transmission coefficient is attributed to nonbreaking waves (ca. 0.78 and 0.55 for forest width of 0.75 and 3.0 m, respectively), while the lowest transmission coefficient corresponds to wave breaking in front of/in the forest model (ca. 0.5 and 0.3 for forest width of 0.75 and 3.0 m, respectively).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Research Council</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/7455</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.9753/icce.v34.management.13</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Coastal Engineering Proceedings; No. 34 (2014): Proceedings of 34th Conference on Coastal Engineering, Seoul, Korea, 2014; management.13</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2156-1028</dc:source>
	<dc:source>0589-087X</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://icce-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/icce/article/view/7455/pdf_766</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
