<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2573</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-16T21:48:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Artwork of Gamini Ratnavira</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There was almost instant magnetism when first meeting Gamini Ratnavira at the AFA's National Convention in Phoenix, Arizona in August, 1989. Not only was I taken by this man's personality but I thoroughly enjoyed his impressions of the many types of wildlife he had observed throughout the world. Having personally been in Ecuador and in the Panamanian jungles, I could relate so well to Gamini as he discussed the intricate behavioral details of many Central American bird species. From the majestic coloration of the Hawk Eagles to the distinct clapping sound of the mannikins, Gamini's observations were exciting. An added surprise was to find out that this energetic man was also a superb wildlife artist. I was immensely impressed to see how he could put his feelings and detailed observations of many species of birds, mammals, reptiles and amphibians so magnificently onto the canvas.It was at this first meeting with Gamini in Phoenix, that many of us were able to observe first hand his portfolio of Sri Lankan birds. These original paintings included a great variety of native species including the rare and beautiful Emerald-collared Parakeet (Psitaculla calthorpae). The birds in his paintings seemed so active and alive whether they were flying or working on the bark of a tree looking for insects. Although Gamini uses several media in his paintings including oils, most of his recent art work is done with water colors.Born in 1949 in Colombo, Sri Lanka, Gamini Ratnavira was attracted to the world of nature very early in his life. The jungle was just outside his home and he began to appreciate the many animals and plant life he encountered. This interest was to influence the rest of his life.Although not always welcomed in the house by his parents, as a young boy Gamini housed a great variety of wildlife creatures including tortoises, frogs and snakes as well as more commoo pets such as parrots and fish. Gamini developed a lifelong love for these creatures and early in his adult life his house became a nursing home for many exotic animals. These animals were mostly sick or injured and were rehabilitated to the point where they could be released back into the wild. They included Grey Langurs (a member of the primate family), civet cats, mongooses, monitor lizards, pythons and a great variety of other reptiles. Birds were always around and these included cockatoos, lorikeets and other parrots.Gamini's late father, Sardha Ratnavira, encouraged both of his sons in the love of nature and they spent many hours observing the wonderful wildlife in the forests of Sri Lanka. Gamini's father was also in the art field and is famed as the first qualified gemologist in that part of the world. He initiated an interest in shell craft and feather craft and work with sea weed and driftwood as well as many other handicrafts with nature in Sri Lanka.Although Gamini's father wanted Gamini to follow in his footsteps, Gamini chose a different type of artwork in which to excel. As a young boy, Gamini would sketch drawings of flowers and other types of nature. Later in life, these became fully colored and brilliantly blooming flowers. Since his great love was wildlife, it was natural that wildlife subjects would become the center of his artistic talents. Gamini is a self-taught artist who puts his passion for wildlife, the natural environment and his interest in conservation to visual splendor for many people to enjoy.Gamini, having spent many hours in the jungles and forests of Sri Lanka, became very familiar with its many exotic inhabitants. He learned many of their secrets through observation. Nature became his world and it taught him well. His great attention to detail becomes evident as he sketches his subjects. He paints exactly as he sees his subjects living their lives. Much of his artwork depicts the natural interaction that occurs in the wild. He portrays his subjects against their natural background using native species of plants, vines and trees. Through self-training, Gamini has intensified his natural ability to remember exact details and colors with almost photographic accuracy. He has applied this ability to his artwork with superb results.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2573</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 5 (1990): OCT- NOV 1990; 36-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2573/2543</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
