<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3806</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-20T02:33:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Kaka: One of New Zealand's Jewels</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Welch, Jade</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Originating from New Zealand the Kaka is a brush- tongued parrot of great intelligence and interest. To some they may look somewhat odd and out of this world and not be immediately recognized as a parrot. A parrot they are though indeed and like many parrot species they have declined throughout their range. The following is a small article that has been compiled with the assistance of aviculturalist’s and zoo people. Sub-species There are two sub-species of Kaka. Quite simply the two are divided between the North and South Island. The South Island containing the nominate race Nestor m. meridionalis. The North Island sub-species Nestor m. septentrionalis is said to be smaller and not as intensely coloured as the nominate form. They are found in native forests and on islands and at times venture close to suburbia. Current Status There are currently estimated to be between 1,000-5,000 individuals in the wilds of New Zealand. As it stands the Kaka is listed as vulnerable and breeding programs have worked on producing birds in captivity and releasing them into the wild. These have been quite successful with captive bred released Kaka being seen in areas they had disappeared from long ago. These captive bred birds appear to mix in well with wild Kaka and are breeding. Threats Threats come in the form of habitat clearing and predation and competition for food by pest species. These include possums, cats, stoats and more. The advent of pest free fenced off reserves has helped not only the Kaka but also other native species. Diet Wild Kaka consume a diet of seeds, berries, honeydew, nectar, sap, and live food. The foods consumed are seasonal...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-04-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3806</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 44 No. 2 (2017): Number 2; 31-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3806/3781</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
