<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2316</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-08T18:07:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Hispaniolan Amazon</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sjodahl, Steven</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This small parrot, also called the Santo Domingo, or Salle's Amazon, is one of the presently threatened West Indies Amazons. It is quite attractive and well liked as a pet in its native islands, yet little information on this bird is available to us here in the states, even though several people seem to have successfully bred them.The Hispaniolan's native range today is Haiti, the Dominican Republic, Puerto Rico, and possibly Culebra Island; however, the only one of these places where their population seems to be growing is Puerto Rico, where they may now number in the hundreds. The ironic thing is that their introduction there was somewhat accidental. It seems several hundred of these birds were brought over from the Dominican Republic, but were refused entry. The return of the birds may have resulted in legal action, so they were released outside the port of Mayaguez to make shore on their own.In Haiti, because of the destruction of mountain vegetation, they are forced to come down to lower elevations to feed. This gives the illusion of increasing numbers, when the opposite is probably more the truth. Further study is necessary to fully understand their plight.Amazona ventralis is currently proposed for Appendix II, (threatened) of the CITES Convention; however, I must agree with Tony Silva who believes they should be re-classified and placed with the leucocepbala which would automatically make them Appendix I, (endangered). They seem to lack the red breast feathers and purplish cast to the abdomen seen in the Cuban, but in every other respect the resemblance is very keen.In March or April of 1984, I went to visit a friend, Sandy Michaels, and let me tell you that I was shocked by what I saw as I entered her kitchen. On a chair by the dining room table sat Ouisseau (Wee-zoo), one of the most striking Amazons I had ever seen. None of the photos or illustrations I'd been able to find did these little birds any justice at all.One is first taken by the white frontal patch and pinkish horn-colored beak. Then the attention falls on the crown and nape, which have a very defined scalloped appearance ranging from almost black in the front, to a mixture of green and black at the rear. This is accented by a blue irridescence that seems most visible in direct sunlight. The ear coverts are marked with a round, black spot about the size of a nickel, and the eye is surrounded by a white ring as in the Cuban Amazon. The general body color is a rich Amazon green, with the black edging effect going almost to the darker, olive tail. At the ends of the outer flight feathers and tail is the most brilliant shade of blue you can imagine. The other interesting feature of this bird is the reddish area above the vent that extends downward into the outer tail feathers. This is much brighter than I would have thought from the descriptions in Forshaw, and other texts. In fact, it's every bit as bright as that of the pionus parrots.Sandy had received 24 of these Hispaniolans from a breeder in Costa Rica. They were all around two and one-half to three years of age and just coming into maturity. In fact, she told me that Ouisseau had selected a mate, and that they were keeping separate from the rest of the birds and feeding one another. This excited me because it indicated a natural pair bond, which I consider one of the most important aspects of breeding any of the parrots.Ousseau 's mate, Monjoli, was similar to him in almost every respect except that the white frontal area was smaller, and the cheek patch wasn't quite as dark, or circularly defined. The red area above the vent was also dissimilar to the male, but each of the birds I saw that day were equally different, regardless of sex.Needless to say I purchased the two birds, and quickly took them home where I busied myself for the next couple of weeks designing a suitable cage and nestbox for breeding. I also took the birds to my local veterinarian, and even though I was sure that Ouisseau was male, and Monjoli female, I had them surgically sexed. This was more to find out the actual maturity and condition of the two birds, and to be sure that no internal problems existed. I was informed that not only were the birds in good health, but their condition suggested breeding could take place at any time.That was all I needed. A cage 2 ft. square by 4 ft. long was set up with a large hollow log at one end. Half the log is out of the cage and has an inch thick maple door on it. Cedar shavings were placed inside, and a perch put across in front of the entrance hole.The pair was fed a diet of parrot mix (sunflower, safflower, millet, corn, pumpkin seed, melon seed, peanuts, and peppers), mixed fresh fruits (apple, pear, banana, kiwi fruit, melon, grapes, and assorted berries), mixed fresh vegetables (corn, potatoes, turnips, carrots, onions, bean sprouts, and radishes), greens (most endive and parsley), and a generous portion of both Top Choice W/Cheese &amp;amp; Egg soft, and Purina Hi-Pro dry dog foods. They occasionally received cooked meats like chicken (including the bones), and beef. They didn't get all these foods every day, but received a varied diet of different combinations. I also used a water soluble poultry vitamin, Headstart, which I put in all my birds' water to insure daily intake.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2316</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 3 (1985): JUNE-JULY 1985; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2316/2290</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
