<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1173</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AVIAN INTELLIGENCE ... Parrot Behavior and Toys</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Duncan, Bonnie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">fl:.'ditor's Note: We welcome Bonnie Duncan. an avian bebaoiortst. as a columnist in the vaatcbbtrd journal. Duncan's longterm attraction to parrots came in full bloom 10 years ago iohert sbe was given two baby Cockattels to bandfeed. At the present time sbe bas six parrots=tuo Blue and Cold Macaws. a Congo African Crl'.)1, a Solomon Island Edectus and two Cockatiels.Duncan is 1 tee president of the Nortbuest exotic Bird Society; a member of the American Federation of Ariculture (AFA); a rolunteer bird consultant at tbe Wood/mid Park Zoo; a ioiunteer for the Pacific Rim Wildlife A11 Shoui and a speaker at national and local area bird clubs. We knoio ber best from her presentauon and presence at the1996 AFA national coniention ill Concord, California. Those meeting Bonnie Duncan at Ibis convention can well remember berentbusiasrn and insigbtfulness ill both pet and breeder bird bebaiior.As a pet-parrot bebaoiorist during the past fi: e years, Duncan bas combined her understanding, looe and knowledge of parrots untb her training as an information-systems analyst to eualuate and resolve several hundred baby-pan-at situations that included buing, screaming, fearfulness, feather-plucking and more. She was able lo happily reconcile these birds with theirfrantic owners through teaching, demonstrating and encouraging both tbe birds and their owners-all in their own homes and auiary environments.Duncan's goal as a bebainonst is simpl(}---- 10 ba ue parrots and I heir owners team to enjoy each other. She belieoes tbat humans can learn a lot from parrots about kindness, trust and baoing deltgbt in life. Indeed, Duncan, herself, truly delights in life and one can read this in her umtiugs. Duncan is very unique in the behauiorist field and we are happy that she can sham her tnsigbts with cu r readers. DR7JParrots are agile, intelligent, curious and active. We enjoy watching our parrots have so much fun.African Grey, O'Heriry, has high energy several hours a day. He plays vigorously, swinging toy to toy. He jabs, thrusts and parries in "pretend" fighting with some of his toys. He investigates acrylic and nylon jangling toys. In the process of moving around, swinging, climbing, flapping and hanging upside down, he tones his muscles and releases energy. Displacing his natural behaviors of chewing on trees, he chews on wood 2x2s, organic produce, hanging greens, wood toys. He enjoys food toys. He has a music box toy. He talks to his toys about himself. "O'Henry, up please. Hold on. You're just fine hoy. You are so pretty." He tells the Eclectus, "You are such a good hoy, Plato."Eclectus, Plato, plays with medium energy several hours a day. He likes colors, shapes and textures and investigates parts of toys in detail. Plato interacts with complex wood and leather toys in clusters and hanging from acrylic disks. He chews soft wood 2x2s, leather knots toys and small acrylic hohhing toys with moving segments. He hangs on and slowly rotates the high-impact nylon toys he swings upon. He plays with organic produce and enjoys bathing. Plato lives with O'Henry and two macaws. He often says, "I appreciate it," and learns many words from O'He111y.Blue and Gold Macaw, Tukay, plays with toys in clusters. He has clusters of five acrylic toys, three wooden toys, high impact nylon toys, wood 2x4s, leather . knots toys. He says "rnmm" when he eats his organic produce, greens and in-shell pieces of coconut'. He enjoys whole greens and large pieces of produce as well as chopped veggies. Tukay weaves himself among his acrylic toys and sometimes naps with them. He has a large steel bell, an acrylic swing, and a four foot play shelf along the hack of his cage. He enjoys the play shelf, putting smaller toys on it, such as paper rowel rolls and red lava rocks for heak grooming. Tukay has a large water dish and gives himself a mini-bath frequently. Toys help Tukay develop his curiosity, his agility and his relaxed fun. (Tukay was fearful and abused in his past.) He displaces aggression onto a soft folded blanket that he grabs and bites until he releases the urges. He laughs, chortles, and has a few words. He plays with whole greens and has gorgeous plumage. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1173</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 4 (1997): JULY-AUGUST 1997; 13-16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1173/1152</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
