<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3883</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-17T03:14:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Conference speaker, Conference Recap, In Memoriam</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferragamo, Concetta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Kashmir Csaky has a way of mesmerizing an audience with her adventures of how she fell in love with avi-culture (birds). She shared a story about her grandfather who grew up only believing that birds were meant to be eaten or worked until he ended up meeting a conure named, Mickey, with which he fell in love. Mickey became her grandfather’s beloved pet who was so loved that it made an everlasting impression on Kashmir. Birds were part of her entire family. Kashmir’s great aunt in Japan raised budgies and adored and loved them. Her uncle’s best friend raised pigeons, and she had close friends who raised finches. Kashmir re-marked that she has been around people who love and adore birds her entire life starting as a young child. Aviculture became a positive loving constant, always surrounded with joy, love and laughter.  
[. . . ]
 
The AFA annual educational conference and avian expo is where professionalism of every facet of avicul-ture comes together with motivational collaboration. No nonsense drama – this is where aviculturists work together respectfully and professionally – we get things done, all for the sake of keeping birds in our lives. At AFA conferences you never know who you will bump into, literally. This year’s conference brought together world renowned veterinarians, conservationists, behavior consultants, breeders, res-cues, sanctuaries, bird clubs, national bird organizations, artists, food manufacturers, nutritionists, toy manufacturers, cage manufacturers, bird supply companies, free flyers, educators, authors, pet owners, zookeepers, bird show exhibitionists, legislative educators, social media influencers (Robin Shewokis &amp;amp; KeriEllen – Rockstar Rescue Tours), Zeb Ernest (Blue Planet Pets) and Mark Purden (The Avian Exchange), museum exhibitors…literally, all things aviculture. AFA is truly the “go to” for anyone interested in birds.
 
[. . . ]
Dr. Benny John GallawayThirteenth President of the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc., passed away peacefully at his home on November 11, 2025.
Benny Gallaway will be remembered as the funny, kind, and above all, determined man that he was. He took the bull by the horns and made sure the various projects under his supervision in AFA were accom-plished and done so in a professional manner. One notable project he saw as important was to complete the AFA guide of Presidents 1974-2000.
[. . . ]
Sharon Lynn Garsee, 82 passed away on July 24, 2025, in Roseville, CA. Born on March 10,1943, she was part of the first 4 year graduating class of Highlands High School, North Highland, CA where she served as a Majorette with the marching band. Years later in 1979 she partnered with her father to open The Bird Shop, eventually taking full ownership and later passing it on to her daughter in 2013.
 
 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3883</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 52 No. 2 (2025): AFA Watchbird Fall/Winter 2025; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
