<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/864</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:17:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE: ''Patience and the Handfed Male Eclectus''</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Among all the psittacine specieswe have handfed and sold downthrough the years, none is as gratifying tocorrectly raise and wean as the maleeclectus. Ce1tainlywe promote them as a"Cadillac" of the full-sized pet parrots-consideringtheir unsurpassed beauty,their quiet, observant habits, their friendlinessto strangers, and their world-classtalking abilities.Notice I said correctly raised andweaned!For truly this sensitive hookbill genusis a challenge to any handfeeder. Toproduce the optimum pet one must employextra time, understanding, andabove all patience. To make a mistake ortwo with a male (or female) eclectus(unlike with many roly-poly or boisterousparrot species) is to risk creating agrudging battleground between birdand keeper. In some cases, one may aswell pass the parrot on to another handfeederin an attempt to begin anew itssocialization.Our intent is not to sound ominous;we only emphasize that this is by naturean advanced pet species and not one tobe lightly considered or rushed homewith an enthusiastic new owner whohas minimal syringe experience!First a bit of background. FeatheredFriends of Santa Fe has since its foundingspecialized-in male eclectus as pets."Beamer", owner Darlene Vigil's 12-year-old male Red-sided Eclectus, is awell-known fixture in the shop andaround the state. Beamer is an awesomepet. Raised on healthy people food, he ishuge. He talks up a storm but neverscreams. He ignores other parrots, goesto anyone's hand, will not bite, poopsaway from humans--even was cast as anextra in a western movie with MadelineKahn when the second day on the set hebegan repeating, "Action, roll 'em!"To have Beamer around is to selleclectus pets, some years two to oneover greys, amazons or cockatoos. Weprefer Red-sided, slightly calmer in a subjectivepoll, but also sell Vosmari and theoccasional Soloman.Our recommendation to customersto buy a male (despite loving red ourselves!)stems from the professional positionthat grown up imprinted maleeclectus are definitely easier to pair forbreeding with a baby female than theother way around. In this day and agewe encourage new parrot owners not toperfunctorily rule out later purchase of amate for their pet. A well-bonded eclectuspair is an excellent choice to breed ina spare room in the house!Furthermore, female eclectus petsmore often squawk loudly and tend tobond more tightly to a single owner,sometimes to the aggressive exclusionof other birds or humans. (Not to antagonizered eclectus owners, I admithaving raised females that were suchgentle loving talkers that I was sad atheart to see them sold from the shop!)So what is it that makes these furrylooking green psittacines unique tohandfeed and raise? For starters, theydefinitely have an ATTITUDE. Even arecently pulled three-week-old babystill without pinfeathers will guard itsnursery tub with near savage determinationif approached unwarily or is startled.The young pink critter will strikeout and bite with pain-causing strength."Reptilian" is the term I use to describethese chicks which lie coiled likesprings beneath the towel in their tub.We believe this behavior relates directlyto instinctive memories of lifeamongst predators in the wild. Accordingly,we do not encourage rushingyoung eclectus babies into glass aquariumsor lighted surroundings for fear ofquelling such normal behavior. Nevertheless,I have breeder friends who absolutelyrefuse to raise eclectus parrotsbecause of the nasty bites and the attitudeof the youngsters!Patience, we counsel. One has toearn the trust of this species. Hum orwhistle the same way each time you enterthe nursery. Place a gentle hand onthe outside of the tub towel at the backof the baby and talk him out of the darkness.Above all, do not jam the syringe inhis face to feed: it resembles a snake,right? So does your finger.Secondly, eclectus parrots have notthe strongly pronounced bobbing feedingmotion of other psittacines. Gettinga proper load of formula down the gulletof even a willing chick is a bit likefeeding a slug! This takes more time, especiallyfor less-experienced feeders. Ifthe pet's neck is turned or not angledcorrectly, or if the baby is less hungrythan normal, a significant amount of formulacould be "gargled" in the mouthprior to swallowing. A timid male babymay pull back from what it perceives asuncomfortable or over-assertive feedingto leave a formula mess upon youand its feathers. Warm washcloths andpaper towels are a necessity. Take careto guard against aspiration of food intothe lungs.We try to feed quick little squirts withthe syringe in a rhythm the bird will tolerate--never more than he can comfortablyswallow. Each eclectus seems to bea bit different; letting the parrot indicateits own feeding pace can pay off in apositive behavior as the bird matures."I have encountered eclectus babieswho did exhibit a bobbing feeding motionwhen they were extremely hungry," Darlene Vigil explained. "But thiswas normally only one or two bobs,then stop. I have learned to feed in aone, two, three succession of squirts.When our male feeds the female, hebobs to bring up food, then gives it toher without a motion."She added that eclectus are "completelydifferent to feed than most otherparrot species. They are the most difficultif you do not know what you are doing."</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/864</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 1 (1995): JAN-FEB 1995; 44-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/864/846</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
