<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1343</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:24:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bearded Reedling (Natural and Captive)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Flamion, Rosemary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Bearded Reedling Panurus biarmicus was introduced to the American avicultural community about three years ago. I was fortunate to obtain three pairs with two pairs surviving. Since I live near a vast wetlands and in a coastal temperate climate, I felt that Reedlings would adjust easily to an outdoor aviary.Although these small, long-tailed reedbed foragers blend into their native wetlands environment, their tawny and tan tones are striking in an aviary setting. I hear their short wings whirring as they move about in an aviary. Often I hear their metallic contact call "ching", "ching", "ching" sounding like two coins being hit together.Reedlings are excellent aviary and zoological subjects because of their bold nature, inquisitiveness, complex social behavior, unusual feeding habits, and quiet beauty. Yet few zoos have them on display. As of December 1998, only Berlin (1.0), Durham Zoo, PA (1.0), NY Bronx (0.2), Tokyoueno Cl .O) and Zoologischer Garten Koln had specimens. Reedlings are hardy birds and are not usually bothered by humans walking into their aviary. Systematists used to classify them as in the Babbler Family (Timaliidae), then in the Paradoxomithidae, and more recently in Muscicapidae, the current name for the Parrotbill Family, or Panuridae, the Reedling Family. Not only do the monotypic Reedlings have one genus, but they have only one species as well.Although Reedlings are exclusively Palearctic (Europe through Asia) and live in north temperate climates, their numbers have been greatly reduced in severe winters. In an outdoor aviary, setting provisions should be made to keep them above 45F and sheltered from winds above 30 MPH. My Reedlings have endured temperatures as low as freezing where I had to break the ice on their pond, but I wouldn't recommend it. I believe that the upper temperatures should be kept in the 70s and 80s with ventilation in summer, cool areas in the aviary, some direct sunlight but also areas of shade.Reedlings have three different subspecies including the nominate Panurus biarmicus biarmicus, found from East Anglia area of England through most of Europe in wetland patches; Panurus biarmicus occidentalis, found in the Balkan Region of Europe; and Panurus biarmicus russicus, found in southeast Europe, southern USSR, central Asia, and Asia Minor, which has paler plumage than the other two subspecies. Reedlings are permanent residents in most wetlands but may partially migrate to escape harsh weather. They are well known in marshy vegetations, reedbeds, sedge bogs, and freshwater margins and marshes.Reedlings feel at home in my aviary.I planted my aviary with round bladed rushes such as bullrushes (Phragmites), cattail (Typba), umbrella plant (Cyperus alternafolius), miniature papyrus (Cyperus papyrus), low, flat-bladed sedges (Care.x), and grasses such as bamboo, perennial clumping grasses, and others. Some of the plant materials reach the ceiling of the aviary. I pack my aviary with plant materials in spring through summer and reduce the plants during the winter. I have a replacement set of plants if needed.Reedlings drink, bathe, and feed from a concrete pond with four pools and a fountain. They will stand in the uppermost pond, bend their knees to get their chests and wings wet. Then they dry off on a nearby perch by shaking and preening. None of them has drowned in the pools. I add duckweed (Lemna) and other pond plants to the lower pool. They also enjoy scratching in the large metal tray filled with soil.Once they were erroneously called "Bearded Tits," but now Bearded Reedling and Reed Pheasant are the correct common names. Bearded Parrotbill is also used.The French call them mesange a moustaches (meaning tit with a moustache); in Italian, they are called basettino; Spanish bigotudo, German bartrneise; Dutch Baardmannetje (meaning bearded male); Norwegian Slejeggmeis, Swedish Seaggmes, Danish Skaegmejse, Finnish Viiksitimali; Dutch Baardmees, and Japanese Hige-gara. Why is it important to learn these common names? Since Reedlings inhabit the areas of the aforementioned languages, scientific studies and ornithological observations in their native lands are important to research.Bearded Reedlings are about 6 1/2 inches (16.Scm) long including the 3'' inch tail. Although their adult weight is about 17g, they appear much larger 5 than they weigh. They have short E wings necessary for flight in a bed of ~ vertical plant materials. They have rel- ~ atively long black wading legs, and ~ large feet for holding onto reeds in a ~0breeze. They have three long toes for- ifward and one long toe back. Their black nails are relatively long in orderto hold on to plant material. They can use their foot to scratch their head but would prefer their mate to preen them.I have also seen them intentionally stand on a dandelion seed head in order to keep it from moving.At first fledge, I banded with ''.]" bands but feel that these are too large. "E" bands would probably be better. Reedling chicks are not bothered by closed bands, family bands, or the handing process.The eyes of Reedlings are yellow in adulthood with a black iris but totally black as youngsters. They are close-set for greater binocular vision and depth perception. To increase their field of vision when hunting for flying insects, they hold onto the aviary wire or avertical plant and rotate their head in circles. If they should "lock on" to a flying insect, they can accurately judge its distance. They quickly chase and devour it. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1343</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 4 (1999): JULY-AUG 1999; 17-22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1343/1321</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
