<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3056</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-17T17:41:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A.F.A. Visits, Bernard Roer</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">BERNARD ROER'S BIRD FARMTo many longtime aviculturists, Bernard Roer needs no introduction. The diversity and size of his collection, coupled with his marvelous breeding success has earned him an international reputation of excellence. Bernard's collection is unquestionably the most comprehensive of any in private hands in North America and would rival any zoo, surpassing most in breeding accomplishment.Featuring Psittacines, Finches, Softbills, Doves, Pheasants, Waterfowl, Currasows, Spurfowl, and Cranes, the history of the collection extends back to 1926, when Bernard was ten years old.Born in western Kansas, Bernard's family brought him to Arizona at the age of one. The Roers settled in Phoenix, Arizona, then a small western town, where they took up farming. Bernard grew up in the great outdoors with a special feeling for the soil and the pastoral lifestyle. He attended St. Mary's Catholic Elementary and High School.As a young lad, Bernard assisted his folks with chores after school. His interest and eagerness earned him the responsibility of caring for the chickens at age ten. That same year he acquired his first exotic - a Peacock. Later came some pigeons, which he bred; thus was planted that avicultural seed, which would grow so well in the years to come.In 1941 Bernard acquired three acres in what was then the country on 27th Avenue, west of Phoenix. His original plan called for the establishment of a commercial poultry ranch, which he hoped to vary with a few ducks and Guinea Fowl. At that time he was also dabbling with Budgies. Soon he came to the realization that chickens were not as economically attractive as Budgies, nor as much fun.Like so many aviculturists, Bernard decided his avocation would become his vocation. Beginning with his Budgies, he expanded breeding operations into Doves, his once and favorite birds. The first were a pair of Greenwings obtained from J .W. Steinbeck in 1935. Since Mr. Steinbeck resided in Concord, California, near San Francisco, the birds had to be shipped. In those days shipping was done by rail and the freight cost Bernard a mere $J.50.The Roer collection of Doves today boasts of Nicobar, Zebra, Ruddy Ground,Inca, Peruvian, Ground, Mourning, Bartailed Cuckoo, Crested, Tambourine, Violet, Mountain Witch, Luzon Bleeding Heart, Cape, Diamond, Dwarf Turtle, African Turtle, Senegal, Band-tailed Pigeons, and Gourra Crowned Pigeons.Doves, of course, do not occupy all of Bernard's interest. His first fancy with Budgies has expanded into many other Psittacine species. His favorites are the Amazons, of which he has many varieties including the rare Vinaceous and Caiman Island species, the former being on the endangered species list.Numerous representatives of the Cockatoos and Macaws are also in abundance at the Roer Bird Farm. These include the Leadbeater, Rose-breasted, Sulphur Crested, Citron Crested Cockatoos; Scarlet, Blue &amp;amp; Gold, and Military Macaws - all of which have been bred at various times over the years. Many of the young have been hand fed with a formula Bernard obtained from K.C. Lint, Curator Emeritus of the San Diego Zoo (see Watchbird, Oct. 76 for formula). </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3056</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 3 (1977): JUNE-JULY 1977; 30-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3056/3040</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
