<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1491</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:51:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Happy Greys are Here Again (African Grey Parrots Psittacus erithacus erithacus at Disney's Animal Kingdom)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bockheim, Greg</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionIn April 1998 Disney's Animal Kingdom (OAK) received two previously unpaired African Grey Parrots from a Colorado based foundation dedicated to accepting or rescuing unwanted pet birds. Both Greys, a male and female, had their original USDA quarantine bands and were therefore known to be wild caught specimens. The records available revealed that the birds were not strangers to captive life, the male being a pet bird for approximately 19 years and the female for nine years. The birds have contrasting personalities, the female heing very skittish, growling when approached by humans, while the male is not shy andwas stick trained easily. Both birds often carried on with the familiar repertoire of wolf whistles, cat meows, and assorted calls that most pet Greys seem to quickly learn and mimic. Both birds arrived with clipped flight feathers and were quick to become friends with each other when placed in adjoining cages during their quarantine period.Subtle variations in color make this Grey subspecies easily sexed visually, the male having more evenly dark charcoal gray coloration from his wing coverts to his primary flight feathers and from chest to vent, while the female has more defined contrast in color from light gray to charcoal gray in the same areas as well as the gray scalloping coloration of the chest continuing through the red feathers surrounding the vent (the male has solid red feathers surrounding his vent). A slight size difference also exists between the pair with the male' weighing 480g and the female 430g. The Greys were brought to the Africanaviary for introduction following the required quarantine period and medical examination in which fecal samples are taken and blood chemistries performed.The HabitatTI1e African Aviary at DAK covers an area 162 feet Jong by 62 feet wide and 45 feet high. The aviary space is approximately 450,000 cubic feet and includes mature trees that create a nearly unbroken canopy overhead. A two story waterfall pours into pools at two different levels intentionally flooding areas which become "tidal zones." A path meanders through the center of the aviary allowing guests a close encounter with 23 avian species--over 140 individual specimens.Inlune of 1998 we were prepared to introduce the Greys to their enormous new home. Since neither bird had regrown its primary flight feathers, and therefore was incapable of comfortably and confidently reaching feeding areas, nor capable of retreating from curious and not always friendly aviary inhabitants, a unique process of introduction would have to he employed. We decided to place the birds in one of the mature trees in the aviary so that they had the opportunity to become accustomed to guests and other aviary inhabitants while remaining under the watchful eye of the aviary staff. We soon found that the Greys had other plans. We hoped that the pair might remain within arms reach or within a close proximity so that they could he easily retrieved with a stick, hut they traveled on foot, climbing through the tops of the trees with no intentions of coming aviary for introduction following the required quarantine period and medical examination in which fecal samples are taken and blood chemistries performed.The HabitatTI1e African Aviary at DAK covers an area 162 feet Jong by 62 feet wide and 45 feet high. The aviary space is approximately 450,000 cubic feet and includes mature trees that create a nearly unbroken canopy overhead. A two story waterfall pours into pools at two different levels intentionally flooding areas which become "tidal zones." A path meanders through the center of the aviary allowing guests a close encounter with 23 avian species--over 140 individual specimens.Inlune of 1998 we were prepared to introduce the Greys to their enormous new home. Since neither bird had regrown its primary flight feathers, and therefore was incapable of comfortably and confidently reaching feeding areas, nor capable of retreating from curious and not always friendly aviary inhabitants, a unique process of introduction would have to he employed. We decided to place the birds in one of the mature trees in the aviary so that they had the opportunity to become accustomed to guests and other aviary inhabitants while remaining under the watchful eye of the aviary staff. We soon found that the Greys had other plans. We hoped that the pair might remain within arms reach or within a close proximity so that they could he easily retrieved with a stick, hut they traveled on foot, climbing through the tops of the trees with no intentions of coming down when called. By the end of their first week the pair was roosting overnight in the top of their favorite tree and climbed through the mid and upper canopies to reach feeding stations located in the aviary introduction cages.Meeting the NeighborsThe OAK African Aviary is home to a wide range of birds and, being clever, intelligent, and curious, the Greys were likely to cross paths with a variety of avian species. The other aviary inhabitants include aquatic birds such as African Jacanas Actopbilornis africanus, Pygmy Geese Neuapus auritus; Whitebacked Ducks Tbalassornis leuconotus, and Hottentot Teal Anas hottentota. The more arboreal bird species that the Greys may have occasional or frequent contact with include Hadada Ibis Hagedasbia hagedosh breuirostris, Hammerkops Scopus umbretta, Superb Starlings Spree superbus, Gold-breasted Starlings Cosrnopsarus regius, Emerald Starlings Lamprotornis iris, Amethyst Starlings Cinnyricinclus leucogaster, Olive Pigeons Columba arquatrix; Lady Ross's Turacos Musopbaga rossae, Long-tailed Magpie Shrikes Connnella melanoleuca, Carmine Bee-eaters Merops n. nubicus, Snowy-headed Robin Chat Cossypha niueicapilla, White-bellied Go-away Birds Corytbaixoides leucogaster; Blue-naped Mousehirds Colius indicus, Tavera Golden Weavers Ploceus castaneiceps, and Racket-tailed Rollers Coracias spatulata.Once the Greys became familiar with their new home they began to interact unfavorably with several of the other aviary birds. The first of their had habits was to eat from feeding stations that were customarily used by the more shy or delicate birds. Though their wings were clipped, only allowing for short bursts of energy, the Greys frequently lunged at smaller passerines, such as mousebirds, weavers and even bee-eaters. They also took up parttime residence within the feeding zones of many other birds, displacing anyone that approached too closely.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1491</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 1 (2000): Jan-Feb 2000; 34-37</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1491/1468</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
