<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/567</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Vultures: The Finishing Touch on the African Veld</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Polich, Carol</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">''For some five minutes wewatched the cheetah enjoying thefresh, hot meat, before leaving thekill. Ten minutes later it was backwith two other cheetahs. The threeof them had a hearty meal. By thistime, the vultures were circling thescene, waiting their turn and weleft." (Custos, Nov. 1991; vol. 20, 8;pg. 8)Vultures ... YUK! This seems to bethe usual statement attached to theseugly, feathered scavengers. Peoplecontinue on with their game viewingwhen they see these raptors (birds ofprey) sit hunched in lifeless treeswith necks drooped between theirrounded "shoulders:' Against the silhouettedsky, they seem to hover over the African veld waiting fordeath to occur. With keen eyesight,they can find the best, or worst, ofdead carcasses. The carrion, which tous might be the most sickening ofsmells and most vulgar of sights, maycause a vulture to drool and froth atthe beak. Yes, their job may be thepits. They have the ghastly task ofcleaning up the South African veld.But, as in the human world, the Africanwildlife ecosystem also needs itslocal garbage disposal, the vulture.The rest of this natural phenomenonis unraveled in the next scene of thiscycle ....</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/567</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 36-38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/567/550</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
