<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2371</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T14:46:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Photo Contest Winners - 1985</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Black and White Print Category1) Ring-billed Gull in flightG. (Skip)F Madsen,Jr., Woodland Hills, CAHonorable MentionAfrican Crowned CraneLinda Sanders, Baton Rouge, LA CockatooMadelaine G. ConbOJI, Ann Arbor; MIColor Slide Category1) Paradise TanagerDale Thompson, Canyon Country, CA2) Andean FlamingosLine Farr, Philadelphia, PA2) Little Corella Cockatoos 45, 47 days oldUlf Roblin and Monica Rosenlund, Taby, Sweden3) Regent Bowerbird Craig Mole, Vallejo, CA3) Little Corella Cockatoo, new hatch Ulf Roblin and Monica Rosenlund, Taby, SwedenHonorable MentionRap torColleen Summerfield, Monterey Park, CAColor Print Category (adult birds)1) African Crowned CraneLinda K. Sanders, Baton Rouge, LA 2) Half Moon ConureThomas]. Leahy, Chicago, IL3) CassowaryTim Scbexnaydre, Convent, LAHonorable mentionsBlack SwansJulia K. Nagel, Kenner; LA Yellow Naped AmazonLine Farr, Philadelphia, PA Tragopan PheasantDale Thompson, Canyon Country, CACockatooMary Watkins, Cocoa Beach, FL CockatooTim Scbexnaydre, Convent, LA CockatooMaryEllenKolsky, Hallandale, FL Yellow Naped AmazonMichael Thielle, Closter, NJ African Grey parrotPaul J. Spohn, Mayfield Hts, OH Color Print Category (babies, youngsters, adults)1) Kookaburra feeding young Dale Thompson, Canyon Country, CA2) Hyacinth macaw with new hatch lingJohn Hollingshead, Tarzana, CA3) Red fronted macawsCindy Holtingsbead, Tarzana, CAHonorable MentionCockatiel babiesSharon Unterreiner, Abilene, TX  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2371</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 5 (1985): OCT- NOV 1985; 51-56</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2371/2344</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
