<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1205</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Conservation of the Hawazian Avifauna A Program of the Peregrine Fund</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lieberman, Alan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Peregrine Fund (TPF) is a non-profit conservation organization founded in 1970 at Cornell University by Professor of Ornithology Tom J Cade in response to the catastrophic decline of the Peregrine Falcon throughout much of North America. The pioneering efforts to save this species resulted in breakthroughs in the field of endangered species research and restoration. Today, TPF has many programs around the world focusing on preserving and restoring endangered birds, their habitat and improving local peoples' conservation awareness and ability.Our organization employs the interdisciplinary principles of conse1vation biology. We strongly believe in cooperative efforts involving individuals. organizations, corporations and government, a belief that has been the cornerstone of our programs. We are a results oriented organization that works locally, nationally and internationally. Preserving highly visible, pop- ular, far-ranging species such as 'Alala (Corvus baioaiiensis), California Condors ( Gymnogyps californianus) and Harpy Eagles tHarpta batpyia) has many benefits, By focusing on birds and their ecological requirements and providing sufficient protection to sustain viable populations. we are using birds to provide an umbrella of protection for the diversity of life and the entire ecosystem associated with them.Successful conservation programs must he based on good information and experience. Sound scientific research and practical management provide the basis for what we do and the decisions we make. Over 150 scientific articles and hooks have heen produced hy our biologists. TPF is involved in community education through lectures. tours, newsletters, popular publications, and film. We are committed to conservation education because we believe teaching today's children will enhance the conservation awareness of tomorrow's leaders. Our Educational Center in Boise, Idaho, makes it possible for the general pub- lie to learn more about birds, conservation, and The Peregrine Fund. About 30,000 people visited in 1995 and we expect about 50,000 visitors per year from 1996 on.The Hawaiian SituationWith the The Peregrine Fund's long and successful track record restoring mainland species of endangered birds, TPF was contracted by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (F\XIS) [O undertake a similar program in Hawaii. Beginning with the 'Alai a, and expanding [O a current total of eight species programs, TPF's efforts in Hawaii have grown to include managing [WO propagation facilities, a sraff of 11 persons, a capital investment of $2.5 million. and an annual operating budget of SJ million.The phenomena of island extinc[ions, historically repeated as a testimony [O [he expansion of humankind across [he oceans. is nowhere more dramatic than throughout the Hawaiian archipelago. An isolated island chain, the Hawaiian Islands enabled nature to display species evolution and diversity unlike any other landmass on earth. However, today many endemic populations are extinct or rapidly declining. Hawaiian forests have become "the endangered species capital of the U.S" with 70 hird extinctions since the arrival of the Europeans only 200 years ago. This island state is the last stronghold for one-third of America's endangered birds and· plants. Perhaps more alarming is that even populations of the common hi rd .. are disappearing. A concerted effort involving habitat management, conservation education and "hands-on" species restoration to include captive propagation and reintroduction has hegun, hopefully in time to avert an extinction disaster unlike any other in recent history. Beginning in 1993. The Peregrine Fund, in collahoration with the U.S. Department of the Interior and Hawaii's Division of Land and Natural Resources hegan programs for restoration of native Hawaiian hi rd species. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1205</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 5 (1997): SEPT-OCT 1997; 28-32</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1205/1184</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
