<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3849</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-04-14T23:29:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Press Release</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">College Station, Texas- Researchers at the Texas A&amp;amp;M College of Veterinary Medicine &amp;amp; Biomedical Sciences (CVM) has developed a highly effective vaccine against a lethal virus disease of captive parrots. The disease, called Proventricular Dilatation Disease (PDD), results in blindness, heart failure, or intestinal blockage. It is caused by a virus called Avian Bornavirus. Use of disease in captive birds with no obvious adverse effects.The investigators- Drs. Ian Tizard, Jianhua GUo, Susan Payne, adn Samer Hameed- work at the Schubot Exotic Bird Health Center at CVM. The research was supported by the Schubot Center at the college. The center is dedicated to conducting research that will improve the health and quality of life of both captive and wild birds. While currently focusing on diseases of parrots, investigators at the center are also studying diseases of water birds, quail, and cranes."Proventricular Dilatation disease is an especially nasty infection that kills large numbers of captive birds each year." said Dr. Ian Tizard, the project leader. "parrot owners are naturally very distressed when their beloved pet dies in such a manner. The new vaccine is expected to stop the development of this disease and prevent...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-04-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3849</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 42 No. 3 &amp; 4 (2015): Vol 42, No 3 &amp; 4 (2015); 5</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3849/3819</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
