<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3995</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T20:18:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Masters of Wind and Wave</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Darden, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (October/November 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Conservation The osprey stared at the sunfish between his legs. The fish ’s lips were puckered from the hi - tech surgical job of cutting the corners and spreading the lips apart, that it had received from the rehabilitators to entice the finicky bird to indulge. Normally, he would start at the lips and dig in, but ospreys are unique and unpredictable but also routine and process oriented and this raptor recognized that he had not endured the rigor of hunting and fishing to retrieve this meal, so he continued his hunger strike. 99% of the time theywill not eat on their own in captivity. Fortunately, for this osprey and other patients around the world, there was a falconer on campus… The Raptor Center is located in Saint Paul, Minnesota as part of the University of Minnesota, College of Veterinary Medicine and serves Minnesota, Western Wisconsin and Eastern South Dakota. An average of 1000 patients enter annually. Birds that are not releasable must pass a physical and behavioral assessment to determine placement as ambassadors. Only one or two usually qualify based on what is best for thelong-term welfare of the bird. For example, joint injuries can result in arthritis and immobility; not placeable. Blindness in one eye or it needing to be removed, maybe. Formidable and flawless in flight, these globetrotters are ancestors of the wild, not willing to adapt to a confined life in the comfort of humans, so they’re not ideal ambassadors. Due to their gregarious personality and lack of grace on the perch, they often harm themselves by injuring their two wrist bones, located at the very tip of their wings. When under going care they requirea lot of space to prevent this open wound from happening. Ospreys less than one year are more adaptable, less likely to imprint on humans and respond to rehab more positively. In 1974, four baby great-horned owls became the first of many success stories and the catalyst for founding The Raptor Center, when a vet student brought them in to Dr. Gary Duke. He used them to study avian meat eaters and Dr. Patrick Redig, a sophomore vet student who went on to get a PhD in avian physiology and was also an avid falconer, cared for and learned to repair their injuries for release back into the wild. Dr. Redig pioneered the avian orthopedic and anesthetictechniques used today and began using non - releasable birds to educate the public about raptors. Masters of Wind and Wave - the OspreyBy Jennifer Darden Write for Birds Young osprey Thank you to Lori Arent, Assistant Director of The Raptor Center for her time in providing information and photos. Conservation Master of wind and wave, ospreys are members of the hawk family with superior angler skills, scoring a sushi meal seven out of ten times. Ospreys are built for aquatic hunting. Transparent eyelids, resembling a contact lens to protect their eyes underwater, nostrils that close, a black hooked bill and long muscled legs with short heavy thighs. Toes, feet and lower leg arecovered in scales. Ospreys ’ feet are zygodactyls; two sharp talons in front and back, one of which is a reversible outer toe, a feature they share with owls and parrots. Most birds of prey have anisodactyl, with three toes forward and one backwards. Toes have barbed pads with spiky projections called spicules covering them.This creates a sandpaper texture and gives them a Velcro type grip on their slippery prey. Curved black talons, rounded on top and bottom, resemble fish hooks to grasp its food in flight and feeding. Ospreys have a different bone structure and wings that are larger, longer, thinner, have a high arch and contain more feathers than other predatory birds, enabling them to fly in place when fishing. These exclusive physical characteristics power ospreys’ ability to catch and carry fish close to their own weight and to transport large nesting material.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3995</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 4 (2023): Watchbird October/November 2023; 18-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3995/3955</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
