<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2905</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-10T17:00:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">1979 AFA Convention. Hollywood. FI</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Excellence was the by-word of the A.F.A. 's 5th Annual Convention held in Hollywood, Florida August 23rd through 26th.Tomlreland,Chairman of the Convention Committee, displayed his organizational skills in arranging a smooth flowing event that elicited the accolades of the over seven hundred aviculrurisrs in attendance, the largest crowd ever at an A.F.A. Conference.The guest speakers represented a broad spectrum of the best bird people in the U.S. and Europe, who presented well documented reports on developments in breeding techniques, status of endangered species, first captive breedings, advances in avian medicine, and a series of "how to" workshops. There was literally something for everyone and so much for everyone, that it proved to be a truly great learning experience. For list of speakers and topics, please refer to the full page ad on page 23 of this issue of Watchbird. All the lectures have been professionally taped and are availabe for your personal library.Capping the four day event was the Saturday night banquet, featuring an excellent meal, entertainment by Alba Ballard and her trained Moluccan Cockatoo, and presentation of the Avy Awards in recognition of contributions to aviculture. Particularly noteworthy was this year's Presidential Award given by Dr. Richard Baer to the State Co-ordinators in appreciation for their dedicated support of A.F.A. activities, so important to our overall success.The final day's events included tours to Parrot Jungle, an attractive private collection of large Psittachines open to the public. Unusual sights of note include the beautiful tropical botanical gardens, free flying Macaws, and excellent bird show. Other tours to various facilities were also available as part of the convention package.Highlights of the convention were the good fellowship enjoyed by those in presence. Never have so many bird people come together in one place at one time. Large breeders and small, zoo professionals and amateurs, famous and not so famous-all sharing their experiences and enjoying the festive occasrion. Cocktail parties lasred into the morning (it is rumored some people never slept). Energy permeated the air, and people returned home full of inspiration in preparation for the next breeding season.A.F.A. owes irs rhanks to all rhe people who worked so hard in organizing the event, as well as to rhose speakers, who shared their knowledge wirh us e </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2905</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 5 (1979): OCT- NOV 1979; 31-32</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2905/2889</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
