<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1197</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Proposed American Standards for Mutations</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perry, Fred and Lyrae</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The idea for an American Standard for Mutations came about because aviculturists who are interested in raising Psittacula mutations want and need to communicate more effectively with each other. The many problems with identification and naming of mutations can be reduced and someday eliminated by the adoption of a standard for notation and nomenclature.Interest in Indian Ring-necked Parakeet mutations is at an all time high. Enthusiasm with the purchase of a beautiful mutation often gives way to frustration when it comes to locating a suitable mate.The problem isn't a lack of birds, but rather a lack of consistency in nomenclature and understanding of inheritance modes. Different breeders are using various names for the same mutations. Understandably, those new to the mutation field are "put off' by the confusion and contradiction in terms. Many do not understand the inheritance modes and promises are made to buyers that cannot he fulfilled. Some people feel they have been cheated, although in most cases this was unintentional due to lack of knowledge on the part of both buyer and seller. So who would you believe? We desperately need the American Standard for Mutations so anybody and everybody has a standardized reference.An American Standard will help the many new mutation enthusiasts and long-time breeders by providing a concise reference guide. The American Standard is a "work in progress." As long as there are new mutations popping up, the American Standard will continue to grow. The information in the Proposed American Standard is intended as a framework for discussion and hopefully adoption by all interested parties. The Standard can also be adopted/adapted for use by breeders of other bird species that have mutations.While the American Standard for Mutations will provide us all with a common language and written identification of mutation types, it can't offer any guarantees. The phrase "caveat emptor" still applies. Individual aviculturists will have to educate themselves on what the various mutations should look like and make their purchase decisions accordingly.All questions, comments, and suggestions should be directed to Psittacula Sightings in care of the AFA Watchbird magazine.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1197</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 5 (1997): SEPT-OCT 1997; 16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1197/1176</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
