<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3208</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-30T12:46:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Emergence of Mutations</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perry, Lyrae</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Moore, Mark</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Color mutations in birds occur in nature frequently. Many mutations born in the wild don't survive because they are easy for predators to spot, whereas more subtle mutations often survive. In some cases naturally occurring mutations are replacing the wild type, as in the wild Snow Goose. Mutations can either help or hinder a species survival-much depends on timing, location and a host of other factors that would fill volumes!Several decades ago, it was common avicultural practice to euthanize mutation chicks as they were considered inferior. Fortunately the times have changed and aviculture now includes both wild type birds and their genetic mutations in breeding programs around the world.It takes many years and more often decades to establish a mutation in captivity. On paper we can easily predict outcomes and potential numbers of mutations that should show up. Like the weather, forecasts don't always match the reality. This doesn't mean our genetic forecasts are flawed, it just means mother nature has her own timing. There's also a certain amount ofluck, skill and art involved in bird breeding.Genetic forecasts are based on the theoretical 100 chicks produced. If a pair only produces 10 chicks in a year, it's going to take ten years to reach the 100-chick mark. Therefore, over that 10 year period, your original forecast should match the reality ... and most of the time this works out just about right.During the 10 years, you are likely to find the individual clutches of chicks are going to have more males than females, or vice versa. The same will be true for the appearance of mutations. In other words, some years you won't get any mutation chicks and other years all of them may be mutations. But over the 10-year haul, the percentages should work out to what's on paper for the 100 birds.Many birds take two to five years to grow up before they are fertile and produce offspring, and a lot of bad stuff can happen along the way. Young birds are like young kids, they tend to get into trouble, and there are losses. Add to that predators, illness and injuries. Aviculturists spend a lot of time figuring out how to avoid problems and maximize survival. It's a lot of work-usually thankless. But we love our birds and working with them compensates us in ways that are hard to describe to those who are not in aviculture. The avicultural stakes are already high in terms of successful breeding and raising of chicks. Add in the mutation aspect, particularly a beautiful new mutation, and the stakes are multiplied many times over. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3208</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 37 No. 4 (2010): Number 4  2010; 35-38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3208/3192</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
