<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1271</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SOFTBILLS: The White-collared Kingfisher (Halcyon chloris)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vince, Martin</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Ten families make up the order Coraciiformes: most are tropical or sub-tropical birds and all have syndactyl feet, i.e., two of the forward pointing toes are joined for at least half of their length. Motmots, todies, bee eaters, and certain rollers and kingfishers nest in burrows that they usually excavate themselves in earthen banks, and their syndactyl feet are presumably an important adaptation to help in such work. Most of the species in this order are insectivorous or carnivorous, although the Asian hornbills also eat a considerable amount of fruit.The 92 species of kingfishers (family Alcedinidae) are cosmopolitan, except for the polar regions and some particularly remote islands. Only six species are found in the New World, with most living in South East Asia and Indonesia. They vary in size from 4-18 inches (10-45cm) and are thick-set birds with short necks, large heads and long, heavy bills. Some of the Old World species are very beautifully colored, while the New World kingfishers are green, blue, brown or white.Alcedinidae, for avicultural purposes, can be divided into two broad groups: the aquatic kingfishers (subfamilies Alcedininae and Cerylinae) that live primarily on fish and crustaceans; and the forest kingfishers (subfamily Daceloninae) that do not rely on water for their living but instead eat insects, rodents, small birds and reptiles. Generally these forest species nest in pre-existing holes such as tree cavities or earthen burrows, while the aquatic kingfishers tend to excavate their own burrows in earthen banks. Kingfisher eggs are white and almost spherical, and number 2-3 in the tropics and up to 10 at higher latitudes.The White-collared Kingfisher comprises 47 sub-species which can be found over an enormous range, stretching from the Red Sea, eastwards through India, Burma, Thailand, Malaysia and Indonesia, affecting also the Philippines and many islands in the Pacific Ocean. Indeed, 40 of the sub-species can be found only on islands which are mostly very small and remote: Erromanga, Torres, Pavuvu, Nissan, Duff, Malaita, Utupua, Rota, and many more (Howard and Moore 1991). Each island is the home of a unique form of the White-collared Kingfisher which, because of their relatively small and exposed populations, are vulnerable to any environmental change, whether natural or man-made.At Sedgwick County Zoo we have a three-quarter acre tropical jungle exhibit which houses about 200 freeflight birds representing 80 species. Most are hardy softbills ranging from Pekin Robins Leiotbrtx lutea to Imperial Pigeons and starlings. But there are also Amazon parrots, partridges, ducks, crakes and guans that live together in the free-flight environment amongst the tropical vegetation, streams, lake and waterfall. Temperatures in the building vary between 85° F. (29° C.) in the summer and 70° F. (21° C.) in the winter.At the beginning of 1992, we received a six-month old pair of captive bred White-collared Kingfishers. Side-by-side, differences in the sexes can be seen, but they are so slight and variable that surgical or laboratory methods should be used to determine a pair -- these birds had been surgically sexed. Having been quarantined and then "howdied" in an introduction cage, the pair were released into the three-quarter acre exhibit.They were always exceptionally nervous and, even now, remain as far from people as possible. We have never had any problems with aggression of any kind, although a group of six Blue-grey Tanagers that originally lived in the building, would often chase or displace both kingfishers; and they were such a nuisance that we removed them to off-exhibit breeding aviariesThroughout the building there are six food dishes raised six-and-a-half feet (2 m) above the ground on metal poles, as well as dishes on the floor for the ground birds. For the arboreal species, insectivore and frugivore diets are offered in the same dish, but not mixed together. A tiny proprietary pellet called "Tropical Bits" (manufactured by Marion Zoological, P.O. Box 875, Wayzata, MN 55391) provides the essential nutrients for both diets and, because of its size, is eaten by the smallest insectivores and frugivores alike. The insectivorous diet contains chopped hard boiled egg, meal worms, waxworms and large crickets (for recipe see Vince 1994). Most of these foods are eaten by the kingfishers; and pinkie mice and small fish are also mixed in.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1271</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 2 (1998): MAR-APR 1998; 21-22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1271/1250</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
