<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/813</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EDITORIAL PAGE It Seems to Me ...</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Change is ablowin' in the wind.Gone are the old days when exoticbirds could be imported from anywhereand quarantine hadn't beeninvented yet.Nowadays, a few birds are importedfrom a few Third World countries andthey go directly into governmentcontrolledquarantine stations. Thereare permits, vet inspections, healthcertificates, fees and folderol whichare always connected to governmentalenterprises.And what the future holds, whoknows? You can bet, however, thatthere will be more and more regulationsregarding wild birds and themulti-million dollar business ofaviculture.It seems to me that there are at leastthree ways to react. First, you can holeup with your shotgun and blast awayat the authorities until you, yourself,go up in a great puff of smoke (thishappens a lot here in L.A.). This mightbe a more memorable exit than youhave any right to, but, in the long run,you can't win that war.Second, you can scoop seed left andright into the bird cages, eyes glued tothe seed bucket, blithely unaware ofthe real world. Again, you will notprevail. One day you'll look up inamazement at what the new avicultureis like. And you could even wakeup in a jail cell scratching your headover what violation got you there.Third, you can make informed decisionsabout the oncoming rules andregulations and manage your birdkeepingin such a way as to minimizethe effect the new laws have on youroperation. We all do this regarding theuniversally hated - but inevitable -income taxes. We learn the rules. Wehire tax experts. We organize ouraffairs to ensure our maximum benefit(within legal bounds, of course). Ithink we should try this little knownand seldom used method with respectto our aviculture, too.Gentle reader, it pains me to have topoint out that many conservationistsand ecological "Greens" look upon usas the last remnants of Genghis Khan'spillaging hordes. In some quarters,our reputation ain't so hot. If, in theold days, we "took," I believe thatnow we have a chance to "give back."Not that anyone's eff01ts can perfectlyrestore the earth to its pristine condition,but we can do several thingswhich, in my view, will add legitimacy,purpose and responsibility tothe sometimes misunderstood field ofaviculture.• The first thing you can do is checkout the Model Aviculture Program(MAP). This voluntary program hasestablished guidelines for responsiblebird husbandry - recommendationsfor safety zones, accurate recordkeeping and inspections by a veterinarianof your choice, for example -things most responsible aviculturistsdo routinely. This program doesn'trecord how many birds you have orwhat kind. The inspecting vet willrecommend that your facility be approvedor may recommend changesthat will improve the quality of life forthe birds in your charge. I feel that thisis an excellent program and that MAPcertification will become a badge ofhonor to distinguish the professionaland responsible aviculturists from theothers. Send a self-addressed,stamped envelope to MAP, P.O. Box1657, Martinez, CA 94553 for an informationpacket.• The second important thing youcan do is to get involved in the AF AExotic Bird Registry. It is my sincerebelief that gradually increasinggovernmental control will eventuallyrequire all exotic birds be registeredjust as automobiles and dogs are now.Indeed, the Wild Bird ConservationAct of 1992 contains some languagethat may eventually cause everyimported exotic bird to be marked. Nomark, no control. Currently, markingincludes leg bands, microchips, tattoos,etc. Since all of these things canbe moved from bird to bird, they willnot satisfy the demands of the governmentwhen it becomes more seriousabout bird control. I believe that theonly acceptable bird marking for thefuture is DNA "fingerprinting" andthat the marked birds should be registered.There is an article on this subjectin the making.Take heart, though, there are a numberof pluses to having your animalsmarked and registered - especially ifyou do it before the mandate hits. TheState of Arizona, for example, requiresthat all horses have a registration slipsimilar to the one for your car that youcarry in your glove compartment. Ithas cut the horse-stealing (a very bigbusiness here in the West) by 90%.Marking and registering can serve toprotect your valuable birds in a similarmanner. There are many other managementbenefits to having registeredbirds and I believe that the bird fancyneeds to gear up to the idea and getgoing. Information on the AF A ExoticBird Registry is available by calling1-800-BIRDCALL or by writing theAF A Home Office.• A third exciting thing is going on.The AFA has taken the initiative andactually put some scientists in the fieldin the first step of the AF A Recoveryand Management Plan for the RedfrontedMacaw. Actually, the first stepwas taken several years ago when anAFA member put together a computerbasedmodel conservation managementprogram for this CITESAppendix I endangered parrot. Andnow AFA-sponsored scientists are inthe field in Bolivia conducting animportant conservation-oriented studythat, hopefully, will provide a basis formoving this macaw from CITESAppendix I to Appendix II. This Recoveryand Management Plan mayalso serve as a model that can beimplemented in conservation studiesof other birds. There isn't room in thiseditorial to lay out the details of thisprogram but we'll try to get an articlefor an upcoming edition of Watchbird.Well, now you know some of mythoughts on modern aviculture. Twoof the "Opinions" letters expressrelated thoughts. The old ways arefading, new things are comingand I've pointed to three new thingsthat I like. We are very interested inwhat you think. What is your opinion?Send us a letter. •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/813</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 58</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/813/795</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
