<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/537</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS:</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Curator, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Mariana Crow Subcommitteetraveled to the islands of Guam and Rota, Mariana Islands,Micronesia, during the period of April 12 through 22, 1989, toconduct field investigations of the endangered Mariana Crow(Corvus kubaryi). The primary goal of my field trip was todevelop a live-trap method for the crow. Coordinator for theproject, I function in association with the Houston ZoologicalGarden, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS),the Guam Department of Aquatic and Wildlife Resources(GDAWR), and the Commonwealth of the Northern MarianaIslands (CNMI) in a joint effort to one day develop a captivemaintenance and propagation protocol for this bird. Major fundingfor this project has been provided by the AFA with additionalmonies provided by the Louisville Zoo. An American Associationof Zoological Parks and Aquariums (AAZPA) project initiatedby Dr. Robert Beck, GDAWR wildlife biologist, and Mr.Larry Shelton, former Curator of Birds at the Philadelphia Zoo,to save Guam's endangered forest avifauna from extinction bycaptive culture, led to my 1985 field study of the crow on Guamand my subsequent reinitiation in 1986 of a 1984 plan to captivelyculture the crow.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/537</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 49-55</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/537/521</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
