<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3063</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-17T18:44:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Canary Calendar</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nierenberg, Charlotte</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">GIVE YOUR BIRDS A BREAK SEPARATING THE SEXES SORTING AND SELLING HINTS FOR THE NEXT SEASON BREEDINGGIVE YOUR BIRDS A BREAKIf two healthy clutches have been raised by a hen, it is sometimes a temptation to allow a third clutch.Since breeding takes its toll, a third nest should not be permitted unless a previous try resulted in unhatched eggs. Another exception and an excuse for breeding as late as August is the possibility that a hen will show her first real interest in building a nest at that time. This may be due to the fact that she was a "third-round" baby last season and did not reach maturity in the Spring.If the breeder has cool indoor facilities, he may change his schedule to conform to the hen's. However, he must realize that he will cause the same situation next season, both for the hen and any young she might produce. If most of his flock came into condition in the Spring, it seems to be more of a chore than usual to have to prepare egg food for one or two late breeders.When these late breeders are outdoors, it is a heart-rendering sight to see hens and babies gasping for breath in torid temperatures - almost anywhere in our vast country in late summer.Most birds start their moulting process at this time, and those that start on their last clutch may lose their feathers while feeding young. They might try to perform the necessary feeding chores but their strength ebbs during the moult and they may not finish the job.SEPARATING THE SEXESFor those with only indoor facilities, it is best to plan on allowing the hens and babies to fly together in larger community flights. Cocks are more aggressive and argumentative and, until they are in the throes of moulting, can be vicious in their attacks on each other. When breeding chores are over, there are usually individual cages empty for the cocks.If you are planning an outdoor aviary, a well-sheltered structure will house your birds throughout the summer and in milder climates will suffice until the birds are again ready to breed. A hastily built aviary may not shelter the birds against the cold winds, and rain, when winter comes.For canaries, a two-section aviary is a wise decision. When the young birds are housed with the adult hens, as soon as a young cock is heard singing, he may be removed to the boys' quarters. If the male section is ample, the cocks will have enough room to get out of each other's way when they squabble. If separate quarters are not available, a split plastic band may be added to the same. leg that carries the original band for easy identification of the young male.SORTING AND SELLINGBy September, most youngsters and adults will have completed their annual moult. This is the time to select those who show promise as show prospects and others as future breeders.Choose your hens for conformation, stance and past reliability in the breeding room. A less-than-perfect hen can produce beautiful babies if bred carefully to a cock chosen for his fine attributes. She may also be invaluable as a possible foster mother in an emergency.A breeder is expected to retain his best birds and he should. However, a conscientious breeder will produce many "best" birds and these will be appreciated and recognized by other breeders.There are others who will never come up to show standards and yet are healthy, vigorous birds. Mediocre cocks may possess beautiful song tones and give long years of happiness in a pet owner's home. When sorting, do remove the beauties you wish to retain to another area. If left with the birds you offer for sale, the others will suffer by comparison and this is not fair to the birds or the buyer who will invariably want what he cannot have.Do offer a list of "basics" to a pet owner who admits he has not owned a canary since childhood. Offer a small container of the seed your bird has been accustomed to, and, if the buyer lives in a distant area, send a bottle of your water along to be mixed gradually with his own.Above all, deal fairly and honestly with your buyers to protect your reputation and future business. There is a market for any bird at a reduced price as long as the buyer knows what he is getting.HINTS FOR THE NEXT BREEDING SEASON1. Rinse and save egg shells throughout the year. Make your family and non-bird friends feel guilty when they toss egg shells! I have a steady "paper-bag delivery" of egg shells from many people. When enough are accumulated, I boil 'em, dry 'em at "pilot light" warmth in the oven, crush and store them for future use. They can be added to condition food or serves in a small container as an excellent source of minerals.2. Plastic-lined jar tops make excellent egg food containers.3. For a large flock, try a meat or vegetable grinder for hard-boiled eggs. A slice of whole wheat bread can be inserted after the last egg is ground. My recipe for a dry nestling food can be premixed with the ground egg and stored in the freezer in small plastic containers for daily use. (One container is removed from the freezer each night, placed in the refrigerator section and is defrosted the next morning for the day's ervings.) This recipe for a non-soggy mixture is available to all upon request.4. Store containers of seed and gravel in your bird room for easy distribution •  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3063</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 4 (1977): AUG-SEPT 1977; 14-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3063/3047</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
