<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/427</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Shushi' s ·Story ... Don't give up too soon</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Andreoli, Liz</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Life presents us with an endless arrayof threats or challenges dependingupon which way we look at it. At thevery moment I thought I had handfeedingof you ng birds , with all itsdelusions , down pat , disaster struckagain!Shushi (a lutino cockatiel) and hisnest mate hatched on the 13th and11th respectively of November 1987.The hatch was uneventful. The chicksemerged on time and the parents wereknown for taking good care of theiryoung . So I figured I had nothing toworry about. In such cases I do notbother the brood until a few days haveelapsed which gives the young achance to develop some and theparents time to calm down. When I feltcomfortab le enough and decided toinspect the nest I noticed the oldesthatchling had a severe cut across theeyelid exposing the eye prematurely.There was some redness and swelling.This damage at such a young agewould take its toll . I braced myself forthe worst. Apparently the chick cut hiseye while releasing himself from theegg. I administered tetracycline ophthalmicointment for several days. Asconsc ienti o us as these parents werethey obviously could not resist peckingthe strange protrusion at the eye,because blood began to appear. I hadno choice but to pull the ch icks forhand-feeding on November 24th . Theywere ten and twelve days old. At thistime all other va ri ables seemed normal.The chicks were otherwise clear eyed ,seemingly average in size and weight,and they had normal appetites anddroppings.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/427</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 4 (1988): AUG-SEPT 1988; 46-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/427/413</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
