<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/605</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Incubation of Ocellated Turkey Eggs Using the Common Turkey as a Foster Mother (Agriocharis ocellata) (Meleagris gallopavo)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gill, Johanna Motta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionBirds have been playing major rolesin scientific fields such as evolution,biogeography, taxonomy, ecologyand now in conservation. Their studyis giving us insights into the interplaybetween organisms and theirenvironment and is helping us tounderstand the role that they play.However, we actually know very littleabout them in this region, especiallythe tropical species such as theOcellated Turkey, Agriocharis ocellata(Ramos, 1985).Their environment is being destroyedat accelerated rates (Myers1970). Moreover the birds in theseareas are commonly hunted, tradedor trafficked (Nilsson, 1981; Ramos,1982) and their population is decliningat alarming rate (Ramos, 1985).Long term research programs ontropical birds including those alreadyvulnerable or in danger of extinctionis important to make clear that developmentand conservation are notconflicting processes. They actuallygo hand in hand and we should notabuse either one. If deforestationprogresses as fast as it is now, theactual number of species in danger ofextinction would be increasedgreatly (Ramos, 1985).Some groups of birds might disappearfaster than others. Birds that liveunder the forest canopy, are insectivorousor have a territorial socialsystem, may be the first to go. Theyare frequently highly specialized andminor disturbances could have majorimpacts (Ramos, 1985).The future conservation of mostthreatened species will require notonly the preservation and managementof critical habitats but alsoscientifically managed propagation programs.Given the endangered status of theOcellated Turkey (Agriocharis ocellata)and its bleak future in the wild,it is of great importance establishingbreeding programs on behalf of thismagnificent vanishing species.The objectives of this project are:• To favor the incubation of OcellatedTurkey (Agriocharis ocellata)eggs and the survival and developmentof a higher number of chicksusing a Common Turkey (Meleagrisgallopavo) as a foster mother.The broader objectives are:• To favor the introduction of thenew chicks of the Ocellated Turkey(Agriocharis ocellata) into theirnatural habitat.• To learn more about the aspectsof artificial breeding and behavior ofthis species.• To promote general interest inbreeding and conservatiuon of thisendemic species to maintain a viablegenetic pool.Project LocalizationThe aim of this project is to breedOcellated Turkeys (Agriocharis ocellata)in their natural habitat, that iswhy it will be developed in TikalNational Park, located in the state ofPeten, north of Guatemala city (16°55' 07" latitude and 89° 53' 05"longitude).Peten is the bigger state in Guatemala,having an extension of 35,847square kilometers, with less than60% of forest cover and approximately13% of its surface beingsavanna. The annual average temperatureis 26.6°C and the annual rainfallvaries between 1 700 mm and3000mm.Tikal National Park supports a lush,tropical forest characterized by veryseasonal rainfall, with most of theprecipitation falling from June toSeptember. The entire 576 squarekilometers of Tikal is a National Parkof Guatemala, a sanctuary for allplants and wildlife. This protectionhas allowed the Ocellated Turkey tobecome very tame and readilystudied.Here we could find characteristictrees of the tall forest including Ficussp., Swietenia Sp. (Caoba), Brosimumsp. (Ramon) and Achras sp.(Zapote). This type of forest is relativelyunimportant as a feeding areafor the turkeys, but is very importantto the birds as a place of rest andpreening during mid-day. Grassyplots constituted only about three to six percent of the habitat, but is byfar the most important feeding area,as well as the site of most reproductiveactivity. The density and distributionof Ocellated Turkeys in heavilyforested areas such as Tikal may belargely controlled by the distributionand size of grassy areas. However,forests are important for roosting,resting, general maintenance activitiesand nesting. The scarcity of OcellatedTurkeys noted by some observersin heavily cleared areas alsoargues for their need for forests. Thisscarcity in disturbed areas is alsopartly due to hunting pressure fromman which probably not only reducesthe actual density of turkeys,but also makes them more wary andtherefore more difficult to observe.Smithe (1976) reported the turkeysat Tikal to be widespread but notnumerous, and according to Steadman(1979) the density of OcellatedTurkeys in Tikal is about one individualper square kilometer.Bibliographical ReviewThere are two species of turkeys,the Common Turkey (Meleagris gallopavo)and the Ocellated Turkey(Agriocharis ocellata) forming thefamily meleagridae.They are large, powerful birds withstrong legs, spurred in the male, butwith rudimentary webs between thetoes and with non-vaulted tails.The Common Turkey occurs fromeastern United States to Mexico andthe Ocellated Turkey lives in lowlandtropical forests from Peten, Guatemalaand adjacent central and northernBelize, north through theYucatan peninsula of Mexico andwest into the eastern portions ofChiapas and Tabasco. The distributionof the Ocellated Turkey withinthis area is somewhat patchy todaybecause of habitat destruction andhunting pressure (Steadman, Stulland Eaton, 1978). A more ominousthreat to the Ocellated's status is thefear of domestic poultry diseases, towhich they are extremely susceptibleand regularly exposed through frequentcontact with free roaming villageflocks throughout their rangeOennings, 1987). This is a commonsituation in Guatemala.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/605</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 11-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/605/588</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
