<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1057</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-10T22:46:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Gang-Gang Cockatoo in Field and Aviary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hyde, Graeme</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Late last year the Victorian Ornithological Research Group (VORG) published a literature review titled "The Gang-Gang Cockatoo in Field and Aviary." Edited by Lynda E. Chambers on behalf of VORG, a small but active research group based in Melbourne, Victoria, Australia, this new publication has brought together relevant information and data on this most prized of the Australian cockatoos. Published as a soft-cover book which the author believes will " ... be useful to both the ornithologist and the aviculturist as they both have an important role to play in filing the missing details of this species." This statement once again emphasizes and reinforces the relationship that exists between ornithology and aviculture in the State of Victoria (that is another story for another time). Subjects discussed include: History, Description, Voice, Flight, Flock Size, Distribution, Status in the Wild, Relationship with other Cockatoos, Food, Housing in Captivity and Problems that Need Addressing. Most of these subjects, which are amply discussed, would be of interest and benefit to American owners of Gang Gang Cockatoos. The charts, graphs and maps clearly indicate the amount of time devoted to researching the subject, collating the data, and compiling it into a readable format. Although Gang Gang aficionados will be disappointed that no color photos have been included (there are 5 black &amp;amp; white photos) their disappointment should be offset by the amount of data included and, equally as important, the 103 pages of bibliographic listing which include annotations. American aviculturists who have the pleasure of keeping this unique cockatoo would, I helieve, agree that this species requires special treatment to both keep and hreed and, at the same time, keep it in immaculate condition. As wellknown Australian aviculturist (and Gang Gang hreeder) Warwick Remington said in his review (Australian Aviculture, Fehruary 1996), "Much of the information contained in this hook will assist owners of the Gang Gang Cockatoo to provide many of these requirements." Australian aviculturists are ahle to study the Gang Gang Cockatoo in the wild if they so desire. In addition, they have easy access to journals and newsletters of major ornithological and hird-watching organizations including the Royal Australasian Ornithologists Union and the Bird Observers Cluh of Australia which hoth have a fine library of periodicals and hooks. American Gang Gang...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1057</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 4 (1996): JULY-AUGUST 1996; 39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1057/1037</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
