<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/682</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">It's Showtime For Birds!</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wolnik, Ginger</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Is my bird better than your bird?There is only one fair way to answersuch a question: put the birds in similarcages and let an impartial judgedecide! Bird breeders, hobbyists, andpet owners have participated in birdshows for years. Unlike bird fairs andexpos, real shows emphasize judging,not selling. The winners are usuallyexperienced exhibitors, but a novicewith a well cared for pet also has achance. Many shows have specialawards for novices in order to encouragenew people to enter.Bird shows are sponsored by clubs,although not all clubs put on a realshow. The best shows bring in judgesfrom all around the country. Thesemen and women are certified by anational organization specializing in aparticular breed. For example, hookbillstandards are set by the Society ofParrot Breeders and Exhibitors. Someother societies are: National CockatielSociety, American Budgerigar Society,National Colorbred Canary Society,and the National Finch and SoftbillSociety.Many societies have standards forshow cages. The sponsoring clubsusually have members that can lend orsell these cages to novices, or adviseon how to build them. Plain, unmarkedcages are used for largerparrots so as to not distract from thebird or identify its owner.Bird shows are usually held onweekends in the fall. Registration forentries is usually on Friday and earlySaturday morning. The fee is typically$1.50 per bird. A numbered tag isattached to each cage and the showsecretary records the owner for eachnumber. The show catalog lists all thecategories and rules. Copies of thecatalog are available in advance fromthe sponsoring club.Judging is done on Saturday and cantake most of the day. Some showsallow the public to watch the judging.Exhibitors are always allowed towatch, but they must remain quiet andnot let the judge know whose birds he or she is looking at. A good judge willtell the audience what is correct andwhat is a fault. For each category, ribbonsor rosettes are attached to thewinning cages and the cage tag munbersare recorded. An awards banquetis held on Saturday night and theowners of the winners are announced.Trophies and plaques are also givento the winners at the banquet.Most shows are open to the publicon Sunday. The club might hold anauction or raffle to help pay the showexpenses. A sales area may be set upfor the exhibitors to sell birds to thepublic. This provides an opportunityto buy good birds directly from thebreeder. Some shows have a few vendorsthat sell supplies, but most of thefloor space is devoted to exhibitingbirds. Most shows end early Sunday afternoon to allow time for out-oftownparticipants to drive home.If you are interested in exhibiting,get a copy of the show catalog as soonas possible. Better yet, join a showsponsoringclub, attend meetings, andask lots of questions.If you are interested in just attendinga show, contact the sponsoring cluband ask when it will be open to thepublic. The most educational part iswatching the judging, but the mainreason to attend a show is to view thebirds. Where else can you seehundreds of superb specimens oflarge and small parrots, canaries, andfinches in one room! You will findmany breeds and species not commonlyseen in pet shops or zoos. Bestof all, they will all be beautiful,healthy specimens in full feather! •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/682</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/682/665</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
