<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2239</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-02-26T04:56:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The President Reports</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Phillips, Lee</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I am pleased to report to the membership that the fortunes of the American Federation of Aviculture are on the rise. Thanks to the cooperative efforts of officers. committee chairmen and paid staff, A. F.A.'s activities are settling into a solidly-based businesslike operation.A successful and profitable national convention in 1983 helped to ease the financial burden which had become a grave concern. Since then memberships and renewals have risen and there appears to be a steady growth of approximately 200 new members each month. More efficient membership service procedures have been adopted and others are planned in an effort to better serve our members.As the result of refined and more efficient Home Office procedures and the elimination of unprofitable practices, our financial picture is much improved but is still under close scrutiny.Most of our committees are functioning reasonably well - some superblybut we are badly in need of an aggressive, innovative person to chair the Membership Promotion Committee. If you're a self-starter, think about applying for this challenging position. A.F.A.'s future is tied to its growth.A steady trickle of donations has been received for the Avian Research Committee but if a reasonable number of research grants are to be awarded this year, a major source of funding must be found. A creative person is needed to obtain funding for this most important committee which embodies the very purpose of the A.F.A.'s being.Efforts are being made to assure that The A.FA. \Vatchbird will meet its publication dates. A production schedule has been established to aid in monitoring its progress. Additional advertising revenues are being received largely as a result of efforts by our Home Office staff. The high quality of The A.FA. \Vatcbbird continues to be our best promotion tool.Proposed new by-laws were sent out with the May quarterly committee reports and it is hoped that passage of new comprehensive by-laws will take place at the annual meeting in August.A roster of excellent national and international speakers has been arranged for A.F.A.'s 10th annual national convention to be held August 2-5, 1984 at the Hyatt Orlando Hotel near Disneyworld in Orlando, Florida. This promises to be one of our finest conventions and every effort should be made to attend. The veterinary seminar should be attractive to advanced aviculturists as well as to veterinarians.All in all, there appears to be a positive attitude toward the future of A.F.A. and the development of a team spirit so essential to the success of a joint endeavor. It's time for a membership drive by each ofus - if each ofus signed up only one new member each month, our membership lists, our revenues and our "clout" would soar. Let's do it!I'm grateful for the support and cooperation I have had from the members at large and appreciate their concern for the future of A.F.A.If there is a theme to characterize my administration it is "Let's communicate - up and down". I welcome your constructive comments or suggestions for improving A.F.A ..Have you signed up a new member this month?  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2239</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 11 No. 3 (1984): JUNE-JULY 1984; 6-8</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2239/2213</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
