<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1566</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:54:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">This Issue</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This issue is focused on Africa below the Sahara Desert. The region above the Sahara will be treated at a later date.We collected so many excellent articles for this issue that not all of them fit in. Those held out will be published in issues to come.We were able to include an "AFA Visits" to South Africa (Roger Bringas made the recent trip); articles on Cape Parrots; an overview of the African lovebirds; an engaging article on the Lilac-breasted Roller (did you notice the lizard for dinner the cover bird is carrying?); an unusual article on the Bearded Barbet (a bird with a scary beak); "Alex" the brainy and famous Grey Parrot; the Brown-headed Parrot, a little-known species; Lady Ross's Turaco (including one with no tongue); the graceful Cape Dove; the Timneh Grey Parrot; and a lot of other articles not necessarily connected to Africa, including Part II of "Waxb.ills and their Allies" which, by happenstance, is connected to Africa.We have the very popular and longest running series in Watchbird history, "Veterinary Viewpoints," in which several avian vets answer all your questions; an important AFA effort in behalf of the Spix's Macaw; the AF A's Red Siskin Project; a encouraging study on the Dominican Amazon Parrot, and some fun material on the convention.Enjoy.~ </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1566</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 5 (2000): Sept-Oct 2000; 7-8</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1566/1543</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
