<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/657</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding and Rearing African Greys</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wold, Barry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The first thing one learns whenbreeding African Greys is that they areall so different. Each pair will act, reactand do things differently. There is nota common denominator such as iscommonly found in Amazons ,macaws, etc. We have several pairs ofgreys. Some exhibit the sterotypebehavior of greys, of being shy andretiring. Another stereotype is thatthey will shake from fright whenapproached, tJy to hide, and ce1tainlygrowl. Fo1tunately we have none thatexhibit fear but this may be because ofthe physical situation of the birds andtheir cages.The birds are kept in the same cage,with the nest box attached, yearround. The cages are suspended offthe ground, and are made of 12 gauge,half by three inch wire. The cages areeight feet long, four feet high and 30inches wide. They are high enough sothat the perches are at least six feetfrom the gound. This allows the birdsto look down on me. The metal nestbox is boot or L-shaped. Box dimensionsare 18 inches high and long by IIinches wide. The access hole is fourinches square near the top of the L.The boxes are hung on the outside ofthe cage. There is an inspection doorwith wire screen so that when thedoor is opened the birds cannotescape. I feel this is important becauseseveral of the pairs will not exit thebox when I inspect. The inspectiondoor on the boot (leg) should also behigher than normal because of thegreys' tendency to scratch and pile thenesting material up against the door. Iuse one inch thick pine boards forflooring and pine shavings above tl1at.The entire inside of the nest box ispainted with a flat black paint. Thebirds seem to feel more secure in thedarkness.The perches are tree branches,usually eucalyptus, located at eachend of the cage. At the opposite endfrom tl1e nest box is the feeding area.A 12 inch square attachment, thewidth of the cage, holds the water andfood dishes . This area is covered.There is a six foot solid dividerbetween cages. At the food end of thecage, two feet are open to adjoiningcages. Four feet of the cage is coveredon top, including the nest box. At thenest box end, I have hinged plywoodthat is raised in the summer for ventilationand put down in the winter toprotect from the cold winter winds.The cages are located in an Emupasture under deciduous oaks. In thewinter, the birds get tl1e benefit of thesun, in the summer they are shaded.The Emus do not disturb the greys.Our birds generally sit out in the openduring the most inclement weather.They love bathing in the rain and willplay in the snow when it is fresh ontheir cage. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/657</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 13-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/657/640</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
