<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/718</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">African Silverbills</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mosier, Diana</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">African Silverbill, Lonchura (Eodice)cantans, also known as the WarblingSilverbill; Order Passeriformes, FamilyEstrildidae. They average 11 centimetersin length. They are light sandybrown, darker brown on the wingsand tail , and cream colored on theirbelly and tail coverts. There are foursubspecies indigenous to West andCentral Africa, they live in savannas,farmlands, and near villages. They arenot dimorphic.It is virtually impossible, in fact, todistinguish between the sexes untilthe chicks reach four months of age, atwhich time the male will begin to singand display courtship behavior. Thisbehavior may be only singing whilebouncing up and down. It may eveninclude what I call the "grass ceremony",which is singing and bouncingwhile holding a piece of grass inhis bill.Silverbills usually breed at eight to10 months of age. Both the cock andthe hen build the nest. He choosesand brings the nesting material to thehen, who arranges it to her liking. Ihave found Silverbills favor freshly cutstrands of Bermuda grass three inchesor longer, however they will also useBermuda hay, leaves, pieces of cottonballs,or other grasses that grow inthe ir aviary. They seem to prefer thelarger woven baskets (you can purchasethem in any pet or feed store) toany other type of natural or man madehousing. They a lso seem to prefernesting in the open , where they canobserve what's going on in the aviary,unlike Red-cheeked Cordon Bleus,who prefer to hide their nests fromprying eyes.I have observed Silverbills mate forlife, rather than only for the breedingseason. Also, they are very attentive totheir mates, doing everything together from eating to sitting in the sun. It isvery amusing to watch them preeneach other, although the cock maypull feathers from the hen duringmating.I have noticed Silverbills, unlikesome other finches , do not moltannually. The feathers are replaced asthey wear out, the only heavy moltthey experience is their adult moltwhich happens between six to eightmonths of age.Although not as brightly colored assome finches imported from that area,they have a beautiful song (a testamentto this is part of their name, cantans),and they are not aggressive,which makes them an excellent additionto anyone's aviary. Silverbills arealso extremely hardy and can, therefore,be raised without much difficultyby even beginning aviculturists.The hen lays four to six eggs perclutch, and has about five clutches perseason. It would be wise, however, tolimit them to three clutches if at allpossible to have healthier young. Bothparents take turns incubating the eggs,which hatch in 14 to 17 days. It hasbeen said that with Silverbills, nestmonitoring is not possible. I find thatto be untrue, at least with my birds. Iadmit, however, I don't monitor mynests more than once daily, usually inthe morning while both parents areaway from the nest.Silverbills are excellent parents and,a lthough I have heard they can beused as foster pare nts, I cannot substantiatethis as I am against using anybird to raise the offspring of another. Ido know, however, that Silve rbillsstuff their chicks more like Societies orZebras than an African waxbill. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/718</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/718/701</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
