<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3676</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-26T05:20:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Artist Biography: Tony Sánchez</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Born in 1965, on the Canary Islands, Spain, Tony began sketching and painting at an early age. He usually paints in traditional mediums (oil, watercolor, pastel, gouache, colored pencil, airbrush, etc.) and digital art (Photoshop, Painter, Illustrator, etc.).Until the 1980's, Tony worked for different clients that commissioned his artworks using a wide variety of styles.In the 1980's, Tony studied veterinary medicine at the University of Las Palmas de G.C. In the last year, Tony began working professionally as artistic painter and illustrator, going to work in AXIS STUDIOS (Scientific Illustration &amp;amp; Wildlife Art). Tony also painted commissioned works for Medical Illustrations (Doctoral thesis &amp;amp; Professorship, Department of Endocrinology, University of LPGC) and Scientific Illustrations (Department of Biology, University of LPGC). Publications in scientific magazines (Botanic, animals, etc.).In the 1990's, Tony exhibited in various monographic and group exhibitions: Smithsonian Institution (Washington, U.S.A.), "Illuminating Science" (Museum of Art and History, Santa Cruz, California, U.S.A.), Carteles Educativos Loro Parque Foundation (Caja Canarias, Santa Cruz de Tenerife, Spain), Northern Arizona University Art Museum and Galleries (U.S.A.), "Oceanos:Illustrating Marine Life" (Centro de exposicoes da fortaleza de sagres, Portugal.), Large Parrots Collection Exhibition (Centro de Congresos, Puerto de la Cruz, Tenerife, Spain), Iowa State University (U.S.A.) and Palacio Dom Manuel (Evora, Portugal).Tony studied Graphic Design and was selected to work as a graphic designer for the company Philippe Martin &amp;amp; Asociados. Ilustrations for book "Especies ameacadas em Portugal" and CD-ROM "Especies ameacadas em Portugal" (ForumAmbiente magazine). He was commissioned to illustrate and design more than 300 posters for Loro Parque Foundation, as well as working extensively with that foundation during the Christmas season and creating posters for international conventions. Books: "Loro Parque", "La vestimenta tradicional en Gran Canaria (Cabildo Insular de G.C.), "Cetreria, la caza con aves de presa'' (Andres Lopez Sanchez), "Reptiles y Anfibios - Fauna Iberica",From 2000 to 2014: participates in Proyects as Laurisilva XXI, Charca de Maspalomas, Jardfn Canario Viera y Clavijo, Parque Biol6gico de Madrid, etc. In 2002 Tony published his book "Aves de Canarias (Birds of the Canary Islands)" as author of all texts, illustrations and paintings (Editorial Rueda, Spain). Designs &amp;amp; Illustrations for Frutania &amp;amp; Clipper. Commissioned as illustrator of all artworks of the books "My First Book of Garden Wildlife" (2008) and "My First Book of Garden Bugs" (2009) from A&amp;amp;C Black Publisher of Bloomsbury Group ( original publisher of Harry Potter). "Uniforms of the American War oflndependence (1775-1783)" (Lorenz Books, 2008), "I Love Rainforests" (Miles Kelly, 2008), "Les animaux des forets tropicales" (Piccolia, 2011), "Gufa de Aves del Parque Nacional de Timanfaya'' (Gobierno de Canarias, 2011), "Mis primeras exploraciones por las islas Canarias" (Pellagofio Ediciones &amp;amp; Mercurio, 2013). Designs of Posters and T-shirts for Parrots International Symposiums.Magazines: Bird Talk, Ruta Archipielago, Fagelhobby, Australian Aviary Life, Papageienzeit, etc.Tony currently teaches drawing and painting in Gran Canaria (Spain) for Universidad Popular de Agiiimes and works for the London artists' agency Advocate Art, and is preparing a series of books on various themes. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3676</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 3 (2014): Number 3 2014; 28-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3676/3659</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
