<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1099</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:21:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Gordon Taylor McAlpin, a Texas rancher, independent oil man and rugged individualist died al the age of 84 on 26 September 1996. This man, probably unknown Lo all but a few aviculiurists, had a passion for neotropical parrots, especially macaws, and he made a substantial contribution to aviculture that needs to be recognized. His love of these birds was acquired during his business dealings, mainly involving caule, in Central and South America during the 1970s. Wherever he traveled, he saw the plight of wild populations of parrots and the corresponding plight of indigenous peoples. He also recognized the value of parrots in international trade, particularly in the United States. He envisioned a program of population studies to determine sustainable harvest levels, harvest and aviculture programs in the countries of origin benefiting the local peoples (not middlemen), and a corresponding study of the husbandry and health care of parrots in captivity in the United States. His vision was that a healthy trade in parrots would benefit the birds; i.e. their value as a sustainable resource for local peoples would insure habitat protection and even protection against overharvest. His view also included the concept that U.S. aviculture would ultimately need to produce the majority of birds for the pet trade simply because wild populations of most species were simply too small to supply any demand much above those birds that would likely be required for captive breeding purposes.Gordon didn't look to the government to fund and implement his conservation program, he simply did it, drawing upon his belief and faith in the capabilities of the individual to make a difference-and a profit for all involved. He traveled across the neotropics presenting his ideas to local governments and soon found a taker-Bolivia. He personally funded a field research program in Bolivia with a local University; and funded a companion program in the United States with Texas A&amp;amp;M University-the so-called Macaw Project, He provided additional financing enabling the U.S. University in 1983 to import 200 macaws from the Bolivian University to begin research on the husbandry and health of captive macaws. Prior to this point, no one took Gordon's program seriously-it simply couldn't be done, certainly not without funding and support of the U.S. government and NGOs. But, suddenly, here the program was, with the initial and most difficult hurdles already overcome by a man in his 70s with no track record with the conservation community or aviculture for that matter. There then ensued a hail of controversy, particularly from NGOs representing the conservation community, but also including some importers. The numbers of macaws lo be imported were exaggerated by a factor of 10, the rnoti vat ions and ethics of the universities were called into question, and McA!pin and hi Macaw Project were stridently vilified. Research permits were cancelled or became "impossible" lo acquire. The upshot was that the program was quashed at the level achieved prior to the 1983 campaign of disinformation. None of the planned population studies were ever performed, thanks to the conservation community. A promising program was nipped in the bud.Whatever happened lo the birds and the Macaw Project?The birds and selected progeny are thriving in a breeding colony which is operated and maintained in the private sector by McAlpins daughter. This colony is still being utilized as a research and teaching resource by the Veterinary College of Texas A&amp;amp;M University. Additionally, they presently comprise the nucleus of a genetics study being performed by a privatesector company with funding from the prestigious National Science Foundation. Initially, there were problems concerning the ownership of the birds imported by the University. McAlpin's position was that these birds belonged to the School; the School's position was that they belonged to McA!pin. Gordon was strongly disillusioned, and neither party wanted to bear the ongoing cost of maintenance in a program having little chance to pay its own way without outside funding. The default position was that McAlpin's daughter, a local resident near Texas A&amp;amp;M, took possession and maintenance responsibility for the birds in an attempt to bring at least part of her father's original vision to fruition.As time went by, the availability of the birds and the struggling research program attracted more favorable attention to the University as an institution seriously interested in exotic birds. Within a few years, the University received the largest endowment in its history from a wealthy aviculturist to fund a dedicated staff and a comprehensive program of health-care research on exotic birds. With this support, the College ha since become a leader in this field of research. Production from the breeding colony has finally (since 1995) been sufficient tn to support the the cost of maintenance. Aviculture has thus benefited greatly from McApin's original vision.And. by the way, Gordon's vision is how Nancy and Benny Gallaway became involved in aviculture. Prior to arrival of the birds, we had absolutely no interest in birds and, in fact, we had little choice in housing the birds when they first arrived at the University in 1983 (for that story see AFA watctibird August/September 1984 ). Our world was turned upside down on 6 April 1983, and has never righted. Gordon, we wouldn't have it any other way. Thank you. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1099</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 6 (1996): NOV-DEC 1996; 48-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1099/1078</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
