<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1497</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:51:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pairs of Birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Winter, Don</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I t seems that more than any other animal, birds are kept most often in pairs. As a result, it is common to see birds advertised in pairs. A pair means exactly two birds. A bonded pair means exactly two birds, and a proven pair means exactly two birds.When, it comes to pet birds, though, the rule seems to be one bird. The theory is that the bird will bond to you as the second bird. Granted, I will concede there is evidence that some birds will "imprint" on a human but I am not sold on the fact that the bird actually views the human as another bird. I just do not think the bird is that dumb.Wild birds have been often easily tamed; and not just parrots. All my pet birds have mates. I have about 12 pairs of pet birds that can be handled with ease. Some are paired with wild caught birds and some are even paired with a different species. There are exceptions, but I can cuddle nearly every bird I have cultivated as a paired pet. In addition, I can interact with about half of my breeding pairs without getting nipped.My point is that I think even pet birds should be kept in pairs. It is only fair to admit that my experience covers only conures, lories, small macaws, a Goffin's Cockatoo, and a pair of Eclectus. I am guessing that Greys and Amazons would be among the trickier pets to keep as pairs but If I owned any, I would try to keep them in pairs also.Managing a flock of pets is time consuming. Even paired birds must be played with at every opportunity, just as you would play with a single bird. You must be aware of their moods and constantly watch opportunities to befriend them.The advantage of pairing pets is better adjusted birds. They have company when you are not around. Mine pluck less. They are more likely to eat a variety food, since they mimic each other. They can even teach each other to talk. I am pleased with the· results. You may want to try this.Goodluck. ~ </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1497</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 1 (2000): Jan-Feb 2000; 51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1497/1474</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
