<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3183</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-28T08:22:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">In Memory of Leslie ‘Harold’ Bowles</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">December 17, 1935-September 3, 2010It is with a multitude of memories that we say a fond fair-well to Mr. Harold Bowles, 74, of Cedartown, Ga.,who passed on Friday, September 3, 2010 at Polk Medical Center. Harold's contributions to aviculture as a show judge, officer, and exhibitor in numerous organizations spanned several decades, but it was Harold's kindness, gentleness, and unselfish eagerness to help a novice - along with his passion for many species-that many of us will remember.Harold began his avicultural career in 1964 with budgies, but shortly added cockatiels to his aviary, in which he specialized. Eventually, he added more than SO different species to his breeding collection, from finches to macaws.In the world of exhibition, Harold began as a successful exhibitor of show budgies in the American Budgerigar Society, where he bred and produced many champions. When the American Cockatiel Society (ACS) formed in 1976, Harold's interests turned primarily to exhibiting cockatiels through to their championship status. He was elected to the ACS board of directors as vice president, chairman of the ACS judges panel, and then eventually as president and chairman of the board.Harold organized and founded the National Cockatiel Society (NCS) on November 1, 1983, and was elected its first president, serving many years in that capacity on and off the board throughout the next 15 years. He has been its resident agent from the incorporation ofNCS through August 2010, although he was unable to be more active due to his health.A mainstay of the National Cage Bird Show, Inc. (NCBS), Harold was widely known as a board member and exhibitor for more than 20 years. In 1978 and 1990, he was elected show manager, organizing the largest shows in the country. He served the NCBS board in many capacities over the years, and one could always count on seeing Harold as either a judge, exhibitor, or attending the numerous board and general meetings held for both the NCBS, and the specialties in which he was involved.An interest in other parrots prompted Harold to serve on the board of directors of the Society of Parrot Breeders &amp;amp; Exhibitors, and in more recent years, the North American Parrot Society. He also shared his energies closer to home by founding the Georgia Cage Bird Breeders and Exhibitors and organizing local shows. Harold had been a member of the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. for many years and attended earlier conventions.A show judge for more than 30 years, Harold served as a certified panel judge to the American Cockatiel Society, the National Cockatiel Society, the Society of Parrot Breeders &amp;amp; Exhibitors, the North American Parrot Society, and the National Finch &amp;amp; Sofi:bill Society. He had the honor of presiding as judge many times for the above specialties at a number of National Cage Bird Shows.Although Harold will certainly be remembered for his many avicultural contributions, those of us who knew him will remember Harold as always having a kind word to say-and at all times being willing to listen. Harold embodied the belief, "if you don't have something nice to say, then don't say it at all." He was a kind and gentle man who will be missed by his many friends in the fancy.Harold served in the U.S. Air Force and was retired from the Cobb Country Fire Department with 30 years' service. Heartfelt sympathy to Harold's wife, Betty Hood Bowles, and surviving family, including two daughters, three stepchildren, 13 grandchildren, two sisters, one brother and several nieces and nephews. In lieu of Rowers, donations may be sent to Silent Word Ministries, P.O. Box 889, Trenton, GA 30752. Condolences can be emailed to: http://www.sosebee funeralhome.com/ obituaries.htm. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3183</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 37 No. 3 (2010): Number 3 2010; 7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3183/3167</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
