<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/639</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Visits ... the aviaries of Mac &amp; Cindy Sharpe</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The perfect location for an aviarywould be as far away as possible fromyour neighbors, maybe three quartersof a mile away. Surround yourselfwith 3,500 acres of abandonedphosphate mines, 1,600 acres ofcounty parkland and you can dowhat you want. Such are the surroundingsof Cindy and Mac Sharpe,whose 40 acre citrus grove withhome and aviaries 20 miles east ofTampa, provide them with all anyonecould ask for. Just think! Your job,your hobbies, and your getaway allwithout any commute whatsoever!In 1958 at the age of five, Macencountered his first bird, a Bantamchicken. It wasn't long before heknew he wanted to be a farmer, andwas soon an active member of 4-Hand Future Farmers of America (FFA).By the age of nine, Mac was workingfor the J .C. Smith Gamebird Farm.There, Mac learned how to manageornamental pheasants and began toacquire his own. He also becameinterested in the strange family ofMegapodes, whose eggs are incubatedin a mound of decaying vegetablematter, attended by the male bird,who tests the mound temperature atregular intervals, adding or removingmaterial to maintain proper temperature.Mac's collection grew until hewent off to the University of Florida,where other interests got in the way.The collection was dispersed and hewas out of birds until his senior year,when he obtained a pet Screech Owl.After graduation in 1977, he movedto Brandon, Florida, where he beganraising ornamental chickens . By1981, he was raising ornamentalpheasants, Java Green Peafowl andJungle Fowl. That same year he metLyn Ash, the artist at Busch Gardens,and Rodney Michael, a Java GreenPeafowl breeder, both of whominspired him to become more involvedin bird breeding. By the mid-1980s, he was also working withcranes.In 1987, while visiting Busch Gardensto trade some pheasants, henoticed the beautiful variety of touracos, and was moved to acquiresome, and thus began his love affairwith softbills. His first touracos werepurchased from Joe Longo, who hadone of the best collections of touracosin the U.S., and who had developedvery successful techniques fortheir captive breeding. Shortly thereafter,Mac met Richard Schmidt, whoalso lives near Tampa, and theyfueled each other's interest into anaddiction.Mac's first aviaries were a couple ofchainlink pens 8' x 12' with attachedprefab sheds of wood 10' x 16' forshelters. He kept his pheasants andpeafowl in these. As time went on,he built more and more pens, untilhe now has over an acre completelyunder wire.One of the more curious pens is anenclosed swimming pool. It seemsthat Mac's first wife, whom hedivorced in 1983, liked to swim.Against his better judgement, he borrowedthe money to build a pool hedidn't really want. When she left, hewas faced with a useless reminder ofher that he had to continually makepayments on. So, he converted it intoan aviary by constructing a Quonsethut-shaped framework above it andover which he stretched wire. Thepool itself was filled halfway up withsoil and planted. It contains a numberof softbill species including GreyWing Trumpeters, Coletta Mynahs,Indian Rollers, Abdim Storks, FairyBluebirds, and White Breasted Waterhens.It is the only aviary known inthe U.S. to have its own custom, onemeter diving board.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/639</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 60-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/639/622</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
