<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1208</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">MYNAH MESSENGER:If It's Smaller, Why Call it Greater!</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson-Nixon, Gayle</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T here is confusion as to which common name to call each of the two mynahs of the Gracula genus found in aviculture today. The Java, or Java Hill Mynah, Gracula re!igiosa religiosa, averaging 12 inches in length, only one inch longer than the Hill Mynah, C. r. intermedia, has a longer head and beak, and stockier body, giving it the appearance of a much larger bird. The smaller of the two is referred to in various hooks and articles as: the Hill, Greater, Greater Hill, and the Greater Indian Hill Mynah. It most likely acquired the name "Greater" as it was larger than the Lesser Hill Mynah, C. r. indica, which was rarely imported into the pet trade here or in Europe. If any Lessers remain in captivity in the U.S., it is certain their numbers are insufficient for a viable breeding population.Many owners are uncertain as to which species they have. While researching information in theColorado library system, I was disappointed to find incomplete and, sometimes, incorrect information. For example, the Marshall Cavendish International Wildlife Encyclopedia. Vl 5, New York, New York: M. Cavendish Corporation, 1993, incorrectly states, "The largest, measuring 15 inches long, is the Indian hill mynah, sometime called the Greater Hill mynah, popular today in many parts of the world as a talking cage bird. Often referred to in India as a grackle, it is a glossy black with yellow wattles." Only the Nias Island Mynah, C. r. robusta, reaches 15 inches in length and is not available in the pet trade. In this book, as in most books, the only mynah of the Gracula genus pictured is C. r. inter media.No mention is made of any of the approximately 11 subspecies of Gracula in the Eyewitness Handbook, Birds qf the World by Colin Harrison and Alan Greensmith, New York, New York: Darling Kindersley, 1993. Only one mynah is pictured, the "Hill Myna" and the species is described only as Gracula religiosa.Although the information regarding diet and care in Mynahs, by Martin Weil, Neptune, NJ: T. F. H. Publications, 1981, is obviously outdated, and, judging by some of the hairstyles, some of the pictures are probably from the 50s, it is the only book' found to have photos of the three mynah subspecies mentioned above, plus drawings of a few others.For simplicity it is suggested that the common names of these mynahs he referred to as:• Hill Mynah ( C. r. intermedid). •Java Hill Mynah CC. 1: religiosa). • Lesser Hill Mynah ( C. r. indicd).You Don't Know What You've Got Until It's GoneThe majority of the mynahs imported into this country has always been the smaller Gracula religiosa intermedia, the Hill Mynah, not the largerJava. As Indonesia has imposed a total ban on exporting lavas, those that reside in the United States and Canada constitute the only gene pool available for breeding future generations.Now that the door is closed and interest in the Java is increasing, avi- culturists are discovering that these intelligent, raucous, extroverted members of the starling family are not the easiest of birds to breed. The number of people I know who have a producing pair of Javas can he counted on one hand.If we can have at least 100 Javas, documented as unrelated, there may be hope for having healthy generations to come. It won't benefit the birds in any way if we become hacked into a corner by inbreeding-the result will he a situation such as that of the cheetah wherein all individuals in the U.S.A. are so closely related that there is no possibility for genetic diversity in the future.We must not wait until committees are formed, funds are allocated, studies done, and the Java is finally placed on the endangered species list-it will he too late then. The time to initiate a Java consortium is now.Those who have adult pets are encouraged to pair them, if possible, or sell them to a breeder, or donate them in exchange for future hand raised hahies. If, in a reasonable amount of time, a breeder is unsuccessful in raising chicks from a pair. it would be best if the birds were loaned to a successful breeder. There just isn't time to waste speculating and experimenting as these birds grow older. If people will set egos aside and work together, we may continue to enjoy the company of the Javas. If nothing is done, this mynah will disappear from aviculture in one or two more generations.Even though we do not know everything about the dietary requirements of the Hill Mynahs, we know more than we did 10 years ago. Since many adult Java Mynahs have been fed incorrectly (dog or cat food, monkey chow, etc.) their lifespan will be shortened and breeding years limited. If these birds can he given a better diet of fresh fruits, vegetables, quality pellets and insects, and housed in optimal conditions, an experienced keeper may he able to extend their lives long enough to produce another generation.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1208</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 5 (1997): SEPT-OCT 1997; 36-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1208/1187</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
