<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2928</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-12T15:48:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dr. Baer's article "Perils of Buying Birds" in our last issue has evoked much verbal response. Unfortunately, our publishing deadline was so close that time did not permit putting the responses in to print. Our next issue, however, will contain some counter-balancing statements. In the meantime your humble editor will express a few of his personal thoughts on the matter. Just as Dr. Baer 's opinion is just that - his own opinion, so the following lines reflect my own attitudes and ruminations and shouldn't be construed as anything more.There is no doubt that many sick and diseased birds are bought and sold every day. There is considerable traffic in birds and a certain percent of the birds will die, another percent will live but have health problems. Dr. Baer has done aviculture a great service to point this fact out. It is equally true that the Federal and State Governments do not guarantee the health of any birds put on the market and, indeed, some of the birds will be diseased.This is as it should be. Where, dear friend, can you find a guarantee without strings attached? How much of a guarantee do you receive when you buy birds from the local breeders? r personally know many breeders whose flocks are infested with various parasites, have regular bouts with psittacosis, are periodically afflicted with coccidiosis, and have even had Pacheco's parrot disease. The government nor anyone else guarantees the health of these birds.Some very conscientious breeders will do all in their power to raise and sell only heal thy birds, and occasionally they will give a modest guarantee - perhaps to replace a purchased bird if it dies within one day - or something similar. So too are there conscientious bird importers and dealers. Again, I personally know of several instances where a quarantine station has refused to sell birds that were not up to par. In one case a number of parrots were farmed out to a private breeder to see if he could improve the bird's health. None of the birds were ever sold. In another case a large number of birds in poor health were donated to the Federal Laboratory at Ames, Iowa, for avian research. Another importer had a shipment of birds that were unhealthy but did not have Newcastle Disease. He begged the government to kill all of the birds but they refused and he had to do the chore himself.There are good and honest people in all aspects of the bird fancy including importers, dealers, and breeders. There are also crooks in the aforementioned categories. No single category is more clean and upstanding than the others.Another very widespread malady that pervades all aspects of the bird trade is the disease called S.F.N. - i.e., Something For Nothing. Too many people want something for nothing. Too few people are willing to assume their own responsibility. Regarding bird traffic and bird diseases, again everybody wants S.F .N. People want a guaranteed product, a bird that imposes no responsibility on the buyer, a bird that is no peril, a bird whose condition is secure.I, dear reader, do not want the government to guarantee me a secure bird - or anything else. You realize of course that the most secure persons in our society are the prisoners of the government. These prisoners are guaranteed their meals, their clothes, their shelter. All of the necessities of life are supplied with no responsibility to the prisoner. The prisoners are getting something for nothing. Or are they? What about their freedom?I don't want to be a prisoner of the government and I don't want the bird trade to be dominated by government. If we assume our responsibilities there will be no need for government intervention. Once again Dr. Baer comes to the rescue and points out one of the most crucial elements of our responsibility in handling bird diseases. Quarantine Your Own Birds. Never buy a bird from an importer or a local breeder and put it directly into your flock. I refer you to Dr. Baer's discussion of private quarantinefound on page 16 of the Dec/Jan Watchbird, Volume IV,No. 6.If we manage our own birds according to the best avicultural techniques, we can do much to eliminate troublesome diseases. If we shop wisely on the open bird market those dealers who are not responsible will eventually go out of business. These two responsibilities belong to us. Lets not burden the taxpayers with them. There is no such thing as something for nothing. If we, by relinquishing our responsibility, force the government to take over portions of the bird industry, we also relinquish our freedom in those areas and I'm against that.Well, with the above stated philosophy off my chest I suppose it would be wise to explain my general editorial philosophy. In the Watch bird we are willing to present a very broad spectrum of opinions. We, in fact, solicit diverse opinions. We will publish anyone's articulate and well thought out opinion without taking sides. If something appears in the magazine that you feel is erroneous you should submit a rebuttal. When A.F.A' Policy is printed it will be identified as official policy.Now, perhaps we should get on with a few letters that have crossed my desk lately. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2928</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 1 (1978): FEB-MAR 1978; 44-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2928/2912</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
