<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/653</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Understanding Lories &amp; Lorikeets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vriends, Matthew M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionDuring the last few years, lories andlorikeets have experienced a welldeserved increase in popularityamong aviculturists. With their clownlikebehavior and their brilliant colors,they are truly a feast for the eyes andexcellent subjects for aviaries and (forsome species) for large cages. In thepast, fanciers regarded these birdswith perhaps less enthusiasm than they might, due to their specializeddiet and the fact that their droppingsare watery and messy, which meantthat cages had to be thoroughlycleaned on a daily basis. There is thuslittle positive information about themin the literature. As I have personallyhad opportunities to study these birdsin their natural habitats as well as havinghad much experience with captivespecimens, I hope, with this text, tomodestly offer some facts which willlead to a better general understandingof these beautiful and extremely interestingpsittacines.Geographical NotesThe "heart" of "lory country" isAustralasia, but especially NewGuinea and its rich collection of tinyeastern islands which include the last"lory stongholds" of HendersonIsland and the little Pitcairn DucieIslands, where in 1907, the Stephen'sLory (Vini stephensi) was discovered.This bird is now rarely if ever seen incaptivity though I once viewed a specimenowned by a Belgian fancier. I amnot aware of any American or Canadianspecimens. Travelling westwardsfrom New Guinea, we come to themany islands of Indonesia all populatedwith lories as far as Bali andLombok where the Mitchell's Lorikeet(Trichoglossus haematodus mitchelli)is found. This is a splendid bird with alight red breast which appears irregularlyon the market.Some of the lory species from theaforementioned areas (HendersonIsland to Bali) have a surprisingly large range and several occur on twoor more islands. The climate and availabilityof food may have some bearingon the distribution of various subspecies.In some genera there are subspeciesthat we can cautiously sayare questionable. The well knownGerman ornithologist, Dr. H.E.Wolters would recognize 56 species,though I would be doubtful aboutthree of these; another one, the NewCaledonian Lorikeet (Hypocharmosynadiadema), is probably extinct.Of the 134 subspecies recognized byDr. Wolters, there are at least 15 whichcan be regarded as synonyms of thenominate forms or at least with doubtfulstatus. Personally, I do not believeit is necessary to give subspeciesstatus on account of small color differences;alllories and lorikeets (with afew exceptions) possess a varied colorpattern which could easily lead tomistaken classifications. I am of theopinion that further studies based onmorphological rather than color characteristicsare necessary before wecan make any hard and fast ornithologicaldecisions regarding the classificationsof this group of species. As weare here mainly concerned with thecare and breeding of the avialablespecies, we will omit further taxonomicaldiscussion.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/653</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 58-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/653/636</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
