<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/800</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Caging and Housing Lovebirds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">C aging and housing any genusor group of birds will undoubtedlyproduce a diversity of opinions.When we discuss a group as prevalentin aviculture as the lovebirds or genusAgapornis, this may be especially trueas these birds have bred in virtuallyevery type of accommodation. Mysuggestions are based on personalexperience with the eight species wehave kept in American collections. Ihave been fortunate enough to breedseven of the eight species listed (theRed-faced Lovebird, an extremely specializedand difficult species, has notbred for me yet, however, it is currentlyin my collection).I have listed below some specificprecautions which should beobserved for the protection and wellbeingof the birds.• Do not use chicken wire or 1/"hex aviary netting for construction asthe birds can chew through this (I canpersonally attest to this).• Lovebirds chew wood, thereforeaviary frames should be sturdy. Forthe best and safest results, plywoodcovered with wire will providesecurity.• Shelter is necessary. Most lovebirdscan withstand colder temperaturesif properly acclimatized, butdrafts can be deadly. If aviaries aresubject to cold winds, they shouldhave solid "wind blocks" attached toprotect the birds.• A void perches or nesting materialsfrom toxic plants such as oleander orcastor bean. Most lovebirds will destroyplanted flights, so don't wastetime planting aviaries.• See my notes on individual speciesfor compatibility in colonies. Donot introduce new specimens toestablished groups. Do not intermixor hybridize different species.• In aviaries, a safety aisle is manda- tory as escapes can and will happen,even during routine maintenance.• Vermin must be controlled as theywill enter nest boxes, kill babies andadults and contaminate food. Watchfor rats, mice, snakes and, in someareas, squirrels, opossums and raccoons.• Lovebirds must have water -particularly in hot weather. Checkreceptacles daily or even more oftenas needed.• Length is more important thanwidth when building cages and aviaries.This provides for exercise andallows the birds to come in conditionfor breeding.• Provide at least one and a halftimes the number of nest boxes aspairs of birds and don't overcrowd(too many pairs), even in large flights.All of my lovebird aviaries are 7' to8' high, 4' wide and 6' to 12' long. Iuse only welded wire and some are of"erect easy"-type panel construction.All are sheltered at least 4' of thelength and secured from drafts. Mybreeding cages are about 4' long by 3'wide by 3' high.In aviaries, I offer both naturalbranches and "perch ladders" suspendeddiagonally from the top of theflight. In colonies, they help allow thebirds to establish dominance andreduce aggressive behavior. Note: incolonies, make sure there are enoughperches in different locations becausefighting can occur. However, do notcrowd the flight section of the aviaryor cage so the birds are inhibited fromactually flying.I feed in bowls and pans and checkdaily to make sure what "looks full" is,indeed, full of fresh seed (not hulls).Bowls containing soft foods such asfruits and beans are cleaned up anddisinfected with a mild bleach solutiondaily. A great disposable alternativeis paper "French fry boats" availablefrom grocery supply houses ordiscount stores such as Costco. Youjust use the trays once and then throwthem away.I provide fresh water daily in glasspie dishes (automatic waterers arefine, however, lovebirds bathe regularlyand the water they retain andcarry in their breast feathers is importantfor maintaining humidity in thenest.)Below are some brief notes on theindividual species (I will elaborate inupcoming articles covering the individualspecies and their uniquerequirements).Peach-faced. Keep in pairs or controlledcolonies only, as they areaggressive. Cage breeding is preferablefor establishing mutations (particularlythe rarer ones) and monitoringgenetics. Make sure there are evennumbers of pairs and, if kept in colonies,extra nest boxes.Fischer's, Masked, Blackcheeked,Nyasa. Maintain in small,controlled colonies or cage breedindividual pairs when establishingmutations. Hybrids are undesirable sodo not mix species. Extra nest boxesare mandatory.Abyssinian, Madagascar. Singlepairs only/These species are unsuitablefor colonies. Females are veryaggressive so be sure pairs are compatible.Madagascars are nervous andare most stable in breeding cages withprivacy. Abyssinians are calmer andmore "parrot-like" and will do well incages or small flights. Madagascars aresensitive to cold, whereas Abyssiniansare somewhat more tolerant.Red-faced. These birds are quitedifficult to induce to breed. Mostrecent breeding successes have beenin very private cages, however, thislovebird will live harmoniously withother birds (not other lovebirds). Redfaceddo not destroy shrubbery inplanted flights. They require a highnest temperature when breeding.Pairs can be aggressive towards eachother. This is not a bird for beginners.As I mentioned, my recommendationsare based on my own experience.Your opinions may vary, asmany breeders have enjoyed successeven in extremely small cages. Lovebirdswill sometimes breed in verysmall facilities, but the offspring areoften small and sometimes the parentsare so out of condition they can't evenfly.Good housing, good diet and goodjudgment are most important in maintainingand breeding the lovebirds.And remember, do not mix any speciesof lovebird (except Red-faced) incommunity aviaries with other varietiesof birds.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/800</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/800/782</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
