<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1284</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Eurasian Eagle Owl (Bubo bubo) at the Oklahoma City Zoological Park</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Chris</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I t is a cool spring evening in the Scandinavian forest. A full moon illuminates the the night sky. A lemming emerges from its burrow and ventures out in search of a meal. As the lemming browses and grazes though the grass, it fails to notice it is being watched by a creature perched in a nearby tree. This creature has a barrel-shaped body and a small round head with a short hooked beak. Two dark slanted horns over its large fiery orange eyes give the creature a menacing appearance. Suddenly, without a sound, the animal flies from the tree on a direct course to the unsuspecting rodent. The lemming looks up at the winged terror diving in upon it, but it is too late. Eight sickle-like talons tear into the lemming, killing it instantly. The predator rests over its kill for a moment, then flies off as quickly and silently as it had attacked. The creature heads toward a ledge on the side of a cliff. There awaits its hungry offspring. It has been another successful hunt for the Eurasian Eagle Owl, Bubo bubo.The Eurasian Eagle Owl is the largest species of owl. This bird can measure 72 cm (28.3 in.) in length, and can weigh 3,000g (6.5 lbs). The wingspan can reach 175 cm (68.9 in.). Eurasian Eagle Owls are generally colored with various shades of browns and tans arranged in barred patterns on the back and wings, and in streak patterns on the chest and underside. The chin and throat are white. Two dark brown tufts give these owls an"eared" appearance similar to that of its close relative the Great-horned Owl, Bubo uirginianus. The eyes are usually bright orange, but can sometimes be bright yellow. Males and females are similar in appearance, except females tend to be larger and sometimes darker. These owls are also known as 'Tigers of the Sky" due to their large size and fierce reputation.The range of the Eurasian Eagle Owl is vast. These birds range from the Iberian peninsula, across the southern half of France, most of central Europe, central areas of Italy and through the Balkans across most of the Asian mainland, south of Siberia to the southern border of China. These owls also occur in Scandinavia, northern Africa and the Arabian peninsula. On rare occasions, Eurasian Eagle Owls are found in Great Britain, northern Europe and japan.Eurasian Eagle Owls can he found in many types of habitat; coniferous and deciduous forests, scrub, woodland, grassy steppes, high altitude meadows, and rocky and sandy deserts. Although Eurasian Eagle Owls can adapt to a wide variety of habitats, they prefer areas with steep and rocky slopes or cliffs, their usual nesting sites. Eurasian Eagle Owls are gradually becoming established in a few rural areas in Europe and Asia, like the Great Horned Owl has in North America.Approximately 20 subspecies of the Eurasian Eagle Owl are recognized. Each subspecies varies in size and coloration. The largest subspecies, Bubo b. sibericus, is found in southerniberia. Most of the northern subspecies tend to be larger and darker than those found in milder climates. Two desert subspecies, Bubo b. ascalpbus, found in northwest Africa, and Bubo b. desertorum, found in the Sahara and Arabian deserts, are much smaller and lighter in color. Some sources even list these two as separate species. Perhaps the most recognized subspecies is Bubo b .. bubo, which i found in central Europe, and is generally the most common in captivity.The diet of the Eurasian Eagle Owl is quite easy to summarize; anything it can catch and subdue. Prey items range in size from beetles to deer fawns. Like most other birds of prey, these owls usually prey upon the most abundant and available food source. These are most often small mammals, such as rats, voles and hares. Birds, such as pheasants, waterfowl and seabirds are also common prey. Eurasian Eagle Owls are rather unusual in that they will also prey upon raptors and other species of owls. Foxes, bats, chamois, and domestic cats are even predated upon occasionally. The habitat in which the owls live often determines their dietary choices. Owls found on the mainland prey mostly on small mammals, while those bird found near coastal areas consume more birds and fish.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1284</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 2 (1998): MAR-APR 1998; 50-52</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1284/1263</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
