<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1082</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-03T02:39:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Estrildid Finches in Aviculture ... Crimson Seedcrackers Pyrenestes sanguineus</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buckley, Carol Anne</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buckley, Stash</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">When it comes to Crimson Seedcrackers, we do not recommend these to the collector of finches. We agree with Mike Fidler when he says too many socalled aviculturalists are merely consumers of birds, collecting the flashy and rare with no commitment to breed them. Cursed or blessed (depending upon your point of view) with both of these properties, the Crimson Seedcracker seems doomed in worldwide aviculture, short of divine intervention.There are currently three recognized species of seedcrackers although this is still open to debate. As far as we can determine, the Black-bellied Seedcracker Pyrenestes ostrinus is already absent from American aviculture. However, the Riverbanks Zoo, under the guidance of Bob Siebels, did an excellent job of breeding these birds and had a viable self-sustaining population going. Unfortunately, this population no longer exists due to no fault of their own.The second species, the Lesser Seedcracker Pyrenestes minor has not been imported into this country.The third, the Crimson Seedcracker Pyrenestes sanguineus is currently free from import restrictions and is being imported by those who are knowledgeable enough to keep it alive. This is a stunning species. You may consider the Peters' Twinspots Hypargos niveoguttatus to be red or even the Red-headed Parrot Finches Erythrura psittacea to be red, but these pale in comparison to the intensity of the Crimson Seedcracker's red coloration. Offset by the chocolate colored breast and its chunky size, it is truly a breathtaking species. In fact, when viewed under Vita-lites, the intensity of the red almost hurts your eyes.The Crimson Seedcracker has developed an almost mystical following, and keepers and so-called breeders of this bird have developed inflated egos. When we strip away the veneer of self-generated hype, we can find no qualified private breeders of the species, either now or in the past, in this country or abroad.This is an extreme claim but we challenge anyone to offer us proof to the contrary. Breeding seems invariably to be a matter of accident as opposed to diligent hard work to produce generation after generation.We do, however, tip our hats to the hard work and perseverance of Ben Cooper, a dedicated breeder who is putting forth a great effort to produce a viable, self-sustaining colony. Although he is working with only one generation from wild-caught, we feel his unwavering efforts will produce results in the long run.So what is the big deal about breeding this bird? Birds offered for sale anywhere in the world are wild-caught specimens. If a so-called breeder tells you he is. selling domestics, be very skeptical and insist upon proof. Remember, people will tell you whatever they think you want to hear in order to sell you their birds.Seedcrackers are by nature very shy...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1082</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 5 (1996): SEPT-OCT 1996; 44-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1082/1061</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
