<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1499</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:51:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Member Shines at the Great American Bird Show</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The 14th annual Kaytee™ GreatAmerican Bird show was held in beautifulSan Juan, Puerto Rico on October3, 1999. Held at the magnificent SanJuan Grand Beach Resort and Casino,the weather was perfect and the hospitalityof the host club, Organizationde Aves Exoticas, Inc., was overwhelming.In fact, they made it possibleto have two days of judging andawarded double prizes. The GreatAmerican Bird show is the only nationalshow that gives cash prizes in additionto the standard awards.There were a total of nine divisionswhich included canaries, finches, softbills,cockatiels, budgies, lovebirds,and parrots. Participating societiesincluded the National Finch andSoftbill Society, American CockatielSociety, National Colorbred Society,Society of Parrot Breeders andExhibitors, African Lovebird Societyand International Parrotlet Society. Atotal of 1,756 birds were exhibited.The American Federation ofA viculture gives an award at both theGreat American Bird Show and theNational Cage Bird Show for the bestbird in the show that has been bred andbanded by an AF A member. This year'swinner (1999) for the Great American isrenowned Cockatiel breeder, PhillipFeret. Mr. Feret took first place in Cockatielswith a fabulous lutino Cockatielhen. She also turned out to be the secondbest bird in the entire show.Congratulations on a job very welldone, Phil, and thank you for showingand for supporting the AmericanFederation of Aviculture. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1499</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 1 (2000): Jan-Feb 2000; 55-56</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1499/1476</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
