<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/695</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:00:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Jambu Fruit Dove</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bent, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Jambu Fruit Dove (Ptilinopus jambu) is a member of an Old World branch of the large family Columbidae. This branch is sometimes referred to as the sub-family Treroninae, the fruit pigeons and fruit doves (Peters 1937). The fruit doves of the genus Ptilinopus are found in the Australasian fauna! region. Most species are predominantly green in color, with bands and patches of contrasting color and pink or purple caps (Goodwin 1983; see color plate in Skutch 1991). The Jambu Fruit Dove has a fairly wide distribution in the wild. It inhabits forests and other wooded areas in the Malay Peninsula, Sumatra, Bor- neo, and nearby smaller islands. It is at least partly migratory, often coming to grief by landing near lighthouses, on ships, or in cities (Goodwin 1983). Despite occurring in a populous region of Asia and being described in regional bird guides (Smythies 1960; King and Dickinson 1975), little is known of courtship displays or other nesting behavior in the wild. Roberts 0991) provides excellent descriptions of some courtship behaviors and some displays at the Memphis Zoo and Aquarium; however, since their birds did not build their own nests no description of nest building was included. The Chicago Zoological Society (Brookfield Zoo) received its first pair of Jambu Fruit Doves in May of 1987. The birds were imported from Thailand, with the male estimated to be two years old on the basis of his plumage. After the loss of the female the male bird was sent to the St. Louis Zoo in early 1988 on a breeding loan. He was returned to Brookfield in early 1989 and paired with a new wildcaught female. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/695</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 1 (1994): JAN-FEB 1994; 8-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/695/678</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
