<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1063</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:21:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Large Macaws</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elgas, Bob</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Throughout the world there are more than 350 distinct species of parrots. Wher&amp;gt;. compared with the eight species of swans, or the 15 species of cranes, it is obvious that the psittacine family is large. Not only are parrots colorful but many are spectacular. Among the most impressive are the macaws. These large, long tailed, brightly colored birds are truly inspirational. It was once said that a macaw was the Rolls Royce of the parrot world. Few would object to the comparison.The future of many parrots, including a number of macaws, is in jeopardy. Already many are gone. The Cuban, or Little Red Macaw, was exterminated more than 100 years ago. The Spix's Macaw, Cyanopsitta spixii may no longer exist in the wild. The few that have been preserved in captivity are, unfortunately, too frequently maintained as single individuals having no association with others of their own kind, thus with no opportunity to breed and perpetuate the species. Sadly they can be referred to as "the living dead" for. essentially they have little future other than inevitable extinction. (Since Elgas wrote this, we have learned that there are two Spix's in the wild and 31 in captive breeding situations. Editor's note.)The Lear's Macaw Anodorhynchus leari which is similar to the Hyacinth Macaw, has a total wild population of approximately 60. Not only is their status in the wild precarious but they are very rare in captivity. With a population so small the future of the Lear's, at best, is somber. The Glaucous Macaw Anodorhynchus glaucus, a variety very similar to the Lear's, has been unrecorded for years, and indeed may already be extinct.There is considerable concern for the Hyacinth Anodorbyncbus hyacinthinus which is the largest macaw, and indeed the largest of all parrots. It is considered the most magnificent of the psittacine family. Historically, Hyacinth Macaws existed in vast numbers. More recently, however, populations have declined dramatically. So much so that there is concern that wild populations could be exterminated within the foreseeable future. As might be imagined contributing factors, among others, have been habitat destruction and illegal capture for the pet trade. As a result of their spectacular appearance and gentle nature (they are frequently referred to as "the gentle giants" of the macaw world), they have always been highly sought after. Hyacinths are rather well established in captivity, and are being bred with reasonable frequency. If breeding programs are properly managed these splendid birds could become well enough established to ensure their survival. As is true with any rare species, captive reared offspring should not be sold as pets, but should be placed in appropriate breeding facilities.Another species which is not abundant is the Buffon's, or Great Green Macaw Ara ambigua. Its natural range is somewhat restricted, being confined to areas of Central America and portions of western South America. Because its plumage is similar to that of the Military Macaw Ara militaris, it is frequently misidentified as being a member of that species. Although the plumage is similar, there are important differences. The Buffon's is substantially larger than the Military. Both birds are basically green. However, the Buffon's is more brightly colored, being a handsome yellow green as opposed to the darker tones of the Military. During years past, when importations were allowed, Buffon's Macaws were occasionally entered into the country. They did not generate special interest, and were often sold as Militaries. As recently as a dozen or so years ago importers offered them for as little as $300, certainly a much different price than that prevailing today. Recently there has been an escalation of interest in them, and a number of breeders are successfully rearing young. Hopefully, it might be possible to eventually estab- lish self-sustaining populations. It is as yet unclear if the captive population is sufficiently large to maintain a viable gene pool.The Military Macaw, as described above, is a smaller and less brightly colored cousin of the Buffon's Macaw. Although the two are similar in appearance, each is considered a separate species. The name Military is because of the green coloration which is similar to that of military uniforms. They have been kept in captivity for many years, and have frequently bred. They have never enjoyed the same popularity as other macaws, partially because they are less brightly colored than some and, perhaps, because they have sometimes been described as having a dull personality. I find this inappropriate since the Militaries with which I have been associated have been anything but dull. In my own home, living on a large stand, is "Thumper," a wonderfully exciting Military Macaw who is Mr. Personality Plus. There isn't a youngster in our community who doesn't know Thumper, and who is not familiar with the assortment of entertaining tricks he has perfected. Thumper loves recognition, and after completing his repertoire he hangs by his toenails and claps his wings vigorously, encouraging everyone to applaud. Personality? Thumper is loaded with it. Don't sell Military Macaws short.Although Militaries are still being reared in captivity, in view of declining populations there needs to be a greater emphasis on captive breeding.Of particular interest is the Bluethroated or Caninde Macaw Ara glaucogularis. Until recently they were not well know. Outwardly they resemble Blue and Gold Macaws, and it is probable they stem from a common ancestor. They are smaller than Blue and Golds, and have significantly different head markings. They are primarily native to Bolivia, which is also the southernmost range of Blue and Gold Macaws.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1063</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 5 (1996): SEPT-OCT 1996; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1063/1043</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
