<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2519</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-14T12:27:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Pesquet's Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cunningham, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Watchbird editorial staff is pleased to present to its readers significant information on an unusual parrot species - the Pesquet's Parrot (Psittrichas fulgidus). This remarkable species, very un-parrotlike in appearance, has always been uncommon in captivity. The following two successful accounts are from two different continents using, in many ways, different management techniques. This species has seldom been reproduced in captivity, the first being in Europe in 1977. The Los Angeles Zoo in 1980 was the first in North America. Hopefully, aviculturists can use some of the following information with many of their own common species of parrots, gaining some insight into the dedication and often difficult complexities it takes to rear some of the unusual types. The Pesquets Parrot (Psittrichas fulgidus), sometimes called the vulture-headed parrot, is a primitive and isolated form of psittacine. Its plumage is black with varying shades of brownish grey, except for the lower belly, wing coverts and underwing coverts which are bright scarlet. The facial area is bare (it is believed to facilitate cleaning after a messy meal). Males also have a small red patch behind the eye. Found in the mountain forests of New Guinea, it feeds on soft fruits, biossorns, nectar and possibly some msects. A far reaching, piercing call enables it to be heard for long distances in the thick jungle growth. Although not an endangered species, it is rare to collections in the United States.The Los Angeles Zoo acquired two pairs of imported birds in 1977 and a third pair of imports from Cincinnati Zoo in 1980. The adults were fed a diet of grapes, apple, banana, cooked yam, raw ground horsemeat, lettuce and hard-boiled egg. The pairs were housed in hexagonal enclosures 18 feet across and 26 feet tall. Large palm logs were supplied as possible nesting sites.By our observations, the female only chips away at the inside of the nest log, bringing wood pieces out trapped in her feathers which she then shakes off. The nest log is hollowed out up to a depth of eightfeet. Two eggs are laid and incubated by the female alone. The male is very protective and aggressive but does not assist in the work. After the eggs are laid, the female again begins to chip away at the interior of the nest. This time she leaves the chips in the nest. This behavior would allow for better drainage in case of some flooding and also a cleaner nest. By fledging time, the chicks are up fairly close to the nest hole.After several infertile clutches and unsuccessful hatchings, a chick was successfully parent reared inJanuary of 1980. Incubation appeared to be done entirely by the female, but the male was very protective and aggressive. The parents dramatically increased their intake of hard boiled eggs while rearing the chick. At 105 days of age, the chick left the nest. It was unable to fly, but did eat on its own. It never did appear to have full strength and died at 21 months of age of undetermined causes.The Pesquets had been successfully raised in Europe in 1977, but this was a first for the United States.In May of 1980, a clutch of eggs was pulled for artificial incubation from another pair. One chick was subsequently hatched and handfeeding was attempted. This chick died at eight days of age. In January of 1981, it became necessary to attempt hand-feeding again. A closer look at the diet preferred by the parents produced a new hand-feeding formula. This new chick was successfully reared and was totally independent at the age of 75 days. The weaning period, unlike most psittacines, was non-existent. One day it was being fed and the next it was not. (A record of its weight gain and a feeding schedule is found elsewhere in this article.) Unlike its parent-reared counterpart, this chick was always strong and healthy.1982 was a non-productive year plagued by infertile eggs, unhatched fertile eggs and dead chicks.In 1983, a puree' mixture of soaked dog kibble, corn, celery, spinach, banana, broccoli, grapes, apple, raw yam, carrot, orange, honey and a vitamin-mineral supplement was added to the original diet at an equal ratio. When the birds are rearing chicks, they are fed two parts puree' to one part hard mixture. Nest logs that would make inspection easier Nest LogDiagram of nest log designed by Lynda Paul and Dennis Thurslund. Measurements are shown in centimeters. It was designed to allow easy observation and cleaning between uses. It can be plugged by placing a smaller log inside, giving the birds new material to excavate.The top section is solid, as is the bottom section. The two center sections are hollowed out, leaving a 10 cm. thick wall. A nest hole was cut in the second piece from the top and an observation door cut in the third piece from the top. The bottom was left solid for the birds to dig out. This is the section that can be plugged as necessary. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2519</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 2 (1990): APR-MAY 1990; 56-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2519/2489</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
