<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2050</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-29T05:29:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Mew Lory Society</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Lory Society is being formed to fill an important avicultural gap. All persons having lories or an interest in them are invited to join at $9.00 per year in the U.S. and $11.00 overseas.The primary purpose of the Lory Society is to aid and abet the increase of the Jory populations in captivity. The main effort toward this end will be the annual Jory census taken by the Lory Society and forwarded to the A.F.A. Annual Bird Census under Larry Shelton. As always, this data is confidential.This Jory census is extremely important as it will compile the complete gene pool of captive lories and will help greatly in pairing up unmated birds that are sitting alone here and there.A further service of the Lory Society is a bi-monthly newsletter that will contain a wealth of data pertaining to lories and lorikeets. Articles will be written by the most authoritative Jory breeders in the world and much information will be exchanged by all of the members of the society. Each member will be urged to share his or her knowledge and experience. The newsletter will also have a "for sale, trade, wanted" column that members can use at no charge for now.There are 55 species in the sub-family Loridae in the wild. It is not known just how many species are in captivity but access to the wild birds is drying up. It is imperative that we establish self sustaining captive populations of the lories we now have or in a few years these most beautiful birds will disappear from aviculture.Please send your full name, address, and phone number along with your charter-membership dues ($9.00 U.S.A., $11.00 overseas) to Roland Cristo, 11130 Edgewood Rd., Auburn, Ca. 95603.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2050</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 6 (1981): DEC-JAN 1981; 4</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2050/2021</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
