<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2892</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-09T18:14:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Exotic Pheasants. Captive Management and Propagation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ollson, Mickey</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Pheasants are one of the most popular and colorful of all display birds. For centuries their exotic appearance, along with relative ease of captive management, have made them common in most avicultural and zoological collections.No other group of birds has made such an impact on the social and economical history of mankind.since domestic poultry are descendant of the junglefowl, themselves members of the pheasant family. Game Pheasants have been hunted for centuries both in their native distribution and as transplanted sport bird for western man. Few zoo visitors fail to have at least a limited knowledge of what a pheasant is, as they have affected the lives of most people, serving as food source, sport or as display birds in parks and gardens.There are 16 genera comprising 48 recognized species of Pheasants. In some species there are numerous subspecies or races bringing the number of forms to about 150.All of the pheasants, including peafowl and junglefowl, are found in Asia except the Congo Peacock of Africa.During the past 50 years radical changes have taken place in much of Asia which have severely decimated wild populations of many species of pheasants. Human over-population, deforestations, military conflict, coupled with the fact that pheasants are considered good eating and are very colorful, account for the reduction in numbers of wild population.Political upheaval, over-population and poverty in many Asian countries make protection of rare species in the natural population almost impossible. Therefore, it is most important to maintain a viable, productive population in captivity of these disappearing forms.Fortunately, most species can be propagated successfully in zoos and private collections if a few essential considerations are given priority. These include:1. Suitable climatic conditions for thespecies.2. Proper, adequate environment.3. Adequate nutritious diet.I would like to discuss some of the more exotic, rare pheasants, their history, captive management and propagation methods.Most of the species listed as endangered or threatened are receiving attention in captivity and success is being attained with many of these.The Edward's Pheasant is a small and beautiful bird first discovered in 1895 with a small distribution in central Vietnam near Hue (Way). It was first imported in 1925 to France by Dr. Delacour, when he brought some 15 individuals to his collection. It was successfully propagated and distributed to zoo's and aviculturists in Europe and America. But recently it has become increasingly difficult to breed and abnormalities in plumage are appearing. Since these birds are likely extinct in the natural distribution, the World Pheasant Association has recently started a Stud Book under the direction of Dr. Tim Love! to attempt to random pair birds as much as possible. To date, 240 birds in 93 collections have been identified and I urge any collections with Edward's to participate in this Stud Book project.Swinhoe Pheasants, a closely related species to Edward's is a success story for captive propagation. An inhabitant of the interior of Taiwan, it was extremely rare in its' native range. First imported to Europe in the 1860's it has bred in captivity extremely well and was one of the most commonly kept pheasants until the Endangered Species Act of 1973 discouraged its' captive propagation. In 1967, 30 captive raised Swinhoe' s were sent to Taiwan to be re-introduced into their natural habitat in a forest area controlled by the Taiwan National University. More have been sent since the Taiwanese government has also propagated some in captivity to be released and these birds are once again becoming well established.Also closely related is the Salvadoris Pheasant of the interior of South Sumatra. Three were imported into France in 1939 only to be destroyed by the Second World War before propagating. In 1976, they were successfully propagated in Europe, a first captive breeding, and in 1977 were reared in New York in Mr. Charles Sevilles' collection.Fireback Pheasants also are inhabitants of the low lying jungle areas of South East Asia. The most common is the Siamese Fireback which is well established in captivity in both Europe and America.The Malayan Crested and Bomean Crested Firebacks are beautiful birds which have become well established in the past few years in American aviculture.The Crested Fireback Pheasants have been imported several times but seem to be more delicate and have never propagated well. There are very few in captivity today.The Wattled Pheasant from the interior of Borneo has recently been propagated in Mexico for the first time. It is hoped they will become more available as they are very striking birds which need to be established in captivity.All firebacks make excellent display birds as they are usually tame and in warm climates.quite hardy. In cold areas artifical heat is necessary.The Argus Pheasants are junglebirds found on the Malay Peninsula, Sumatra and Borneo. They have always been prized in collections because of their interesting display and beautiful long secondary feathers which grow four feet long on adult males.They lay only 2 eggs per clutch so large numbers are not reared and these birds have always been rare in captive collections.The Palawan Peacock Pheasant is another warm climate bird which has been decimated on the Island of Palawan by forest destructions. It has always been scarce in its range and very localized. Since the l930's there have been several importations and at present we have a fairly strong breeding stock in many collections. However, as with all members of the peacock pheasant tribe, the clutch size is only 2 eggs, so large numbers are not reared.The Hume's Bartailed Pheasants were first imported in the early l960's from their native Southeast Asia. Humes have extremely local distribution and are nowhere abundant. They have proven to be very easy to propagate in captivity and were well on their way to becoming common in captive collections before the l 973 passage of the Endangered Species Act. I received one of the first pairs imported into the U.S. in 1966 and in one year 22 were successfully reared with no major difficulties.The Mikado Pheasant inhabits the indigenous forests of the temperate zones of Taiwan. The Mikado has been declining during the last 25 years in Taiwan, however, it is being raised in some number in captivity. It prefers a colder climate than many pheasants and does not do well in warm climates.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2892</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 4 (1979): AUG-SEPT 1979; 39-41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2892/2876</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
