<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/702</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cockatiels The Perfect Parrot for Everyone</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vanlaningham, Luke</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">If you want a small hookbill that is aprolific breeder and popular as a pet,the Cockatiel is for you. Breeding andraising Cockatiels is a great way to"get your feet wet" with raising exoticbirds and at the same time make a littlemoney while doing so. The Cockatielcan be considered a "bread andbutter" bird. They are always thereproducing babies, both under favorableand unfavorable conditions.Cockatiels are found throughoutAustralia, except for the eastern seaboard.The gray Cockatiel is found inthe wild, while many mutations arenow available due to artificial selectionsmade by man. Although thereare many mutations of Cockatiels, thepied, cinnamon, pearl and lutino arethe most common. There is also thecinnamon-pied, pearl-pied and cinnamon-pearl-pied. In addition, whitefacemutations have recently explodedin popularity. The white facecomes with the same mutations as thenormal Cockatiels: pearl white face,pied white face, cinnamon pied whiteface, etc. Albino Cockatiels are oftenconfused with the lutino. The albinois a mutation of the whiteface and isexclusively white with red eyes. Thelutino also has red eyes but has moreyellow in its color and has an orangecheek patch. An easy way for the beginnerto recognize the differencebetween a normal Cockatiel and awhite face Cockatiel is knowing thatthe normal Cockatiel has orange cheek patches while the white face has no orange cheek patches.There are so many theories andpractices concerning sexing Cockatielsthat it can become confusing. Iwill concentrate on what works bestfor me. I attempt to sex Cockatiels thatare at least six months old, but theolder they are, the easier they are tosex. At six months, the gray, cinnamonand pearl male birds will moltand grow yellow feathers on their ·heads. The pearl male will also losethe pearl markings and become like agray Cockatiel. The hens will keep thesame coloring as immature birds. Theadult lutino can be sexed by catchingthe bird and checking under thewings and on the tail. Females willhave yellow bars on their feathers,while these are absent in the males.This is fairly accurate, but I have seena couple of birds that have had themarkings of the opposite sex.The pieds can also be sexed by themethod above (although it's not 100percent accurate), but I prefer ventsexing. The only problem with ventsexing is that it can be tricky. Usually,if the bird is a female you can fit yourindex finger between the pelvicbones, while the male's pelvic bonesare closer together. The problem withthis, though, is that females that arenot ready to lay have pelvic bonesthat are close together. I solve this byputting all my pieds in a large flightwith nest boxes when they are abouta year old. The females usually startlaying quickly, thus opening their pelvicbones. Remember, six months istl1e minimum age to sex Cockatiels;the older the Cockatiel, the easier it isto sex.A sure-fire way of sexing Cockatielsis to have them surgically sexed orchromosome sexed. However, chromosomesexing is expensive if dealingwith a large number of birds. Itcan be advantageous, though, to surgicallysex young birds that are keptback for breeding stock, in order tokeep only the birds wanted and to sellthe excess birds.I normally set Cockatiels up tobreed when they are at least a yearold. Cockatiels can either be bred asindividual pairs in single cages or colonybred in flights. I incorporate bothof these methods and find advantagesand disadvantages to both. I set theCockatiels up in the fall and let thembreed until the beginning of summer.I put the nest boxes in around the firstof September and pull the boxesaround late May. Our summers herein central California can be brutal sobreeding in the summer months isavoided. Cockatiels will usually breedyear-round if given the chance, so abreeding system based on your climatewould be advised. As mentionedabove, I give the birds threemonths off, during which I pull thenest boxes out of the cages andflights.I usually let new pairs of Cockatielspick their own mates. I do this byplacing an equal number of malesand females in a flight with severalnest boxes. Then it is up to my observationalskills and quickness to catchthe bonded pairs! Usually the pair canbe found in the box together, especiallyat dusk and dawn. If I am breedingfor a certain mutation it is sometimesunavoidable to have to pairbirds up "artificiallY:' This is done byputting the pair in an individual cagewith no nest box for at least a fewweeks in order for the pair to get acquainted.A nest box can then be installed.In colony breeding, four pairs ofCockatiels are placed in a flight thatmeasures 4' x 8' x 10'. Six nest boxesare hung toward the back of the flightin different locations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/702</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 19-20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/702/685</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
