<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1683</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:15:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">To Soar With Eagles</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Andrus, Brent</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"I arn the Eagle. I live in high country, in rocky cathedrals that reach to thesky Come dance on the west wind and touch on the mountain tops. Sailover the canyons and up to the stars. And reach for the heavens and hope for the future and all that you can be and not what you are." From the "The Eagle and the Hawk" by John Denver.The eagle has always symbolized majesty and high obtainment. At the Houston Convention last year the "To Soar With Eagles" AFA affiliated club membership contest and fund raiser was introduced. A packet containing the contest and fund raising information was mailed to all club delegates by the end of August.The American Federation of Aviculture's membership drive allowed it's affiliated clubs to earn money while striving for excellence in gaining membership for AFA. Each club could earn up to $S for each new member recruited and for each member it renewed. The contest ran from September 1 through December 31 of 2001.The TOP CLUB in recruiting new and renewing members receives recognition in the official journal of AFA the WATCHBIRD and will be awarded a plaque and have it's name inscribed on the permanent President's trophy which will be on display at the AFA conventions. The picture of the AFA President awarding the trophy to the top club will appear in the AFA Watchbird. In addition the 2nd and 3rd place clubs will also awarded plaques and be recognized in the AFA Watchbird. There are two categories of awards - one for clubs under SO members and one for clubs over SO members.I am pleased to announce the winners for 2001:Category A(over SO members)1st Arizona Seed Crackers 2nd Dallas Bird Society3rd Avicultural Society of AmericaCategory B(under SO members)1st San Diego Bird Breeders 2nd Arizona Bird club3rd Exotic bird Club of FloridaA special thanks to these clubs for participating: Arizona Avian Breeders Association, Arizona Avicultural Society, Arizona Bird Club, Arizona Seed Crackers, Avicultural Society of America, Avicultural Society of Tucson, Central Coast Avicultural Society, Charleston Bird Club, Companion Bird Club of Atlanta Dallas Bird Society Exotic Bird Club of Florida, Las Vegas Avicultural Society', Oklahoma Aviculru'ral Society, Parrot Breeders Association of Virginia, Pyrrhura Breeders Association, Reno Area Avian Enthusiasts, San Diego Bird Breeders, and Triangle Bird Club. The goal is to have this contest every year. Perhaps your club will "Soar with the Eagles" in 2002! ~ </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1683</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 1 (2002): Fourth Quarter 2001; 31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1683/1660</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
