<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/412</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Closed Banding Your Macaw</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abramson, Joanne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The decision to band your babybirds may originally be difficult foryou. All of us have heard stories overthe years about injuries to birds thathave open bands left on from quarantinestations. Years ago our vet warnedus about the problems associated withthese bands. He had seen multipleinjuries ranging from broken legs tomutilations and death associated withthem. After we listened to his stories, itseemed like the only humane thing todo was remove them. Since he checksall new birds, the bands are removed atthat time, along with routine bloodtests and cultures.In 1986, New York passed a lawrequiring all birds coming into the stateto be closed banded. While there weremixed feelings about the validity of thelaw, the fact remained that it was,indeed, a law and therefore had to beobeyed. Since I had several peoplewanting macaws in New York I dutifullyordered bands and started pullingmy birds at an earlier age in order toclosed band them. We specialize inbreeding the larger species of macaws,so they are closed banded between 16and 20 days (depending on the speciesand how long they are left with theirparents). At first this was a hassle. Mybreeding macaws are very capablebirds, eager to raise their own young,and doing a great job of it as well.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/412</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 4 (1988): AUG-SEPT 1988; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/412/399</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
