<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/634</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Prenatal Medical Management PART III</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clipsham, Robert C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Parent Hatched:Eggs left under the hen should bechecked for signs of pipping dailyand candled simultaneously. Parentsshould be evaluated prior to hatchfor behavioral patterns, such as sittingthe nest tightly and anxietylevels, as problem parents may notaccept chicks readily. Once the firstchick is hatched, close monitoring ofparenting is required to assure thatchicks are being brooded and fedduring the first 12 hours. An emptycrop at the end of 12 hours is reasonto pull chicks for artificial brooding.Subsequent chicks should be checkedjust as closely for good parenting.Any problems that are noted, such asabandonment, cannibalism, mutilationor stunting, dictate that a reviewof the environment and managementbe undertaken. Reasons that mayhave elicited poor chick care by pairsare often manmade. The followingitems should be reviewed by theranch manager:• boxes too hot (i.e., unprotectedfrom direct sun, poor ventilation,etc.)• chicks too cold (i.e., shallowshavings, poorly ventilated nest box)• irregular feeding of pairs by crew• disturbance of pairs by workersor other birds• nest box too shallow• (threat level unacceptable topair)•low ambient humidity (rare)Chick development under the henshould exceed that of hand raisedbabies for at least the first seven daysup to two weeks of age. Growth ratesshould be comparable from then onand any evidence of stunting ortrauma should be regarded as a seri-ous threat to the chicks and thosesurviving should be pulled until adiagnosis can be achieved. Parentsshould constantly groom chicks andhealthy babies should be completelyfree of feces and dried food. Anypresence of debris should sparkfurther investigation.Those parents that persist in abandoningchicks or mutilating themdespite changes in management maybe poor parents and culling must beevaluated as a legitimate solution if allother factors have been stabilized. Beaware that chicks that refuse to eatdue to chilling or illness may beattacked by the parents out of frustration.Species most often noted totraumatize chicks include macaws,Amazons and cockatoos. This prevalencemay represent temperament ora heavily represented portion of birdsbeing captive bred.The previous assumptions thatwild chicks grow and fledge moreslowly has been disproven by twofield surveys where Yellow-napedAmazons and Orange-front Conureshad growth curves similar to chicksin captivity. Wild Yellow-naped Amazonswere observed to be fed onlytwice a day (9:30 to 10:00 a.m. and6:00 to 6:30p.m.) and parent contactwas extremely limited during the firstseveral weeks of life, presumably todecrease the risk of predation. Otherobservations of wild hatched chicksinclude the presence of occasionalstress bars, slight dehydration andone incidence of fly strike in featherfollicles. These observations shoulddisperse some of the myths concerningthe retarded or acceleratedgrowth potential some aviculturistsfeel has been artificially altered incaptive breeding programs.Average daily weight gain inhandfed psittacines should be around15% for the first three to four weeksof life. However, this is an averageand higher weight gains may benoted in early weeks and lowerweight gains recorded later. Weightloss will be noted at the onset of theweaning phase (during the last twoto four weeks of hand feeding).Weight loss should average 10% to15% of the total body weight, but20% may be normal for some largespecies, particularly noted inmacaws. Particular caution should beexercised during the weaning processas it is physiologically stressfulto the baby.Hand Raised Offspring:Record keeping is of prime importancefor accurate hand care of psittacineoffspring. The rate of developmentis substantially greater duringthe neonatal period than mammals oreven precocial birds due to their highlevel of dependency and relativelyunder developed state at hatch.Daily records should include theease or difficulty of hatching, finalhatch date and embryonic age,weight (prefeeding), crop emptyrate, food volume accepted eachfeeding and day, diet used and a completephysical examination and workup.The physical examination shouldbe conducted with clean, warmhands on an insulated surface, suchas a towel, as altricial chicks chill easilydue to their high metabolic rate,lack of feathering and small bodymass. Sick babies chill even morequickly as their thermostasis may bedisrupted. The physical examinationshould include such environmentalfactors as the brooder, bedding material,ambient humidity, thermometerplacement and quality, sanitationprotocol and all clutchmates.The attitude should be carefullynoted for a vigorous vocal responseto tactile stimulation, including arapid and sustained pumping reflexwhen a finger is introduced into theoral cavity. Weak or cold chicks havea reduced pump reflex. However,species variation must -be consideredas well as the hatching order in aclutch. Some babies, such as Eclectusparrots, may have a generally moresubdued attitude than a macaw orconure of a similar age. Youngerchicks will be less vigorous than thatof clutchmates hatched even one ortwo days earlier.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/634</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 43-46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/634/617</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
