<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2617</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-18T16:12:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">New Dominant Silver Mutation of Europe</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A tremendous breakthrough has finally occurred in the realm of cockatiel color genetics. Until recently, the only recognized color mutations to occur in cockatiels have been either sex-linked (Lutinos, Pearls or Cinnamons) or recessive mutations (Pied, Fallow, Recessive Silver, or Whiteface). The wild-type Normal Grey has always been dominant to both the sex-linked and recessive varieties, and any of their combined combinations. Now, however, a new development has given birth to the first dominant mutation, aptly named the Dominant Silver.The Dominant Silver first appeared in the United Kingdom, bred in the aviaries of Mr. Terry Cole. By 1988, Cole established the strain and bred the Dominant Silvers in with many of the existing color varieties to form several new cross-mutations. However, this was not only a "first" for a new variety of cockatiel, and a new mode of inheritance, but it was a "first" for the United Kingdom as a producer of a new cockatiel mutation to date.According to Cole's description, the color of a Dominant Silver is a pastel-silver shade of grey, with the color being somewhat darker in the area of the head and neck, creating the appearance of a "skullcap'.' He feels the yellow pigment is not affected, although it appears that perhaps the yellow as well as the orange cheek patches are brighter. I would speculate that this could be due to the modification of the grey pigment,· allowing the yellow and orange lipochromes to be more easily seen.It is always easy to tell if one has a true Dominant Silver in that the eyes are always black and the legs are dark grey. In contrast, the Recessive Silver is primarily a red-eyed mutation, where a modification of the melanin pigment occurs to produce a steel, or silvery-grey, to a fawnish-brown tone. Individuals may vary quite a bit in color and while many Recessive Silvers have red eyes, others can acquire melanin pigment and so the eyes may, in fact, appear more brown.It is interesting to note that apparently when chicks hatch, there appears to be no difference between Dominant Silvers and Normals, with both having the usual yellow down feathers. However, as pin feathers erupt and they begin to color up, the differences become quite noticeable. The Dominant Silvers can be identified in the nest from their Normal Grey siblings by a light grey, brownishbrick color, along with the darker grey cap of the head, dark legs and black eyes.After the first juvenile molt, the cocks experience quite a spectacular transformation and acquire a beautiful silver-grey plumage. However, the hens remain almost the same, perhaps a little brighter and greyer. Through selective breeding, Cole has produced hens which, over the years, have become much lighter and therefore resemble the cock more closely, including the presence of a skullcap, dark legs and black eyes. Therefore, it can be said that the young do take on the color of the hen.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2617</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 1 (1991): FEB-MAR 1991; 21-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2617/2587</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
