<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/531</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">When Prohibition Isn 't Enough</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomsen, Jorgen B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I often think about the HyacinthMacaw as a macaw designed by birdtrappers:the largest and perhaps themost spectacular of all parrots, andalso the most absurdly easy to locateand catch. Indisputably, Hyacinths areespecially vulnerable to capture andshooting because they are large andconspicuous, noisy, intrinsically fearless,curious, sedentary, predictable,and have extremely specialized feedingbehaviors. A trapper can quicklylearn where a given group of macawssleeps, nests, feeds, and rests. A clevertrapper can determine regular flightroutes into and out of favorite trees,then strategically place nets to capturethe birds . And because theythrive on fallen palm fruits, Hyacinthscan even be enticed into traps on theground.The same qualities which make Hyacinth Macaws ideal prey for birdcatchersmake them perfect quarryfor aboriginal meat or featherhunters. One famous Kayapo' Indianhead-dress included the tail feathersof more than fifty of these charismaticblue parrots.The Hyacinth Macaws' specificfeeding requirements also make themsusceptible to habitat destruction.Their reliance on the fruit of certainpalm trees limits their ability to adaptto changing environments. Althoughthe palms on which Hyacinthsdepend for food are often sparedduring human agricultural activities(because they provide food forcattle), if those species of palms werecut and the rest of the habitat leftuntouched, all Hyacinth Macaws.would quickly perish.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/531</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 28-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/531/515</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
