<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/713</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the editor's desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dear Mr. Thompson:The article titled "Iron Storage,"which appeared in your Aug/Septissue, was of considerable interest tome. The authors state that, "It is notknown whether this iron storage diseaseis a result of a heritable conditionof abnormal iron deposition whichoccurs regardless of iron level in thediet or is a response to chronic ingestionof excessive iron in the diet." Inthe well-studied iron overload diseasein humans (hemochromatosis), it isthe currently accepted belief that theinability to excrete iron is a geneticdefect. Changing the diet has littleimpact on the course of the disease.However, in many cases, the diseasehas been made considerably worse bythe attending physician failing to diagnosethe disease and further compoundingit by prescribing iron tablets.Humans who do not suffer fromgenetic hemochromatosis apparentlyhave a great tolerance for the excessivezeal of the iron wielding physician.If they did not, there would bemany more people with iron overloaddisease.This disease is easy to diagnose bysimply running a serum ferritin level.In humans, it is not uncommon tohave extremely high levels of ferritinby the time the patient is showingsymptoms; i.e., lameness, liver disease,heart disease, neuropathy, etc.Establishing normal levels in the concernedavian species should not be atall difficult and may even be available.It would seem to me that yourauthors should eliminate the birds sufferingfrom the genetic iron overloaddisease from their study. This wouldbe easy to do. They will probably find,as was discovered in humans, thatmost of the birds suffering from ironoverload do, indeed, have the geneticcondition. Of course, iron poisoningcould occur by ingestion of largeamounts of iron or by excessive irontherapy, but that is not too likely. Theonly really effective treatment is, ofcourse, phlebotomy on a regular basis. This works quite well and thefrequency can be reduced over timedepending on the serum ferritinlevels.Sincerely,M.L. Simmons, D.V.M., PresidentVeterinary Resources America, Inc.Parrot Conservation GroupP.O. Box 2200, Vero Beach, FL 32961Phone (407) 562-9745 I would like to thank Jack ClintonEitniearand the Board of Directors forbeing presented a Service Award formy efforts in Hurricane Andrew relief.However, I do not feel right beingsingled out for this award. I feel I wasjust the muscle (and not always thebrains) of a group of aviculturists whowere able to react immediately to thedevastation in South Dade County.Although donations from centralFlorida businesses, veterinarians andbird clubs were received, a largefinancial donation from Town andCountry Feathered Friends of Michiganbank-rolled the first relief trip. Atotal of 13 trips were made by DwightGreenberg and/or myself, includingfour trips before the "official" AFA and SOFAR relief efforts were felt in thedisaster area.We could not have done this withoutthe help of many individuals whoacted as our "procurement and supportcommittee." Debbie Clifton, BethGreenberg, Starr Kirchhoff, DianaSkalsky, Bob Smith and Pamela Willishelped our effort immensely, keepingthe donations coming and taking careof any special orders that we received.Sally Zonner, at Avian Specialties, andRenn Danzer, at Sunshine Bird Supply,made sure no vehicle went intothe disaster area unless it was loadedcompletely with supplies.Our effort was helped by a local"hospitality committee." KathleenHarring and Rick Jordan at Luv ThemBirds, though disaster victims themselves,supplied lodging, excellentfood, security and strong drink to anybodycoming into the area to help.Again, I appreciate receiving thisaward, but I must accept it on behalfof the many people (named and unnamed)who made this effort soeffective.Sincerely,Morgan Knox</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/713</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/713/696</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
