<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2571</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-16T21:48:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Australian Lorikeets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sindel, Stan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In Australia, there are six species and one subspecies of lorikeets. The subspecies, the Red-collared Lorikeet, Tricboglossus baematodus rubritorqu is, is quite distinct and, for avicultural purposes at least, I feel it should be dealt with as a separate lorikeet.When one considers the vastness of the Australian continent and the extensive climatic and habitat variations, and the fact that the nearest neighbor, New Guinea, has a wealth of lorikeets, it is surprising how few species we have in Australia.All Australian species of lorikeets have extensive ranges, all are doing well within their range, and some species are extending their range, perhaps with the help of aviary escapees.The lorikeets' presence in an area is totally dependent on the food source. It has often been recorded how the arrival of lorikeets in an area coincides to the day with the flowering of a particular species of native tree. Some species are so reliable in their arrival to and departure from a certain area that they could be termed migratory. Because of this dependence on flowering and fruit bearing trees and shrubs, all species are mainly nomadic, but there are some resident populations in certain areas, of the Rainbow and Sealey-breasted Lorikeets, where a constant food supply is available. This situation is particularly noticeable around our cities where the native food diet is supplemented by the fruits, flowers and seed of introduced flora.I have been able to observe all species in their native habitat, and have bred all species in captivity.Rainbow Lorikeet (Tricboglossus baematodus baematodus). Length 12'.' The sexes are alike in this species.The Rainbow Lorikeet ranges continuously from the northeastern, through the eastern, to the southeastern half of Australia. It is a very extensive range, and includes a great variation in habitat from rainforest to dry, open Eucalypt forest, to mallee scrubs and mangrove swamps.Their diet, like their habitat, is quite variable, but mainly consists of pollen, fruits, seeds and vegetable matter, plus a few insects.This species of lorikeet is doing particularly well in the wild. It has adapted to human habitation, and may be seen on the outskirts of all towns and cities within its range, and is very common around Sydney.In captivity, this lorikeet is particularly hardy and, unfortunately, because of this it is often kept on a seed diet which usually results in the bird taking fits or suffering paralysis of the legs due to dietary deficiencies. When fed a good, balanced diet, they are very active, long-lived aviary birds.Rainbow Lorikeets are free breeders and have been known to rear four broods per year, each brood taking three months. They lay two eggs. The incubation period is variable, but takes approximately 23 days, and the chicks fledge in about eight weeks. I prefer to use a nest box for all lorikeets as cleaning, which is often necessary during the rearing period, is easier than in the case of a log. I use fine wood shavings for nesting material, and find it is reasonably absorbent and easy to clean from the box.Incubation is carried out by the female in all Australian lorikeets.Red-collared Lorikeet (Trichoglossus haematodus rubritorquis ). Length 12'.' The sexes are alike in this species.The Red-collared Lorikeet ranges over the northwestern section of Australia. I have seen this species mainly in open forest country, but it may be found wherever food is available.Their diet is similar to the Rainbow Lorikeet but, due to their tropical range, their food is more of a tropical nature. They are particularly fond of the fruit of the cultivated mango.I saw this species constantly in large numbers, so I would say their status in the wild is good.In captivity, this species is similar to the Rainbow Lorikeet, perhaps not quite as hardy or quite as good a breeder, but it is still capable of rearing four broods a year. They lay two eggs and the incubation period and rearing time is similar to the Rainbow Lorikeet.Sealey-breasted Lorikeet (Trichoglossus chlorolepidotus).Length 9-1 /2:' The sexes are alike in this species.This lorikeet ranges over northeastern and eastern Australia in forest and scrub land, and most habitat where there is flowering trees. It is often seen in mixed flocks in the company of Rainbows.Their diet is similar to that of Rainbow Lorikeets with a little more preference for pollen and some native seeds.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2571</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 5 (1990): OCT- NOV 1990; 26-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2571/2541</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
