<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/773</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:01:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Red Siskin Project Boosted by Two Talented Artists</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The AFA would like to thank the following two artists who donated their work to the AFA's Red Siskin Project. Signed and numbered prints of both their paintings are offered for sale at the AFA office. Call (602) 484-0931 or write to P.O. Box 56218, Phoenix AZ 85079-6218 for costs and information. All proceeds go to the Red Siskin Project. A gifted artist from childhood, Mark Wade cultivated his talents in Grand Rapids, Michigan at the Kendall School of Design. In 1981, he accepted a position in the art department of the Nazarene Publishing House. Finishing coursework in graphic design at the Kansas Area Vocational Technical School, he then opened "Out On a Limb Studio" located at 5435 Reeds Road in Mission, Kansas, phone (913) 262-4492. Mark's studio specializes in illustration in a wide range of art media and also desktop publishing. He and his wife Linda and seven year old daughter Lauren have been involved in numerous charitable projects including Siskin Summit '93 and the Armenian Earthquake Relief effort. • James' 'Jay" Hamilton Fullmer was born in Sauk City, Wisconsin. He has travelled extensively and lived many places in Europe and Asia when young before his family settled in Wisconsin. His interest in wildlife and nature developed at an early age; he has been drawing as long as he could hold a pencil. Jay studied Biology at the University of Wisconsin-Stevens Point and worked for one school year assisting with the red siskin breeding facility. He has done numerous illustrations and artwork for the Biology Department. The aviary exhibit murals completed in 1991 are his largest and best work. The murals depict Old World and New World rain forest grading into African savannah to compliment the variety of finches housed there. Jay has been most influenced by the work of Robert Bateman, and bas worked with John Seerey Lester and Carl Brenders. Jay is currently pursuing a freelance career, specializing in painting wildlife. "The most important part of my work is to use it to educate people about wildlife and endangered species and to elevate their awareness of the importance of conserving our natural world." </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/773</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 2 (1994): MAR-APR 1994; 60</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/773/756</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
