<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2910</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-10T17:00:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dear Mr. Dingle,Having handled and collected snakes for the last 35 years, I have yet to handle one that is slimy, poisonous or not. I feel you have badly maligned all snakes and you owe them an apology. Only humans can be as low as the people you describe.In answer to "name withheld" (June/ July Watchbird Editor's column), when I say red eyed, I mean like an albino, i.e. lacking the ability to produce melanism in the eye. I don't believe you could produce this bird in a fawn, since this would need melanism for color. Yes, you could see the difference between a normal copper-bar and the red-eye at fifteen feet. In hand examination, the pupil is black and the iris red. In the red-eyed, the whole eye is red at fledging and as an adult the pupil and iris are different shades of red, as in the adult albino cockatiel.I feel that this mutation is an albino, since the original term referred to an animal lacking the ability to produceexpress melanism. This gene can be bred to the standard white to produce a totally white red-eyed bird, also an albino.I hope I have answered all Mr. name withheld's questions.Sincerely, Joseph Lannom Jr.Thanks for your response, Joe.When I spoke of snakes (slimy ones at that), I was alluding to the serpent in the third chapter of Genesis, the same snake who beguiled Eve. Like that ancient serpent, our contemporary crook is intent upon beguilement and deception. I meant no offense to your lovely snakes crawling about in the grass. My apologies to all innocent serpents. Dear Sir:Recently someone told me a story about a man who was cooking with teflon pans and, though the label warns against it, had the heat up too high. His parrots were in the other room with some canaries and other birds. They all died of what was called "teflon poisoning". If you could supply more information of this type of poisoning I believe it could benefit everyone.Thank you.John L. Gagne'J &amp;amp; R PARR OT RANCHI have made several inquiries about "teflon poisoning" but to no avail so far. The people I spoke with had never heard of it. If any of our readers has available evidence either for or against "teflon poisoning" we would be most pleased to publish it. Dear Sheldon Dingle:I am addressing this letter to you for I feel you will understand my misgivings concerning the up-coming National AF.A Convention in Florida. I was truly shocked - couldn't believe what I read - when I saw that the "entertainment" for the banquet - which is the high-light of the whole convention - would be "Alba Ballard and her birds".Doesn't anyone know or doesn't anyone care that she cuts off the poor birds wings and tails, feathers (that is), in order to fit them into the darling little hand made costumes?? She is praised and written about and praised some more for all her expertise, her love of birds, her understanding, etc. I think that what she does is obscene.There was a colorful folder enclosed with the convention literature about Parrot Jungle. This shows cockatoos, macaws, etc. riding bikes, doing tricks, raising the flag - no costume, no play acting - just birds - as birds - enjoying themselves.If you have ever owned a Caique you would know what delightful little clowns they are - they can entertain you for hours playing with a tin can or a baby rattle - they are inquisitive, sensitive and utterly loveable. They don't need any dumb costume to put on a show.Alba Ballard, rather than showing her love of birds in putting on her costumed show, is promoting Alba Ballard. If you really loved your birds you would not subject them to what she does.If I had intended attending this Convention this item itself would keep me away. I would not cross the street to see her.Sincerely, Catherine C. Tyler As you well know, the A.F.A 1979 convention is over. Unfortunately I was unable to attend (rumor has it that I am too shy, that I'm in the midst of aviary construction, and that I'm too poor - all of which are true) and thus I didn't see the Alba Ballard show that you are so against. The reports I have received were generally negative regarding birds dressed up like dolls - but then folks who like that sort of thing probably wouldn't talk to me anyway.Several thoughts cross my mind, though, and the first is that you should not be so f oafish as to miss the hundreds of really outstanding f ea tu res of a great convention just because you object to one program. If you are a starving person and have a sumptuous banquet set before you, don't abandon it just because there is spinach on your plate. My God, woman, just leave the spinach alone and partake of the other nourishment.Second, we live in a relatively free society and people are able to pursue their whims and fancies be they ever so foolish. No doubt there were people at the convention who actually liked Alba Ballard's dressed up birds. There is no accounting for taste. And there is more to Alba Ballard than just her doll birds. She has nurtured and cared for many hundreds of birds that were wounded, injured or otherwise distressed. I don't doubt that she really does love birds. It is just her way of public display that many of us don't care for.I am certain that the majority of A.F.A. members are fine aviculturists who are interested in the finer points of animal husbandry and who want to raise birds under the most natural conditions possible. They see birds as beautiful and fascinating creatures of nature and don't apply any anthropomorphic philosophy to them. Indeed, many of our members like birds more than they like people - and they are to be commended for their wisdom. Most aviculturists deem it a holy responsibility to help perpetuate in captivity the birds which are losing ground in the wild.I can imagine fine aviculturists and serious breeders fidgeting and squirming in their chairs while a pet bird informal dress cavorts about on the stage. I'm sure Mickey 01/son's discomfort was more entertaining to watch that the bedecked bird's antics. But even Mickey, fine gentleman and outstanding breeder that he is, showed good grace while Alba did her thing.Although your philosophy and mine tend to agree, I don't think we should dogmatically close our minds to other view points. I'd be interested in hearing from some of you folks who really enjoyed Alba's dressed up birds. Perhaps Alba herself will respond and broaden our understanding. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2910</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 5 (1979): OCT- NOV 1979; 41-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2910/2894</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
