<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1697</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:15:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Protect Your Rights</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AFA has found that almost all cities and towns, counties and most states have ordinances or laws regulating behavior and ownership responsibility for animals. Since each locality starts with its own set of ordinances and local laws, some research is required for your particular locality. Often these laws were written with dogs and cats in mind, especially city and county animal control ordinances, or pertain to livestock in state laws. Therefore, you will need to do some homework to prepare yourself to inform and educate your legislators, city council, or whoever is responsible for enacting laws in your area. The American Federation of Aviculture has developed this brochure as a quick reference guide.Be prepared as much as possible before you go to argue your cause but do not worry if you can not cite exact ordinance numbers, sections and paragraphs on every possible point. Do get as many of them as your can. Most concerned citizens are not lawyers. The important thing is that you are aware of what is being proposed and that you show up to voice your opinions.Bring as many people with you as possible and present an obviously united front. Know what you want to have happen before you get to the meeting and agree among yourselves on key issues. Do not be distracted from your main objective by side issues. Do not argue among yourselves in front of the opposition. It is extremely important to look like you are a cohesive group of responsible voters to people who have the power to outlaw birds.Decide before the meeting who will be the main spokesperson for your group. Encourage every other person to repeat one fact made by the main spokesperson. We do not want silent people to be counted as part of the opposttion. Individuals proposing restrictive legislation may range from the extreme fanatic who believes no one has the right to keep pets or use animal products, to people who have been misled by staged film propaganda to believe that they are saving birds and other animals from torture and a cruel death. Regardless of each person's beliefs or opinions, they have a right to express themselves. They do not have the right to impose their will on the rest of us. Do not be intimidated or afraid to tell your elected officials what you want. Always be polite to everyone. We want to be the reasonable, good citizens in any disagreement.Finally, please share your experiences with us. We need to build on your successes and learn from other failures. Keep a log of everything that happens; names, dates, events. We will use what each person has learned to help the next one. One of the chief arguments you will hear is regarding health and safety questions related to the keeping of birds. Psittacosis (more correctly called ornithosis) is usually the chief concern. The following facts may dispel the myths:1. This disease is endemic in the wild bird population in the United States. (University of Pennsylvania study showed 70% of pigeons in the city parks tested positive for psittacosis. Dr Joel Murphy estimates that "this bacteria is carried by 70% - 90% of wild pigeons and at least 100 other species of wild birds in North America without causing disease").2. Psittacosis is rarely diagnosed in people. This disease produces mild to strong flu-like symptoms in most people who do catch it. It is not generally a life-threatening disease and is easily treated with antibiotics.Birds Are NotAn Animal Control Problem Birds do not present a problem for Animal Control like dogs and cats do. Birds are not a threat to public safety. Birds do not require collecting of strays. Birds do not require housing and feeding of strayed or unwanted pets. Birds are not produced in sufficient quantities to require them to be euthanized as excess pets. Birds do not cost the city or its taxpayers anything. Indeed, most species of birds are difficult to breed, needing specific amounts of light, food, space, and temperature in order to reproduce. Most species of birds are not produced in sufficient quantities, period. Many species are in danger of becoming extinct.If you become aware of any situations that concern avian regulations either local, county, state, or federal level, please contact the AFA office at (816) 421-2473 or fax (816) 421-3214 for further assistance.Now that you have made the decision to become actively involved, what can you do to start? First, obtain the names, addresses and phone numbers of your state and local representatives. Then your next step is simple:At State LevelContact your state senator and representative via a certified letter. Request distribution of information regarding proposed legislation and changes in laws that pertain to keeping and breeding birds and animals.Phone your state senators or representative's office to determine how to contact your state's information bureau. Each state should publish each of the two documents listed below. Obtain one of each to keep yourself better informed.The Legislative Status which lists by title every bill introduced, giving its status in the legislative process. Check under titles such as Animals, Birds, Wild Animals, etc. If you think you see a bill that involves exotic animals issues, order a copy of the bill from the Bill Room if your state senator or representative can not provide you with a copy of the bill in a timely fashion.The State Register publishes every rule and regulation proposed for change and gives the period for comments. Check with your senator or representative for ordering information.(These may be in local libraries.) </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1697</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 1 (2002): Fourth Quarter 2001; 70-72</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1697/1674</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
