<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1262</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:33:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Convention '99 August 11-15 Denver</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he American Federation of Aviculture is pleased to announce the AF A's 25th Anniversary Convention in scenic Denver, Colorado. Convention '99 will be held at the newly renovated Adam's Mark Hotel, August 11-15, 1999.The Adam's Mark is located on the 16th Street Mall, a mile-long pedestrian promenade lined with shops, restau- rants, and entertainment. Shuttle buses run its length, providing easy access to all Downtown attractions. Denver, known as the Mile High City, has long been a popular gathering place for everyone.Celebrate AF A's Silver Anniversary at Convention '99. Denver is famous for lots of things, one being the climate. Denver has over 300 days of bright sunshine and during August has delightful temperatures in the mid 80s during the day and 60s in the evening. What great weather for all.Denver is located in Central Colorado with the famous Rocky Mountains as a background. The Mile High City is full of activities to meet all interests and all ages. There are many places to visit within walking distance or a short drive from the Adam's Mark. You can walk from the hotel to visit Coors Field (home of the Colorado Rockies), the Denver Art Museum, the U.S. Mint, or the State Capital. While on foot, stop at The Tabor Center, filled with 65 speciality shops, and Larimer Square, where you will find 28 shops, seven restaurants, two nightclubs, and one microbrewery. Just a short drive away is Mile High Stadium, home of the Super Bowl Champion Denver Broncos; McNichols Arena, home to the Denver Nuggets and the Colorado Avalanche; The Denver Zoo, including a giant indoor rainforest; Colorado's Ocean Journey, opening Spring '99; Denver Children's Museum; and Cherry Creek Shopping Center, home to 300 specialty stores, galleries, restaurants, coffee shops, and services all along tree-lined avenues.Denver is more than just snow. Did you know -- the 18th step on the State Capitol building is exactly one mile above sea level, the U.S. Mint in Denver makes over 5 billion coins each year, Denver gets more hours of sunshine per year than either Miami or San Diego, the Denver Zoo has more than 2,500 animals, Denver receives only 15 inches of annual precipitation.AFA plans to make its Silver Anniversary the best convention yet. This year don't miss out on on all the fun and excitement with the Super 25 Raffle, great speakers, awesome exhibitors, not to mention other bird lovers.See you in August!  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1262</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 1 (1999): JAN-FEB 1999; 58-59</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1262/1241</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
