<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3017</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-16T09:58:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Zebra Finch</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Crosby, Joseph M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The mighty little Zebra, native to Australia, but highly domesticated in all parts of the world, is known to almost all aviculturists.The Grey Zebra and its many mutations fill thousands of Aviaries. The Zebra being so prolific makes it possible for millions to be sold each year. Most aviculturists just raise Zebra's, after all "A Zebra is a Zebra!"To a small minority of Zebra breeders there is a good and bad type of Zebra; the good Zebra is one with style, class, good markings and color. I will try to bring forth this class and style of Zebra so that a few more of us may join the efforts to upgrade the quality of stock in our country.A Zebra should be bold throughout and of the "cob by" type, giving the bird a look of substance, wings evenly carried to the root of the tail. The head must be full and round with a slight recession at the neck with the back straightening out to a slight rise in the tail. The back should not be hollow as this gives the appearance of a swayback, nor the neck filled, as this gives the bird the look of a hunchback. Throat and chest should be full.The cock should have distinct chest bars not less than I /8" wide. The chestnut side flanks should be prominent, extending from wing butts to the end of the rump and should have clearly defined white spots. The beak should be coral red (hen orange) with feet and legs a deep pink.Color standards have been established for guide lines to follow in showing all mutations of Zebras. To the best of my knowledge, the standards were first established m England and have heen carried out in the United States by the Zebra Fmch Club of Toledo, Ohio.Whether we wish to show Zebras or not, we all should try and up grade our quality by culling our flocks and trying to establish good select breeders.The Color Standards are as follows:NORMAL COCK. Eyes dark, beak red. Feet and legs pink. Head and neck dark grey, wings grey. Breast bar jet black. Throat and upper breast zebra striped, grey with darker Jines running from cheek to cheek continuing down to chest bar. Underparts white may have some fawnish shading near vent and thighs. Cheek lobes dark orange. Tear markings black and distinct. Tail, black with white bars, side flankings reddish brown with clear white spots.HEN. As for cock minus chest barring, lobe and flank markings. Beak paler in color. Tear markings black and distinct. A lighter shade of normal is recognized.Show faults: Brown shading on wings and mantle.WHITE, COCK AND HEN. Eyes dark.Beak red. Feet and legs pink. Pure white all over. Hens usuaJJy have beaks of a paler shade of red.Show faults: Colored spangles on mantle.FAWN COCK. Eyes dark. Beak red.Feet and legs pink. Head, neck and wings deep even fawn. Breast bar dark. Throat and upper breast light fawn with zebra lines running from cheek to cheek continuing down to breast bar. Underparts white. may have some fawnish shading near vent and thighs, cheek lobes dark orange, tear markings same shade as breast bar. Tail dark barred with white. Side flankings reddish brown with even clear white spots.HEl\. As other hens, but the same shade of fawn as cocks.Show faults. Vanauon in color between cock and hen of pairs.DOMINANT SILVER (DILUTE NORMAL) COCK. Eyes &amp;lt;lark. Beak red. Feetand legs pink. There are various shades of dilute normals, silvery grey being the ideal. Chest bars vary from sooty to pale grey, cheek lobes vary from pale orange to pale cream, flankings from reddish to pinkish fawn with even clear white spots. Tear markings same shade as breast bar. The lighter the general color the paler the chest, tail, lobe and flankings. Tail dark with white bars.HEN. As other hens, but the same shade to match the cocks.Show faults: Variation in color between cock and hen of pairs and variation in color of individual birds. Fawn shadings. Indistinct markings on cocks.DOMINANT CREAM (DILUTE FAWN) COCK. Eyes dark. Beak red. Feet and legs pink. Again all shades from deep cream to pale cream. Markings in cocks to be in general tone to match depth of diluteness. Tear markings same shade as breast bar. Tail deep cream with white bars.HEN. As other hens but of the same shade to match the cocks.Show faults: Variation in color between cock and hen of pairs and variation in color of individual birds. Fawn shadings. Indistinct markins on cocks.PIED, COCK AND HEN. Eyes dark.Beak red. Feet and legs pink. Any other colors broken with white approximately 50% of each color. Cock to retain cock markings in broken form on cheeks, flanks, wings and tail but must be evenly matched pairs of the same color. Tear markings distinct but can be broken.Show faults: Loss of cock markings which should be shown in broken form.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3017</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 1 (1977): FEB-MAR 1977; 16-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3017/3001</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
