<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1148</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:31:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Warbling Finches</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">de Ruiter, Maarten</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he Warbling Finches (genus Poospiza) is a small group of 13 species of Middle- and South American buntings which are almost unknown in aviculture. In Europe several species are now and then available and so far I've seen five species offered by bird-dealers and/or kept by aviculturists. I myself have kept only a single male of one species-the Ringed Warbling Finch (Poospiza torquata)-over a short time and, so far, it has been the most commonly offered and kept species.Strangely enough, I couldn't discover any breeding results with this species. Because I'm best informed with aviculture in the Netherlands, I will discuss here the breeding-results of four species which have sofar been reproduced in this country.Cinnamon Warbling FinchThe first species is the Cinnamon Warbling Finch (Poospiza ornata) also known as the Pretty Warbling Finch. This species appeared recently in the news because the San Antonio Zoo (Texas, U.S.A.) had the US first breeding (anon. 1996). The world first breeding was published in 1960 (Cummings, 1960) and this author has already published some notes about some Swedish breeding results (de Ruiter, 1997).As far as I was able to find out, the species has been bred in the Netherlands only once (Schepers, 1988). Mr. Schepers obtained a pair in 1986 and in a small breeding cage 80 x 70cm and llOcm high (31.2 x 27.3 x 42.9 in.) they soon started to build a nest and in early 1987 four eggs were laid. Two of them hatched after about 12 days of incubation but the chicks lived only for three and seven days. After this failure the birds were placed in an outside flight 5 x 3.2m and 2m high (16.4 x 10.5 x 6.5 ft.) which was well planted. They share this aviary with several species of small softbills, estrildids and finches.Putting a pair of Chestnut-breasted Warbling finches in the same enclosure proved to be impossible and after some fights these were removed.In June a second breeding attempt was made. This time three eggs were laid and all hatched. With lots of living food the chicks developed very fast and after nine days the first young left the nest followed the next day by the other two fledglings. All three were raised to independence and after this the breeding pair made a third breeding attempt which was unsuccessful.Chestnut-breasted Warbling FinchesThe Chestnut-breasted Warbling Finches (Poospiza ceasar) which were removed from the aviary of the Cinnamon Warbling Finches were placed in another aviary which they shared with several estrildids, a pair of Back-crested Finches and a pair of Namaqua Doves. In June 1985 they started to build a nest which was mainly constructed from coconut fiber and on 1, 2 and 3 July, eggs were laid. Only the female was seen incubating and after 12 days two young were found in the nest. A day later the third baby appeared. This last young died however after four days. At the age of 12 days the remaining two young left the nest. The breeding pair bred two more times the same year, both times using-after some renovating---the old nest.Black and Rufous Warbling FinchesAnother successful breeding-result with Warbling Finches was achieved by Mr. Penders (Wessels and Penders, 1980). He obtained a pair of unknown birds in 1977 which later proved to be Black and Rufous Warbling Finches (Poospiza nigroruja). Because they were in perfect condition, they were placed directly into one of his wellplanted outside aviaries measuring 6 x lm and 1.5m high 09.6 x 3.3 ft. and 4.9 ft. high). Only a month after obtaining these birds, they started to build a nest in a low bush. The nest was build from grasses and hay and three eggs were laid. Ten days after the female had started incubating, one chick hatched. After it had hatched all the other birds living in the same aviary were removed to reduce all possible disturbance and risk, something which in my opinion is rarely done.The baby was raised mainly with locktus (up to 100 a day) and after 10 days the chick left the nest. After a further 11 days the young was independent. The breeding-pair made a second breeding attempt but due to weather conditions all three of these eggs were infertile. The raised young started to molt after three months and its breeder was honored with a first breeding certificate for the Netherlands. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1148</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 3 (1997): MAY-JUNE 1997; 15-16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1148/1127</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
