<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/936</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Lory SymposiumThe American Lory Society is sponsoring a LorySymposium on Saturday, October 14, 1995. The symposiumwill be held at the Holiday Inn in the Hotel Circle, San Diego,California from 8 A.M. to 5 P.M. Speakers include RolandCristo (reproducing Lories and Lorikeets), Carl McCullough(Stella's Lorikeet), Gamini Ratnavira (Lories in the Wild),Dick Schroeder (Lories in Captivity), Don Wells (You CanStill Import Lories!- Forming Cooperative Breeding Groups),Wayne Schulenberg (Breeding the Tahitian Blue Lory andOther Rare Lory Species at the San Diego Zoo) and endingwith a Lory and Lorikeet Roundtable Discussion moderated byJohn Vanderhoof.The Symposium Cost is $70.00 (includes lunch and proceedings).Checks and Money Orders should be made out tothe "American Lory Society" and sent to: ALS, P.O. Box 450,Livermore, CA 94551. Hotel reservations can be made by calling1-800-433-2131. Special rates (until Sept. 1) are $75.00which includes a breakfast buffet. For further information,please contact Bobbie Meyer at 1-510-455-1631.Please join in this lory extravaganza, if nothing else visitwith superb wildlife artist, Garnini Ratnavira (and enjoy hisartwork) and exchange ideas with the "genius" of new innovativeideas concerning lories and other psittacines, the elusiveDon Wells.The American Lory Society is an organization dedicated bylory enthusiasts to the collection and dissemination of informationon the care and breeding of lories. Their publication,Network, is published quarterly. Dues are $15.00 per calendaryear, due in January of each year. All dues and editorial materialsfor Network should be mailed to:Bobbie Meye1; EditorAmerican Lory SocietyP.O. Box 450, Livermore, CA 94551 •Cooperative Breeding Programfor Crimson-bellied Conuresby Rick JordanI have received verbal word fi·om Mark Phillips at the Officeof Management Authority that my cooperative Breeding Programfor Pyrrhua perlata perlata, Crimson-bellied Conures hasbeen approved! What does this mean after only a seven monlhwaiting period? Can we expect Section 106 of lhe WBCA to be asuccess with aviculture? Is lhe USFWS making an example ofme?Of course I have not seen the special exceptions that haveprobably been attached to the permit. I probably have to fund afield study for this species in Brazil. Guess we will find out nextweek when the official letter comes. In the mean time, theUSFWS has now got, what they call, justification for their wonderfullaw. •-News ReleaseThirdSpecies of HawaiianForest Bird Hatches inCaptivityA helpless, naked chick pushed its way out of its egg andmade its first begging cheeps earlier this month. An Elepalo, aflycatcher native to Hawaii, was the third species of nativeHawaiian forest bird to be hatched under artificial conditions.The Elepalo joins 18 other chicks hatched since May at ThePeregrine Fund's Keauhou Bird Conservation Center. Theother chicks that share the Elepalo's carefully monitoredbrooder area also native Hawaiian birds - the liwi and theAmakihi. All three species are part of a new program designedto develop captive propagation technology for Hawaiian birds.These skills will soon be called into action to help restoremany of the federally listed endangered bird species of Hawaii.The fiftieth state has more birds listed as endangered than anyother state in the Union.The Peregrine Fund began its efforts two years ago with thecritically endangered Alala (Hawaiian crow, Corvus tropic us, -ed.). In partnership with the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service,private land owners, and the State of Hawaii facility in Olinda,in 1993 and 1994 eggs were removed from wild nests and artificiallyincubated. The hand-reared chicks were raised to independenceand released back into their forest habitat. Thus far,nine Alala which benefited from artificial incubation and handrearingthrive in the forests of South Kona.Following past success with the Alala, preparations arebeing made for similar actions with the other 20 endangeredspecies of forest birds. "With the hatching of the Elepalo, wenow have the tool, knowledge and experience to tackle manyof the truly rare species. We look forward to the challenge ofrearing other species of forest birds, with the hopes of reversingthe current trend towards extinction," said Alan Lieberman,program director for The Peregrine Fund of Hawaii.The eggs of the liwi, Amakihi and Elepalo were collected inthe mamane forests of Mauna Kea ~ith the assistance of theNational Biological Service. Collected early in the breedingseason, the "borrowed" eggs will soon be replaced by the parentswho are capable of laying replacement clutches. This iscalled double-clutching and is a conservation strategy oftenutilized to maximize production of rare species. The youngnestling Amakihi, now numbering 18, will later be fitted withradio transmitters. They will then spend time in a speciallyconstructed forest aviary on the Kamehameha School BishopEstate's Keauhou Ranch on the Big Island. Following a periodof conditioning and acclimatization, they will be released andl!lOnitored to document their fledgling success. "These youngAmakihi are pioneers. They will help us find the best way toincubate, rear and release the other rare species of birds thatare rapidly disappearing from our native forests," commentedMr. Oswald Stender, a trustee for Kamehameha School BishopEstate and a Director of The Peregrine Fund.From The Peregrine Fund Hawaiian Endangered BirdConservation Program.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/936</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 5 (1995): SEPT-OCT 1995; 51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/936/917</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
