<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/665</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-08T05:11:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Vulturine Guineafowl at Tracy Aviary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roles, D. Grenville</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The most nearly beautiful memberof a family of bizarre, though strikinglyplumaged birds, Vulturines arethe largest member of the group,which are distributed over most ofAfrica south of the Sahara, with asmall, possibly introduced, populationof Helmeted Guineafowl (Numeidameleagris sabyi) in Morroco.Certainly the Vulturine is the mosthandsomely plumaged guineafowlwith cobalt-blue, black and whitestriped, elongated neck feathers,lilac wing stripe and with a naked,powder-blue head skimpily adornedwith a small naped patch of deep maroonstubble. The voice is usually aquiet, murmuring conversation of"cheeps" but, once in a while, thebirds will call with a shrill, interrogativeor complaining series ofscreeches. The eggs are pale ivorymottled with fine speckled brownspots. Incubation takes approximately24 days and birds attain their adultplumage at about six months. Theyare sexually mature at two years.Relatively simple to maintain on anordinary gamebird diet, most successfulbreeders almost invariably supplementtheir feed with high proteinitems such as meat, eggs or nuts.These birds are hardy but are very susceptibleto intestinal parasites. It willbehoove the breeder to perform periodicfecal analysis and treat whennecessary.We have a young trio at the aviary who have yet to breed for us, eventhough the male goes through hishigh-stepping courtship routine quitefrequently.The most successful breeders I'veworked with were a pair we had at"Bright Meadows" in Sebastopol, California.There, our pair had quite alarge pen about 25 feet square, initiallywell grassed and planted (eventuallythe birds ate everything ediblewithin reach). We had a magnificentmale and a hen you would not give 10cents for (although we paid almost$300). We purchased her sight unseenand felt we'd been taken for a ridewhen we got her out of her box. Toenailswere missing, she had ruffledplumage and was lethargic; we'd havesent her back if we thought she wouldhave survived the journey.However, survive she did and,although she always looked wretched,she gave us 54 chicks in the first year.She went on to lay in every month ofthe year, sometimes laying as many asthree eggs in 48 hours, and producedover 100 eggs within 12 months. Sheeventually started eating her own eggsand it became quite a challenge torescue them before she got to them.Luckily, she usually laid early in theevening and would call incessantly fora short while before she produced.Her nest was in a clump of NewZealand Flax (Phormium tenax) and Icould clearly see her from the pathway.The trick was to get into the aviaryand snatch the egg away in thethree or four seconds it took her torecover from laying (the "thank Godthat's over" phase), before she couldturn around and have a really freshdinner. Not being stupid, she got wiseto me and would parade around hernest for an hour or more sometimes,in the hope that I would leave and shecould eat. If I tried to fool her andmove any distance at all, she couldpop that egg out in seconds flat andscramble it before I could get back.The diet of this pair was supplementedwith raw hamburger, hardboiledegg, sunflower seed and peanuts- small items fed at intervalsthroughout the day. Feeding the"good stuff' in this way also ensuredthat the birds became tame veryquickly and could be checked withease. Remarkable and distinctive,these birds can really be recommendedto the experienced aviculturistwho is looking for something...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/665</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 32-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/665/648</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
