<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/416</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">CONVERSATION update</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A p air of Mauritius parakeets(Psittacula eques) has success full yh atch ed in the wile! . T his is th e f irstkn own bree ding r ecord f o r theseverely threa tened p arrot in recentyea rs. T he adult p opul ati o n is es ti matedat ei ght indi v idu al s. (Wo rldBirdwatch, Vol. I 0 , No. 1. 1988)A shipm ent o f capti ve bred Balimynahs (s tarlings) (Leucop sar rothschildi) f rom Ameri can zoos and the.J ersey Wildli fe Preservati on Tru starrived at th e Su rabaya Zoo in Decemberto provid e a stock from whi ch toproduce offspring fo r release into thew ild . In .January the first eggs were laidand the building o f a pre- release train ingcentre in t he h ea rt of Bal i Barat;\/ational Park w ill shortly begin . Sadly,a census ca rri ed out by the Nati on alPark staff late la st yea r revealed thewile! p opul ation is still in decline. Only55 indiYiduals were sighted during thece nsus of all prn io usly kn own roostsites. T his clea rly highlights the plightof th e sp ec ies and emphas izes theimpo rtance of the pro jec t . (Wo rldBirdwa tch, Vol. I 0, No. I . 1988)</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/416</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 4 (1988): AUG-SEPT 1988; 16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/416/403</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
