<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4031</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">My Feathered Companions ~ After I’m Gone</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Robinson, Sheryl</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 2 (April/May 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.by Sheryl Robinson As pet owners we love our pets and always worry about them. As a rule, most pets, such as cats, dogs, hamsters, bunnies, snakes, fish, etc., don ’t outlive their human caretakers, but parrots of the Psittacine family may, and if cared for properly, most likely will. What happens to the pet parrot or parrots in the case where the human caretaker gets sick, injured, or even worse, dies. Hopefully, the person has formed a plan in advance for their long -lived pet to be well taken care of in their absence. If you truly love your feathered companion, then don ’t leave theprocess to chance after you are gone. Start working on a written legal plan now so you know your beloved companion will be well taken care of long into the future. This is a difficult topic and most people do not wish to think or talk about it. But it is extremely important for our long -lived feathered companions. Since I am not a lawyer, this article will not give you any specific information, but will rather be a guideline for you to follow to find the information needed to protect your pets. The best protection for your companion parrot is throughthe use of wills and trusts. Wills, trusts, and estate planning laws vary from state to state, but all 50 states have pet trust statutes. Each is slightly different, which is why you need to contact an estate planning expert in your state.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4031</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 2 (2024): Watchbird April/May 2024; 26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4031/3991</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
