<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2837</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-07T17:25:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">SirI would like to get involved in rare breeds of birds. Can you tell me where I can see such birds, or where some bird shows are? I want to see some black and white turkeys for one.E.H. Calimesa, CAYour hometown is about midway between the San Diego Zoo and the Los Angeles Zoo. Both of these zoos have outstanding displays of rare and beautiful birds. You might also take notice of the Watchbird listing of bird shows. Many shows are listed several months ahead of time so you can make preparations to attend. Any A.F.A. board meeting has an ample display of turkeys but, alas, they are mostly white.Ed. Dear EditorI was referred to you by the Southern California Bird Club. I am interested in keeping a falcon as a pet and I need more information about them. I would also like to know if there are any clubs I could join. Your help is appreciated.A. Jones Newport, CASorry, Miss Jones, the law does not permit you to have a pet falcon. Only if you participate in the ancient sport of falconry can you keep a falcon. In order to protect both the sport of falconry and the native wild population of raptors (hawks, falcons, etc.), the government has outlined a few simple rules you must comply with. I will give you a very brief sketch of the California rules.First, you must be sixteen years old.You must have a license to keep a raptor.To get a license, you must pass a supervised written examination on the regulations pertaining to raptors; on the care of raptors and the art of falconry; and on the natural history of raptors.If you pass the examination you will be given an application for a license. Before you submit the application you must have a sponsor who is already a falconer and you must have your raptor housing facilities inspected by your local wildlife protection officer.The government has rules regarding what your housing should be like. If you have done things properly and your bird house passes inspection, you may pay $15.00 and submit your applicationfor a license.Your apprentice falconers license permits you to have one raptor - a Sparrow Hawk or a Red-Tailed Hawk.Once you have your sponsor, your approved raptor housing facilities, your mandatory equipment, and your license, you may go into the field between November l and January 31 and catch your bird in a government specified trap. The bird can not be a nestling and can not be over a year old when you catch it.It is illegal to buy or sell any raptor. When you hunt with your bird you must have a valid hunters license. Before you can get a hunting license you must take the Hunters Safety course.If your raptor lays an egg you must notify the fish and Game Department in writing within 48 hours.You may not transfer possession of your bird, even while you are on a three weeks vacation, without written permission from Fish and Game.It is illegal to keep or exchange feathers moulted off of your bird or feathers of a bird that died except for repairs of your birds wings.There are more details but I am growing weary and shan't recount them. Young Lady, if you really want a falcon you can get one, but unless you are really dedicated I suggest you pursue something more simple, such as a doctorate in nuclear physics.Greetings:What a pleasure, what a delight! Your cover photo on Oct./Nov. '78 issue is a masterpiece! It will be decopauged and added to my collection. Between your covers are valued ideas and information. You could split each issue half and halfwild bird and cage bird; cover all-and print each month! What a library of information!So happy the "Cocky" has it's own "Society." They are indeed in their own Society. I missed the issue of it's formation-who and where do you send your membership application? Maybe they can solve my problem-a pair of "Pearlies" insist on a shoe box for a nest box! In a 4' x 4' x 6' flight yet.Also love your humorous caustic answers in "From the Editors Desk." Hats off to Lee Horton-living the life of a "pampered" cage bird finally. What color are his feathers?It's lunch time and Bobbie, the Blue Fronted Amazon wants his apple, Charlie, the half moon screams "grapes," Corky, the albino Cocky wants his bell pepper seeds, Baby, the hyper American Parakeet is vain, she'd rather bathe than eat, Topper, the scalped English demands formula, and breeding pens one thru nine beg for soaked oats. The breeding room is full of hungry new life. The peach face babies just found their wings, the resting finches chirp for a nest, and Rex, the cocky softly asks Ruth, his mate, "Hello, how are you?" All because I'm delayed-thanks to your great issue.Dorothie M. Slade Wheatland, CAThe rewards of letters such as yours make my pay seem insignificant. For the Cockatiel Society, you may contact Dee Dee Squyres, secretary, 9812 Bois D'Arc Ct., Fort Worth, Texas, 76126. Ed.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2837</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 1 (1979): FEB-MAR 1979; 41-44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2837/2821</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
