<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3784</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-20T02:49:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Lineolated Parakeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ivić, Dr. Slobodan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Lineolated parakeet can be found in southern parts of Mexico, Guatemala, Honduras, Nicaragua, Costa Rica, western Panama, also in all the states in Central America, Venezuela, Colombia, Ecuador, in southern parts of west Colombia, in parts of the Andes in north-west Venezuela, in north-west Ecuador and in central Peru. Also, the presence of these birds was recorded in Bolivia as well. Dense mountain forests are specific for these areas. Lineolated parakeet can be found in the mountain areas to an altitude of 2,000 meters. During winter time they can be seen in lower altitudes searching for food. These birds spend most of the day on the ground. After sunset, they seek shelter in the treetops of the high trees, mostly in the openings. It is very hard to spot them in the trees due to different shades of green and black spots on the feathers.Subspecies, Bolborhynchus lineola tigrinus, can be found in South America, along the Andes mountain range, at altitudes between 1,500 and 3,000m, from northern Colombia and northwestern Venezuela to northwestern Ecuador and the central part of Peru.The Lineolated Parakeets are small birds, with an weight from 1.6 to 2 ounces (47 to 55 grams) and 6 to 7 inches (16 to 17 cm) in length (this includes the short tail which is 6cm in average). These birds have a harmonious anatomical structure. Dominant colours are different shades of green, inwrought by black mottles which can be shaped like black spots or stripes. There are two subspecies: Bolborhynchu lineola lineola and Bolborhynchus lineola tigrinus wich has more visible black stripes and darker green feathers and dark green stripes. The head is evenly rounded. The eyes are big, round and clear. Featherless ring around the eyes is gray while iris is dark brown. The forehead is yellow-green. The feathers on the neck and back are </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-04-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3784</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 43 No. 3 &amp; 4 (2016): Special Double Issue; 48-55</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3784/3759</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
