<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1171</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE PRESIDENT'S COLUMN ...   Working Today, Planning for Tomorrow</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Desborough, Laurella</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The AFA in TransitionT he American Federation of Avic~lture is in the midst of a transition to a new Board of Directors and a new President. Also during this period, the organization is continuing work on restructuring. These two coinciding events will have an impact on our work, but we are preparing to make the impact positive. New board members will receive transition information to help them prepare for the important task. The AFA of today is not the AFA of five years ago. We now have a well-informed proactive board with individual members taking on difficult committee projects and moving the organization forward.Most organizations benefit from working boards, and each hoard makes its contribution The present board is no exception. We have achieved important accomplishments in the past four years. Highlights included the following:• Two trips to Washington to present aviculture's interests and concerns to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and to the Congressional Committee with oversight on U.S. Fish and Wildlife;• Sending Alister McNahney to the CITES Animals Committee meetings to present information on captive breeding:• Kelly Tucker's published work, The Birdkeepers Legislative Handbook,• A special AFA Delegates Training session at the 1996 convention;• And moving forward with the difficult work of re-doing the Policies of the AFA Board.Others will remember other events.For me, these were the special accomplishments of the present hoard.AFA Has a Philosophy of InclusionAn avicultural philosophy that needs discussing here is the policy of inclusion. Rumors sometimes surface that the AFA is an elitist organization, only for the most advanced hi rd breeders or the highly specialized avicultur- ists. This is truly sad as so much of our work is for the advancement of aviculture-for all bird owners, not a special few.During the past four years this board has worked to hring together the various specialty avicultural organizations and other types of avian organizations. Our work must he for the whole of aviculture or it will he incomplete and ineffective. It must encompass the owner of a Budgerigar, as well as the owner of a Hyacinth Macaw, and the hreeder of pheasants as well as the hreeder of cockatoos. The American Federation of Aviculture is an organization which extends a welcome hand to all people who keep and breed hirds.AFA Convention inSan Antonio ... See You There!! The AFA Convention in San Antonio in August is almost here! We are all looking forward to a great convention and visiting with old friends, meeting new friends, hearing great lecturers and seeing the sights of the old wild West. See you there!AFA and AAV in Reno in SeptemberThe next event is Reno, Nevada, on Friday, September 12, at John Ascuaga's Nugget, where the 1997 AAV Aviculture Program will be cosponsored by the American Federation of Aviculrure and the Association of Avian Veterinarians.This one day program, Flock Management: A Critical Element in the Breeder's Success, will focus on all of the aspects of aviary management that make bird breeders successful.Topics will include• An Overview of Flock Management by Dr. Scott Echols;• Reproduction in the Aviary by Dr. Darrel Styles;• Incubation and Hatching by Dr. Darrel Styles;• Pediatrics: An Aviculturist's Perspective, hy Joanne Abramson;• Pediatrics: The Veterinary Perspective, by Dr. Margaret Wissman;• Marketing and Business Management, by Joanne Abramson;• Putting Flock Management Thoughts To Work For You, By Dr. Brian Speer.Following the presentations will be an Aviculrure Question and Answer Forum with all speakers participating. Early registration (before August 14) is $95. and thereafter, $115. Registration includes a proceedings of the program. Further information can be obtained by reviewing the full page announcement in this "Watchbird or by phoning 303- 756-8380 or faxing 303- 759-8861 and asking for information on the 1997 Aviculture Program.Presidential FarewellThis will he my last column as your AFA President. I want to wish you all many happy hatchings. I encourage each of you to continue your support for the only national organization that works continuously to support you. The American Federation of Aviculture is able to accomplish much, but only with the continuing support of the members of the avicultural community. Please be there for A.FA so the AFA can he there for all of us.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1171</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 4 (1997): JULY-AUGUST 1997; 8</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1171/1150</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
