<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2860</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T04:02:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">An Open Letter from the Canary Editor</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stubbart, Kenneth</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"In the Dec. '78 - Jan. '79 issue of "Watchbird," p 12, in the article "Thoughts for the Novice" by Mrs. Janice Pritchard, there were a couple of ideas that could be misleading and therefore they deserve some comments. I am sure Mrs. Pritchard's major concern was to comment about exhibitors raising birds to be judged at specific standards of excellence.""Regarding the comments on the gloster, there are two issues that need to be set straight both for research and posterity, and for potential influence on the novice. Gloster canaries have been bred buff to buff for many generations. They, like other buff-to-buff breedings, tend to become loose feathered and "shaggy" when this mating procedure is followed for several generations. Correcting this fault will require that a yellow or high buff bird be bred into the line to correct the fluffy or shaggy feather condition." (See J.G. Cross' The Gloster Fancy Canary, p 55- 61)"Also, in an attempt to encourage breeding canaries to meet a particular judging standard, Mrs. Pritchard has encouraged breeding to a particular size and she has cited 411.z'' as the proper length for a gloster. That would be nice. However in the Feb. - Mar. '79 issue, in Mark Whateaker's article on glosters, the fact is ably pointed out that the International Gloster Breeders Association promotes the size of the bird as "tendency to the diminutive." Size is only 15 of the 100 points. Therefore, head (20 pts), body (20 pts), and plumage (15 pts) are each as important or more important point wise than is the size, and they should each be given appropriate attention by the breeder.""Also, regarding the "Columbus Fancy," which is the only type canary to originate in the U.S. , the sketch that accompanied the article (possibly not provided by Mrs. Pritchard), is not one that a serious breeder of Columbus Fancy Canaries should breed toward. It would not, in most instances, be a winner in a show. For a proper sketch and standard of excellence to use as a model toward which to breed, may I suggest that any breeder who is interested in raising canaries purchase a "blueprint" of the type of bird she/he is interested in breeding and exhibiting. I would further recommend that every club would greatly benefit from purchasing these blueprints, having them laminated to protect them, and then sharing them with the club members. They could work wonders in upgrading the quality of canaries that would appear on the show benches.""Finally, I whole heartedly agree with the many people who have written and who have discussed the above ideas and problems with me. We all agree that we do not want to discourage Mrs. Pritchard or any other future writer from putting their ideas to the test of print. We need to share our ideas with each other and as Mrs. Pritchard seriously pointed out, we need to breed toward a standard of excellence.""As "Special Editor of Canaries," I would appreciate hearing from clubs and individuals in the canary fancy. I need articles to submit for print as well as your letters regarding your problems and your aspirations so that "Watchbird" can carry articles of help and interest. It is only through a sharing and a concerned love for both our birds and our fellow breeders that "Watchbird" can maintain its standard of excellence. (I will not respond to any requests if a self-addressed, stamped....</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2860</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 2 (1979): APR-MAY 1979; 40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2860/2844</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
