<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3997</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T20:18:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Parrot Festival (NPRPF)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Staff, AFA Watchbird</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (October/November 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Answers to Bird Brain g. Gaggle of Geese (on ground or in water) i. Muster of Peacocks a. Cast of Hawks j. Parliament of Toucans h. Covey or bevy of Quails c. Murder of Crows b. Murmuration of Blackbirds d. Mob of Cockatoos e. Flamboyance of Flamingos f. Colony of Penguins I am an Albatross The radio-tracked amazons were found in areas within the community and the community protected forest. However, most of the fixes were obtained from sites outside the community areas, and therefore these places are very important for the survival of the Lilacine Amazon, especially given thatmost of the observations were of feeding behaviour at what must be considered key locations. In addition, lots of other amazons foraging alongside the individuals with the radio -collars were recorded.Because of the higher rate of occupation suggested by the current results, the roosting sites (Río Piedras y El Corozo) located in Las Balsas are considered the priority places to be protected. Overall, these results indicate a predominant occupational zone outside the community protected area (excluding the roosting sites which are the most important), which suggests a wider area where the parrots are obtaining their resources.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3997</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 4 (2023): Watchbird October/November 2023; 26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3997/3957</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
