<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1100</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:21:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Basics of Breeding Gouldians</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fidler, Mike</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">These days the husbandry ofbreeding the Gouldian Finch iswell understood, making it easyto breed providing basic rules are followed.Although, as we all know, itcan be a very difficult species if treatedin a conventional fashion.There is nothing wrong with keepinga few Gouldians in an ornamentalmixed species aviary but, obviously,you should not expect to breed exceptaccidently. These notes, however, arefor the person who is serious aboutbreeding Gouldians and are somewhatuncompromising.What Not To DoColonies. Do not try to colonybreed Gouldians. In a colony, only thedominant pair or pairs will breed.Depending upon the number of birdsper square foot, those at the bottom ofthe pecking order are likely to die fromstress.Outdoors. Do not breed them outdoors.Gouldians do not adapt well tochanging weather.Hygiene. Do not shortcut onhygiene. Gouldians have low resistanceto bacterial contamination.Pampering. Do not pamperGouldians with a large variety of foodsand avoid the "drug store" syndrome.In the wild, Gouldians feed off of onlyone species of sorghum grass and afew insects (20o/o of the diet). This is aspecies which can easily be killed bykindness by feeding too rich a diet.Remember, it has spent millions ofyears adapting to life in a very harshenvironment.Success? Inevitably, you will talk topeople who have broken these rulesand are still claiming success. First ofall, how do you measure success? Issuccess breeding 12 phas youngstersper pair year after year?' Or is successjust managing to get one or twoyoungsters "onto the peg?' You willhave to set your own standards. Sheerbehavioral diversity will ensure that afew birds breed, no matter what theconditions, preferring to ignore MikeFidler's rules.What To DoThe Gouldian is an ideal aviculturalsubject well suited to standard birdroom conditions.Temperature in the bird roomshould he maintained at a minimum of63° F. Humidity is unimportant withinvery wide tolerances.Cages can he any type. Most of mybreeding pairs are housed in 19 in.cube cages which I suggest is a minimum.Anything from that size up issuitable and there is no advantage orbenefit in any particular size or shape.Nests. Gouldians use any kind ofnesting receptacle. In the wild, no twonests are the same. However, moreconsistent self-rearing results will heobtained with nest boxes that areapproximately 4'12 in. square by 11 in.long. These can he mounted eithervertically or horizontally, the birds donot care.Diet. The basic diet should consistof a standard plain foreign finch mix.My own mix is 25o/o canary, 25o/o whitemillet, 25o/o red millet, and 25o/oJapanese millet. This is not particularlybetter than any other mix hut doesminimize wastage from uneaten seed.Soft food. Provide a proprietary16o/o protein egg food or soft food mixduring molting and breeding to whicha small amount of multi-vitamins mayhe beneficially added.Grit. Gouldians need grit. I knowthat there has been some debate in theU.S.A. as to whether grit is necessary,hut, please believe me, for consistentresults feed grit to all Australian finches.Water. It is important to supply freshwater every day in clean containers.Gouldians have a low tolerance tocommon bacteria and contaminatedwater containers in a warm room arethe perfect media for breeding bacteria.Separate. Better results are obtainedif cocks and hens are kept separate inlarger flights or cages while not breeding.During this period they should bekept on a basic maintenance diet andgiven soft food only once a week. Tobring them into breeding condition,start feeding soft food at the rate of '/zteaspoon per bird per day. Within sixweeks your birds will he in breedingcondition.Pairing. Pair up your cocks andhens. It matters not who goes in thecage first. Put some dried grass orcoconut fiber into the nest box to givethen a start and leave an adequate pileof nesting material in the cage. It isimportant to let them build their ownnest as it is a part of the pair bondingprocess and also helps bring both partnersinto breeding condition.Eggs. Within a further three to sixweeks you should have eggs. If youare just starting out with Gouldians andhave just a few pairs, it may he betternot to inspect the nest box once broodinghas begun. Although most pairs arehighly tolerant, the occasional pair willdesert if interfered with.The eggs hatch after 16 days atwhich stage start to increase theamount of soft food provided. By thetenth day after hatching, they will heconsuming three to four teaspoons perday depending upon the number ofnestlings.Juveniles will fledge on the 27th or28th day and may be weaned at 35days.Now what? Provide the parentswith a fresh clean nest box on the 30thday as they will he getting ready torecycle and have often built their newnest and begun to lay before the juvenilesare weaned. Do not attempt tohalt this recycling in the mistaken beliefthat you are giving the hen a rest. It isentirely normal for them to recycle andholding them hack will only convincethem that conditions are no longer suitablefor breeding, bringing on an interimmolt.Your only problem is likely to he thefailure of the parents to rear. This islargely due to the number which arebeing fostered in today's aviculture. Ifthey fail, let them have another try.Pairs which fail the first or even the secondtime often succeed on the next.There are husbandry techniqueswhich can he employed to enhanceyour success in self-rearing but that isthe subject of a future article.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1100</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 6 (1996): NOV-DEC 1996; 50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1100/1079</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
