<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1553</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:53:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question #1: I received two peach faced lovebirds for Christmas. Six weeks later, the male died suddenly. Autopsy showed Polyomavirus. The surviving female has lost most chest feathers and has a poor appetite. If she is a carrier, does she need to be put to sleep? I don't want her to suffer and she seems to be content. What should I do? Thank you for your recommendation.e. Ba11c'Lutt, NevadaAnswer #1: Your female lovebird probably has polyomavirus infection since she has lost the chest feathers and has a poor appetite, which can be a sign of illness. It is possible that she could overcome the disease and clear the virus out of her system. Lovebirds are not really carrier birds of this disease, only Budgerigars. So, she will. eventually get rid of the virus if she doesn't get too sick in the meantime. It is also possible that she does not have the virus but misses her friend and has picked her feathers. It is a good idea to have your avian veterinarian do a DNA probe blood test for the virus. She should also be tested for the Psittacine Beak and Feather Disease, since that disease can also cause these symptoms and this virus will not be cleared. If she tests positive for polyomavirus and negative for PBFD, you can test her every six months until she tests negative for the polyomavirus. At that time, you can consider another bird in the household. IF she tests positive for the PBFD, you should not get any other birds, since there is not a treatment nor a cure. When she is suffering with this disease, euthanasia is a reasonable option.'RhoM.a f{. Stet1e11so11, DVM, ABVP-Avian, Jacksonville, FloridaAnswer #2: Have your veterinarian test the lovebird for both polyomavirus and beak and feather disease virus. If either test is positive, strict isolation of the bird from other birds is appropriate. If you have only this bird, there is no need to isolate unless you plan on acquiring more birds If the polyomavirus is positive, retest in a couple of months. As long as the bird is comfortable and has a good quality of life, there is no need to euthanize it.:James /1t. J-la'l'lls, DVMOakland, CAAnswer #3: I'm sorry about the loss of your male lovebird. Birds as we all know, can appear to be fine and healthy but can be hiding signs of disease. Such may have been the case with your male lovebird. The remaining lovebird, has of course, been exposed to the polyomavirus and should be tested for its presence. Additionally, a test for another virus, Psittacine Beak and Feather Disease (PBFD) should be run. Depending on these test results you can make an informed decision about the remaining bird in regard to your specific circumstances. The most important issue to me is the quality of life that we can offer an animal. Regardless of the birds viral status, if she is clinically doing well at that time and you plan on obtaining no additional birds, you may consider to leave her alone.If she is not doing well and you would like to obtain other birds, your decision may be different. It is prudent to know that these virus infections can persist in the environment for extended periods of time, and bringing new birds into the household should be well thought out and considered prior to purchasing new birds.Am11 B. Wouli, DVM, ABVP-Avian, West Hills, CAQuestion #2: Can you explain why some pet parrots are able to eat avocado and chocolate with no ill effects? I often hear of owners who feed these foods on a regular basis before learning of their dangers. Apparently, the birds suffered no ill effects.B. Vaz11ez, ColoradoAnswer #1: The original study on avocado toxicity was done with Cockatiels and Budgerigars. They found varying toxicity depending on the species of avocado (do you know what species your avocado is?). So, the result of ingestion of this fruit would depend on the species of the avocado, the size of the bird, and the amount that is eaten. The birds develop breathing difficulties and die within 24-48 hours after ingestion. So, it is possible for a bird to eat avocado without dying but who wants to take the chance?Chocolate toxicity is also dependent on the type of chocolate, size of the bird, and the amount that is eaten Theobromine is the toxic principal in chocolate, which is extremely high in unsweetened baking chocolate and very low in white chocolate. The effect of this substance is that of a stimulant including nervousness, heart irregularities, tremors, seizures, and death within 6-24 hours. So, again, it is possible for a bird to eat chocolate without dying, but it is safer to avoid the risk.'R.ho11tfa f\. Ste11e11So11, DVM, ABVP-Avian, Jacksonville, FloridaAnswer #2: Avocado is known to make birds sick. Some birds tolerate it· without a problem. Chocolate is toxic if consumed in large enough quantities. Pure bakers chocolate is much more toxic than chocolate that has been diluted with milk, sugar, and other additions. Some birds live very long on terrible diets and are given alcohol, salty foods, and caffeine containing beverages all of which are toxic to birds as well as chocolate and avocado. It just goes to show how resilient some creatures are. Just because this happens does not suggest that you should count on your bird tolerating the problem foods. Stick to a good diet.James M Harris, DVMOakland, CA </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1553</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 4 (2000): July-August 2000; 28-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1553/1530</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
