<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1965</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-22T04:12:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Boston Regional Convention Successful</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Phillips, Lee</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Echoing the theme "Breed Today, You May Not Import Tomorrow!" more than a hundred bird enthusiasts attended A.F.A.'s fourth regional convention the weekend of May 9-11 at the Park Plaza Hotel in Boston. Under the co-chairmanship of Dr. A. E. Decoteau of the New Hampshire Bird Breeders and Miss Linda Rubin of the Boston society of Aviculture and with the enthusiastic help of members of both clubs, A.F.A. has chalked up yet another successful and profitable regional convention.Opening with a wine and cheese reception on Friday evening, the convention provided the background for "bird" talk as old friendships were renewed and new ones formed. Registration began at 8:00 a.m. on Saturday followed by a bird mart. The A.F.A. Board of Directors' meeting was called to order by President Dick Baer and proceeded smoothly and efficiently through committee reports and new business.Seminars began promptly at I :00 p.m. with talks by Dr. Margaret Petrak, Nancy Reed, Dr. Margarie McMillan, Don Langell, Dr. William Satterfield, Cliff Witt, Tom Ireland and Gerry Brisson. Supplemented by slides and live birds, the talks were interesting and very informative.President Dick Baer spoke briefly at the banquet which culminated Saturday's activities. Stressing the three-fold needs of A.F.A., Dr. Baer stated "We are a powerful organization and greater power comes from increased membership. We need to increase our membership to strengthen our position and to obtain the added revenue to operate our programs; further, we need the active participation of the membership to carry out the work."Dr. Larry Shelton, Curator of Birds at the Philadelphia Zoo, spoke after the banquet describing the new Breeders' Registry which he is establishing under the sponsorship of A.F.A. and his slide presentation included examples of proper record keeping in regard to breeding birds and illustrated many of the birds now housed at the Philadelphia Zoo. A lively raffle added spice to the evening. On Sunday morning most of the convention guests traveled by bus to visit Franklin Park Zoo's World of Birds and went on to the Stoneham Zoo for a conducted tour. Convention guests returned to their homes with great enthusiasm and useful new ideas. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1965</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 5 (1980): OCT-NOV 1980; 24-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1965/1936</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
