<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1124</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:30:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Hookbill Hobbyists of Southern California</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hudson, Kathryn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T his last year Hookbill Hobbyists of Southern California celebrated the 20th anniversary of its founding, making it the first and oldest continually meeting parrot duh in the United States. Yes, we are proud. But more than that, we are still having a good time and continuing to learn.And Hookbill Hobbyists supports the AFA. Indeed, at our annual Educational Bird Fair and Mart this year we sponsored the Harold Brown Memorial AFA Fundra ising Raffle. Donations came in from individuals, businesses and clubs across the country and were coordinated hy Kerri Muller. Many spectacular and favorite birds were donated-a Congo Grey, a handfed male Eclectus, a Timneh Grey, an Australian King Parrot, a hand raised Patagonian Conure and many other small parrots, cages, toys, Tshirts, T-stands, treats, and too many other items to list were also donated hy supporters of the AFA.At our December 1996 meeting, a check for $2,300 was presented to Many Muschinske. the AFA State Coordinator for southern California, in front of 90 of our members at our holiday potluck dinner. It was our pleasure to support the AFA in this very tangible way.As an active duh, we support a small breeding program enabling members to explore the responsibilities of caring for and raising parrots in a semi-permanent situation. This also helps provide healthy birds at reasonable cost for our raffle table-and we have had uonderful raffle tables.In October each year we have a club bird show where members can show their birds in an informal and professional setting. We have had experienced judges who inform us just what the standards are for each bird, why one is chosen over another. Awards and ribbons are given to the winners.Educational Outreach is another opportunity for us to reach the poor birdless masses. Many of our members have taken this chance to both assist in socializing their pets and to teach about parrots to elementary school classes where we join in second grade and forth grade classes on endangered wildlife and rainforests. We share the concept of captive breeding and encourage concrete ways of preserving the remaining rainforests while exploring habitat destruction and economic necessity. I particularly enjoy sparking the ideas of discovery in an under explored part of our world! \Xlith a few parrot feathers as motivation. the students come up with myriads of questions and possible discoveries.\Xie have had space to exhibit at the Southern California Exposition. known locally as the Del Mar Fair, for many years. Many of our members first heard about our duh hy talking to the members who volunteered to man (bird) our booth. \Xie also have been given time on the presentation stages to promote our organization and goals.I asked a few of my bird friends at the last meeting what their favorite things about the club were. The leading response was talking about birds Seeing the variety of pet birds and learning about them from their owners was the biggest thrill. It was closely followed hy the raffle table. For as little as a dollar (for most of us it's a lot more') you have a chance to win the bird of your dreams. or to try different feed or toys.Thank you to Hookhill I lobbyists and the members who make it work.Visitors and new members are always welcome. \Xie meet at 6:30 P .. \t. the second Sunday of each month at the MITE Bingo Hall, 1365 North Johnson Avenue, El Cajon, CA.Our mailing address is P.O Box 3495 La Mesa, CA 91941-3495. We also operate the Parrot Hotline with voice mail and referral numbers at 619-IIOK-BIRD ( 465-2473). President Bill Hudson or his wife (me) can he reached at 619-528-1526 .• </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1124</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 1 (1997): JAN-FEB 1997; 56</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1124/1103</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
