<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1272</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">from the field: Australia Revisited: Gouldian Finches in Their Natural Habitat</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bucci, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I twas always my desire to see and study Gouldian Finches Chloebia gouldiae in their native habitat. I have visited Australia in the past and made attempts to see Gouldians but failed to do so. Last spring, while "surfing" the Internet for Australian bird web sites, I came across a Gouldian Finch site. Michael Fendley, a coordinator of the Threatened Bird Network at the RAOU Head Office in Australia, was looking for volunteers to help count Gouldian Finches in the Northern Territory. My first thought was: Here is my chance!Immediately I sent Mr. Fendley email indicating that I was interested in volunteering for the survey. The next day I received Mr. Fendley's reply telling me that he had sent my name to Mr. Peter Dostine, Senior Research Wildlife Officer with the Parks and Wildlife Commission of the Northern Territory in charge of the Gouldian Finch project.Several days later I received a letter from Mr. Dostine informing me of details for the Gouldian count project. He stated, 'The main objective of the work is to derive population indices to monitor trends through time and infer responses to management actions to assist the conservation of the Gouldian." 1997 would be the second year for the project of counting Gouldians at waterholes during the dry season in the Northern Territory.In order for me to participate in the project, I was to be in Darwin or Katherine, Australia, on July 28th. There I would be met by a Northern Territory ranger and taken to the location. I left Los Angeles on the 7th of July, landed in Sydney, then proceeded to the city of Perth in Western Australia, a region I had never visited before. In Perth I visited with my cousin. I knew it was mid-winter in Australia, but I did not realize that it would be so cold in Perth. I was forced to buy some winter clothes.Perth and its port at Fremantle were beautiful places to visit. My cousin insisted that I visit with him longer. He drove me to Albany in the southwestern part of Australia, and then headed toward Cape Leeuwin. The century- old lighthouse at Cape Leeuwin at the southern tip of the state of Western Australia is the guiding light for sailors entering Australia's South Sea from the Indian Ocean. The next day we travelled north along the beautiful southwestern coast and returned to Perth.It was then time to part with my cousin. I left Perth by bus and travelled north toward Broome. I chose to ride a bus in order to see more of Western Australia. It was a gruelling two-daysand-one-night bus ride to reach Broome. Broome has beautiful beaches and a tropical climate. I was now wearing shorts, a tank top, and sandals. This would be my "uniform" for the rest of my stay in Australia. I rested in Broome for two days then proceeded with another night's bus ride to Katherine.I stayed in Katherine for two days and visited the famous Katherine Gorge. It was now July 28th, and I anxiously waited to be picked up by the Northern Territory ranger. To my surprise, I was picked up right at 2:00 P.M., as planned, by Mr. Peter Dostine, and we drove to Edith Falls where we made our base camp.I immediately pitched my tent on nice grassy ground. This was to be my home for the next seven days. I met all of the Australian volunteers and a couple from Germany. In total, we were 15 enthusiastic "bird nuts," there to do our job. Mr. Dostine was in charge of the project.Every morning we got up at 5:00 A.M. A quick breakfast was available on a "help yourself" basis, which was reminiscent of my army days. By 5:30 we were on our way to the Yinberrie Hills.The Yinberrie Hills are used by Gouldian Finches each year during the dry season to feed and nest. It is the site of the largest known breeding population. Study of the area is there- fore of obvious importance to assess the conservation status of the Gouldian Finch. Results from simultaneous counts conducted in 1996 suggest that this method provides a useful index of population size.Our group would do the same as was done previously: simultaneous counts of birds' daily watering points conducted at the same time. That was the reason why many volunteers were needed.We left in groups of three to four volunteers in four-wheel drive Toyota trucks and Land Cruisers. The roads are very rocky and dusty in the Yinberrie Hills. In fact, the truck in which I was riding had two flats before we got there. One at a time we were dropped off at different locations. Each of us had a location assigned each day. Most of the time, after being dropped off, we had to walk to our location through riverbeds to reach a waterhole.Waterholes in the riverbeds varied in size. Some were about half the size of a backyard swimming pool, while others were much smaller. At the end of July, it was well into the dry season. By season's end in November, these waterholes would be totally dry.In addition to the riverbed waterholes, there are artificial waterholes in the Yinberrie Hills, maintained by the Mt. Todd Gold Mine workers. The artificial holes are maintained by the mine to help Gouldians survive the dry season, Also, it discourages Gouldians from visiting contaminated waterbodies on the mine site. The artificial waterholes are made with black plastic sheeting placed amongst rocks to form a small pool. The pool formed is approximately 3 feet in diameter, and some rocks are placed in it to create an island for Gouldians and other finches to land and drink The water supply is kept in a drum placed about 30 feet away. A small hose supplies the waterhole by a gravity drip system. I was told that Gouldian Finches prefer to drink from these small artificial holes.As I mentioned before, we were left alone at the waterhole. I usually positioned myself about 40 feet away from the waterhole, a good distance from which to observe using binoculars.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1272</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 2 (1998): MAR-APR 1998; 23-26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1272/1251</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
