<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/677</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Mulga Parrot (Psephotus varius)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Drew</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Also known as Many-colored Parrot,the Mulga Parrot is a particularly beautifulmedium to small parrot which isrelated to the Red-rumped Parrot and,more distantly, the Hooded, Goldenshoulderedand nearly, or supposedly,extinct Paradise Parrot. Unfortunately,it is this last species that some individualshave tried to reproduce, unsuccessfully,by hybridizing Mulga Parrotswith either Hooded or Goldenshouldered.It is likely that the ParadiseParrot is the nominate form, fromwhich the other species developedand is, therefore, unattainable throughhybridizing, as much as it would beimpossible to reproduce a wolf bycross breeding domestic dogs, theancestor from which they originated.Description and SexingMulga Parrots are sexually dimorphic,which is to say the feather colorationbetween sexes is quite different,thereby allowing simple and obviousvisual identification of sexes, fromprior to fledging and onwards.Male: Predominately a light greenbird with a varying degree in depth ofcolor being darker particularly on thedorsal surface. The cheeks, ear covertand throat area have a distinct iridescenceand slight aqua appearance insome birds. There is a prominent foreheadstripe which can sometimes beevident in some females althoughmuch paler. There is a dark crimsonpatch on the crown of most males andsome females will show a slight degreeof this also. The wings, which arepredominantly green, exhibit a brightyellow or golden blaze on the shoulderwith the outer or leading edge ofthe wing dark to light blue and theprimaries and secondaries dark blue.Primary flight tips are black. Theunderside of the bird has a light greenbreast with a bright yellow vent andlower chest surrounding, in mostbirds, a bright red or orange abdominalpatch. The tail feathers are greengraduating to blue and the bird has adull crimson strip across the upper tailcovert to rump area. The eye is darkand the bill is dark grey with a silversheen.Female: Is distinctive and shouldnot be confused at all with Redrumpedfemales. Although they havea similar olive green color, the Mulgahas many more colors, with notably ared shoulder blaze. There is also theslight red crown in some females, theoccasional frontal stripe and definitelya bright pastel green abdominal area.Some individuals can exhibit a slightdegree of dull crimson in the abdomenarea.Immature: Birds can be sexedaccurately as soon as the feathers onthe dorsal surfaces have developedenough to give clear indication ofcolor. The shoulder blaze is notalways clear and may show a slight degree of both colors, red and yellow,in the early stages, most particularly inmales. The general body color givesclear enough indication of sexes in thesame fashion as immature RedrumpedParrots, Psephotus haematonotus.One very important considerationis that young birds, when firstfledged, have yellow bills to somedegree. Other than this, immaturefemales closely resemble adult females.Therefore, it is worthwhile tohave the adult female leg rung, as theyellow in the bill of immatures canquickly disappear.If this should occur, the adult femalewill be a slightly bigger bird, haveolder, greyer looking legs and feet andthe bill should also be darker with thesilver white sheen more developed.She will also, no doubt, be a moreaccomplished flier and therefore wiserabout the net and how to avoid it.Immature birds should not be left withthe adults long enough for immaturemales to color sufficiently to make ifdifficult to distinguish between theadult male. Whether you observe it ornot, in most cases the adult male willbecome aggressive towards his offspring,most notably the males.DistributionAs the colloquial name suggests, theMulga Parrots inhabit low rainfallareas such as Mulga scrub, Acaciaaneura, Myall, A. sowdeni, Blue bush,Maireana sp. and Saltbush, Atriplexsp., as well as Casuarina/ Saltbushcountiy and a large degree of the variousMallee habitats. Generally speaking,they are an inhabitant of arid tosemi arid, hot dry climates south ofthe Tropic of Capricorn. They arefound often in association with the differentspecies of Blue-bonnets overtheir range. Blue-bonnets, onceregarded as Psephotus, have beenrenamed as a separate group, genusNorthiella, being distinctive fromPsephotus in many ways.The sight of Mulga Parrots lowdown on dead and fallen timber of theMallee, flitting low over the undergrowthor alighting on a saltbush isindeed a memorable sight, difficult tosurpass. All of their colors becomebrilliantly apparent, as if lit up, whilethey are in flight and all the whileuttering a beautiful fluty call quitedifferent to so !11any parrots. They are,indeed, a gem.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/677</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 10-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/677/660</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
