<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3750</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-08-06T18:55:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Health and Reproductive Assessment Of Selected Puerto Rican Parrots (Amazona Vittata)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clubb, Susan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Velez, Jafet</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zaias, Julia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Garner, Michael M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cray, Carolyn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Captive production of the Puerto Rican Parrot (Amazona vittata) has been instrumental in recovery of the species from only 13 individuals in the wild in 1975 to a total population of approximately 500 in 2015, (20 to 25 in the wild population in El Yunque National Forest, approximately 100 in the wild population in Rio Abajo State Forest, and over 415 in the captive breeding facilities of the Luquillo/Iguaca and Rio Abajo aviaries). The Puerto Rican Parrot has become an iconic and high-profile conservation species. The cornerstone of the recovery plan for this critically endangered species is an active captive breeding program, management of the wild population, and long-term reintroduction program. The two aviary populations in Puerto Rico (Iguaca, formerly known as Luquillo, and Río Abajo) were this health and reproductive assessment of a sub-set of the species took place, are the only source of parrots for release. Reproductive assessment is a tool used to enhance reproductive potential and produce productive pairings. In 2002 a number of adult birds, which had not produced viable offspring were selected for reproductive assessment, in an attempt to augment the population growth and provide ample individuals for re-introduction. Normal productive individuals were not examined. This assessment included thorough physical exam, endoscopic evaluation, hematology and blood chemistry profiling, viral screening and hormonal assessments.Key words: Amazona vittata, Puerto Rican Parrot, psittacine  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3750</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 43 No. 1 &amp; 2 (2016): Special Double Issue; 12-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3750/3726</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
