<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3885</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-17T03:14:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Everything You Need to Know About Emu Eggs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Turner-Ray, Dorthy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">What Do Emu Eggs Taste Like?
This is often the first question asked by those unfamiliar with emu eggs—and the answer is usually a pleasant surprise. Not only are emu eggs much larger than chicken eggs (roughly 12 times the size), but they are also described as more decadent in flavor.
Their richer taste is often compared to duck eggs and comes from a higher yolk-to-white ratio than in chicken eggs. The texture differs slightly as well: the whites are lighter and almost meringue-like, while the yolk has a smooth, putty-like consistency.

Cooking with Emu Eggs
Emu eggs are a versatile ingredient that can be used in a wide variety of dishes. Their rich, creamy texture makes them especially popular in baking, where they add moisture and depth to cakes, pastries, and custards.
Beyond baking, emu eggs can be prepared much like chicken eggs—but on a much larger scale. A single egg can easily feed a group. You can whip up a fluffy omelet with your favorite fillings, scramble one for a hearty breakfast, or create a frittata that serves the whole family. They also work well in quiches, soufflés, and even homemade pasta.

How to Crack an Emu Egg
Emu eggs are extremely durable, designed to withstand the weight of a large bird during incubation. Their thick shells require more effort—and often tools—to open, as standard egg-cracking methods typically won’t work.
Here are a few recommended techniques:

Use a nail to make a small hole at one end, remove the membrane, and shake the contents into a bowl. Some people use a bicycle pump to blow the egg out.
Use the claw of a hammer to tap around the egg’s center, then gently pry it open.
Use a hacksaw to create a clean, even opening.

[Please continue to PDF for the full article and images]</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3885</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 52 No. 2 (2025): AFA Watchbird Fall/Winter 2025; 16,18-19</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
