<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2842</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-03T19:44:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Presidents Message</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baer, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Approximately one hundred A.F.A. delegates, coordinators and independent members braved the post-blizzard weather of Chicago to attend a most successful Board meeting and mini-convention in February.The Board members brought back to their fellow membership the following important considerations:First, the awareness that we are still confronted with government restrictions and that such repressions are best opposed through strong political action. It was pointed out that though A.F.A. is strong now, every additional member makes us just that much stronger.Each member must be active in membership solicitation. You, as a member, can best further aviculture by talking up A.F.A. and giving out a brochure every time you have a visitor to your aviary and each time you sell a bird. (Brochures are available to you free by just requesting them from the Home Office.)Secondly, the Board members were impressed with the need to promote "across-the-counter" sales of Watchbird in pet shops and other retail outlets in order to reach those who may have an interest in the conservation of avian wildlife, and to acquaint them with our organization.Each of us knows one or more retail outlets or pet shops who would be only too happy to promote aviculture by selling Watchbird, and at a profit to themselves. The Watchbird will sell itself; it need only be made available for sale.(Dealer applications are obtainable from the Home Office without charge. Ask for some today when you send for your brochures.)And, last but not least, the Board members were asked to urge all A.F.A. members to patronize those in industry who support us.This is a competitive world and no one has a monopoly on any item. We are thousands in numbers; so the next time we need feed, buy a bird, or shop for a cage or supplies, let's buy it from someone who advertises in Watchbird.Are you concerned about honest dealers and suppliers? Advertisers in Watchbird must comply with our code of ethics. This is....</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2842</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 2 (1979): APR-MAY 1979; 6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2842/2826</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
