<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/492</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding and Handfeeding Bronze-winged Pion us</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Carpenter, Stan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Although I have been an activeaviculturist since 1 was 16 years old, Iwas totally unprepared for my introductionto the pionus group. Whenwe obtained our first bronze-wingedpionus in the winter of 1982 I wasimmediately impressed by theirgentleness, their subtle colorationand, of course, by the lack of the loudshrieking. that I had experienced withthe Amazons. It was what you mightcall love at first sight. I had to havemore, so we arranged to buy threeadditional specimens which, whencombined with our first, gave us twopairs.As we were living in the city at thetime, the birds spent their first severalmonths living in a common parrotcage. In April 1983 we moved out toour present location in the desertand, shortly thereafter, each pair wasgiven permanent housing. est boxeswere not provided until the fall of1983.In)anuary 1984, pair no. 1 consistingof a mature male and what I wasinformed was an immature female,were observed copulating. They werehoused in a 3' suspended cube with a10" x 12" x 18" nest box. Sometimeduring the month she began to lay, so we kept a close eye on the pair andwere rewarded by two more eggs onthe 6th and 9th.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/492</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 35-36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/492/477</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
