<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/655</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Rueppell's Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Garvin, Cyndee</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Rueppell's Parrot, Poicephalusrueppelli, is native to southwest Africa,specifically Damaraland north to coastalAngola. This is a very dry area withannual rainfall under ten inches ayear. These birds are reported to travelin small groups consisting of one ortwo pairs of birds.Although some may compare theRueppell's Parrot to the Meyer's Parrotin size and appearance, there is adefinite sexual dimorphism in this Poicephalus species with the femalebeing the more brightly colored bird.The hen is more delicate in her featuresand bone structure also. Herbeak size is slightly smaller than thatof the male bird. She has dark pigmentedfeet, a dark colored beak andfiery red eyes. Her overall body is agreenish-charcoal, shoulders are yel lowas is the underside of the wings.Her abdomen is a brilliant blue thatencompasses both her upper thighsand rump. Her orange-yellow socksfinish her wardrobe making her amost impressive bird.Despite his Jack of color, her malecounterpart is not to be underestimated.His beak is the same darkcolor and slightly larger than that ofthe hen. Both birds have the same coloredfeet and those gorgeous redeyes. His body is the same greenishcharcoalcolor and his rump a brightblue but he lacks the blue abdomen.Shoulders are yellow and stockingsare orange-yellow. The juvenile birdhas the appearance of the hen, onlywashed out. The young we raised hadyellowish scalloping on the feathers asis common with other Poicephalusbabies. They lack yellow on the shouldersand the yellow-orange stockingsof the mature birds. Although the eyesare black in babies, they turned redwhen the chicks were four monthsold. We noticed considerable developmentof brighter plumage at the firstmolt.We have found some similaritiesbetween the Rueppell's Parrot's dispo-sition and that of the other Poicephalusspecies we keep. As with most ofour other pairs, our two pairs of Rueppell'sParrots are timid and aloof, hidingin the nest box during feeding andcleaning time. Our proven hen is theexception. She is always out of thebox at feeding time, whistling andhopping on the cage bottom muchlike a Hyacinth Macaw. We have alsonoticed a great deal of displaying onthe part of the hen. She raises herwings, showing off her yellow undersideand her calls remind us more of aBudgie than of a Poicepha/us. In general,with our mature hens and nowour young hens, we can clearly seethat the female is the more aggressive,treating her mate similar to the way inwhich the Eclectus hen treats hermale.Our two pairs of domestic Rueppell'sParrot's were a very generouswedding gift from a good friend wholives in South Africa. The birds werequarantined in San Diego by USDA.Upon release by USDA and FWS, weextended the quarantine here at homebefore putting them into a breedingsituation with the existing flock.Although two of the birds were obviouslymature, they were not markedas pairs, so we colonized them inhopes that they would repair. Apparentlythey did, with the mature pairbeing the dominant two, exhibiting astrong bond. Even in this colony situationthe mature hen presented herselfas the self-appointed monarch.We breed many species of parrots,but our Poicepha/us species arehoused together in their own separatesection. Once the Rueppell's Parrotshad passed all of our medical tests,they were added to the establishedflock. They are housed, as are theothers, in 2' x 2' x 3' cages made with1" x 1" wire. Two natural manzanitaperches were hung, one slightlyhigher than the other. The nest box isa deep Cockatiel box approximately10" x 10" x 20". We feed a diet offreshseeds, nuts and various fruits and vegetables.The Rueppell's Parrots arefond of any fruits and vegetables weoffer, particularly green beans,oranges and corn.Having read literature concerningtheir natural habits, we learned that the Rueppell's Parrots were not largelygregarious. In view of this, dividerswere placed on both sides of the cageand six cages, housing other Poicepha/us, separate the two pairs. Themature pair began digging in the boxonly three clays after being introducedto it and both pairs were sleeping intheir box after two weeks. We had situatedthe mature pair in a location thatwe could observe from a distance.Although we were discreet and somewhathidden, the male knew we werewatching and was noticeably nervous.We decided to heed his warning signsand block off our field of view. Twoweeks later we had four fertile eggs.Normally we allow our Poicepha/uspairs to incubate their eggs and feedthe young for ten days to two weeksbefore they are removed from the nestfor handfeeding. Our parent birdsalways do a wonderful job caring fortheir young and we are not particularlyexcited about feeding babies thatweigh only five grams from clay one.However, we decided to feed thesechicks since they were so importantto us.Incubation began when the first eggwas laid and since the female wasdoing such a terrific job of incubating(the male stayed in the nest but wasnever on the eggs) we chose to leavethe eggs with her for as long as possibleand pull them just before hatching.Well, you know what they say aboutthe best laid plans ... just twelve claysinto incubation we had a huge earthquake,and needless to say, she abandonedthe eggs and they had to bepulled for artificial incubation. As itnu·necl out, all four eggs were cracked.We lost the first baby but managed tohatch all the others. Incubation timewas 28 clays but draw clown to externalpip time is not known as all eggshad-to be assisted. Hatch dates areMay 7, 9 and 13 of 1991. Weight athatch for all chicks was five grams.The first two chicks hatched withwhite clown, light colored feet andwhite beaks. The last baby also hadwhite clown but the toenails had clarkpigment and the beak was black. Wehoped this had to be some type ofsexual dimorphism. This chick turnedout to be what we deemed, the male.After only one week, feeding a commercial handfeeding formula, thebabies had more than doubled theirweight with the exception of the male.Although his cultures were clean hewas red in color and failed to thrive.At times he seemed to be almost in afrenzy. An article was brought to ourattention in which the author, havingexperienced the same thing in herPoicepha/us chicks, added creamedcorn to her handfeeding formula withgreat results. We tried it with instantsuccess.The babies were weighed daily andphotographed constantly. By fourweeks of age they weighed 104 gramsand at 11 weeks old they wereweaned and independent. Visual sexingindicated we had one male andtwo females. The male had biggerbone structure and less blue on hisabdomen. We had to separate thebabies once they were completelyweaned as outbreaks of fighting werebecoming more and more frequentbetween the young hens. We keptone young hen in the house, andplaced the other related pair in a holdingcage, waiting for the onset ofmaturity and hopefully, unrelatedbloodlines. The siblings gave us everyindication that they could be compatiblecage mates. When they wereapproximately nine months old, wewere horrified to discover our youngmale had died at the hands of his sister.Our older pairs of Rueppell's Parrotshave never been observed fightingin such a way, however, the malesdo seem to know their place.Our proven pair is once again sittingon four fertile eggs which are hatchingas we write. Our other pair shows nosign of producing anytime this season.Our plans are to let our proven henincubate as well as feed her young.We are keeping our fingers crossedthat the earth stays still long enoughfor her to hatch all of them this time.Rueppell's Parrots are indeed rare inprivate aviculn1re. We encourage anyonehaving a pair to seriously attemptbreeding, and if successful, to avoidplacing the offspring into the pettrade. We hope that anyone with asingle bird will contact us or try to findanother breeder willing to cooperatein the propagation of this species andavoid hybridizing at all cost.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/655</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 8-9</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/655/638</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
