<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3168</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-26T09:12:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">10 Ways to support AFA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Whittaker, Jamie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en"> I have an important job for everyone who wants to volunteer-support this organization any way you can. If everyone reading this does the things listed below, AFA will be able to accomplish so much. Thank you to everyone. You are making a huge difference!1 Talk about AFA when you talk about birds. Mention AFA and send people to the website for information.2 Give away the Watchbirds you don't want to keep. Some of you get multiple copies. Put the extras at the hair salon, at the vet's, at the library, at the school.3 Get people to take the Fundamentals of Aviculture course when they ask for advice on birds.4 Talk to other bird people and encourage them to join AFA. It's only $40 for one year for an individual.~ Talk to people you do business with, and encourage them to join as commercial members and advertise in Watchbird. Ask them for raffie donations. It is $125 for a year, and they get a free classified in Watchbird and their name and link on our website and in every Watch bird. 6 Talk to every bird group you know or can find and tell them why they should be affiliated with AFA if they are not. Contact your state coordinator with information for the group. If you are in an affiliated club, speak up in favor of AFA when the subject of re-affiliation comes up.P Join at least one AF A-affiliated organization and promote it. If you don't have a local club, there are many national organizations. There is strength in numbers. The more of us there are who work together, the better off we will be.8 Get a group together to attend the Convention.Just think how much fun you and two or three of your favorite bird friends can have in St Petersburg talking about and learning about birds.9 Watch for official legislative alerts from the office and from Legislative Vice President Genny Wall and act on them. When she says it's time to write letters or call your representative, she needs as many people as possible to do it.~ @ Be positive in your interactions with others about birds and about AFA. This organization is only here because there are people who love birds. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3168</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 37 No. 2 (2010): Number 2  2010; 14-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3168/3152</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
