<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1671</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:51:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding Yellow faced Parrotlets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A lthough imported into the United States in the 1970s and early 1980s, Yellowfaced Parrotlets Forpus xantbops had all but disappeared by the 1990s. In spring of 1994, I was fortunate enough to obtain five pair ofYellowfaced Parrotlets and have had much success in breeding them.DescriptionYellow-faced Parrotlets are the largest of the Forpus genus. Approximately six inches in length, they can weigh up to 45 grams. Yellow "Faced" is a misnomer as the entire forehead, cheeks, chin, chest and belly are bright lemon yellow. Males have deep cobalt on the wings, back, rump and eyes streaks, very similar to male Pacific Parrotlets Forpus coelestis. Females have light blue backs, wings, rumps and eye streaks, which is the same as female Forpus coelestis lucida. A feature unique to the Yellow-faced is a black streak that runs down the middle of the top mandible.Status and RangeYellow-faced Parrotlets are often considered to be one of the rarest species of Forpus both in captivity and in the wild. There are believed to be less than 50 birds in the United States. Europe reportedly has a number of breeders but even so, their availability is very limited. In the wild, they are found in the upper Rio Maranon Valley in Northern Peru. Fortunately, they are prolific breeders in captivity so that makes. it much easier on aviculturists working with this species. The International Parrotlet Society is one organization dedicated to conserving the Yellowfaced Parrotlet and has set up a breeding program for it.In Aviculture HousingYellow-faced Parrotlets do well in large cages that are 2' tall, 2' wide and 3' long. The pairs should he visually separated so they can hear hut not see each other. This helps prevent aggression and keeps the pairs focused on breeding rather than fighting.Each pair is given a variety of natural wood perches and given a lovebird-style (7"w x lO"t x 7"d) nest box attached to the outside front of the cage. The pair will see only the inside of their cage while in the box, thereby making the pair feel more secure. Boxes are filled with untreated pine shavings to within 2" of the nest hole.Unlike other species of Forpus that are mature at one year, Yellowfaced have much better breeding success at two years of age. Youngsters of the same sex can he housed in large flights until they are breeding age then paired into individual cages with nest boxes. Yellow-faced Parrotlets seem to he much less aggressive than other species of Forpus which is especially good since there are so few of them available.FeedingYellow-faced Parrotlets are delightful birds to feed as they eat just about everything given to them. Most parrotlets eat large quantities of food for their size, hut Yellow-faced consume a huge amount even for a parrotlet. We feed a safflower based hookhill mix that contains peanuts, sunflower, and hemp as they need the extra fat and protein. We also feed Tropican™ pellets and Petamine™, which, along with cuttlebone, mineral block, and clean water, are always available.The bulk of our diet is fresh foods that include two or three different fruits and up to 10 different vegetables plus cooked rice or pasta and dried beans daily. They also receive chopped greens and whole wheat or multigrain bread as well as sprouted seed and egg food. Vitamins and powdered calcium supplement are sprinkled on the soft foods several times a week. They are also given bee pollen, Spirulina™ and wheat grass powder weekly.Nesting and BreedingNesting behavior is much the same as other species of Forpus. The male usually investigates the box first and once he deems it safe, is followed by the hen. They do not build nests hut chew and rearrange the shavings into shallow depressions. Females pluck their breasts to make a brood patch and leave the feathers in the nest. Before she lays the first egg, she will consume huge quantities of cuttlebone - often as much as a 6" cuttlebone everyday for several weeks prior to laying. Hens will lay one egg every other day and have an average clutch of four to six. She will sit on those eggs, leaving only to defecate, until the last chick has left the nest. The incubation period is slightly longer in this species with chicks hatching at 24 days instead of the usual 21 Interestingly, the Mexican Parrotlet Porpus cyanopgyius also hatches at 24 days.Yellow-faced Parrotlets will feed and fledge their own young if allowed, As with other species, the adult male ought to be removed from the c:ige when the young start to fledge. This will prevent aggression between parent and offspring. Adult males have been known to maim or even kill their male chicks upon fledging. The female will continue to feed the young and teach them to eat on their own. The male can return once the chicks are weaned and are placed in another flight.We handfeed our chicks. This is done even though they aren't to he sold as pets. Often, handfed parrotlets that are not socialized to he pets, make steady, reliahle parents that are not overly sensitive to human intervention. They are used to hut not handed to people, therefore they raise healthy chicks without causing havoc when humans are in the aviary. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1671</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 3 (2001): Third Quarter 2001; 62-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1671/1648</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
