<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/635</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Golub, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Symposium CrucialTo AvicultureThe University of California at Davis held a fact-filled symposiumon Parrot Biology on October 17, 1992. The event wasculminated by speaker Gary Lilienthal who is the AFA legalcounsel. Lilienthal has been involved in the current Federallegislation that will curtail and limit the importation of birds.The symposium was coordinated by Ann Brice, Ph.D. of theDepartment of Avian Sciences at the University of Davis, andfeatured guest speakers Catherine Toft (Hybridization - Prosand Cons), Nursery Management by Jeanne Smith, FactorsAffecting Psittacine Fertility and Hatchability by UrsulaAbbott, Avian Nutrition by Tom Roudybush, Preventing Diseaseby Patricia Wakenell, and the Postmortem Exam by LindaLowenstine.A strong case was made against hybridization or the takingof different species and mating them to produce a differentlooking bird. It is generally agreed that many exotic bird species,mostly tropical, are becoming endangered and threatenedthrough a combination of the trade in wild-caught birds, smuggling,slaughter and habit destruction. While most species arenot endangered because of hybridization per se, nonetheless,interspecific hybridization in captivity threatens our ability tomaintain exotic species in captivity in their "natural" state.Of particular interest to those breeding birds was the topicand discussion on Nursery Management. Diseases are introducedinto the avian nursery by food, water, utensils and otherequipment, caretakers and the birds themselves.While food does not have to be absolutely sterile, it shouldnot be contaminated with gram negative bacteria. It is stronglyrecommended to purchase formulas from reputable and establishedmanufacturers. Avoid reheated leftover formulas as itbecomes a growth media for bacteria, yeast and fungus. Evenrefrigeration does not stop organism growth.Beware of water softening treatments. Salt in softened waterhas been known to kill young chicks. Be careful when usingwater-warmed brooders as they can become contaminated byenvironmental contaminants unless attention is paid to frequentcleaning and disinfecting.Foot traffic through the nursery should be kept to a minimum.Often we see a heavily trafficed place such as the kitchenused as a nursery. Avoid the temptation to utilize part of thenursery as a sick room as this presents an extreme risk tohealthy baby birds.By using good sanitation procedures and being consistent,good management can keep your chicks in good health.Incubation of eggs is increasing with aviculturists. A suitableincubator and hatcher should be able to maintain a temperatureof up to 38°C with less than 1/4°C fluctuation and a relativehumidity of at least 60%. It should be equipped for automaticturning of eggs through at least 90°. If turning is not automatic,it should be accomplished without opening the incubator. Themachine should have an internal fan so that temperature andhumidity are the same in all parts of the machine. An adequatesupply of fresh air should be available. Many breeders prefer tolower the temperature of their incubators by a degree or twoand increase the humidity to facilitate hatching. Hatching differentspecies separately in hatchers thoroughly disinfectedbetween each use can be important in the prevention of diseaseproblems.There are areas of avian nutrition which are on the cuttingedge, particularly with new data. Very popular today withhuman diets, a decrease in fat in the diet, particularly withobese birds, is practiced. Fat, of course, in excess is nothealthy. In any weight loss program, the bird must be closelymonitored to assess the rate of weight loss and whether anynewly substituted diet is being consumed. If possible, a birdshould be weighed at regular intervals if on a weight reductionprogram. Weight loss should not be more than three percent ofthe bird's body weight per week. Examination of the bird'sdroppings is an easy way to detennine whether the bird is eating.The dropping color may change, but the volume should belarger than the volume of urine and bile combined for a fastingbird.The event culminated with a detailed discussion on the Federallegislation that will curb importation of many birds, andslow down the exportation of birds around the world. Guestspeaker Gary Lilienthal said the legislation was workable aslong as all parties to the legislation work together in harmony.Lilienthal has donated his time as an attorney for four years tofurther the American Federation of Aviculture 's position on thelegislation. He is a second generation aviculturist, and hasworked long and hard for the interest of the AFA. In his concludingremarks, he related that he was disappointed that individualstates could still impose their own regulations and certainaspects seemed restrictive but, by in large, the legislationwould have been totally restrictive had the American Federationof Aviculture and aviculturists around the world not lettheir voices be heard.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/635</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 47-50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/635/618</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
