<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3930</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-09T03:48:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">In Memory of Kathy Heaton and Laurie Baker</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">of Aviculture, American Federation</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 3 (July 2024). The text below contains excerpts from the original article. For photographs, figures, advertisements, and the complete formatted version as originally published, please use the PDF link associated with this article. Kathleen B. Heaton (Kathy), 74, of Shreveport, Louisiana, passed away at her home in Houston, Texas June 10, 2024. She was born on December 31, 1949. Kathy retired from Southwestern Bell after 32 years of service. After retirement, she enjoyed working at ABC Birds part time. She always gave all the birds her special attention. She was a hobby bird breeder of lovebirds and other small exotic birds. She loved her birds and all birds! Her first bird, the bird of her heart, was a Senegal named Star. She once rescued a blind Amazon that was over 50 years old. He lived with her for the rest of his life. Her double yellow head Amazon was with her when she passed. Kathy was a dedicated volunteer in aviculture. She had an active Yahoo group, Bird_Breeder-Hobbyist, with over 5000 subscribers. She passed along relevant information related to the birds in our care. Updates on health, legislation, conservation and avian activities were sent out daily to keep us all informed. It is with heavy hearts that we share the passing of Laurie Baker, the esteemed founder of Feathered Follies. Laurie's dedication to the exotic bird community was unparalleled, and her impact on both birds and people alike will be forever cherished. Since founding Feathered Follies in 1993, Laurie has been a beacon of knowledge, compassion, and advocacy. Her commitment to the well-being of birds has touched countless lives, and her legacy continues to resonate throughout our community. Click the PDF link associated with this article to view the complete article as originally published in AFA Watchbird.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3930</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 3 (2024): AFA Watchbird July 2024</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3930/3895</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
