<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1665</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:51:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question #1: I have a female Cockatiel, which has been showing signs of fluffed feathers, sleepiness and labored breathing. Her nares look darkened, possibly inflamed. I took her to an avian vet who treated her with amikin for 10 days, then doxy and baytril with no improvement. Her CBC showed an increased number of neutrophils and lymphs. Then he came up with the idea of lead poisoning with injections twice daily with no improvement. The bird's appetite is good and she drinks. I placed two heat lights to keep her warm. There is no change in the bird's condition. Also, she is not egg bound. Could you please give me some direction to follow or how should I proceed with her care?K. Dayne, ConnecticutAnswer #1: I would suggest that a further more complete workup be done on your Cockatiel. Repeat the blood count, add a chemistry panel and check for viruses with the blood sample. Screening for disease producing bacteria and radiographs of the bird would be useful to rule in or out certain diseases and suggest further specific procedures. Unfortunately, your description of the bird is a generalized picture of a bird that does not feel well but is not specific for any one particular disease.James M. Harris, DVM Oakland, CAAnswer #2: It sounds like more tests need to be run on your bird to try to pinpoint the problem. The signs she is showing of being fluffed and sleepy are not specific and can fit almost any sick bird. The labored breathing could be an indication of a respiratory problem or abdominal swelling. The darkened nares could be due to debris buildup in the nostrils and are not necessarily an indica- tion of inflammation. You said she is not eggbound, but do we know this from a physical examination or a radiograph? The elevated heterophils and lymphocytes indicate inflammation but are not specific as to cause. Since she has been treated with a variety of antibiotics, it seems probable that the problem is not bacterial but other organisms can cause respiratory signs and elevated WBC including fungal, yeast, or even anaerobic bacterial infections. There are specific tests that can be run to determine this. She also could have yolk in the abdomen from an internal ovulation, which could cause the swelling in the abdomen and inflammation. At this point she needs a thorough physical examination, radiographs, a recheck CBC, bacterial and fungal culture, fecal gram stain, an Aspergillosis test (for fungus) and a chlamydia serology test for psittacosis. If her abdomen is swollen, she also needs a fine needle aspirate and microscopic exam of the cells to determine the cause.Rhoda. Steven.son., DVM, ABVP-Avian Jacksonville, FloridaAnswer #3: Many birds will respond to symptomatic care that may include antibiotics when they are ill. In the situation where several antibiotics have been utilized without a positive response, it would be highly advisable to consider a more complete diagnostic workup. Any test that is performed can best be viewed as a potential diagnostic aid, and may or may not result in an answer as to what is ailing the bird. It might also be prudent to consider visiting a second veterinarian that is knowledgeable and experienced with birds. After a through physical examination, a complete blood panel that consists of a complete blood count, serum chemistries, amylase and a bile acid, a protein electrophoresis, radiographs or X-rays, and a fecal parasite exami- nation might be considered. Depending on what the attending veterinarian finds, he or she may suggest additional diagnostic tests for your pet.Amy B. Worell, DVM, ABVP-Avian West Hills, CA. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1665</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 3 (2001): Third Quarter 2001; 38-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1665/1642</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
