<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/628</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Those Wonderful Neophemas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Atkinson, Joe</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Editor's note: The Turquoise Parrotthis article refers to is Neophemapulchella. In American aviculture, itis more commonly known as theTurquoisine Pm·akeet.Neophema is the scientific genusname given to a group of small,Budgie-sized parakeets from Australia.Neophemas are quite beautiful,all being grass-green except onemember, the Bourke's Parakeet. TheBourke's Parakeet is light brown witha soft pink chest and belly and large,dark eyes. These large, dark eyes givethem the ability to see better at twilighttime than other grass parakeets,thus earning them the name of theNight Parrot in their native Australia.The grass-green Neophemas, whospend most of their time on theground, have been given the nickname"grass parakeets.''Grass parakeets are not considereddifficult to raise, in fact, some membersare quite good breeders. However,like all birds we attempt to raisein captivity, they have their specialrequirements. This article is by nomeans the last word on raising grassparakeets. Birds seem to know whentheir keepers are thinking too highlyof themselves and will show us justhow little we do know.In any new undertaking, trial anderror is the best rule of thumb. Grassparakeets are no exception. Over theyears, I have certainly made my shareof errors and hopefully I have learneda few things along the way. I hopethis article will smooth the road foryou and help you have an enjoyabletime with your grass parakeets.Flights And Nest BoxesGrass parakeets will reproduce injust about any size flight, from 2'x 3'indoor setups to the largest outdoorflight. Because they will not normallycolony breed, it is best to have onlyone pair per flight, so large outdoorflights are not practical for the seriousbreeder. In California, grass parakeetsare kept outside in flights thatare two feet wide by four feet high bysix feet long. Four feet of the flightshould be covered, containing thefeeding and nest box area. Theremaining two feet of the flightshould remain uncovered, allowingthe birds access to any available sun.Nest box privacy is essential. Therefore,if you have side-by-side flights,you must place partitions in theflights which will provide adequateprivacy. Weather is usually not amajor problem, but cold windcan be. Many breeders prefer tocover their flight with plastic neopreneduring stormy weather.In the wild, grass parakeets arecavity nesters, using hollow treebranches and hollow tree trunkswhich are their preferred nest sites. Ihave used natural nest boxes madefrom hollow logs and the birds lovedthem, but these natural nests are difficultto clean and impossible forbanding the baby birds. The commonBudgie box works great, is easy toclean and easy to repair. Fill the boxthree inches deep with pine shavings,and pack it down smooth. Grassparakeets like to dig in their nest box.With the shavings packed smooth,you can tell if your birds are workingthe nest box in preparation fornesting.Nesting takes place in the springand throughout the summer. Theclutches are usually three to five eggsin number but can go as high aseight. Grass parakeets will stop nestingon their own in late summer andshould be encouraged to do so. However,in indoor setups where lightand temperature are controlled, they.will nest all year. In outdoor setups,leave the nest boxes up all yearbecause on cold winter nights theywill use them for sleeping.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/628</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 26-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/628/611</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
