<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4004</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Scientific Test Turkey at Work</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">PhD, Constance Woodman,</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 1 (January/February 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Loretta is a Naraganset breed turkey with an important job. Because of her job, Loretta has been in multiple news publications, including The New York Times , Scholastic News , Up Front magazine, Texas A&amp;amp;M Today , and the science website Phys.org, and quick read websites such as Petnews2day.In the October 2023 WatchBird issue, I talked about Loretta the house turkey, and what it is like to have a litter box trained, harness trained, and free-flight trained turkey. In this article I will share Loretta’s job as a Scientific Test Turkey.Loretta earns her poultry crumbles by testing artificial eggs. These eggs, if they pass, are then used to study wild birds. Loretta is suspicious of the visible seam in this egg design. This egg design was rejected, though an improved version was accepted.The artificial eggs hold sensors and tiny computers to record incubation. The sensors are made by Dr. Scott Shaffer at San Jose State University, and I design and make the artificial shells. Science writer Sean Michael Ragan programs the loggers and repairs them.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4004</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 1 (2024): Watchbird January/February 2024; 8-9</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4004/3964</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
