<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1355</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:24:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ROSELLAS; A U.S. VIEWPOINT: The Green Rosella</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wrigley, Blue</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he Green Rosella, also known as the Tasmanian Rosella, and sometimes called the Mountain Rosella in Australia, is the largest of the P/atycercusfamily. It is found in its natural habitat in Australia, mainly on the island of Tasmania, hence its name, and on occasions in the state of Victoria, which is across the Bass Straight Sea, separating mainland Australia from Tasmania.The Green Rosella is the largest and rarest of the Rosellas. Its average size is approximately 13 inches (340mm),including the tail. It's coloration is a lemon/yellow colored head and neck with a red/scarlet patch above the upper mandible, with the cheek patches being a deep blue. The hack has green-black feathers, the wings are black with blue inner-flight feathers, outer coverts are bright blue, inner coverts are jet black. The tail is bluegreen and the underside or belly is yellow, and sometime splashed with orange patches. These orange patches are more predominate in the hen and can extend upwards towards the breast area. Uncommon in the USAThere are not many pairs of these hirds in this country because of the cost, the uncertainty of breeding, and. at times, the aggressiveness of their nature, so most aviculturists have not included them in their aviaries. This is unfortunate because they are a magnificent member of the rosella family. Another reason for their lack of popularity is that they are the least colorful of all of the birds in this group. It is sad to see that not all, hut a lot of breeders, like to breed only the eye-catching, colorful birds that sell commercially.FeedingOur birds are fed a mixture of various seed that is sprouted/soaked 12 months of the year. This is broken up into the following approximate percentages:• Sunflower 20%• Canary 20%• Parakeet 30%• Oats/Groats 10%• Safflower 10%• Buckwheat 10%We also add two cups of hoiled rice, finely grind/chop-up various fruits and vegetables and mix these with frozen peas and corn, and then add and thoroughly mix this cornhination with the seed mixture. Vegetables used are carrots, yams, turnips, rutabaga, green cabbage, red cabbage, and spinach. The fruits are apples and pears - hard, not soft. In two gallons of sprouted seed we add 8 cups of the fruit/rice/vegetahle mixture. We also add 1 oz. of wheat germ oil to this mix. You can use just about any vegetable or fruit that is in season to mix with the seed. This mixture is fed daily. We have found that with the fruit/vegetable mix being so fine, the birds tend to eat this first, thereby eliminating any possibility of spoilage. All of our hirds love honeysuckle vine. If there are vines around a flight, they are immaculately trimmed by them. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1355</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 4 (1999): JULY-AUG 1999; 61-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1355/1333</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
