<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1189</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question #1: I have several pet birds and my veterinarian has talked to me about the new polyomavirus vaccine for them. I am concerned about giving them something that they don't need. Is it safe? Why or why not should I give my birds this vaccine? I have a Senegal Parrot and a Blue and Gold Macaw.S. Vaughn, ConnecticutAnswer #I: Polyomavirus is a serious problem for hatchlings and nestlings who succumb and die from this virus. Once birds have an adequately developed immune system, and then are exposed, they can become carriers and shed the virus from time to time or eliminate the virus from their system. By 60 days of age, most birds are immune competent and do not develop symptoms if exposed. The vaccine has its place in breeding situations where polyomavirus has caused losses of chicks, but it is not a substitute for good sanitation and "the closed aviary principle." There does not seem to be any reason to vaccinate your two pet birdsfames M. Harris, DVM Oakland, CA Answer #2: The use of the polyomavirus vaccine is controversial, although it is considered safe and efficacious. There is only a small chance of getting a reaction to the vaccine, such as a scab at the injection site, and that is only when the vaccine is administered incorrectly (in the skin as opposed to under the skin). For this reason, it is recommended that only veterinarians administer the vaccine as an inexperienced person could accidentally give the vaccine in the skin (intradermally). In studied research trials, the vaccine protects birds adequately for at least one year. Until more is known, it is advised to revaccinate the birds at yearly intervals.The controversial aspect comes from when birds should receive this vaccine. Most veterinarians would agree that the vaccine should be used in growing chicks and those under a year of age. It is during this period that birds are most likely to die from the disease, especially if they are exposed to groups of birds from other breeding facilities. Adult birds that have low exposure to other birds (no new birds come to live in the house and birds do not leave the house to mingle with birds from other households) are generally not vaccinated, especially if there are only a few pet birds in a single house. Without a doubt, the need to vaccinate is considered on a bird by bird basis and the past, present, and future flock history of the birds.Kim L. Joyner, DVM, MPVM Raleigh, NCAnswer #3: Use and recommendations for the polyomavirus vaccine vary greatly from veterinarian to veterinarian. The pet birds that are presented for veterinary care in my practice are handled on an individual basis. Many of these birds reside in their owner's homes only, and may make occasional trips to their veterinarian for routine veterinary care or grooming. Others may be taken to pet stores for procedures, taken to bird club meetings, or have a variety of exposures to other psittacines. In the first situation, where the birds are home bodies, I do not actively encourage use of the polyomavirus vaccine. In the second situation, where other exposures are probable, I think use of the polyomavirus vaccine is warranted. My breeder clients, including my own birds, have not been vaccinated.Amy B. Worell, DVM, ABVP, Avian West Hills, CAQuestion #2: My pet Cockatiel has been laying eggs in the seed dish. She does not have a mate and I don't want to breed her. Is it best to leave the eggs with her or should I throw them away? If I throw them away, do I let her have the whole clutch or do I remove each one after it is laid? Why did she all of a sudden decide to lay eggs? She is five years old and I have had her since she was six weeks old P Haggard, Kentucky</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1189</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 4 (1997): JULY-AUGUST 1997; 52-54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1189/1168</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
