<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3066</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-17T18:44:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">State Co-ordinators</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baer, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One of the most important functions in the administrative organization of the American Federation of Aviculture is that of the State Coordinator.The State Coordinator is the representative to the A.F.A. of the membership at large in his/her respective state; and is responsible for organizing the state program of member solicitation, both at the individual and club level.A.F .A. depends upon the State Coordinator to disseminate official information and policy to the club delegates and individual members in his/her state. It also relies on the coordinator to keep abreast of legislation affecting birds at the state and local level and of forwarding such information to A.F .A.The membership at large and the local clubs, through their delegates, look to the coordinator for enlightenment on official A.F .A. policy and for leadership and guidance in our fight against anti-aviculture legislation and arbitrary rulings that effect a vi culture.The coordinator therefore is our most important link in the chain of communications between A.F .A. and its membership.The State Coordinator has delegate status and serves as a voting member on the "board of directors of A.F .A. Any complaint or suggestion by any member can be channeled through his/her coordinator directly to the board of directors for action.The coordinator can and does serve on various committees, and if elected, is eligible to serve in any administrative office of A.F .A.He/she can be removed from his/her appointment as coordinator only through his/her own voluntary resignation or by action of the board of directors' ruling upon written complaint by a member citing the coordinator's malfeasance of office 9r neglect of duty. From time to time we do have coordinators resigning due to their lack of sufficient time to meet the demands of their assignment or for other personal reasons.In times of non-emergencies, the duties of State Coordinator are not overly demanding, but are important. Duties include attending local bird club meetings, both member and non-member clubs, to explain our goals and purposes and to distribute our literature.In times of emergency, such as the recent Newcastle Disease problem, the task of the State Coordinator can be quite demanding and time consuming.As A.F .A. is a non-profit organization whose officers all serve without compensation, we must rely on the dedication of the coordinator to aviculture to give of his/her ability, energy and time and be content with the satisfaction that through this effort restrictive legislation has been thwarted or changed.We need coordinators who have the zeal and the time to carry out these responsibilities and duties. This is not an honorary position and anyone who does not have the interest nor the time to devote to these duties should not aspire to the position.In subsequent issues of this publication, A.F .A. will acquaint its membership with a State Coordinator of a different state each month with a photograph and brief biography of that person. We are justly proud of our coordinators and wish to acknowledge the contributions that they make to the success of the American Federation of Aviculture . </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3066</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 4 (1977): AUG-SEPT 1977; 20-21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3066/3050</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
