<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2993</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-15T08:02:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Building a Nest Box</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sharp, Dick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Do it yourself!! - and cut down on some of those expenses. This is an easy and inexpensive box to build from 1,4" plywood.The material I used is as follows: %"PlywoodI Jlh" X II Vi" - 3 pieces (top and bottom)11 Y2" x 12" - 2 pieces (front and back) 12" x 12" - 2 pieces (sides)Y-i" Lumber3,4'' x 3,4 '' x 1 1 V2'' - 2 pieces 3,4" x 3,4" x IO" - 2 pieces ¥.i" X ¥.i" x 3"-1 piece% " Wood Dowel%" x 16"Wood glue,%" wood drill bit, small 3,4" wood screw, 3,4'' wire brad, nails (small nails)Assembly1,4'' x I I Y2'' x I I V2'' - 3 pieces - one piece for the top and two pieces I glued together to save from buying 1h'' plywood for the bottom.1,4" x II Vz'' x 12" - 2 pieces - Front and back, glue and nail together to bottom piece (2 pieces glued together, I I Vi" x II Y2 "). I used 3,4" length wire brad nails. Small nails are used so the plywood will not split.14" X 12" x 12" - 2 pieces, for the sides - glue and nail on the parts already assembled.¥.i" x 3,4" x I Jlh" - 2 pieces, and ¥.i" X 3,4" x 10" - 2 pieces. These four pieces are glued and nailed inside, \4" from the top. This is for the top to rest on and to support the nest. This is a good place to put your hangers, whatever type you like.I also used a 3" x 3,4" x ¥.!" for a handle for the top.% '' X 16'' dowel for perch, through the nest. This I used a wood screw to fasten through the back and glue in the front. Drill a small hole, smaller then the screw, in one end of the dowel. I did this to keep the dowel from splitting. I used a % " wood drill bit to drill the hole in the front.After the glue has dried, I used a jig saw and cut a 3'' hole as in the diagram I have drawn.You may also like to sand the edges of the top so as to fit a little loose. I also put 2%" holes in the sides at the top for ventilation. With this nest box, you do not need hardware (hinges).I like this type box for with the top opening, the chicks cannot fall out. Also, if the temperature gets too warm, you can leave the top part way open for more air. I have never had trouble with birds getting out with this type of nest.I prefer to use wood chips in the nest box for cockatiels. The chips make a good nest for the eggs and gives both the hen and cock bird something to chew on to keep them occupied while setting on the eggs. I find that the birds will not chew on the nest box as much with chips in the nest box.I also have found that by using chips of cedar, you may not have as much trouble from mites and lice. By using the wood chips, I am now using my nest boxes for the fourth year and there is very little damage to the boxes from chewing. This damage is at the 3'' diameter hole only. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2993</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 5 (1978): OCT- NOV 1978; 40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2993/2977</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
