<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4068</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:17:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Papercraft Toys</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Woodman, Constance</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 1 (January 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.By Constance Woodman, PhD. Conservation Grants Manager, Texas A&amp;amp;M UniversityOnce, my African grey parrot hen got stuck inside a loop of chain. She chewed away a circle of pine wood squares while I was work. When I came home, I found my bird frozen in panic, the chain around her chest, slowly spinning from the c-clip! Luckily, I had two pairs of pliers and was able to open one of the chain links and free my bird. After that, I have been very careful about loops and strings in bird toys. Paper bird toys allow for safer play. Long and thin strips of paper tear before they can wrap up and tangle or choke a bird. Ring and donut shapes, or shapes with cut out holes, are also safer. When the bird puts a head or leg through an opening, the paper will give way when the bird tries to pull it off. Similar shapes made of metal, plastic, or cottonbe cut with a paper cutter and used for foraging. Easy to fold boxes with fun cut-out shapes on the lids may be for candy in the eyes of a paper crafter but they are prime foraging boxes to me!Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4068</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 1 (2022): Watchbird January 2022; 10-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4068/4028</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
