<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1502</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-19T21:23:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Lory Collection at the San Diego Zoo</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schulenburg, Wayne A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionHistorically lories have heen an outstanding feature of the avian collection at the San Diego Zoo. Beginning in 1925 with Swainson's Lorikeets, as many as 28 different species were exhibited at one time during the late 1960s and early 1970s.During this period the lories were housed in a' group of 35 enclosures known as Benchley Plaza. For the lory enthusiast, this provided the opportunity to view the obvious differences between such genera as Eos, Lorius and Chalcopsitta, as well as compare the subtleties between subspecies of Tricboglossus and Eos. Unfortunately, it was not uncommon to exhibit singles or same sex individuals of any particular species; therefore, breeding and maintaining a self-sustaining population was rarely possible.In the late 1980s a new emphasis emerged in the zoo community -- conservation and the need to establish self-sustaining captive populations. With a limited number of enclosures, this new emphasis had its effect on the lory collection. The number of different species and subspecies has decreased to allow for more pairs of some of the critical species to be worked with. However, the lory collection still remains impressive with species that include: Tahitian, Cardinal, Solitary, and Red-flanked Lories.Species Tahitian LoryThe Tahitian Lory, Vini peruoiana, was first received in 1978 as a result of a confiscation. The current captive population is limited to the San Diego Zoo and Loro Parque. Because of its rarity in captive collections, this lory is Europe and South Africa, but to our knowledge it has not bred in the U.S. The pair exhibited at the San Diego Zoo was received in 1991 when a small number of these birds were imported into the United States. Even though they have been given a number of different enclosures, the birds have not yet bred.Red-collared LorikeetThe Red-collared Lorikeet, Tricboglossus haematodus rubritorquis, of northern Australia, is certainly one of the most striking of the rainbow group. It was once listed as the most common Jory species held in European aviculture, but recent reports indicate that it is now found in only a few collections. It has never been common in the United States. Twenty-eight were produced in the late 1960s and early 1970s but were not kept in the collection. In 1988 two pairs were received from the Melbourne Zoo in Australia. Unfortunately, the two females died soon after arrival and it was not until 1995 that we obtained a captive-reared female from Walsrode Bird Park in Germany. Since that pairing, seven young have been produced with offspring returned to Walsrode.Purple-capped LoryThe Purple-capped Lory, Lorius domicellus, from the Indonesian islands of Ceram and Amboina, has always been an uncommonspecies in captivity. It was first displayed at San Diego in 1928 with chicks hatching three times. Unfortunately, none have lived beyond two days.Black-winged LoryEven though the Black-winged Lory, Eos cyanogenia, from the western section of New Guinea known as Irian Ja ya, was imported into the U.S. in large numbers in the 1970s and 1980s, it has become uncommon in U.S. collections. This species was first acquired by the San Diego Zoo in 1969. However, all 38 offspring produced have been from one pair which was set up in 1988.Goldie's Lorikeetlarge numbers of Goldie's Lorikeet, Tricboglossus goldiei, from central New often thought to be equally rare in the wild. However, it appears to be rather common in its indigenous habitat of the Cook, Society and westernmost part of the Tuamotu Islands of French Polynesia. Even though 61 chicks have been hatched at the San Diego Zoo, it has been difficult to establish the desired self-sustaining numbers...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1502</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 1 (2000): Jan-Feb 2000; 60-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1502/1479</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
