<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2343</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T14:45:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">In Praise of the Pigeon</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Parrott-Holden, Jan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Capistrano is noted for its swallows.So why, on my first visit, did I take pictures of pigeons? Why, too, did my husband and I use every last coin in our pockets to purchase packets of wheat to feed these ordinary birds? And why did I _want to kick the old lady who scolded her grandson for carrying one of the slate gray birds upon his shoulder?I can still hear her cranky voiced command, "Don't touch those pigeons! They're dirty birds."Perhaps I might have felt more sympathetic with the old woman several years ago. For it wasn't until recently that I discovered the value of Columba Livia. Since that time it has been my secret hope to help dispel many of the deep-rooted prejudices within our society toward an all-together remarkable, but thoroughly misunderstood bird-The Pigeon.For centuries the pigeon has dwelled in cities and towns across our wide world, growing in numbers while maintaining an uneasy alliance with man.Man, in truth, doesn't bother thinking about the birds he sees pecking nervously at bits of popcorn or the leavings of someone's brown bag lunch. Perhaps he feels they don't even merit thought. But, if you ask that casual observer to tell you the first thing that comes to mind when you say the word "pigeon," chances are he would, like that old woman, mention the word ''dirty.''Pigeons weren't always held in such low esteem, and this statement can be proven by a brief look at history.We humans are always asking' 'What will it do for me?" The Orientals found pigeons had worth during the time of the Manchu emperors, when the birds and their eggs were considered a valuable food source. The ancients, too, were extremely zealous in their pigeon breeding. Not only were the birds valued as messengers but their fertility was considered an attribute worthy of worship. The Romans became extremely sophisticated pigeoneers with wealthier fanciers owning numbers in the thousands. It is interesting to note that the name "Columbi dae'' has been considered a derivative of the Latin term "Columbarium" which was used to describe what the modern fancier calls a dovecote.Literary works, penned by both ancient and contemporary authors, helped promote the dove, the smallest member of the pigeon family. Among these references, the Biblical story of Noah is probably one of the best known. Practically every member of theJudeo-Christian world has heard of Noah's use of doves to signal that the flood level had subsided enough for a bird to return with an olive branch. But this is merely one of several Biblical passages concerning the pigeon.More recently, noted writers like Shakespeare and Dickens have displayed interest as well as surprising knowledge concerning pigeons. Incidentally, these noted authors equated the dove with images of peace, modesty, innocence, beauty and purity. At least to their minds, the pigeon was not a dirty bird.Pigeons continued to win admirers as messengers, especially during wartime though most of us don't reflect much upon their use during the reign of Caesar and Napoleon. In fact, few people consider the birds' tremendous role in saving lives during World Wars I and II. Yet the Signal Corps thought enough of their pigeons to give them monikers like "Winkie," "Spike," "President Wilson," and "Cher Ami."Cher Ami, French for "Beloved Friend,'' proved to be one of the greatest heros of World War I, credited with the distinction of saving "The Lost Battalion." When flares and rockets were useless, Cher Ami was tossed into the air as a final resort. Though badly wounded, the bird rallied and made for home with an important message. That message proved responsible for saving hundreds of lives. Again, pigeons proved their worth to man. Thankfully, the military recognized this worth and made Cher Ami their mascot. Today, the bird's body is mounted for public view in the Smithsonian Institution, U.S. National Museum, Washington, D.C. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2343</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 4 (1985): AUG-SEPT 1985; 30-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2343/2316</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
