<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1919</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-06-28T02:33:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bird Annual Meeting U.S Animal Health Association</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baer, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">[Editor's note: A.F.A. members unacquainted with the U.S.A.H.A. and its function are referred to an account of this organization published in Vol. VJ, No. 1, Feb. I Mar. '79, issue of Watch bird entitled "The United States Animal Health Association Establishes Sub-committee on Diseases of Cage and Aviary Birds".)The United States Animal Health Association met in San Diego, California on October 28 - November 2, 1979, to hold its eighty-third annual meeting. At the session of its Committee on Transmissible Diseases of Poultry, considerable attention was given to the problems of cage and aviary birds. Two resolutions passed by this committee are of importance to aviculturists and to the pet bird industry.The report of the Sub-committee on Cage and Aviary Birds is of especial interest to all bird breeders and to the bird business.The following particulars selected from the Poultry Committee summary are pertinent to avicultural concerns:(Excerpts)"REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE ON TRANSMISSIBLE DISEASESOF POULTRY"Chairman: Raymond A. Bankowski, Davis, CA"Newcastle Disease"During fiscal year 1978, domestic surveillance of poultry did not reveal any causes of exotic Newcastle disease in poultry in the continental United States. Increased effectiveness in border and port enforcement and alert surveillance by field personnel aided in the effort. In the early part of 1979, two infections were detected in caged pet birds which were recently introduced into the United States."On February 20, 1979, exotic Newcastle disease was confirmed at the National Veterinary Service Laboratories (NYSL), Ames, Iowa, from specimens submitted from a citron crested cockatoo at Stanton, Orange County, California. The disease was traced to a bird-holding facility to house birds as they were released from a privately-owned import quarantine station, both under the same ownership and management. Sales and shipments of birds from the holding facility were traced and evaluated. As a result, birds on ten commercial and seven privately-owned premises in Los Angeles, Orange, San Bernardino, and Riverside Counties, California, were positive for exotic Newcastle disease. In addition to California, movements of birds from infected premises were traced to Arizona, Illinois, Minnesota, Nevada, Oregon, Texas, Utah, and Washington."On March 24, 1979, another case of exotic Newcastle disease was confirmed in the holding facility used to house birds after release from a USDA-approved, privately-owned import quarantine station at Miami, Florida. A total of 109 shipments were made from this infected facility to 29 states and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico. As a result of these tracings and evaluations, positive cases were disclosed in Illinois, Michigan, North Carolina, Ohio, and Texas. No commercial poultry were involved in either the California or Florida outbreaks. Since there is no known treatment for this disease, the infected caged birds involved were appraised and humanely destroyed and the premises cleaned and disinfected. The cost to eliminate these outbreaks to APHIS was estimated to be $1.8 million."Puerto Rico currently is under Federal quarantine for exotic Newcastle disease. Dr. D.C. Johnson reported on a surveillance for exotic Newcastle disease on the Island, which began on June 4, 1979. After an extensive study involving 64 laying flocks, an equal number of broiler flocks, 105 fighting cocks, and 217 backyard flocks, no evidence of VVND was detected. lt will be recommended that the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico be released from quarantine for exotic New Castle disease . . . . . . . . . . "" Cage and Aviary Birds"The report of the Sub-Committee on cage and aviary birds presented both areas of positive development and points of urgent concern among aviculturists and the estimated $500 million pet bird industry. The following outlines major findings -"Positive DevelopmentsI. Active support of pet and exotic bird disease research on Pacheco's Disease vaccination, psittacosis, salmonellosis, bird pox, and colibacillosis, by several major aviculturist associations and institutes.2. Universities, colleges, aviculture and veterinary associations have begun vigorous promotion of continuing education in aviculture and avian medicine.3. Mutually satisfactory accords have been achieved between government and aviculture on: the handling of future out- breaks of exotic Newcastle disease; and, the effective captive propagation of rare or endangered species.4. A positive, promotional rather than negative restrictive strategy towards a national supply of safe, healthy birds is being developed. The American Federation of Aviculture and the Pennsylvania Department of Agriculture are initiating ambitious programs to promote domestic production of cage pet and exotic birds that will hopefully and eventually curb the trafficking in smuggled birds. The former beginning to establish and maintain a national breeding registry of birds not commonly raised in captivity. The latter developing a state directory of small or large local operations providing domestically bred cage pet birds for retail sale."Urgent Concerns1. Possible over-restriction of the legitimate, responsible importer and possible weak prosecution of quarantine station operators guilty of questionable activities, poor sanitation, inhumane management of birds, violation of USDA regulations, and seriously deficient antibiotic treatment for psittacosis.2. Deleterious effects from unsanitary conditions possible during 30-day quarantine period in USDA 'isolettes'.3. Continuing weaknesses in identification techniques for all birds and especially regarding smaller species.4. Import station permits may not be granted in the most democratic, impartial basis so as to preclude monopolization and possible arbitrary bird price increases.5. Lack of attention at quarantine stations to diseases of birds that do not affect poultry but can cause major losses to bird dealers and breeders.6. Need for recognition and classification of aviculture as a significant, multimillion dollar, form of agricultural livestock production."General Recommendations"The sub-Committee on Cage and Aviary Birds should continue its function and next year's activity should emphasize: expanded and strengthened, instruction by veterinary colleges in avian medicine; and widespread development of state and other official directories of domestic bird breeding operations as positive rather than restrictive programs for aviculture."The Committee recommends that USDA, APHlS, Veterinary Services, take corrective action concerning the several urgent quarantine facility concerns Listed above.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-10-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1919</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 1 (1980): FEB-MAR 1980</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1919/1890</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
