<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/549</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The National Cockatiel Society 1991 Annual Show</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of the 2,888 birds benched at theNational Cage Bird show heldNovember 15 and 16, 1991 in Dearborn,Michigan, 199 entries wereentered in the cockatiel division. Itwas the third largest turnout ever forthe National Cockatiel Society, and asthe panel judge selected by the NCSmembership, I had the pleasure ofjudging the division.Traditionally, the National CockatielSociety's Annual Show is heldunder the auspices of the NationalCage Bird Show, Inc., where the BestIn Division winner of each of theshow's 13 divisions, including BestCockatiel, receive the covetedKellogg Trophy. Kellogg Inc. Seedsand Supplies, manufacturers of acomplete line of quality bird foods,has been the sponsor of the KelloggAwards at the National Cage BirdShow since its inception in 1947.In addition, the National CockatielSociety provides its own handsomeplaques and awards, plus show sponsorspay for section trophys. And, in1991, the rosettes provided by NCSwere generously subsidized by L/MAnimal Farms, maufacturers of a fullline of cage bird foods.During our charter year in 1984, Ihad the honor of authoring the writtenNCS Show Standard of Excellence,which consists of a detaileddescription of the visual qualitiessought for in the Ideal ExhibitionCockatiel. Although it is alwaysemphasized that birds are judged bythe comparison method and neverassigned points at shows, a pointedstandard is included as a guide forboth the judge and the exhibitor,weighing the attributes of the Standardin their relationship to eachother.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/549</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 3 (1992): JUNE-JULY 1992; 31-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/549/533</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
