<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4112</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:18:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Message from the President</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">LePage, Mary Ellen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 4 (October/November 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Sadly, our Board member, Janice Boyd, has passed. Janice has been a long-term member and volunteer Board member of The American Federation of Aviculture (AFA). We all respected her intelligence, and her commitment to conservation. Instead of spending on herself, Janice chose to donate generously to AFA and conservation projects. Janice has greatly influenced the development of AFA and has had a positive effect on many conservation projects throughout the world. Lately, she was excited about her aviculture research projects. Janice’s passing has left a huge hole in aviculture. We are grateful for the time we had with her. Thank you, Janice, for being our friend, and for all you have done for aviculture.We had a great time at the AFA 2022 Conference in Virginia. There were great presentations by many speakers on a variety of topics. Attendees loved the hotel, and the friendly atmosphere of all our group.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4112</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 4 (2022): Watchbird October/November 2022; 3</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4112/4072</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
