<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/646</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-08T05:17:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Bleeding Heart Dove</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roles, D. Grenville</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"Hey, Mister! You've got a birdbadly hurt over here, you'd bettercome and take care of it!" I wish I hada dollar for every time I've heard that!If it's not a bird appearing to have suffereda stroke (Crowned Pigeon sunbathing)or experiencing a seizure(pheasant dustbathing) then it has tobe every visitor's cries of concern(those who don't read the labelthat is), the Bleeding Heart Dove(Gallicolumba luzonica).What subtle influences of evolutionconspired in the development of thisbrazen stigmata can hardly beguessed at. This savagely marked birddisplays an apparently fresh wound inthe middle of its white breast. However,it is also beautifully glossed iridescentpurple and green on the neckand mantle of its dark grey upperparts. The wings are barred chestnutand grey, the cap light grey; while itsunderparts below the white throat andbreast are buffy peach, legs are darkred, bill black, and eyes brown. Males,in my experience, tend to be largerthan hens. Chunky in appearance, andabout two thirds the size of a common pigeon, Bleeding Heart Doves aremostly terrestrial in their foragingbehavior, arboreal, in fact, only whileresting, roosting and nesting.I am able to work with two pairs ofthese handsome little birds at present.The first pair professionally at TracyAviary, which have frustrated me foreight years, and the second pair I haveat home which have driven me nutsfor only two years.There are, of course, those paragonsof avicultural virtuosity such as GarrieLandry in Louisiana, who are able tobreed these birds at will, but forme, it's been a struggle.The Tracy Aviary pair, consisting ofa 10-plus year old male and a two yearold female (obtained from Garrie)were initially housed together in amixed species aviary where someintermittent egg production (no incubation,mind you) took place.I was experiencing similar problemsat home with my year old pair (henfrom Paddy Lambett, male from GarrieLandry).Over the same weekend last fall, Imoved both pairs to new accommodations The Aviary pair to a triangularshaped cage 8' x 8' x 8' with a solidwall at the rear, upon which was hunga bushel basket stuffed with hay. Thiscage is totally indoors, with a sandfloor, a couple of perches, and otherwisebare with no other occupants.My home pair is in my basement in acage three feet square by 12' long,containing some Lantana and BostonFerns, Gouldians and Diamond Doves,and a drawer 6" deep by 10" x 8" andhalf filled with bark chips provided fornesting, hung on the rear wall.Within two weeks both pairs laidand incubated! My home pair, whichhad previously shared a flight withnumerous Diamond Doves, Societyand Zebra Finches, became very territorialand killed the female DiamondDove sharing their flight and beat upthe male (they would have killed him,too, if I had not come home in time).Both pairs incubated solidly, theaviary pair on a single egg, my ownpair on a two egg clutch. The dietwhich is normally a grain mix withdiced fruit and some hard boiled egg(at the Avia1y) was supplemented by asmall quantity of mealworms scatteredon the floor of the cage three or fourtimes a day. At home my feed is apellet/ grain mix with canned corn inthe morning and soaked seed in theevening, and a few mealworms threeor four times a week.Thrilled by the birds' behavior andclaiming all responsibility for theclearly proven, new found techniqueof "if they don't breed, move 'em", Igreeted each day with some degree oftrepidation expecting the eggs to beeither broken, abandoned, or disappeared.Imagine my delight, therefore,not to mention my relief, upon findingthe cleanly evacuated and e jectedshells upon the cage floors.Clothed in surprisingly long, whitedown, the pink-fleshed chicks continuedto be closely brooded by either,sometimes both, parents.Having laid three or four daysbefore my own birds, the Aviary chickleft the nest first. Such a peculiar littlechick at almost two weeks old, almostall wings and legs...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/646</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 32-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/646/629</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
