<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4105</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:20:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Wins - Eagles Soaring High</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Darden, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (January 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Soaring High with Our National Symbol!Bigamy, divorce, murder, love and romance. Eagle watching is a soap opera that fans tune into every day, featuring courageous, charismatic and colorful characters that they cherish and cheer for. Such as, one finicky female eagle who was playing house and raising one chick at Stumpy Lake natural area and then would leave dad with the kid and fly over for a fling with her other man at Honey Bee golf course. Or the male eagle, that over three seasons, went from not attracting any females, to courting two that were not interested in mating, to finally finding his true love, only to have another man take over his nest and kill him. Eagles do mate for life, unless one dies. Each year, happy couples rekindle their relationship with pecks, nibbles, footing, displaying and body brushing, along with hours of perching and vocalizing.encourages people to care about helping these majestic birds of prey, but the general public doesn’t view the harsh reality of eagles’ lives through the scientific lens of a biologist. It’s hard to accept that in order for one creature to survive in the wild, another must be sacrificed. Battles are waged daily in the eagle’s pine tree pent house. Siblings bully each other, weaker eaglets may starve and predators are always soaring around, eager to steal an egg or swipe a baby from the nest. Feeding babies is a fulltime job for dad while mom protects the family. They are carnivores so meal times can be messy. One eagle’s nest was being harassed by a crow that would not leave. Guess what the babies had for dinner on live TV?Adult eagles have no natural predators, except humans. Eggs and chicks are preyed upon by hawks, owls, racoons, bobcats, squirrels and ravens. One nest was visited by a great-horned owl at night, startling the female. She sat up quickly and crushed the two eggs she was incubating. The next day a third was laid. That bird contracted avian pox, resulting in a deformed beak. He could not hunt so he is nowThere’s an admiration for these gorgeous goliath raptors that causes people to stop what they’re doing when an eagle is sighted so they can capture the moment on camera. Pam Monahan, a former wildlife rehabilitator and Virginia Master Naturalist is a long-time eagle watcher who has done an amazing job of telling their stories with her beautiful award -winning photographs! She has been center stage working with wildlife experts to document the heartwarming tales and harrowing sagas of these resilient feathered warriors. Individuals and communities watching over and monitoring eagle nests have had a positive impact on rebounding eagle populations across the country.Eagles have become webcam celebrities and attaching a face with a causeBuddy, the ambassador at The Wildlife Center of Virginia.Reese F. Lukei, Jr. is a research associate with the Center for Conservation Biology and recipient of the 2022 Mary Reid Barrow wildlife advocate award for his contributions of celebrating, advocating and educating peopleClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4105</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 1 (2023): Watchbird January 2023; 14-19</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4105/4065</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
