<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/564</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Legumes in the Avian Diet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abramson, Joanne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Legumes, by definition, are plantsthat have edible seeds enclosedinside a pod. They include beans,peas, lentils and peanuts. They containa rich source of incomplete protein,iron , thiamin, riboflavin, andniacin . Once sprouted, somelegumes have an excellent source ofvitamin C. Combined with rice (especiallybrown or wild rice) they providea more complete protein source.Both brown rice and wild rice havesignificant amounts of vitamins andminerals compared to white rice.Rice can be sprouted with thelegumes, utilizing the same technique.In the early 1980's, several wellknown people began experimentingwith legumes in parrot diets; mostnotably John and Pat Stoodley,Raymond Kray, D.V.M. and GregHarrison, D.V.M. Since that time, severalfeed distributors have createdand marketed packaged mixes ineight ounces pet size to fifty poundbreeder mixes. Some of these mixeshave added colored pasta, rice andother treats to entice birds to eatthem.Legumes have the advantage overmany other commonly offered parrotdiets due to their availability. Virtuallyevery country has access to anassortment of legumes. Because theyare a dried seed product, the movementof them across internationalborders is permitted. Most legumesare cultivated both inside and outsideof the United States.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/564</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 23-26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/564/547</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
