<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2208</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-15T08:22:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ex Libris - three book reviews</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Low, Rosemary</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sutherland, Pat</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">During the past few years, the enormous strides which have been made in breeding raptors have highlighted the lack of authoritative and up to date books on the management, breeding and diseases of these birds. Although entitled Recent Advances in the Study of Raptor Diseases, this volume does an enormous amount to redress this lack, for its scope is wider than the title suggests.It comprises the proceedings of the first International Symposium on Diseases of Birds of Prey which was held in London in July 1980. The first international meeting ever devoted to this theme, it brought together most of the world's authorities and specialists in the field of Rap tor disease. These included the British veterinarians John Cooper and Andrew Greenwood, who edited the 34 papers in this volume.The papers are presented in three pans: pathology and microbiology, surgery and anaesthesia, and medicine and therapeutics. Among the subjects covered in the first part are the effects of chronic lead ingestion, causes of death in trained raptors, handrearing of vultures and abnormal and maladaptive behaviour (the result of imprinting).Surgical treatment of burnblefoor is one of the papers in the second part which has a wider application than birds of prey, although it refers specifically to raptors. This is also true of the paper on diagnostic avian laparoscopy. Not only can the laparoscope be used to determine sex, but to diagnose disease. It has been found to be a safe, rapid and effective method of direct observation of the abdominal contents and can be used to examine many organs.Most serious aviculturists will find something of interest in this volume and to rapror breeders and falconers it will prove indispensible. It costs £11. 50 (including postage) in Britain and Europe, £12 elsewhere, from Chiron Publications, P. 0. Box 2 5, Keighley, West Yorkshire BD22 7BA.AUSTRALIAN PARROTS INBUSH AND AVIARYby Ian Harman, EnglandDavid &amp;amp; Charles, Lrd., 1981; hardcover, 200 pp .. $32.00. Published in the U.S. by David &amp;amp; Charles. Inc., North Pomfret, Vermont 05053.Review by Pat SutherlandJackson Heights, New YorkWere it not for he recent appearance of Forshaw's second (revised) edition of Australian Parrots, this just-released (December 1981) book by Ian Harman would have been the talk of the town. Regardless of the ominous competition, however, Harman's book is good reading and splendidly illustrated. Some of the photos are positively breath-taking - a Little Corella about to alight on a tree; a flock of Galahs feeding; a cock Crimsonwinged Parrot displaying; a Galah, a Princess Parrot and a Crimson Rosella in flight, among others. Practically every species of Australian parrot is illustrated in color (often both cock and hen) and the color reproduction is true to life. Lest I mislead you, this is not a picture book. Harman covers all species of Australian parrots and provides chapters on aviaries, breeding, feeding and ailments, making this a complete reference.Harman, though born in England, spent his early years in Tasmania and now lives near Melbourne. Thus, this book is basically by an Australian for Australians. As a result, the reader must cope with a few minor inconveniences, like measurements in meters and centimeters, Australian common names and breeding seasons for the opposite hemisphere. On the plus side, who could better qualify to produce an avicultural book on Australian parrots than an Australian aviculturist?The first part ofthis book is devoted to history and general management. The int rod u ct ion describes the gradual discovery of Australian parrots by European explorers and is very interesting. Harman's subsequent chapters on aviaries, breeding, feeding and ailments are just adequate. In the chapter on breeding, Harman devotes some attention to the subject of fostering and this will interest most breeders, I'm sure.The strength of this book lies in Harman's treatment of the species. In tenchapters, he covers one or more genera of Australian parrots individually, e.g.,Rosellas, Psephotus parrots, Neophema parrots, Eclectus and Geoffroyus parrots, etc.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2208</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 10 No. 6 (1983): DEC-JAN 1983; 16-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2208/2182</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
