<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3140</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-02T21:31:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">USDA/APHI S History Regulations, Milestones, Poultry/Avian Diseases</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">1883 Veterinary Division established by the Commissionerof AgricultureMay 29, 1884 Congress creates the Bureau of Animal Industry(BAI) within USDA to eradicate contagious bovinepleuropneumonia and other contagious animal diseasesAug. 25, 1884 Animal quarantine stations of the Treasury Departmenttransferred to the BAI; facilities were near Baltimore, Md.;New York City, Boston and Philadelphia.1887 Congress gives BAI authority to purchase and destroydiseased animalsAug. 30, 1890 Congress gives BAI quarantine authority over domesticruminants, swine1900 Lacey Act prohibits the importation of injurious animals,birds and fish1903 Animal import center established at Clifton, N.J.; replacesquarantine station at Garfield, N.J.1924 First reported U.S. outbreak of fowl plague spreads toeight Eastern and Midwest States; eradication measuresare effective1929 Fowl plague eradicatedMarch 2, 1931 Congress passes the Animal Damage Control Act; ADCEstablished within USDA1935 National Poultry Improvement Plan begins with majorgoal of eliminating pullorum diseaseJuly 1, 1939 In a government reorganization, Animal Damage Controlis transferred to the Fish and Wildlife Service in theDepartment of InteriorApril 1950 First detection of exotic Newcastle disease in the UnitedStates in chukars and pheasants Contra Costa County, Calif.Aug. 4, 1950 Congress authorizes the National Poultry Improvement PlanNov. 2, 1953 In a major USDA reorganization, the “Bureaus” (Bureauof Animal Industry, Bureau of Entomology and PlantQuarantine and Bureau of Plant Industry, Soils andAgricultural Engineering) are abolished and theirfunctions transferred to the Agricultural Research Service1954 National Poultry and Turkey Improvement Plansbroadened to include control of fowl typhoid andsalmonella infections1961 Domestic animal health research and diagnostic workconsolidated at new facility in Ames, Iowa1962 Animal and plant health regulatory staffs relocated fromUSDA South Building to Hyattsville, Md.July 2, 1962 Congress updates animal quarantine laws to give theSecretary power to declare an extraordinary emergencyAug. 24, 1966 Congress passes the Laboratory Animal Welfare ActMay 6, 1970 Congress authorizes high-security quarantine centerfor animals imported from countries with Foot &amp;amp; MouthDisease and other exotic foreign animal diseasesDec. 24, 1970 Congress amends the Laboratory Animal Welfare Act;renames it the Animal Welfare ActOct. 31, 1971 Animal and plant health functions in ARS are transferred toa new agency, the Animal and Plant Health Service (APHS)November1971Mexican double yellow-headed parrots from SouthAmerica introduce exotic Newcastle Disease intocommercial poultry in southern CaliforniaMarch 14,1972Emergency declared to combat a spreading outbreak ofexotic Newcastle disease in southern California; 45,000square miles quarantined, task force eventually reachespeak strength of more than 1,300 peopleApril 2, 1972 Meat and poultry inspections functions are transferredto APHIS and the agency is renamed as the Animal andPlant Health Inspection Service (APHIS)Nov. 10, 1972 Extraordinary emergency declared to let APHIS conductthe exotic Newcastle disease task force under Federalauthority, including the of sentinel chickensDec. 28, 1973 Congress passes Endangered Species ActJan. 14, 1974 United States ratifies the Convention on InternationalTrade of Endangered Species (CITES)July 3, 1974 Exotic Newcastle disease eradicated after the destructionof nearly 12 million chickens; eradication campaign costs$56 millionApril 22, 1976 Animal Welfare Act amended to cover animals intransportation and to prohibit animal fighting venturesFebruary 1977 Serious outbreak of exotic Newcastle disease in pet birdseradicated from 40 states and Puerto RicoMarch 14,1977Meat and poultry inspection functions in APHIS aretransferred to the Food Safety and Quality Service, butAPHIS retains its name (the agency performs many otherinspection functions)1979 National Poultry Improvement Plan transferred toAPHIS from ARSJuly 20, 1979 New building at National Veterinary ServicesLaboratories in Ames, Iowa, dedicatedOct. 19, 1979 Dedication of APHIS’ high-security Harry S TrumanAnimal Import Center (HSTAIC) at Key West, Fla.March 21,1980Official opening of New York Animal Import Centerat Newburgh, N.Y., which replaced the import centeroperating since 1903 at Clifton, N.J.Dec. 22, 1981 Congress gives APHIS extraordinary emergency authorityfor plant pests, an outgrowth of a confrontation with theGovernor of California over Medfly eradication measuresOct. 25, 1982 New biocontrol facility dedicated at Mission, TexasSeptember1983APHIS establishes the National Animal HealthMonitoring System (NAHMS) to measure the statusof U.S. animal health1983-84 Outbreak of highly pathogenic avian influenzaeradicated from Pennsylvania, Virginia, Maryland andNew Jersey; 17 million chickens destroyed at a cost of$65 million1984 USDA Beagle Brigade begins with one dog team atLos Angeles International Airport to detect prohibitedagricultural items in the baggage of internationaltravelersMarch 1984 APHIS port inspectors can levy spot fines on smugglers(based on passage of new penalty legislation in 1983)May 29, 1984 USDA observes “100 years of animal health”(BAI-ARS-APHIS)1985 APHIS adopts official logo, a stylized cow and plant designDec. 19, 1985 Animal Damage Control transferred to APHIS from theDepartment of Interior</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3140</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 36 No. 4 (2009): Number 4  2009; 42-46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3140/3124</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
