<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/609</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T03:32:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question #1: My lorikeet has beenhaving difficulty passing stool for along time. It moves its tail vigorouslywhile it is trying to pass stool. I provideit with sunflower seeds, safflowerseeds, and baby cereal everyday. I also offer fruit three to fourtimes a week. I have taken it to severalveterinarians but they are notfamiliar with birds. What proceduresor tests should I have them run?L. Crimson, Hong KongAnswer #1: Birds that have difficultypassing stool and demonstratethe straining that you have describedcan have a number of problems. Oneof the most common reasons for thistype of difficulty in defecating occursduring egg laying. When the egg isbeing delivered into the cloaca from the oviduct, the bird will strain untilthe egg has passed. Because thecolon is being displaced by the egg,the feces cannot be delivered into thecloaca until the egg has passed. Additionally,potential other causes ofstraining include:• any space occupying lesion suchas a tumor can create the same problem.• problems associated with thethickening of the lining of the cloacacan also cause this type of difficulty.• any obstruction in the intestinaltract is another reason for this type ofclinical presentation.• the consumption of excessiveamounts of grit and gravel causingcomplete or partial obstruction ofthe gizzard can also cause this type ofsymptomatology.A complete physical examination,which includes exploration of thecloaca with an otoscope or laparoscope,and possibly radiographicexamination, is necessary to developa differential diagnosis. If possible, itwould be advisable to consult with aveterinarian who has avian experience.Robert B. Altman, D.V.M.Franklin Square, NYAnswer #2: I would suggest thatyou find a veterinarian with experiencein treating birds. Your lorikeetneeds a proper physical examination,including examination of the vent(anus) and cloaca (the portion of theintestinal, urinary, and reproductivetracts where waste is stored before itis passed). If no structural problem isfound, then laboratory tests for bacteria,yeast, and parasites would be inorder. If that does not identify thecause, radiographs (X-rays) and otherprocedures would be advisable. Youshould consider improving the bird'sdiet. Lorikeets in nature are nectarfeeders. There are special diets thatare commercially available for theseinteresting birds which are semi-solidto liquid in consistency. This willcreate more of a cleaning problem for you but may solve the bird's difficultyin passing its droppings.James M. Harris, D.V.M.Oakland, CAAnswer #3: Finding one's self in asituation such as yours, where onehas a bird in need of veterinary care,but a veterinarian with knowledge ofavian patients is not available, is alsoa problem realized here in the States.Probably your first step would be tolocate a veterinarian in your area thatis willing to work with you in learningabout avian medicine. Thesecond step would be to obtain aEuropean or American veterinarypublication, such as a textbook, toaid in this process. Hopefully, thetwo of you would then be betterequipped to aid your avian friend. Acomplete physical examinationshould be conducted first. If physicalabnormalities are noted, than thoseshould be addressed. If not, routinescreening tests such as blood work, afecal parasite examination, andmicrobiological assays of the cloaca,should be considered. Further diagnosticsmight include radiographsand an exploratory surgery. Goodluck with your lorikeet!Amy B. Worell, D.V.M.West Hills, CA•Question #2: I have a problemwith my pearllutino cockatiel. He isalert, has good plumage, is very talkative,has good eating habits, and isplayful. He has had a sagging eyelid,somewhat like a Basset hound's eyes,for a long time. I have taken him tothree different avian veterinariansand he still is no better. He has hadthree blood tests, which were all negative.He has had cream placed in hiseye which did not help, he was onoral Vibramycin for two monthswhich seemed to take some of thesagging away but not completely,and then he was placed on a powdermedication for eight months. Thethird vet also took a swab of the eyesand gave him a vitamin A injection.Nothing has helped, so I have just letit be. I notice now that he is turningslightly more yellow. What should Ido?H. Kaminski, Ontario, CanadaAnswer #1: Lutino cockatiels areyellow. If the yellow color is intensifyingin the feathers, it may be quitenormal. Age and diet can affect plumage.Additives can also affect color if given while the feathers are formingduring a moult. I wonder what the''powder medication" was that yougave for eight months? Regarding theeye, the sagging eyelid might be indicativeof nerve damage secondary totrauma. It might be appropriate toget copies of all the records and testresults from the three veterinariansyou have consulted with in the pastand choose one of them or anotheravian veterinarian to review the caseand check your bird.James M. Harris, D.V.M.Oakland, CA</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/609</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 22-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/609/592</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
