<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1295</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:34:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Red--capped Parrot  Another Australian Gem</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Owen, Mike</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A ustralia is known as the "Land of Parrots" and not without good reason. With over 50 species ranging from the majestic Black Cockatoos to the raucous Sulfur-crested Cockatoo, from the subdued Bourke's Parrot to the beautiful Scarlet-chested, and from the humble little Budgie to the magnificent King Parrot, Australia's parrots are renowned the world over. One of the most colorful and unique of our parrots is the Redcapped Parrot Purpureicepbalus spurius, a true kaleidoscope of colors. From the ruby-red head, to the limegreen cheeks and neck, purple chest, green back, yellow rump, red under tail coverts, and deep blue wing and tail feathers, it is truly an amazing mix of color. While not uncommon in Australian aviaries, it is rare in North America and Europe, but the Red-capped is a bird well worth trying to add to any collection of Australian parrots. The Red-cap, often known as the Pileated Parrot outside of Australia, is a medium sized bird, length about 35 cm. 03.65 inches) and weight in the 120 to 140 gram range. It is sexually dimorphic, with the hen being a duller version of the cock, particularly with the purple chest color. Hens also tend to have a smaller, rounded head and In the Wild In the wild, the Red-capped Parrot is restricted to the Southwest corner of Western Australia where it mainly inhabits Eucalyptus forests and woodlands within 100 km (65 miles) of the coast. However it has also found suburban gardens, and particularly orchards, in its range to be a rich source of food. Its main food is the large seed capsules of Eucalyptus trees, especially the Marri, and its large upper beak is well adapted to remove the seed from the capsules. It also is known to eat insects and nectar and is a pest of fruit orchards. Adult birds are normally seen in pairs or small family groups, but younger immature birds often form quite large flocks, and are the most likely to invade orchards as the fruit is ripening. It is this destructive behavior that has resulted in large numbers of Red-caps being legally culled each year by orchardists keen to preserve their crops from destruction. Until recently, large numbers were trapped for the avicultural trade in Australia, but this has now stopped and only culling is presently allowed. It is because of this large trade in wild caught birds until recent times that the Red-capped has a reputation as a difficult bird to keep in aviculture. These wild birds often remain high-strung and nervous for their entire life in aviaries and will fly in panic when approached by their keeper. As a result, they are difficult to induce to breed. In the Aviary By using birds that have been handraised before returning to the aviary, much better success can be achieved and they can become a relaxed aviary bird and a ready and reliable breeder. In North America, where they will have gone through many generations of captive breeding and hand raising, this nervous behavior should not be a problem. My first introduction to the Redcapped was many years ago in a bird park in Southeast Queensland. I was wandering past a group of aviaries when a cheerful "Hello" came from behind some bushes almost hiding the last aviary on the block. A look behind the bushes showed this most amazing bird. Between displaying and trying to mate with his hen, he kept running along the perch to say hello to me and to get a quick tickle on the top of the head through the wire. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1295</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 2 (1999): MARCH-APRIL 1999; 16-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1295/1274</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
