<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2895</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-09T18:14:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dear Editor.According to my record my subscription is up for renewal. If you have a computer it will be six months late. Enclosed find a check to renew us - don't want to miss a single issue.We are constantly delighted with your photos - hats off to your great talents.In what manner does a subscriber and member purchase a longer membership, two years, or three, for instance?Keep up your fabulous work and causes.Now, may I suggest a column by average aviculturists? I refer to the small scale, independent enthusiasts who by labor and love of feathered friends have learned valuable lessons that should be shared.Dorothie M.Slade Wheatland, Ca.Thank you for your accolades and appreciation. Your letter deals with a number of points beginning with membership. We do use a computer and are presently switching to a faster, more efficient computer for your better service. If any questions or problems arise regarding your magazine please contact A.F.A. membership services listed on the first page of the magazine.I too share your delight with the photos we publish. All credit, of course, goes to our really fine staff of photographers and to our Art Director, M. Jean Hessler. Without them we could do nothing.Now I refer to your suggestion about articles by average aviculturists. I examined at random a few of our past issues and found that about twenty-five percent of our articles were written by professional zoo people or by veterinarians. The remaining seventy-five percent were written by what I consider average aviculturists. "Average" is, of course, an ambiguous word. Most of our articles were written, however, by smaller scale, independent enthusiasts who by labor and love of their feathered friends learned valuable lessons and shared them with us.What may throw you off the track is the language of our articles. Most of them are written in a rather formal style; they are usually grammatically correct; they are generally well organized; and they most often have good photo support. These are signs of an above average professional staff of writers - right? Wrong. Dead wrong.These are signs of a harried, weary, almost blind old editor poring over obscure manuscripts, pipe in mouth and magnifying glass in hand - with piles of research books all over the desk and.floor.Honestly, madam, it is easier to translate Latin, Hebrew or Sanskrit than to decipher Average Aviculturese . It is only through the most herculean efforts that I am able to make order out of most of the manuscripts that cross my desk, (that should get me a raise). But I don't want to discourage the average aviculturists from sending manuscripts, to the contrary, I encourage such action. We invite any who chooses, to send material to us. All I ask is that the manuscripts be typed and doublespaced and photo support is appreciated.Someday, when I am about to go belly up. I will publish all of the articles just the way they are received. Then, from my station in Old Editor's Nirvana, I' II take perverse pleasure in observing all the ruckus the illiterate Watchbird causes.Ed.Dear Mr. Dingle,I felt I had to write you this fetter to let you know that I am very pleased to have subscribed to the A.F.A "Warchbird " magazine. My husband and I have found it to be extremely informative and helpful for those of us who own birds. We own a Blue Fronted Amazon and a Cockatiel whose name is ·'Gray''. Our two birds are magnificent creatures and are in the finest health.We have learned a lot in this past year about birds and we have a great love for them. I want to take this time to thank you and the President Richard Baer and your staff for helping people like us to see the beauty of birds and the advantage of owning birds.I want to start an aviary very badly, but unfortunately we are still in the Air Force and we don't have the advantage of staying put. But someday we hope to start one. In the mean time we have a great chance to obtain a lot of information on avian life as well as to observe varieties and species of birds all over the world.Sincerely,Beth and Dwight Greenberg Tullahoma, Tenn.Thank you for your very kind thoughts. fl anything we have done has enhanced your love and appreciation for birds then we are rewarded. While you are in a rather mobile state of affairs you might consider selling up a bird room rather than an outdoor aviary. Many delightful birds can be kept and bred in small cages indoors. lovebirds, budgies. canaries, finches, and a number of other birds do very well in individual breeding cages that can be well established in one room of your house.I appreciate very much your offer of thanks to President Baer and the ''Watchbird' ·staff.In fact. I want to emulate your example and offer my own thanks to our glorious leaders. Thanks, Glorious Leaders'!' </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2895</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 4 (1979): AUG-SEPT 1979; 45-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2895/2879</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
