<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/497</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS: State of California Moves to License Bird Breeders</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Assembly bill #2232, introduced by Bradley of Escondido onMarch 10, 1989, attempts to license all bird breeders, dealers andexhibitors. To qualify for a license under AB2232, a personwould have to be at least 21 years old and have apprenticed fortwo years under a curator at a zoo or another licensed birdbreeder. The bill would further specify minimum cage sizes forparrots, finches and other birds. Minimum space for parrots wasdefined as a cage with six square feet of floor space, three squarefeet of floor space for one finch. Shipping regulations are alsoprescribed, requiring the height and width of the containers to be1-1/2 times the length of the bird being shipped. Containerswould require absorbent litter on the floor.AB 2232 had its first hearing for the Water, Parks, and WildlifeCommittee on May 2nd. AFA appeared before the committeeopposing the requirement for licensing of breeders, special usepermits, the minimum cage sizes for parrots and finches, and thespecifying of container sizes with absorbent litter on the floor(birds can ingest litter and suffer serious harm).The bill was published on short notice after its introduction,giving AFA little time to respond. Nevertheless, California legislativeliaison Laurella Desborough was able to visit a number ofcommittee members a couple weeks prior to the hearing as wellas organize a telephone campaign to get AFA members torespond in writing to oppose this bill.Good news - the hearing held May 2nd was amended toexclude birds from its coverage. Neeclless to say, AFA members,along with bird breeders from all over California, responded tothis bill and were certainly instrumental in getting "birds"dropped from its coverage. The bill has been rescheduled forhearing May 9th, as amended.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/497</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 48-51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/497/482</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
