<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/708</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Raising the Charming Bourke's Parakeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kennedy, Jami D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I remember the day well when myhusband brought a small bowl with adiaper in it into the kitchen and placedit in front of me. As I peeled back thefolded diaper, there huddled a pieceof grey fluff with the smallest beak I'dever seen! As I looked quizzically atmy husband, he explained that as hewas making his routine inspection ofour small bird aviaries, and the nestboxes in each flight, he found a disastroussight. Inside one of the Bourke'sParakeet nest boxes he found themother and three babies dead, andone baby, about two weeks old, clingingto life. This is what he presented tome. I told him that I couldn't feed abird that small, and who could findthe beak on a baby Bourke's anyway!(I was used to hand feeding parrottypes, after all!) He informed me that Iwas "a pro" and could do anything Iset my mind on. Looking back, I realizethat this was probably a butteringup job on his part, but it worked. I ranover to the feed store and purchased a1 cc syringe, because the smallest Ihad in the house was 20 cc at thattime, and that just wouldn't do. I successfullyraised that little Bourke'sbaby, and she became my constantnursery companion for the next threeyears, flitting from cage to cage andriding atop my shoulder as I fed mynursery full of cockatiels, rosellas, andassorted parrot babies.I know I'm known for telling sentimental,almost unbelievable storiesabout my birds, but I swear they areall true. This one is as well. This littleBourke's did not have a cage, shelived in my nursery, occasionally flyinginto the kitchen to see if I was preparingthe next batch of handfeedingformula. She monitored my feedingeach time, watching intently from myshoulder. Since I was usually feeding60 cockatiels at a time, there wereoccasions where one would flutter down from its cage. The nursery atthat time was my small family room,so with the clutter of many, manycages, piles of diapers, and the aquariumsI used as brooders, the cockatielwould be lost. On one of my missionsof cockatiel finding one day, theBourke's flew off my shoulder andonto the floor. She started to chirp andexcitedly hop back and forth whilefacing a folded pile of diapers. Ilooked around the diapers and therewas my baby cockatiel! From that timeon, when I had a baby to find, I justwaited, and my Bourke's would eventuallyfind it and "point" to it. She wasmy unofficial nursery attendant. Truestory!Now that I've gotten the sentimental"mother hen" story out of my system,I'd like to tell you a little about one ofthe most precious, docile birds ever tocome out of Australia, the Bourke'sGrass Parakeet. They belong to thefamily Psittacidae, a large family ofbirds which belong to the Psittaciformegroup, and bear the name Neophemaburkii, or Neopsephotus bourkii.Of all the grass 'keets, I believe theBourke's Parakeet is the hardiest,even though it is the most docile. Wehave only raised the Bourke's, but thisis comparing notes with other grass'keet breeders.We found the Bourke's very easy tobreed, and I would highly recommendthis bird if your're thinking of gettinginto breeding small birds for the firsttime.If you are hurting for space, you cancolony breed the Bourke's but wehave found that this does not producethe best results. They are not aggressiveto their mates, other Bourke's, orother birds in the cage, but the productionis not what it should be whenyou colony breed them. We have,however, placed a pair of Bourke's in a flight with a pair of cockatiels andboth pairs had successful breedingseasons.For one pair of Bourke's, our flightswere 4' by 8' by 8', constructed out of1x1/2" wire. Several flights stood sideby side, and there was a center aislewith more flights on the other side.This safety area is a must so you donot suffer the loss of a fly away bird.Plywood covered the top and sides ofeach flight, but only one third of theway from the back forward. The restof the flight was open to the elements,but enclosed with a safety area, so thebirds could enjoy all the seasons andfresh air.If at all possible, do not place yourflight on a ditt floor. This goes for allbirds, but the neophemas are prone togetting worms, and they dearly love tofly down and check out what interestingmorsels of food lay in the dirt. Ifyou have dirt floor flights, try puttingwire over them to dissuade therodents from entering the flight. Thebirds should be wormed once a year,no matter what type of floor yourflight has.The nest box was a simple lovebirdbox, wooden, about 6-1/2" x 10-1/2"x 9-1/2", with a little porch on the out-side so the male could stand watch.We placed clean pine shavings in thebox. If you choose to tty your hand atcolony breeding, be sure to put oneand a half times as many nest boxes asyou have pairs of birds in the flight.They like a choice, and this avoids anysquabbling over boxes. For one pairto a flight, one box is sufficient.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/708</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 30-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/708/691</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
