<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4137</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T23:43:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA’s Disaster Relief Takes to the Road</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Fred</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 48 Number 1 (October 2021).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.In the Wake of Hurricane Ida AFA Disaster Relief takes to the RoadOn August 29, 2021, the 16th anniversary of Hurricane Katrina, Hurricane Ida hit Louisiana as a Category 4 hurricane with sustained winds of a 150mph, just 7mph short of the designation for a Category 5. After hitting New Orleans hard, Ida then traveled inland through Mississippi and on north. I had my eyes glued to the TV days before the storm made up it&amp;#x27;s mind as to where it would hit, as I always do when a disaster is a possibility. After the storm decided where to land, the State Coordinators as well as the Regional Director and I worked on a plan of action. Knowing the problem we had after the last hurricane to hit this area with trying to get bird supplies shipped in, and hearing that this hurricane caused much more damage, and knowing the trucking situation was as bad as it was, we decided to deliver the supplies ourselves.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4137</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 48 No. 1 (2021): Watchbird October 2021; 26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4137/4097</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
