<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1419</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:53:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Electus: Winged Flowers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perdomo, Jose MI.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">[Author's Note: In the last two issues of Watchbird, we have crystallized, or perhaps just encapsulated, some of the basic infonnation on the eclectus parrots, those "Winged Flowers" originally inhabiting one of the most unique and exuberant comers of our planet. Tbese efforts were intended to provide our readership a starting point for the better understanding of these wonderful birds, and simultaneously, to create a condensed guide to the characteristics, requirements and general care of these colorful parrots. As we conclude this series with this last segment, we hope to have at least partially achieved our original goals. Only our readers will be able to assess if such expectancies met with reality, and if any value could be denied from these efforts. Let's now continue .. .}Maintenance of the Eclectus FeedingThe Eclectus Parrots are not exclusive seed eaters. Avoid a diet containing only seeds. The best is to feed them a well-varied diet which should include vegetables, fruits, and sprouted beans. In addition, you may want to supply to the Eclectus 'h of its diet in the form of a high quality parrot pellet such as Roudybush, Scenic Paradise, Hagen's Tropican, Harrison's, or equivalent pellets. For additional information on these and other pellets, consult the telephone directory located at the end of this article. Keep pellets available to the parrots all the time. In addition, or alternatively with the sprouts, the Eclectus should be fed soft food on a regular basis. The cooked bean recipe included below is a convenient form of meeting this soft food nutritional requirement. The diet of an Eclectus is very important for its growth and gen- eral health. A well-fed bird will considerably reduce your trips to the vet. Do not feed avocado or chocolate to your Eclectus as they may get very ill following ingestion of these.Providing soft food to your bird is not a major enterprise if you organize its preparation efficiently. Make a good soft food meal once a week and freeze the daily portions in plastic bags. All you will have to do daily is simply defrost and mix before feeding.Purchase the following, preferably "organic in origin" from your local health food store or supermarket or at the source noted.• Calcium carbonate or "Calcium Care" available from Phoenix Unlimited, Irving, TX, 214-554-8318• Dry soybeans• Dry com• Rice• Wheat germ oil• Spirulina and or wheat grass powder.These dry powders are available from the health food store or from Earthrise, Petaluma, Ca., 800-995- 0681. Many people prefer the wheat grass, over the spirulina. Another alternative is alfalfa powder.From your local pet shop purchase the multivitamin and mineral powder for birds. The necessity of using vitamin and mineral supplements is questionable if good nutrition is supplied to your bird. Although if used in small quantities, it is unlikely to cause any problem to your bird, excessive doses could create some health hazard by causing a hyper-vitaminosis. Therefore, we list this ingredient as optional. Preparation of Soft FoodPlace equal amounts of soybean and corn in water overnight. Boil for 10 minutes and add 1/2 volume, relative to the soybean amount, of rice. Allow the rice to soak in water for approximately 15 minutes. Drain the water off and rinse the mixture with cold tap water. After reaching room temperature, place the amount required for a daily feeding in individual plastic bags and freeze them. Each bag should contain less than 1/2 cup per bird to be fed.At feeding time, defrost a bag until it reaches room temperature. Sprinkle some multivitamin powder (optional), calcium carbonate and one drop wheat germ oil. Mix well and feed to your Eclectus. We have found that if you add a hard-boiled egg smashed with the shell to this mixture they will like it even better. Another way of introducing the egg is to scramble together the defrosted meal with egg and cook it as you would make your own scrambled eggs. Make sure that the egg is not soft as it may carry avian infectious agents, which could infect and kill your parrot. Minced chicken meat could be added to this too. For the same reason listed above, make sure it is cooked completely.Based on my personal experience, I recommend adding spirulina or wheat grass powders at least three times a week. Just apply a pinch of either or both powders before doing the final mixing of the food. Some people prefer to use alfalfa powder.Don't feed ground oyster shells to your parrot, it is unnecessary and dangerous. The diet suggested above will supply the calcium needed. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1419</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 3 (1998): MAY-JUNE 1988; 53-55</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1419/1397</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
