<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1302</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:34:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EX liBIRIS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hyde, Graeme</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">KEEPING AND BREEDING FINCHES AND SEED-EATERS by Russell ]. Kingston, Indruss Productions, New Farm, Queensland, Australia. Over 270 color photographs, plus numerous black and white illustrations and distribution maps for each species. Hard cover, 526 pages, 6.6 x 9.5 inches, 3lbs. $A70 ($US45.50) retail. Although American readers of Watchbird may not be aware of the ornithological, birdwatching, and avicultural books published "Down Under" I can assure them that Australia has produced several fine publications. In fact, I could quite easily write an article discussing the range of titles that have hit the bookstores during the last decade, and their specific contributions to the "world of birds." The book under review - Keeping and breeding Finches and Seed-Eaters - is an excellent book by one of Australia's best, and best-known, finch breeders. Published about the middle of 1998 it is an updated and, dare I say it, an improved version of Kingston's earlier work, A Complete Manual for the keeping and breeding of Finches, which was launched by the author at the Avicultural Federation of Australia's (AFA) Seventh National Avicultural Convention held in Melbourne, Victoria, in March 1994. (The AF.A. in Australia, which was fledged in 1980, is based on the American Federation of A viculture.) When reviewing the "Manual," Ian Lynch, a well-known and successful Victorian finch breeder, wrote: " ... it represented one of the most significant additions to avicultural literature for many years" (Australian Aviculture, June 1994, pp. 131-132). Although I agree with Lynch's comment, I believe that I am obligated to say that, in my opinion, although the Manual is an excellent publication (despite its softcover), Kingston's latest book will become the definitive Australian work on finches and seedeaters well into the next millennium. It is well planned, well researched, well written, well produced, and beautifully illustrated with over 270 color photos. It highly informative, "chock-full" of valuable information based on the author's personal experiences and, most important of all, it is easy to read. In an effort to keep the retail selling price as low as possible the publishers (husband and wife team, Russell &amp;amp; Indra Kingston, viz, Indruss Productions) decided that the original 1994 book would be a soft cover. This was of concern to many Australian aviculturists because a book as thick and as heavy as the Manual requires a hard cover simply to prevent it from coming apart at the seams - especially if it is in constant use as an avicultural reference tool. What then are the author's credentials? He has kept and bred finches and seed-eaters since 1956 when his (late) father gave him a pair each of Zebra Finches, Owl Finches, Red-browed Finches, and Spice Finches. Over the ensuing 40-plus years, Kingston has kept and bred Budgerigars, canaries, finches, pigeons, quail, parakeets, lovebirds, pheasants, and waterfowl. However, despite his wide-ranging experiences, his first love (read: obsession) has always been finches - both Australian grassfinches and nonAustralian species. In 1987 he became co-owner and the hands-on manager of a large commercial bird-breeding farm at Caboolture, Queensland. He has since returned to being a hobbyist concentrating on breeding Australian and exotic finches and seed-eaters at his Brisbane home. The 14 chapters cover and discuss an incredible range of topics including Preparation and Stock Acquisition, Housing, Husbandry, Breeding, Nutrition, Health, and Trouble Shooting. The birds featured in the text are grouped into five separate chapters in an interesting way, i.e. all subspecies and common (English) names are listed alphabetically which, according to the author is to "facilitate easy finding." He comments, "As this is an avicultural publication, they [viz, species and subspecies) are not listed in scientific order. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1302</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 2 (1999): MARCH-APRIL 1999; 32-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1302/1281</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
