<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2813</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-05T18:52:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From Out of the Past</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Quinn, Joseph W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As I review the research on pigeons collected in a lifetime of search, I often regret that the young are usually denied this privilege because of the value and rarity of the older books and journals. W.B. Tegetmeier is one of the founders of the present day pigeon fancy. It was through Tegetmeier that the knowledge of Rev. E.S. Dixon, B.P. Brent and J.M. Eaton was brought to the attention of Charles Darwin. The impact of Darwin's works on science is well known; but we often miss the point, it was the breeders of England who provided the data and experimentation which developed into the evolutionary thesis he presented. Darwin properly credits Tegetmeier, "I have drawn up this brief synopsis from various sources, but chiefly from information given me by Mr. Tegetmeier'' (Animals and Plants Under Domestication, Vol. 1, 1868).Tegetmeier in 1868 wrote his famous "Pigeons: Their Structure, Varieties, Habits and Management" which is a foundation work on fancy pigeons. Three years later (1871) his work "The Homing or Carrier Pigeon (Le Pigeon Voyageur), Its History, General Management and Method of Training" established a scientific base for Racing Pigeon knowledge. All his works are collector's items, but I have found the only record of a speech delivered to racing fanciers. It was recorded by an unnamed club secretary in April 1889. Might I share with you the words of a man who through his friend Charles Darwin, has influenced scientific thought more than any pigeon racer in history?Mr. Tegetmeier on Homing Pigeons The great authority on Homing Pigeons - Mr. W.B. Tegetmeier, F.Z.S. - honoured the town of Basingstoke with his presence, and gave a lecture on the subject, in connection with which he has acquired quite a European reputation. Mr. Tegetmeier addressed the audience as follows: "Ladies and gentlemen, I did not intend to deliver a formal lecture on this subject. I think a conversational discourse, stating what's been done with regard to the utilization of these birds, will be lighter and more amusing to you. To begin with, I may tell you that all pigeons with which you are acquainted are descendents from a wild bird that inhabits this country and almost all other countries in the globe. It varies a little in plumage in one place and another. To us it is known as the blue rock pigeon. It inhabits the cliffs along the sea coasts; in India it is found among the excavated ruins; and in other parts of the world in corresponding situations. As its food is not very abundant in the places where it lives, the parent birds have to fly a long distance - sometimes twenty, thirty, and forty miles - in search of food for their young. Hence it is necessary that the bird should have the instinct of locality. It flies very high, has a very acute vision, and possesses the faculty of domesticity and also that of returning to its home, which unite to give the peculiar value of this pigeon as a horning bird. It was proved by Darwin - with whom I had the honour of working many years - that the homing pigeon has ...  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-05</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2813</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 11 No. 6 (1984): DEC 1984- JAN 1985; 36-40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2813/2797</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
