<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/650</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T03:49:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question #1: What's the storywith sunflower seeds? Do they reallycause hyperactivity in parrots?M. Thomas, CaliforniaAnswer #1: Sunflower seeds arenot psychedelic. They are high fatcontent seeds that "junk food" birdslove. Like all seeds, they are deficientin calcium, vitamin A, and protein.Sunflower seeds, as well as almost allthe seeds fed to birds in this country,are not native to Central and SouthAmerica or the Pacific, Asia, or Africa.They are organic but not "natural:'I do use some sunflower seeds inmy bean, wheat and corn mix which Isprout for my birds, but I do not feedthem raw. I would suggest discussingwith your veterinarian a properexpanded diet for your birds. TheAssociation of Avian Veterinarians hasan excellent booklet on feeding. Askyour veterinarian for a copy.James M. Harris, D.V.M.Oakland, CaliforniaAnswer #2: There have beenrumors for some time that sunflowerseeds are addictive in parrots and maycause them to become hyperactive.There is no scientific evidence to supportthis. Sunflower seeds are a tasty,high energy food source that parrots,people and a lot of other animals like.Parrots will eat sunflower seeds to theexclusion of other foods. Sunflowerseeds are deficient in vitamin A and Das well as calcium and essential aminoacids and are very high in fat. Theyshould be fed to parrots only as part ofa balanced diet.Nicole VanDerHeyden, D.V.M.Indianapolis, IndianaAnswer #3: Many individuals, aswell as one well-known seed distributor,have propagated the myth thatsunflower seeds are addictive becausethey contain an addictive narcotic substancecalled papaverine. This narcoticsubstance is said to cause hyperactivityamong those who partakeof it. At this point in time, there is noevidence to support the presence ofpapaverine in sunflower seeds or thatit would be a harmful ingredient if,indeed, it were present.Papaverine is usually classified as amuscle relaxant rather than a narcotic.So, if such a substance were found tobe present in sunflower seeds, a birdeating the seeds possibly might berelaxed and enjoying life, rather thanstressed and hyperactive as has beensuggested.Amy B. Wore!!, D.V.M.West Hills, CaliforniaQuestion #2: What could cause anoccasional white feather to appear ona Hyacinth Macaw? Is there a dietarydeficiency?A. Boblett, MissouriAnswer #1: Feather coloration inparrots involves both pigments andstructure. Melanins and lipochromesare pigments that produce black,brown, yellow, and red colors whileblue color is structural as it resultsfrom light scattering by small, air filledspaces in the feathers. The green....</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/650</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/650/633</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
