<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/711</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Importance of Reading</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">O'Neill, Linda M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">We are all told as children that read- .ing enhances our life. I never came tofind this more true than when Idecided to purchase my first cockatiel.Always admiring the beauty of thecockatiel, I finally convinced my husbandthat I just had to have one so onour anniverasary one year he led meto the pet store to choose which oneI'd like.Knowing nothing about cockatiels, Idid know at least the basics of lookingfor a healthy bird. When I chose themost alert, attentive one there, thestore clerk removed her from the cageand clipped her wings. I had neverseen such a process before and wasadvised that this made it easier to train them. With my new bird (who nowhad stubby wings) and a "How to . .. "book under my arm, we left the store.The very first lesson I learned aboutcockatiels was that when they wereupset ... they hiss/You could haveimagined the look on my face when Ifirst saw her do this. She also did a littlerocking side to side to accompanythis hissing noise. I had no idea whatwas wrong with her. I did get theimpression that she definitely was tlyingto intimidate me. So for the firstfew lessons of trying to get her out ofher cage I used a perch-stick. Shefound that less intimidating than myhand.The second lesson I learned was that even though her wings wereclipped, she could still fly somewhat,not enough to gain height, but wellenough for me to have to chase her.Her perch training had begun down along hall with all the doors shut withno where for her to go except by me.She realized that every time she flewto the floor from her perch, I wasgoing to retrieve her and place her onthe perch again. After a few of theseill-fated attempts, she gave up. Everytime she did sit still she got a treat ofmillet spray or some loving from me.She learned to sit so well that myhusband constructed a playpen forher to sit on during the day. This waskept on my coffee table in the middleof the living room and this suited herjust fine. She loved to be where theaction was. She ended up becoming aregular member of the family, more sothan a pet. The playpen consisted of awooden swing, a spiral step ladderand a tall balance beam. There werecups available for special treats. Sheturned out to be a ve1y healthy, happycockatiel.She developed a bond with me,(Ispent most of my time wih her andtrained and tamed her alone.) We hada little deal going between us. Sheloved to have her head scratched, andI loved being kissed. So it always costher a kiss for a scratch. I think that'spretty fair.A couple of years later, she beganlaying eggs. She did not have a mate,nor was there another bird in thehouse. This got to be quite a problembecause she would lay egg, after egg,after egg. This is where the readingbegan. I had talked to several differentpeople in pet stores, and it seemed themore people I talked to the more confusedI became. It seemed that no twopeople had the same answer oradvice. I figured I would get my handson everything I could concerningcockatiels. I borrowed books from thelibrary, I subscribed to different magazines,and I sent away for mail-orderbooks. After reading all the material Icould, I then could form my ownopinion on what the right treatmentwould be for each situation. If I hadonly done that first before I had purchasedmy cockatiel, I probably couldhave done things better. Not that Ididn't meet with the same results, Iwould have just gotten there faster.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/711</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 44-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/711/694</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
