<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/726</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Christmas Rainbow for Molly</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The line waiting to talk with SantaClaus seemed endless. But Molly wasever so patient. She knew exactlywhat she would say to him.Besides, six years of living in legbraces from a childhood paralysis hadtaught Molly about patience.Finally it was her turn, and as herparents lifted her onto Santa's lap shecould feel the warm smile and sensethe magic within this man dressed inred."Oh yes, that is all I wish," Mollyrepeated slowly, "All I have everwished for was a real rainbow.""That is a very tall request," noddedSanta thoughtfully. "Nevertheless, Iwill do what I can.""Thank you," Molly said as she wascarried away.The following weeks were busy anddifficult for Molly's mother and father.The more they searched, the morethey realized the impossibility of findinga true rainbow for their six yearold daughter.As Christmas eve approached,Molly's spirits rose. Her parents hadnever seen her cheeks so rosy, hereyes so bright and gay. Though shenever spoke of it, everyone knew herwish to Santa was foremost in hermind.Three days before Christmas,Molly's mom and dad sat talking longinto the night. "It just can't be done,"her father said. "How can we locate arainbow for Molly's Christmas gift? I'velooked at rainbow coloring books,rainbow T-shirts, rainbow unicorns,even rainbow Chrismas cookies. I giveup.""I know, but she has her heart so seton this," her mother answered."Tomorrow is Christmas eve. I will goto town one more time and look forthe best rainbow gift I can find." The bustle and cheer were overflowingthe next day as Molly'smother tramped from store to store,seeking the elusive rainbow to fulfillher daughter's wish. She had aboutgiven up hope when she stumbledinto a tiny pet shop on a cozy sidestreet."Hello," smiled the young owner."May I help you?""Well, I just don't know," Molly'smother replied. She went on to tell theman the entire story of Molly's Christmaswish."I might have just the answer foryou," he said. "For years I have beenin love with a small species of parrotknown as the rainbow lorikeet. Come,let me show you."In the rear of his shop, the owneropened a tub to reveal three fuzzy,brightly feathered baby birds. "Theseare rainbow lorikeets," he explained,"and a more beautiful, delightful petparrot there could not be!""Oooh, may I hold one?" Molly'smother exclaimed."Let's just wash your hands and youcan help me feed the babies," heanswered. "They are beginning theirweaning - something easily accomplishedwith baby rainbows."Placed on a clean towel, the lorikeetswere given a brief taste of awarm mixture of lory powder, applejuice, baby food, yogurt and spirulina.Remaining formula was squirted into alow glass saucer nearby. The oldest ofthe babies promptly ran over andbegan lapping up the liquid food onlyto be joined by his two siblings. AsMolly's mother watched, the pet storeowner talked enthusiastically of thepet qualities of the rainbow lorikeets."There are about nine different varietiesof rainbows," he explained."These baby Swainson's or BlueMountain Lorikeets are my particular favorite . Their colors are green, yellow,orange, red, blue and violetmelted together in shimmering light."Not only are they playful andfriendly to strangers, but they canbecome accomplished talkers in a tinyvoice, and are quick to learn. Most ofour lorikeets are trained to go 'poo' oncommand by age 16 weeks."We like to sell lorikeets to healthfood conscious families," he went on."They love foods prepared in a blender.Banana smoothies, papaya juice,ground coconut, mushed berries, soymilk, even brown rice and soups."Of course, rumor has it they aremessy birds, but I find the larger loriesare by far the more messy. Rainbowsseldom throw large pieces of fruitabout. What's more, their droppingsare often like warm apple juice - notgreen and smeary like other parrots'.Lory poo on my shirt often does notleave a stain. They are the one bird inmy collection I allow run of my household."We recommend keeping them inlong, low cages near the ground withcedar chips in the bottom tray andplenty of grass and leafy branches tocatch squirts."Their pet behavior is one of purejoy!" he added. "They are as comfortableon their backs as upright and willhop over to examine any new objectplaced in their cage or path. Not shy,suspicious parrots at all, these livingrainbows . .. "</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/726</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 24-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/726/709</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
