<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1883</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-29T21:04:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">American Federation of Aviculture 1 AFA LOGO BANDS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">EVERY BIRD BR.ED SHOULD BE BANDED ?,J AFA LOGO CLOSED ALUMTNUM BANDSIf you only need one or two bands, you can purchase what you need with no minimum order required. AFA has available, suitable band sizes from Canary to Macaw. All bands will have the AFA logo imprinted. The bands will be traceable through a special coding and numbering system formulated by the AFA. The bands will not have a year imprinted or any customizing. They are only available in silver and are priced per band. Any inquiries as lo the origin of a band will be forwarded to the registered code owner. lt will then be up to them to contact the inquirer.THESE BANDS ARE NOT RECOMMENDED FOR HYACINTH MACAWS.CUSTOMIZED CLOSED ALUMJNUM BANDSThese bands require a minimum order of 10 or 25 per size depending on the size. All bands will have the AFA logo imprinted. A customized code consisting of two to four letters up to four sequenced numbers and can contain the year and your state as well if you wish. (For example ABC I, ABC 2, .. ABC 1234_. etc.) T11e letter code will be recorded to prevent issuing duplicate coding to any om: else. These bands wi 11 then be traceable to the breeder. Any inquiries as to the origin of a band will be forwarded to the registered code owner. It will then be up lo them lo contact the inquirer. Bands ordered for a succeeding year will be shipped after December 26th. These bands are available in silver. black, blue. yellow. red, green. orange and violet.THESE BANDS ARE NOTRECOMil1ENDED FOR HYACINTH MACAWS.CUSTOMIZ~D CLOSED STAlNLESS STEEL BANDSThese bands require a minimum order of 10 per size. They are not available in all sizes. All bands will have die AFA logo imprinted. A customized code consisting of two to four letters, up to four sequenced numbers and can contain the year and your state as well if you wish. (For example ABC I, ABC 2 ... ABC 1234, etc.) The letter code will be recorded to prevent issuing duplicate coding to any one else. These bands wi 11 then be traceable to the breeder. Any inquiries as to the origin of a band will be forwarded to the registered code owner. It will then be up to them to contact the inquirer. Bands ordered for a succeeding year will be shipped after December 26111 •. These bands are available in silver onlyOPEN STAJNLESS STEEL BANDSThese bands are made from 300 series stainless steel and are the same as what is being used by USDA quarantine stations. If you only need one or two bands, you can purchase what you need with no minimum order required. AFA has available suitable band sizes from Cockaticl to Macaw. All bands will have the AFA logo imprinted. The bands will be traceable through a special coding and numbering system formulated by the AF A. The bands will not have a year imprinted or any customizing. They are only available in silver and are priced per band. Any inquiries as to the origin of a band will be forwarded to the registered code owner. It will then be up to them to contact the inquirer.A special band pliers are required Lo properly apply and close the band. AFA offers this 1001 at no cost for a returnable deposit of$25 per pliers needed. (You will need a different one for different sized bands) Please send a separate check from the band order to be held until the pliers have been returned.American Federation of Avlculrure PO Box 7312N. Kansas City, MO 64J 16 www.afabirds.org1 Size requirements for individual birds may vary. The band sizes are suggested by the manufacturer. 'he APA does Dot take responsibility for tbe suggested sizes.2 tndlvldual States may have their own banding requirements for exotlc birds. AFA cannot guarantee that these bands comply with those requirements. Each aviculturists should independently verify these requirements.3 The band manufacturer is closed during the month of July. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1883</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 31 No. 4 (2004): Number 4 2004- Number 1 2005; 48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1883/1854</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
