<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1550</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:53:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Pink-necked Fruit Dove Ptilinopus porphyrea at Disney's Animal Kingdom (DAK)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bockheim, Greg</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">DescriptionThe Pink-necked Fruit Dove, also commonly referred to as the Temminck's Fruit Dove, is found in forest habitats on the islands of Sumatra, Java, and Bali (Delacour 1979). As with many island animal species the Pink-necked Fruit Dove's status relies on preserving its natural habitat. At present it is not listed as globally threatened but as forest regions are reduced so is its natural range. In captivity it is one of the more well represented species of fruit dove, yet their numbers are small requiring a studbook to preserve genetic diversity. At present there are 12 male and 10 female Pink-necked Fruit Doves registered with the AZA sponsored studbook (Morris 1998). The low ratio of females hatched in comparison to males and the overall low numbers of birds in captivity have created problems in pairing.The head, neck, and upper back of the male is a pinkish lavender extending into crimson lavender on the lower chest, throat, and nape; the mid chest is bordered by a band of white and then a narrow blackish green band. From the chest bands to the abdomen the male is powder grey. The upper parts are a rich grey/green tinged with yellow; the tail is also grey/green with a grey band on the tip. The feathers of the abdomen, vent and legs are a mixture of white, blue/green, yellow and apricot in the male.The female is a slightly smaller bird with less clearly defined coloration; the head and neck being a muted lavender and the white and black bands of the chest being less pronounced.· Underwing coverts are blue/grey in both sexes. Females lack the apricot color of the leg, vent and abdominalarea. Mature birds are easily sexed visually. Young are overall shades of grey/green extending into iridescent green of the upper back, wing coverts and flight feathers. The. feet of both sexes are coral pink with grey toe nails. The bill and nares are grey.History at DAKDisney's Animal Kingdom acquired a male in early 1998 followed by a female in 1999. The pair appeared to bond quite quickly and after the required quarantine period was "howdied" and then released into a large mixed species Asian aviary. The aviary measures 100 feet by 55 feet and is 40 feet tall. Thirty-eight bird species inhabit the Asian aviary from Tri-colored Flycatchers Ficedula zantbopygia and Dhyal Thrushes Copsycbus saularis to Azure-winged Magpies Cyanopica cyana and Amboina King Parrots Alisterus amboinensis:Nine other species from the family Columbidae also share this enclosure including Sulawesi Quail Doves Gallicolumba tristigmata, Wompoo Fruit Doves Ptilinopus magnificus, Green-winged Doves Cbalcopbaps indica, Pheasant Pigeons Otidipbaps nobilis, Jambu Fruit Doves Ptilinopus jambu, Barlett's Bleeding-heart Doves Gallicolumba criniger, Nicobar Pigeons Caloenas nicobarica, Papuan Mountain Pigeons Gymnopbaps albertisii, and Pink-necked Green Pigeons Treron vemans.DietThe diets fed to the OAK aviary birds are complete and varied but relatively simple to prepare. The majority of the diet bowls included Mazuri brand parrot pellets and Mazuri small bird breeder pellets (both soaked until moistened through), 50/50 mix of finch seed and dry small bird breeder pellets, freshly chopped fruit mix containing grapes, cooked sweet potato, apple, raisins, pear, and pineapple. Shredded carrots and dark leafy greens, along with a commercially prepared insectivore mixture are also sprinkled in the mix. Soaked parrot pellets seem to he the Pink-necked's favorite food item. Several of these diet dishes are placed throughout the aviary in an attempt to dissuade displacement and aggression between species. The diets are prepared and offered to the birds in the morning and again fresh diets are prepared and fed at midday. Diets are pulled overnight unless chicks are being reared. Large ficus trees Ficus microcarpa also offer the birds fresh figs, buds, and flowers which they relish.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1550</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 4 (2000): July-August 2000; 20-22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1550/1527</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
