<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3096</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-18T09:38:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Presenting the State Coordinator - Dr. Barry Adler -</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baer, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the last issue of WATCHBIRD, the membership of A.F.A. was introduced to two coordinators from the New England States, one of whom is our youngest representative.This issue presents one of our newest coordinators, Dr. Barry M. Adler, newly appointed coordinator for the State of New Jersey.Barry, 27, is a recent graduate (1977) of Ohio State University, College of Veterinary Medicine. In addition to his D.Y .M. degree, he holds a B .S. degree in Animal Science from Rutgers University and is completing a masters in Reproductive Physiology.While a student of O.S.U. he was very active in the A.F.A. affiliated Central Ohio Bird Fanciers, Inc. Club.His aviary in New Jersey contains cockatiels, lovebirds, finches and Amazons. With his avocation for aviculture , Barry combines an interest in photography and pottery.Barry's wife. Blanche. has her B.S. degree in Landscape Architecture from Rutgers, shares with Barry his varied interests, and has a green thumb for plants and growing things.Dr. Adler is at present in practice at the Central Animal Hospital, 1067 Commerce Ave., Union, NJ. where his enthusiasm and concern for cage bird medicine is being put to good use. Aviculturists on the East Coast are fortunate to have Dr. Adler, a veterinarian skilled in avian veterinary medicine.For the A.F.A., Barry is at present authoring a bulletin on the External and Internal Parasites of Cage Birds - their identification and treatment, which we hope will be published under the auspices of A.F .A. He is also working with our education committee in the promotion of A.F.A. and the WATCHBIRD in the colleges of veterinary medicine and in the orientation of veterinary students toward greater interest in aviculture and cage bird medicine. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3096</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 6 (1977): DEC 1977- JAN 1978; 34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3096/3080</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
