<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4118</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:18:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Peregrine Falcon: The Perilous Return from Near Extinction</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Darden, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 4 (October/November 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Raptor Conservation and RehabilitationThe Peregrine Falcon; the Perilous Return from Near Extinction by Jennifer DardenPet Bird Association of Virginia, www.pbav.orgEverything about the Peregrine Falcon is fast, from 129 blinks and four wing beats per second, 600-900 heart beats per minute and a 200 plus mph dive when targeting prey. Peregrine falcons have been pushed into city living and decided that nesting on the ledges of tall buildings is close enough to their preferred cliff dwell-crops and livestock. Its wide use in agriculture and residential settings had a negative impact on land and sea food chains, decimating birds of prey populations by affecting the production of calcium, which caused thin eggshells that cracked under the weight of incubating adults. Their population plummeted to only 30 pairs in the U.S. and they wereClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4118</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 4 (2022): Watchbird October/November 2022; 14-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4118/4078</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
