<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2369</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T14:46:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Avy Award Winners - 1985</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">U.S. First Breeding Awards Brown-headed parrotFred and Robbie Harris Red-faced lovebirdWayne and Charlotte Offerman D'arnaud's barbetLawrence and Clarissa Cook White-collared mynahLindsay ClackAfrican grey hornbillLindsay Clack Chestnut-bellied starling Lindsay ClackWeber's loryJanR. van Ooosten Bill de la Mare Red-billed toucan Jerry Jennings Spot-billed toucanet Jerry Jennings Red-bellied macawRayburn and Norene Smith Black-bellied fire finch Riverbanks Zoological Park Bar-breasted fire finchJohn and Kristin Round Bronze-winged pionusStan and Fay Carpenter John RobertsBlue-eyed cockatooGloria AllenHooded pittaPhiladelphia Zoo/Larry Shelton Orange-bellied euphonia Philadelphia Zoo/Larry SheltonCaninde macaw Kevin Clubb Scott Riviere Fred CubbedgeMuller's parrot KayK.Muser M.D.MollSilver Avy AwardsCategory III - for most progress with color mutations and pied Indian ringnecksJaynee SalanCategory I - for species establishment of the Pacific parrotletJack and Connie BrooksCategory IV - for show standards Carter Atwood Zoo CategoryCategory I - for establishing captive bred penguinsSea World, Frank Todd,Scott Drieschman, Frank Tuioby Category II - most progress with an individual species using good management techniques for Emperor penguinsSea World, Frank Todd,Scott Drieschman, Frank TwohyAvy Appreciation Awards (for outstanding contribution and leadership)Glen Gibson, National Cockatiel SocietyCharlie and Lorene Shepard, Arizona Avicultural Society/ Arizona Budgerigar Society Charles E. Clift,Central Alabama Avicultural SocietyGold Award(once in a lifetime for outstanding contribution to aviculture)Frank Todd, California GameBreeders AssociationWatchbird Awards(fine articles with photo support, 1984)DebraArgel, "From Antarctica to San Diego by Egg''Ramon P. Noegel, "First Captive Breeding of the Dusky Pion us"Bronze Avy AwardsPhyllis K. MartinFor Outstanding Service as Chairman of the 1984 National ConventionJoe McLaughlinFor Outstanding Service as Chairman of Membership PromotionGary LilienthalFor Outstanding Service as Legal CounselDarel CavenderFor Outstanding Service as Chairman of Speakers' Committee Certificates of Appreciation Walter WilloughbyIn appreciation of his efforts as State Coordinator of Connecticut in preventing the passage of legislation inimical to aviculture.Central Alabama Aviculture Society In appreciation of their generosity and continued support of A. F.A. and its programs.Dick SchroederIn appreciation of his efforts as State Coordinator in promoting A.FA. and disseminating useful information to bird owners.President's Award Gary LilienthalPhyllis Martin Membership Promotion AwardBill Wilson </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2369</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 5 (1985): OCT- NOV 1985; 48-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2369/2342</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
