<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2961</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-14T08:52:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">And For Flavor Mix in a Few Doves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Believe it or not, doves are a very fine gamebird and in several states the dove season has an important economic impact. On the other hand, there are many dove species that no one would ever shoot at. Many of these more exotic species are beautiful additions to any collection of birds.In fact, most collections - be they parrot, finch, or pheasant, have a sprinkling of doves scattered throughout. Of course the most common dove is the Barbary Dove or the Sacred White Dove. A close second for popularity among aviculturists is the tiny Diamond Dove with its plaintive coo. Diamond Doves fit very nicely into a Cockatiel flight. They add warmness and music to a parrot or finer pen.If one is careful the beautiful but timid Cape Dove can be kept in a mixed collection. They are so timid though that I almost lost a pair that was in a Zebra Finch pen. The aggressive finches kept the doves away from food and water. Capes do well with gentle parrots in a large flight. I kept some with a breeding pair of Princess of Wales Parrots and everyone got along quite well.Doves have a reputation for being gentle but any one who keeps doves knows that is not true. Doves are extremely aggressive - but usually with their own species only. The Galapagos Doves are great fighters. I had two pair in adjoining Cockatiel flights but the males fought so much through the wire that they did not breed well. When I separated the pairs each male commenced to trounce his female. They just love to fight I guess.Doves such as the magnificent Bleeding Heart species will receive more attention than the parrots who share their pen. The Bleeding Hearts spend almost all of their time upon the ground so there is little or no conflict with most parrots or finches which stay up on the perches or in the trees. A beautiful bird in the upper reaches of your pen and an equally delightful bird on the ground provide a scene that is hard to walk away from.If you have a huge walk-in flight pen that covers an acre or so - fine. There is just the dove for you to blend in - the giant Victoria Crowned Pigeon. On the other hand, if your largest flight is 4 feet by 8 feet, the tiny Diamond Dove will think it room enough.Delightful birds are doves. Their cooing is eternal and very soothing. They become very tame and friendly with their keeper. They have color from the most subtle greys and violets to the most gaudy reds and greens. Most doves breed well and they are hardy. All things considered, your collection of birds is not complete if there are no doves gracing it. Add a little flavor - mix in some doves. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2961</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 3 (1978): JUNE-JULY 1978; 40-41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2961/2945</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
