<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2522</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-15T14:01:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Gamebird Conservation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">During the first half of the nineteenth century, had you ventured into a meat market in New York or Baltimore, you might well have encountered a rather "fishy" tasting duck offered for sale. That duck, often said to have rotted as few desired to eat them, was that of a Labrador Duck (Camptorbyncbus labradorius), a now extinct species. While discovered inhabiting the northeast seaboard in 1789, the duck, for reasons unknown, had disappeared by 1878.While at least four species of waterfowl have passed into extinction, I know of only one Gallinaceous bird, the Himalayan Mountain Quail (Opbrysia superciliosa) that can be added to that list. This is not to say that many additional species are not heading in this direction. Habitat modification and hunting seem to be reducing gamebird numbers everywhere at a rapid rate. While efforts by the International Council for Bird Preservation (ICBP) and the World Pheasant Association have made some substantial progress in aiding some of these species, as you can see from the list at the end of this article, they have a rather formidable challenge ahead of them.While it is encouraging to note that a number of species facing troubles in the wild are well represented in captivity, it is equally saddening that most are not. Having had the pleasure of working with tragopans, as well as brown-, blue- and white-eared pheasants in the late sixties, I know well of their awe-inspiring beauty. Anyone who is tempted to associate bright colors of enchanting combinations with only small birds needs to visit a pheasant collection. We can only hope that the next ICBP list contains no more, perhaps fewer, species of gamebirds. In order to help and/or learn more about pheasant conservation, write to:World Pheasant Association,P.O. Box 5, Child Beale Wildlife Trust, Lower Basildon, Readings RG8 9PF,England.Threatened Gamebirds taken from "Birds to Watch", ICBP Technical Publication No. 8, Smithsonian Institution Press, Collar and Andrews, editors, 1988. Threatened Ducks and Geese West Indian Whistling Duck Hawaiian GooseFreckled DuckCrested ShelduckBaykal TealNew Zealand Brown TealLaysan DuckPink-headed DuckMadagascar PochardScaly-sided MerganserLesser White-fronted Goose Red-breasted GooseRuddy-headed GooseWhite-winged DuckMadagascar TealHawaiian DuckMarbled TealBaer 's PochardBrazilian MerganserWhite-headed DuckThreatened Pheasants, Francolins, Quail &amp;amp; Peafowl Bearded Wood-partridgeGorgeted Wood-quailMount Cameroon FrancolinNahan's FrancolinManipur Bush QuailRickert's Hill-partridge Chestnut-headed PartridgeChestnut- necklaced Partridge Western TragopanCabot's TragopanChinese MonalVo Quys Pheasant Swinhoe's Pheasant Crested Fireback Bulwer's Pheasant Brown-eared Pheasant Hume's Pheasant Reeve's PheasantMalaysian Peacock-pheasant Crested ArgusCongo PeacockChestnut Wood-quail Djibouti Francolin Swierstra's Francolin Swamp PartridgeSichuan Hill-partridge Orange-necked Partridge White-eared Hill-partridge Himalayan QuailBlyth's TragopanSclater's MonalImperial PheasantEdwards' Pheasant Salvadori's Pheasant Siamese Fireback White-eared Pheasant Cheer PheasantMikado PheasantGermain's Peacock-pheasant Palawan Peacock-pheasant Green Peafowl • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2522</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 3 (1990): JUNE-JULY 1990; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2522/2492</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
