<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2148</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-07T19:47:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Brown Pelicans Maimed- A Visit with the Victims and their Veterinarian</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Beane, Charlene</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In mid-October, California brown pelicans whose top beaks had been chopped off received national media coverage. Such an act, had it happened to any living creature, would have been hideous, but the gravity of the crime was compounded because the California brown pelican is an endangered species.On October 30, Jean Hessler, Watchbird an director, and I visited the Crown Valley Animal Hospital in Laguna Niguel, California to see the mutilated birds. As we arrived, a Fish and Game officer was leaving-he had just brought in another pelican whose beak had been severed.Dr. Gayle Roberts took us back to the pelican pen. Although I thought I was mentally prepared for what I was about to see, the sight of the injured birds, coupled with the overwhelming smell of fish, almost made me faint.After the initial shock, I regained my composure and started seeing the good things. Except for their stubs of top beaks which ranged from one to four inches in length, the birds were in excellent condition. They are housed in a large area with vinyl coated concrete floor, tile walls, and a temporary ceiling of poultry netting to keep the birds from flying into the adjacent dog runs. As amenities, the pelicans have a child's wading pool, several tires to dim b on and a large window with iron grillwork where they perch to admire their admirers. The pen also contains a fake fire hydrant, a reminder of the intended purpose of the space.California brown pelicans are a little smaller than the Canada goose, 7-9 lbs. Their necks are longer, more like swans, and their heads are large like geese and swans, but rounder, more domed, in appearance. The top back of the neck carries about a six-inch row of tufting that becomes yellowish in adults, possibly due to sun bleaching.Although they lack the dramatic markings of the Canada goose, the color tones are similar. These injured birds are young, probably last springs chicks, because their heads are dark, velvety, chocolate brown. Only one is showing a lightening of head feathers. This bird is probably older than the others. Dr. Roberts said that this bird had trouble adapting to handling and hand feeding. Now that the pelicans are accustomed to humans, the bird that appears to be the oldest is the most aggressive. As the birds stabbed at me with their lower beaks, begging for food, this bird with the lighter face made the most vigorous thrusts. The younger birds were curious and gentle with their probes; the older bird wanted to be fed and he meant it!Back and wing feathers are dark to medium brown, variegated but not patterned. The breasts are a soft beige, and the color tones are blended, not delineated.The feather texture is harder and rougher than that of a goose, and the feathers are not quite as smooth lying, but this may be partially due to these birds' inability to groom themselves. It was pitiable watching them reach back to their oil gland with their single lower beaks, making grooming gestures, rubbing their heads on their feathers. Since they cannot groom properly, these birds may have to wait through an entire moult to be sea-worthy; without the proper distribution of natural oil, the feathers will absorb water and the birds would sink and drown.The legs and feet are slate colored and medium in size. I was surprised to notice that their fourth (hind) toe is the same length as the others and that it is also webbed, in contrast to domestic waterfowl which have three long roes and two webs with a short fourth toe that is used for balance. My geese want their feet on terra firma; they seem afraid to walk up steps or ramps. The pelicans, with their four long toes and three webs, were climbing all over the place. They seem to have much greater ability to grip and perch than the more earthbound domestic waterfowl. No doubt that third inside web in their feet gives them extra power when they are swimming.The pelicans have about a seven foot wingspan, and they are fortunate to be in large enough quarters that they can spread and flap their wings. The force of those wings was formidable when they smacked me in the face.Pelican eyes are larger than a dime, more than twice the size of goose eyes, and dark, liquid brown. The expression in those eyes is so innocent and trusting, it is hard not to wax anthropomorphic. The pelicans are eating well. Local fishermen are donating part of their catches each day-mostly bonito-to feed the birds. The fish is cut into bitesize pieces and dropped into the elastic lower beaks. A man from Canada sent 100 lbs. of frozen mackerel which the pelicans relish because it can be eaten whole. The mackerel is being rationed to use as treats and to tempt reluctant diners and newly rescued patients to eat. The pelicans at the hospital when I visited consume 40-50 lbs. of fish per day. They also get vitamins. In the wild it is thought that they favor anchovies.Their weight and condition was good.Dr. Roberts said that they were not emaciated when they were brought in. She speculated that fishermen had been throwing them fish. She thinks most of the injured pelicans had not learned to fish on their own, and this dependence contributed to their vulnerability.The beaks were cut off with a serrated tool, perhaps something like a fish knife. Some of the beaks were cut off entirely; others, especially those cut closer to the nostrils where the beak is thicker, were still attached at the lower edges, but were severed to the point that they flapping and useless. A few were cut through into the edges of the lower beak. These wounds have already started to heal and gain strength. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2148</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 9 No. 6 (1982): DEC-JAN 1982; 38-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2148/2119</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
