<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/644</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The A riel Toucan - beyond the first generation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Breeding toucans has been a hit andmiss proposition with only a handfulof aviculturists pursuing any coordinatedeffort with vigor. It is quiteunfortunate since toucans are large,attractive, and entertaining birds thatmake wonderful subjects for exhibitionin zoos (you can actually findthem in a large, planted flight), backyardaviaries, and they can be tamedthrough training or handfeeding andare thus suitable as pets. They are veryintelligent, hardy, and friendly.Why then, are so few people workingwith these birds? Perhaps thisshould change, and hopefully so,since the importation of toucans has ended. With that in mind, what toucansare available and which ones aregood breeders? All of the species oflarge, black toucans have been bred incaptivity, but only a few have done sobeyond the first generation. Thechampion in that competition is theAriel Toucan Ramphastos vitellinusariel, a subspecies of the ChannelbilledRamphastos vitellinus vitellinus.The Ariel toucan was first bred incaptivity by this author in 1978. It hasnot been imported since 1983, andthere are only a few pairs in the U.S.,perhaps as many as 20, of which halfare in zoos and the balance in privatecollections. There are undoubtedlyabout 500 meters, where they forageon a wide variety of forest fruits andinsects .</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/644</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 27-28</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/644/627</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
