<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2835</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-07T17:25:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Membership Promotion</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dahle, Tim</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hi I Many of you may not be aware that the Membership Promotion Committee has both some new faces and new goals this year.As Dr. Baer mentioned at the 1978 Dallas convention this August, AFA 's objective this year is to double its membership.While the state coordinators have by this time received a detailed memo outlining some techniques and procedures for increasing membership, doubling our ranks is going to require a little work on everyone's part.Each AF A member should attempt to increase the size of our organization by enrolling 2 new members this year. There are people we all know who should belong but don't. Show them Watchbird and explain to them what AFA represents and can do for them.Put an application in their hand and get them signed up. The next time you see them ask if they have joined - if not, talk it up some more - repeat this procedure as often as necessary to achieve success.Applications and a mimeo explaining AFA are available through your club delegates and state coordinators. Remember -Numbers Talk. (But only if we do first!)If anyone out there wishes to become a member of the membership promotion committee or has any ideas that would help, please drop me a line.Tim DahleMembership Promotion Committee Chairperson913 Genine Dr.Glen Burnie, MD 21061 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2835</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 1 (1979): FEB-MAR 1979; 39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2835/2819</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
