<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/476</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Raising Canaries for Show and Pleasure tips for the novice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cisper, Naomi</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Preparing Canaries for ShowCatch all birds you anticipate showingeight to ten weeks ahead of theshow. Pull broken wing and tailfeathers so they will grow back completelybefore the show. Check formissing toes; these birds are still goodfor breeding but not for show. Trimtheir beaks and toenails. Rub a smallamount of oil (olive, mineral, etc.) intotheir legs taking care not to get oil onthe feathers. Place each bird in anindividual cage and study them forundesirable characteristics: crookedbeak, crossed wings, fan tailed, etc.Study body type for desirable characteristics.Make a final selection ofwhich birds to show including acouple of spares and keep them in individualcages. This will prevent glostercoronas from being picked and lizardrowings from fading and feathers beingpulled out by other birds. Keep cagesclean, offering baths as often as possible.Spray each bird several timeseach week with whatever mixture youuse in the mornings. Three are listedfor your use:1. Two tablespoons of Listerine toone quart of water.2. One tablespoon Listerine plustwo teaspoons glycerin to one quart ofwater.3. One teaspoon each of EpsonSalts, Listerine, malt vinegar, and glycerinto one quart of boiling water. Usethis spray while somewhat hot.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/476</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 2 (1989): APR-MAY 1989; 46-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/476/461</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
