<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/647</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Illigers Macaw BREEDING CENTRE in South African Aviculture</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lavril, Carine</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">DescriptionAlthough the Illiger's Macaw, (Aramaracana), is described accurately inRosemary Low's book, "Parrots -Their Care and Breeding" and inJoseph Forshaw's "Parrots of theWorld", I will briefly say that it is themost beautiful of the seven species ofdwarf macaws existing today. Theyinclude the Red-fronted (A. rubrogenys),the Noble (A. nobilis), the Yellow-collared (A. auricollis), the Redbellied(A. manilata), the Chestnutfrontedor Severe (A. severa) and theBlue-headed (A. couloni).It is mainly olive green with blue primaryfeathers and its distinctive markingsare patches of red-orange on theforehead, the lower back and the middleabdomen between the legs. Thetotal length is 16.9 inches. Crown andcheeks are bluish, the bill is black, theiris red and the legs pinkish. Immatureshave less extensive and dullercoloration markings. Although it hasbeen fairly common up to now in itsoriginal habitat (forests of easternBrazil and Paraguay), these birds sufferloss of habitat as much as manyother species of neo-tropical parrots.Deforestation is the main reason for itsrecent decline.The Illiger's Macaw was imported insmall numbers into the U.S.A. in thelate 1970s and again in the late 1980s.It was listed on CITES I in 1989. It isone of the rarest dwarf macaws in a vicultureand is not often found as a pet.There is very little information about itin avian magazines worldwide.BreedingDue to the rarity of the Illiger'sMacaw in captivity, aviculturists keepingthese exquisite parrots should beconcerned about inbreeding andmake every effort to avoid breedingfrom related individuals.At the Parrot Breeding Centre, thisspecies is kept in suspended cages,seven feet long by three feet squarewith nesting boxes hooked on the outside of the cage. Two of the breedingpairs have horizontal boxes andfour have vertical ones.The birds are offered a great varietyof fruits and vegetables along with ourmixture of sprouted seeds. They arevery fond of A vi-plus which is givenprior to the breeding season and thediet is highly supplemented with calciumpowder at the same time of theyear so the shells will not be brittle orshow stress lines after two or threeclutches.Some pairs prove to be very prolificthough others are difficult to establishin captivity. Out of the six pairs weacquired originally, three bred immediately.One of these pairs lays up tofour clutches a year but unfortunatelyignores the chicks once they are born.They will not harm them but refuse tofeed them. They seem to think there issomething wrong when creepycrawliescome out of their eggs!Two other pairs are wonderfulbreeders. They both lay three clutchesfrom three to four eggs each and willraise whatever they are allowed tokeep and will readily accept chicksfrom other nests. They also startbreeding as early as July. Naturally, itis out of the question to leave thenewborn babies in the boxes whenthe weather could prove fatal to them.A fourth pair has started to breed thisseason but gave us only one clutch.The other two pairs should bemature enough to start breeding nextseason. These parrots enjoy the companyof a mate and will sit for longperiods of time together, occasionallypreening.At the start of the breeding season,pairs can be seen mating many times,careless of what may go on aroundthem and the males will often feedtheir hens. They are very concernedabout the well being of their familyand will spend more and more timeinside the box with the females,mainly during incubation, feedingthem and the babies once hatched. Incubation lasts for 26 days approximately.Chicks are ringed when theyweigh about 160 gm (between 18 and20 days of age) with 9.5 mm rings.Hand RearingHand rearing from the egg is quiteeasy and straight forward, using AviplusN1 for the first eight days, thengradually adding N2. Birth weightsvary between 9.5 and 12.3 gm, theusual being around 10.5 grams.Some pairs are very choosy abouttheir food which leads to a lack of theB vitamins. It shows occasionally inchicks. Soon after hatching, they willshow signs of a neurological disorder.The legs are stiff and consequentlywill not fold under the baby. It willfind itself lying on its back or side. Ihave talked to different aviculturistskeeping this species and they havehad the same problem with somebaby Illiger's. It is not a very seriouscondition if attended to early, as thefollowing example shows.This chick was hatched in our nursery,rather than in the nesting box. Idecided to assist it when, from candlingthe egg, I noticed somethingwas wrong. It was quite agitated so Iopened the shell before the chick hada chance to pip. This is when I realizedit was upside down. It finallyhatched and weighed just below 6 gmat birth. Soon after this, the neurologicaldisorder appeared.The baby was kept in a small containerwith as little space as possible inorder to keep it on its belly and force itto keep its weight on its legs so thatthey could fold in the normal position.It was checked very often and putback on its feet when needed. VitaminB complex was administered, onedrop in the morning feed every dayfor five days then three times the followingweek. This was repeated onceafter a month. No antibiotics weregiven since this condition is not a diseasenor due to any infection.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/647</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 35-36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/647/630</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
