<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3405</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-14T03:45:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Softbill Propagation in U.S. Zoos: A Thirty Year Perspective, Part I: The ‘70’s</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lindholm III, Josef H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The three decades following the establishment of the American Federation of Aviculture have seen remarkable developments in the management of captive birds in North America. Several species of macaws and cockatoos, as well as a variety of other parrots, are now maintained as self-sustaining populations, chiefl y in the private sector. Species of waterfowl, such as Ringed Teal, Hooded Mergansers, and North American Ruddy Ducks, formerly considered rarities, have now become standard features in collections. A number of pheasants once unobtainable in America can now be procured from breeders. The dream of creating a stable population of critically endangered species, then reestablishing them in the wild from captive-bred stock is being achieved with California Condors and Whooping Cranes, and appears to be on the verge of success for other birds.The role of soft-billed birds as U. S. zoo animals has changed profoundly over this period. Through 1972, when import restrictions to combat Exotic Newcastle's Disease were imposed, softbills were essentially unmanaged. When imported birds were ridiculously inexpensive and easy to replace, the expenditure of paid time spent meticulously monitoring individual specimens, maintaining their records, and providing them with the same standard of veterinary care expected for Oharismatic Megavertebratesraould be difl.cult to justify to a municipal Park and Recreation Department or a society's Board of Directors. Literally hundreds of birds might be exhibited in one aviary, quite often as single specimens, or, almost as often, as DibcksPNhen a single pair should ideally have been maintained. When breeding did take place, it was a matter of interest and congratulation, but, in most cases, the goal of predictably repeated successes, culminating in a stable population, did not exist for softbills. More often than not, as soon as one species had bred (and sometimes been written about), institutional interest might focus on the next species to do so. Thus, in 1970, when the San Diego Zoo held over a thousand taxa of birds, 34 species and subspecies of birds (mostly psittacines) were fully reared. The most successful U.S. Zoo in 1970 was St. Louis, where the total number of bird taxa fully reared was 46, while over 400 were kept there. That year, the Bronx Zoo held over 400 taxa and reared 40, Los Angeles held over 400 and reared 41, San Antonio held around 500 and reared 13, and the Lincoln Park Zoo held nearly...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-01-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3405</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 32 No. 3 (2005): Number 3  2005; 27-38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3405/3389</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
