<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/608</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-08T05:08:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Grey Peacock Pheasant at the Tracy Aviary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roles, D. Grenville</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One of the most delightful, elegant,subtly patterned and adorned of all ofthe pheasants, this beautiful creatureis deservedly popular with a widerange of aviculturalists.In the wild it is found in five differentforms from Sikkim and Bhutan inthe westernmost part of its range, tothe Island of Hainan in the east. Preferredhabitat is dense vegetation upto 4000 feet elevation.Even though it is labeled P.b. ghigi,it is impossible for me to knowwhich form is represented here atthe Aviary. The differences betweenmost forms are subtle, ranging fromgreyer in the west to browner in theeast. However it is clearly not thesmallest, brownest P.b. katsumataefrom Hainan.Although the largest of the Genus,Grey Peacock Pheasants are stillquite small birds - rather like a smallchicken with big feathers.The male is a warm grey shadedusted with tiny, paler grey spots andvermiculations and bearing jewel-likeocelli on his wings and tail, which areeither amethyst or emerald dependingupon the angle of light. His onlyother adornment is his bushy, erectilecrest. The scientific name Polyplectron(many spurred) bicalcaratum(double spurred), emphasizesthe variability of the number of spurswhich can be present on the males'legs - sometimes three on one leg,two or one on the other.Hens are much smaller, darker andwithout the colorful ocelli and spurs.For the most part they are fairlysilent birds, conversing in subdued,throaty purrs and clucks. Springtime,however, stimulates the males to callloudly and frequently with a two-partwhistle very early in the morning,which will not endear them to yourneighbors. .Our birds live in very large, plantedaviaries which they share with a greatmany other species. They havealways been well behaved and nonaggressive,giving way before smallerand feistier species. Males, however,will scrap with each other throughan adjoining fence, so a solid barrieris required if pairs are to be neighbors.We know of a number of people inthe Salt Lake area who successfullykeep and breed these birds best intheir tiny winter quarters, which canbe as small as 4' x 3' x 3' high. Photoperiodand ambient temperature aresignificant factors in those breedings,of course.They are simple and easy to maintainon a diet of gamebird pellets supplementedthree or four times aweek with tidbits of mealworms,chopped fruits, greenstuff, raw meat(hamburger) or hard-boiled egg.They should always have access toclean water and oystershell grit.Birds will breed at one year old (oreven a little less) and make excellentnatural parents. The one or twochicks which make up the clutch willfollow the hen very closely, stayingbeneath her tail for the first few daysas she moves around - and thendarting forward as she calls them totake a morsel she has found, directlyfeeding the chicks from her bill.When pulled for handrearing(which can induce the hen to multiclutch)the chicks are rather moredifficult to rear, often requiringhandfeeding and coaxing to eat at allin the first few days. Sometimes thechicks are encouraged to eat by givingthem a self-feeding companion,either a Golden Pheasant or Quailchick - depending upon what happensto hatch simultaneously. Thiscompanion usually induces thechicks to start eating, particularly ifmealworms are supplied. Typically,as the worms are dropped into thebrooder, the Quail (or Pheasant)chick will madly dash around with aworm in its beak exciting the PeacockPheasant chicks into chasingthem and attempting to snatch theworm from the other pheasant's bill(bug-mugging?), thereby learning torecognize food. They will also learnto show interest in food scratchedand picked at by the companionchick.The chicks are initially delicate anddo require heat, around 90 degrees,for the first week or so, the temperaturegradually being lowered as thechicks get older. They do requireclose observation to ensure that theyare getting enough to eat and thatthey are being kept warm enough.Chicks raised by their parents seemrobust and competent from the wordgo, and are certainly a lot easier toprovide for.As mentioned earlier, the birds canbe induced to multiclutch if theireggs are removed, and they canbreed (given heated quarters andappropriate lighting), at any time ofthe year. The male has a beautiful displayin which he will call the henover to a tidbit, picking it up anddropping it again to pique her interest,then launching into an initiallylateral then full frontal display, inwhich he places his breast on theground and partially spreads hiswings in front of his fully spread tailto display his family jewels.These birds are delightful, beautiful,readily tamed and easy to maintain.Though not quite a beginner'sbird, they can really be recommendedfor the aviculturalist of some..</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/608</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/608/591</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
