<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/533</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Recognize ... Don't Hybridize</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abramson, Joanne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the last decade, aviculture has increasingly taken a strong role in conservation.The need to maintain self-sustaining captive populations of pure species cannot be overemphasized. For genetically sound captive breeding to occur, there needs to be a significantpopulation of genetically pure parent stock and careful pairing of the chicks. Asthis article shows, hybrids create a particularly difficult concern because they havephysical traits from both parents. Several Buffon's mated with Militaries are known toexist. In the wild, macaws do not hybridize. In captivity, they are entirely dependenton our choice for a mate. Although macaws will interbreed, when given the optionthey will choose their own species. Long term pairs can and will accept new mates.They are truly beautiful creatures that are not improved by our meddling. We are allaware of habitat destruction caused by man and nature. Yet, by hybridizing, we destroytheir unique genetic material. Hybridizing has no place in responsible aviculture.Please complete the questionnaire (among the center insert sheets) so we know whatthe current status is of true Buffon's Macaws. If you need a mate for your Buffon's orhave an extra one that needs a home or mate, let us know what you are looking for andwe will try to get potential mates together. Contact: Buffon's, c/o P.O. Box 620707,Woodside, California 94062.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/533</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 35-37</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/533/517</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
