<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/909</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:18:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EDITORIAL PAGE It Seems to Me ...</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Things are changing soquickly that I'm having troublekeeping up in these bimonthlyeditorials. For several years now,the Federal Government has beenintent on heaping more and moreburdensome regulations onto thebacks of an already overburdenedpopulace. This "Big Brother" attitudehas been prevalent in everyaspect of life from taxes andhealth care to the merest keepingof a few birds in one's backyardaviary. There are a few powerfulpersons in high places who feelthey know what is best for us"little folk" whether we like it ornot. To say nothing of all the otherproblems in the world, there arethose dedicated ARFs (AnimalRights Fanatics) who have theirown agenda that they wish to imposeupon the rest of us. (Indeed,I have a dear misguided vegetarianfriend who is appalled at the highfathigh-fried ethnic diet thatprevails in our neighborhood.She'd force health food upon theneighbors for their own good ifshe knew how.) The ARFs havehad a pretty good show lately becauseso many elected officials ingovernment have had the samefeeling that they "know what'sbest" for us.Now, it seems to me, the wormhas turned. We little folk have spokenout against big governmentcradle-to-grave control of ourlives. Why in the world, whensuch control has proven a failurein every other country, do someof our leaders feel it would workhere in the U.S.A.? I don't knowjust where the new Congress willtake us, and we'll have to keepan eye on them just as we didthe previous Congress, but I getthe feeling that the current Congresswants to lighten the number of dumb, restrictive regulations that now harass the ordinary folks.We have long been in a damage control mode with regards to legislation affecting our birds. Some of you may not know it but the AF A has always been opposed to additional unnecessary and burdensome regulations. Perhaps you don't remember when (in the early 1970's) the U.S. Department of Agriculture was invading local California aviaries and ruthlessly putting all birds, exotic, pet and even endangered species into the mobile gas chambers. News photos showed piles of rare birds that had been gassed and heaped up. The government's policy of total depopulation was devastating emotionally and economically. The Exotic Newcastle's disease that touched off the murderous frenzy was eventually controlled without such drastic measures.But it was the AFA's lawsuit against USDA that finally resulted in the making of a better policy. What? You didn't know the AFA sued the Feds? And prevailed? It was the beginning of a 20 year relationship that has had its ups and downs. The past few years have been downers. It seems to me, though, that the time is now ripe for some improvement. The Feds now seem more inclined to listen to the people rather than to a few special interest groups (ARFs, if you will).One major concern right now is that the avicultural community remain united and uniform in the effort to ameliorate or eliminate lousy legislation. There are many facets of the bird fancy that may seem to be independent from one another or unconcerned about bad laws that seem to affect just the other person. There are bird fanciers who have just a few backyard birds for aesthetic pleasure; commercial breeders with huge farms who raise birds specifically to sell at a profit; pet stores that carry birds; veterinarians who have large avian practices; canary breeders; pigeon breeders and racers; ratite farmers; zoos, large and small; growers of bird seed and manufacturers of other commercial bird food; cage, wire and equipment manufacturers; the list is almost endless. All of these peo- ple depend to a degree upon a healthy bird fancy. What affects the breeder will, somewhere down the line, affect all the others involved. In truth, we are all united in the wish to see a strong, healthy bird fancy that is as prosperous for the birds as it is for the bird keepers.I know that there are a few small items of disagreement among various contingents of the fancy. What I suggest here is that we rise above these petty differences and unite in our efforts to get rid of bad legislation but also to promote professional standards within our own industry. Simple items like to hybridize or not or whether a cage is six feet long or eight should not put us at one another's throats. (Within your own club, I suppose, it is still OK to backstab and throatcut over important things like whether donuts or chocolate cakes were served, but lets keep that stuff in-house.) As far as I know, every aviculturist still has the right to operate their facility as they choose, providing they don't violate the basic humane and smuggling laws already on the books.Because the AFA has a long and productive track record fighting for and protecting the individual's rights to keep and breed birds, it has gained the prominent position in this effort. The AF A is the major grass roots avicultural organization recognized by the government as representing the interests of the bird fancy. Like it or not, the AF A has that distinction and, I might add, has earned it-often before many of you possessed even one bird. There are a number of additional clubs and societies that also represent large portions of aviculture. The wisest course suggests that these groups communicate and harmonize on the best actions to take in the effort to promote good aviculture and to get rid of the dumb, counter-productive regulations that work to the detriment of the world's birds.Take my word for it, the ARFs are reading these very words. Their aim is to divide and conquer us. If we keep a united front, we'll prevail. If we fragment, we'll fail. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/909</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 3 (1995): MAY-JUNE 1995; 48-50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/909/891</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
