<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1879</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-29T21:04:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">wayne E. Smyth</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">{J) ayne E. Smyth has been an accomplished, professional artist for more than thirty years. His workhas been exhibited in galleries all over the world. He has a wealth of experience and is highly regarded in the art community. Wayne's paintings reflect a true understanding of the birds he captures. Each one is presented in such a lifelike way, that one may think they could reach out and touch them. For the past ten years, Wayne has donated his fine artwork to the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. and its members.We all missed Wayne at last year's convention in San Francisco. Unfortunately, he had a small bone in his hand that was pressing against a nerve and was unable to attend the convention, much less paint. Luckily,his surgery was successful. Infact this year's artwork, theBearded Barbet, was the firstwork he has done since thatsurgery. This magnificentwork was created fromphotographic referencestaken at the Houston Zooand at Hill Country Aviariesin Dripping Springs, Texas.Wayne has proven year afteryear, painting after painting,that his talent is unparalleledwhen it comes to capturingbirds in watercolor. In keepingwith his continued generosity, Waynehas created exclusively for AFA this finepiece of work.In the tradition of the American Federation of Aviculture, Wayne will be present at this year's convention in Miami. For those of you attending, be sure to stop by the AFA Store booth and say hello to Wayne. Additionally, his artwork will be auctioned at the closing banquet Saturday evening. Up for auction will be a one of one signed artist's proof of the Bearded Barbets and a one of one embellished giclee print of the Bearded Barbets depicting the AFA convention theme, "TheDiversity of Aviculture". Bothpieces are museum mounted and professionally framed.Silent and absentee bids will be accepted for these two incredible items. This first time opportunity is open to everyone. Totake advantage of this unique offer, please photocopy and fill out the following bid submission (nextpage). All bids must bepostmarked by July 22, 2005. •  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1879</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 31 No. 4 (2004): Number 4 2004- Number 1 2005; 31-32</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1879/1850</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
