<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1686</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:15:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">First U.S. Breeding of the Rose-fronted (Painted) Conure? Pyrrhura picta roseifrons</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cusick, Richard</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Note: This may be a first U.S. breeding of Pyrrhura picta roseifrons. If any reader knows of an earlier breeding of this bird, please send complete information and verification to the AFA office.P yrrhura picta roseifrons, often referred to as the Rosefronted Conure, is a subspecies of the Painted Conure. At 22 cm. or 8.5 in., the Painted Conure is the smallest member of the Conure group. Like all other sub-species of the Painted Conure, the Rose-fronted is predominantly green and the sexes are similar in appearance. Once mature, the forehead, forecrown, lores, and upper cheeks are scarlet. In some cases, this bright red can extend to the nape. Juveniles show only a faint blush of red, if any at all, in these areas, with an occasional scarlet freckle peeking through.The plumage of the roseifrons' throat and upper breast is brownish, edged with buff or off white, creating a scalloped appearance. There is a rosy tinge in the upper breast that is more prominent in some individuals than in others. The ear covert, periophthalmic ring, and cere are off white or buff colored. The carpal edge and under wing coverts are green, with some red at the bend of the wing. The maroon patch, both in the center of the abdomen and extending from the lower back into the upper tail feathers is much redder than in the nominate form (Pyrrhura picta picta). The outer webs of the primaries and the primary coverts are blue. The flanks and under tail coverts are olive and the wings are slightly lighter greenas well. The tail feathers are greenish at the base of their upper surface, turning maroon. The beak is grayish, while the legs and feet are grayish black.This beautifully colored jewel is found only in northeastern Brazil, near the upper Jurua River and possibly northern Peru. The Rose-fronted Conure seems to be common within its limited range.There are currently two co-operative breeding programs under the supervision of the USFWS. Both are approved to import a number of Pyrrbura species, including Pyrrhura picta roseifrons. It was as a member of one of these consortiums that I had the great opportunity to import 29 Rose-fronted Conures. After completing all of the necessary paperwork and agreeing to a deal with a breeder from the Netherlands, the 29 birds finally arrived in Los Angeles, CA on May, 18, 2000.The birds were immediately transported to a quarantine station in San Ysidro, CA, where they spent the next 30 days. Because of the fine care the birds received in this station, all 29 birds made it through this ordeal in great shape.On the 19th of June, I picked them up and brought them home. I was excited to see this species for the first time and couldn't wait to let them out of their boxes and into the quarantine cages I had set up for them. I'm sure they didn't like it, but after getting them into cages and making sure they all had food and water, I just stood and stared at them until it was too dark to make out their shapes. They were more beautiful than I had imagined.After another 60 day quarantine period, during which I re-sexed the birds, tested them for virus and simply watched their behavior, the birds I intended to keep were taken to their permanent breeding cages. Each pair was separated into its own 2'X 2'X 4' cage, hung side by side and suspended 4.5' above the ground under an aluminum pipe style greenhouse. The greenhouse is 70 feet long and houses several other other species of Pyrrhura. The roof of the greenhouse is rounded and covered with fiberglass sheeting and shade cloth.The roseifrons pairs are separated with a visual barrier that blocks only the front half of each cage. This provides the birds privacy when eating or entering the nest box - which is hung on the front of each cage - but allows them to socialize and squabble with their neighbors at the back of each cage, which I feel is important behavior for a social, f1ock-type parrot. Behind each cage there is a mister that I turn on for long periods, during hot weather, to cool the environment or for their 15 minute shower time every other day.The nestbox I use for all of my Pyrrhura Conures is 16" tall, 10" wide and 8" front to back. The boxes are built out of 3/4" plywood and the dimensions stated are outside dimensions. The entrance hole is 2.5" in diameter and is located at the top, right hand side of the box.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1686</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 1 (2002): Fourth Quarter 2001; 36-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1686/1663</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
