<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/717</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Convention '93 Salt Lake City</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">People, including your humble servant,are creatures of habit and accustomedto routine. My troubles beganwhen I left my downtown Los Angeleshome to attend the AFA's 19th AnnualConvention in Salt Lake City, Utah.As the plane crested the ring ofjagged mountains and dipped into theGreat Salt Lake Valley, I knew somethingwas wrong. The sky was blue.Really blue blue, with a scattering ofsnow white clouds. The air was crystalclear.When I debarked and tried tobreathe, I panicked. I couldn't see theair nor feel it. Perhaps Utah doesn 'thave air. I'll die.Well, I didn't die but the invisible airwas not easy to get used to. Fortunately,the van from the hotel arrivedand took us aboard. On the plane, mytravelling companio ns had banishedme to a distant seat and asked me toact as though we didn 't know oneanother- they do this routinely -but the van was small and cozyenough that we three , Aletta Long,Jean Hessler and myself, arrived at theconvention as a group. The others on group- naturally.The Little America Hotel, I mustadmit, was a very pleasant and comfortableplace to stay. The ambiencewas a mixture of comfott and modestluxury situated in an almost park-likeenvironment. It was a very enjoyableexperience to walk about the groundsamidst the intense colors, greens andblues for the trees (yes, folks, bluetrees) and the brilliant red, yellow andpink of the flowers . And an unlookedfor blessing was that of being able tomeander freely about the grounds andsu rrounding neighborhood without athought of getting mugged or havingto dodge the drive-by shooters. Capitalfolks , those denizens of Utah.Inside the hotel , a friendly, homeyatmosphere prevailed and promoted arelaxed sense of ease and comfort.The convention meeting rooms, largeauditorium , banquet hall and commercialdisplays were very convenientlylaid out in close proximity sothat it was quite easy to get fromattraction to attraction.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/717</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 58-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/717/700</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
