<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1779</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:14:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Cuban Macaw, A Work of Art by Wayne Smyth</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jordan, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">K nown only from preserved skins, Ara tricolor, or the Cuban Macaw was last reported alive in 1864. Over the past few decades, several artists have presented their rendition of Cuban Macaw as the subject of their talents and work. In his latest work, Wayne Smyth has captured the brilliant colors and sleek body form of this extinct subject. He has used his knowledge of birds, and his incredible talent as an artist to add lifelike expressions to his paintings that bring this species back from extinction and into view for art collectors and bird lovers alike. even if only on paper.Wayne has donated these two recent pieces of art depicting the Cuban Macaw to the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc." and its members. He has recreated this incredible bird from slides and photographs of the almost 100 year old skins now maintained at the Smithsonian Institute in Washington, D.C. Wayne's unrivaled talent is reflected in these two pieces and they are sure to send a chill up the spine of any ornithologist or aviculturist that sees them.Be sure to attend the AFA convention this year in Tampa where these two breathtaking pieces of art will be on display and will later be auctioned off to benefit a viculture through the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1779</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 2 (2002): Second Quarter 2002; 28</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1779/1754</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
