<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1146</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:31:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Cape Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Natural History(Dale R. Thompson)T he Cape Parrot is the largest representative of the Poicepbalus parrots in Africa and there are three subspecies, two being found in South Africa. The smaller P robustus robustus is endemic to Eastern Cape and Natal where it can be found in the high altitude forests which is dominated by Yellow Wood or Podocarpus trees. The larger subspecies, P r. suabelicus is only found in the northern parts of the country which has much drier forests.The nominate race is by far the rarest in captivity and is seldom kept. This subspecies is different from the other subspecies in that it has a much browner head. The other two subspecies, P r. suahelicus and P r. fuscicollis are distinguished by a gray head coloration. The race suahelicus is the most common subspecies found in captivity. Both the fuscicollis and suabelicus subspecies are sexually dimorphic in their adult plumage. The female is more colorful with her forehead up to the crown being orange in coloration. Immature Capes are similar to the adult female having the orange head coloration but during the first molt the maturing males will lose this coloration.Cape Parrots are noted for their large oversized heads and beaks. Males usually have a larger beak than the females and this can even be observed when immature. This large beak of the Cape Parrot is very powerful, especially because of its very curved upper mandible descending to a narrow tip and powerful lower mandible used as an anvil. Cape Parrots should always be given branches of trees or even timber to chew on and they will destroy this material with great efficiency.Wild-caught birds can have a very shy and nervous temperament and this should be considered when placing this bird in a captive breeding situation. Well sheltered aviaries assist in giving this parrot a sense of security, and having the nest entrance area dark will enhance this feeling. I personally use the L-shaped cage for this species as I do with many of my wild-caught Greys. The front foot portion of the Lshaped cage is completely divided off on the outside with plywood partitions and this is where I place their nest box.It seems that the great lack of females in captivity is the norm and this may be part of the reason that this species in not well reproduced in captivity. Rosemary Low relates in her writings (Avizundum, Dec. 1996/Jan. 1997) that she came across a reference to Cape Parrots in The Gambia. Hans Anderssen 0984), who had lived in West Africa for 16 years, sometimes found dead fuscicollis beneath the roosting trees. They were nearly all females. He carried out autopsies on them and noted that they all "had a very badly infected ovary and oviduct and the spleen was black and enlarged on all." Could this be possible with the other subspecies as well?Due to the destruction of their native habitat, the populations of Cape Parrots are declining on a whole. There are, however, several areas where they are still fairly common. Due to farming and forestry practices, large areas of indigenous forests have been cleared or have been replaced with non-indigenous trees which do not give the parrots the nesting sites and food supplies they need. This leaves great gaps in the forests which forces the parrots to fly great distances between indigenous forest for food sources. This is especially true during nesting times in which the parent birds may have to fly to far distant new forests to satisfy the feeding needs of their growing progeny. There are still some inaccessible forest where P r. robustus exist is some numbers.It is P r. suabelicus which has really suffered from the destruction of its habitat and from the demand for captive birds.It has been found that handfed Capes do have some excellent pet qualities. But keeping this species as pets should not be encouraged as the captive populations of the Cape Parrot are extremely low in their numbers. Young Capes should be held back as future breeders, especially the females. If this is not done, this species may easily disappear.Cape Parrots are similar to the African Grey Parrot in voice and behavior. Male Cape Parrots will often drop their wings during courtship as do male Greys. When frightened, both birds will make a growling sound and try to get away and hide. Both the African Grey and the Cape Parrot have pleasant sounding voices when not disturbed and will often make melodious whistling sounds (especially in the evening).The diet given to Cape Parrots should consist of seeds and nuts, fruits and vegetables and any type of the "soft-type" of food diets. They are similar to the African Grey Parrot in their high Vitamin A requirement. This will assist in eliminating recurring upper respiratory infections, sinusitis and sinus abscesses. In fact, this is important for all Poicephalus species. Rosemary Low found Capes need a fairly high fat diet but sunflower and nuts can fill this need. Capes are especially fond of pine nuts. While she was at Palmitos park, Low found that orange was their favorite fruit and she fed the fruit of the Arecastrum palms which were oily and orange in color. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1146</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 3 (1997): MAY-JUNE 1997; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1146/1125</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
