<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/707</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Society Finch A Bounty for Beginners</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weedn, Lisa</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">You're in a pet store and find yourselfstaring, fascinated by the activitycreated by a group of brown andwhite little birds in a little wire cage.The longer you watch, the more youconvince yourself these would begreat little birds to add to your domesticdwelling. Well, may I say- goodchoice! And w ith a little care, thesesmall birds will bring you hours ofavian enjoyment.The Society (or Bengalese) Finchhas a long history behind it. Believedto have been bred first in China, thenintroduced to Japan, this totallydomesticated bird has been cared forfor over 250 years. It is a small bird,about 10 em (4 inches) in size. Colorvarieties include very dark browns(chocolates), cinnamon (fawns) andwhite. Solid colors are called "selfs."Birds with a mix of white and variousshades of brown are called "pied";chocolate-pied and fawn-pied. Notwo patterns are alike and may help todistinguish individuals. Males andfemales appear identical and cannotbe visually sexed. Bengalese Finchesare sexed by their behaviors. Gainingmaturity at about nine months, maleswill sing, hop about with bodyfeathers fluffed and neck stretched,head lowered and bouncing, or displayingwith grass or nesting materialin their bills. Females do none of thesebehaviors. The only sound they makeis a slight buzzing or humming sound.Upon discovering these, try to makenote of the color patterns of each birdto form your pairs.·society Finches are year-aroundbreeders, but it is recommended thatyou allow only three clutches per yearwith a one-and-one-half months restbetween clutches to prevent overtaxingthe birds' reproductive system.Ideally, breeders should be kept insingle pairs, in individual cages; but inlarger aviaries pairs may be successfullyhoused with other small finch species such as Zebras, Cut-throats orGouldians with no ill effect.Single pair cages should measure35.5 X 35.5 X 60 em (15" X 15" X 24")with 3/8" to 1/2" wire mesh spacing.Any larger mesh and the birds couldpossibly escape. The cage should belonger rather than taller, to provideadequate flying as they fly horizontallyrather than vertically. Provide varioussized diameter perching to keepfeet in good condition. Small cleantree or shrub branches may be used.Keep perching clean of fecal build-up.In an aviary, you might consider addingpotted bushes or trees along withthe perching for privacy. Artificialnests provided can be the finch wickerwoven baskets found in most petstores or a simple cardboard orwooden covered 4-1/2" square box with upper front open for access.Place nests in upper corners or midheight in cages. In aviaries, hang several at different heights. When adding  nests, don't forget to provide nesting material or the b irds may try to use their food for material, causing thenests to foul quickly. Materials utilizedare hay, washed and dried grass, horsehairnest material (sold in stores),burlap pulled apart and cut, or evendryer lint- it's been already sterilized!Interest in the material may takeplace as soon as it's added, with malesbeing the nest builders.Within a short time after a completednest, a mature, bonded pair willstart egg production. A completedclutch is usually four to eight eggswith the average being five smallwhite eggs. Incubation is sharedbetween the male and the female andlasts 12 to 14 days. Society Finches arevery devoted parents so your inspectionof the chicks will not disrupt theirparental care. The chicks fledge inabout three to four weeks, but chickswill continue to beg for one to twoweeks after fledging.Basic diet for Society Finches is simple- millet, vitamins, minerals,greens and water. Seeds that are eateninclude canary, rape, poppy, flax ,niger, hulled oats or commercial finchmix. You should check to confirmseeds are fresh by sprouting a smallsample . Soak the seed and, in two tothree clays, sprouts should appear.The sprouted sample may then be fedto the finches. A 75% sprouting indicatesseeds are fresh. Afterward,sprouts may be fed to birds, but allowno mold to form. Finches do not eatthe whole grain of a seed, but crackanct dist~n·d the outer husk, leavingthe chaff, so it is always wise to blowon a dish filled with seed to removeuneaten parts. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/707</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 29-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/707/690</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
