<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3658</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-26T04:33:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Teamwork Works in New Hampshire</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wall, Genny</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This winter AFA's legislative team had a positive result in the state of New Hampshire. Last year a bill was signed in New Hampshire which inserted the word "bird" into the existing dog and cat law regarding selling pets. Unfortunately, that bill had unintended consequences for bird sellers and owners which needed to be corrected.APA legislative team members Concetta Ferragamo, Rick Jordan, Mark Moore, and Genny Wall worked with APA members Alan Fox, Ray Schwartz, Dave Smith, and several others in New Hampshire to get the necessary correction made into law. The team supported the efforts of Jeanine Notter, New Hampshire House Representative, who was willing to sponsor a new bill, New Hampshire HB 1367, to remove the word "bird" from the existing law. AFA's legislative team members assembled information to support HB 1367, and APA provided a detailed letter explaining why birds should be exempt from certain provisions regarding the sale and transfer of animals. You can read AFA's letter below.George Messenger, DVM, APA New Hampshire State Coordinator, met with the New Hampshire State Veterinarian, Dr. Crawford, and got his support for the bill. Dr. Messenger also testified before the Environment and Agriculture committee and used the APA letter in this testimony. Dr Messenger was successful in convincing the legislators to remove birds from the language of the law, and the bill passed out of the committee with a unanimous vote in favor.At the time of this writing, the New Hampshire legislature is still in session and the bill has not been signed by the Governor of New Hampshire; but we're optimistic that it will be signed into law.Our experience working with bird owners in New Hampshire to protect their ability to continue to keep, breed, and sell birds was very rewarding and encouraging. Keep up the good work! Dear Ms. Notter,The American Federation of Aviculture (AFA) (see footnote 1) supports New Hampshire HB 1367, and we request that you, and all members of the New Hampshire legislature, consider the following information regarding birds, as well as the following discussion of the specific provisions of HB 1367 and the effect that passage of HB 1367 will have upon bird breeders, sellers, and the economy of New Hampshire, when you vote on HB 1367. We request that you share our letter with your co-sponsors of HB 1367 and with other New Hampshire legislators who will consider and vote on HB 1367.New Hampshire HE 1367 is intended to correct the unintended consequence of the 2013 passage of HB-328-FN In an effort to ensure that birds sold as pets were healthy, the word "bird" was inserted into HB-328-FN Unfortunately, in 2013, because of a lack of information on, or understanding of the nature of the many species of" birds", the legislators'good intentions resulted in a completely unanticipated and untenable situation when applied to the sale of pet birds in New Hampshire. In fact, the requirements of HB-328-FN impose unacceptable burdens on those who breed and sell pet birds in the State, and if left in place, will ultimately eliminate the humane breeding and selling of birds as pets in the State.GENERAL COMMENTS ON THE SIGNIFICANT DIFFERENCES BETWEEN BIRDS AND DOGS, CATS, AND OTHER MAMMALS:1. Birds Are Not Like DogJ and Cats and Other Mammals 1hat Are Keptas PetsBirds that are sold as pets cannot be compared to dogs cats and other small mammals that are sold as pets. All pet "breeds" of dogs are members of one species (canis familiaris). All pet "breeds" of cats are members one species (felis domesticus). 1he other small mammals that are sold as pets are members of only a few species of mammal.Because each of these mammals is essentially similar to the others within its' own species, all of these mammals can be cared far and can thrive when provided with a relatively well known range of acceptable physical conditions, nutritional requirements, and veterinary care. For example, all dogs and cats are carnivores and eat meat. Some of the other small mammals are herbivores and eat a plant based diet. All of these mammals are insulated by fur, and can survive and can thrive in a relatively broad range of temperatures similar to those acceptable to humans. All of these mammals need a certain amount of exercise. When their nutritional, husbandry, veterinary, and social needs are met, each of these mammals can thrive in a pet setting.In contrast, there are more than 9000 separate and distinct species of birds. Each species of bird has its own distinct physical characteristics, as well as separate and distinct nutritional, habitat, and veterinary needs (when veterinarians are available who see and treat birds). When kept as pets, each species of bird has its own husbandry and care requirements. 1here is no "one-size-fits-all" when it comes to birds (other than they all have feathers).2. Each Unique Species o,,fBird Has Its Own Species Specific Requirements1he thousands of species of birds have evolved over millenia to survive in the wild in very specific and different habitat conditions. Each species has developed particular physical characteristics and specific nutritional requirements that enable that particular species to survive in its' own particular habitat. Some birds live in tropical jungles (for example, some parrots). Some birds live grassy plains (for example, the budgerigar, commonly known as the "parakeet"). Some birds live in deserts (for example, the ostrich). Some birds live in high altitudes (for example, the andean condor). Some birds can live in the snow (for example, the Kea, a type of parrot, and many North American birds). Some birds live on or near the water (for example, pelicans, seagulls, ducks, and geese). Some birds eat grain (for example, the budgerigar). Some birds eat fruit (for example, parrots and toucans). Some birds eat insects (for example, some of the finches). Some birds eat meat (for example, vultures and some cockatoos). Some birds live their entire lives in a very small area (for example, some hummingbirds). Some birds travel very long distances in search of food (for example, other hummingbirds, some parrots). 1hese attributes, which were developed to enable each species to survive under diverse natural conditions, dictate the conditions that are required to keep any particular species of bird in captivity. 1here is no one-size-fits- all husbandry requirement far birds. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3658</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 1&amp;2 (2014): Number 1&amp;2  2014; 30-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3658/3641</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
