<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2175</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-15T06:26:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Canary Culture-the Pearl Canary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bucci, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">For the past ten years, there have been rumors of a new canary. Bird related publications in Europe have mentioned on many occasions the possibility of creating this new canary called ''Pearl.'' The book, ''Coloured Canaries" by G.B.R. Walker, which contains pictures and descriptions of color canaries, is one of the best reference books to date for the color breeder. It contains a chapter dedicated to the possibilities and hypothetical expectations of creating the Pearl canary.The idea of the Pearl canary had a great appeal to me, and instead of waiting for it, I decided to go after it myself. So for the past four years, I have devoted part of my breeding space and time toward the creation of the Pearl canary. My efforts paid off; the 1982 breeding season produced three Pearls and several valuable combination carriers of Satinette and Lizard.The Pearl canary is a cross of a Satinette and a Lizard canary. The two mutations combine into one to produce a very interesting effect. The end result is a red-eye Satinette with a Lizard pattern.In order to create this interesting canary, several years of selective breeding is necessary. Also, it requires some basic knowledge of genetics (mainly the concept of Mendelian ratios), some luck and, most of all, perseverance and pauence.The Satinette mutation is sex-linked recessive. Effects of the mutation are the disappearance of black eumelanin and brown phaeomelanin within the feather pigment. The black eumelanin is the black melanin located down the center of the feather and on the under-feather in green canaries. The brown phaeomelanin is the brown melanin located on the edges and tip of the feather in self canaries. Another feature of the Satinette canary is its distinct red eyes.Brown and Isabel Satinettes exhibit brown striations. The Green and Agate do not. Therefore, Green and Agate are not suited for the making of the Pearl canary. Only brown and Isabel Satinettes should be used to have the best results.The Lizard mutation is autosornal recessive. The effect of the Lizard mutation is an unusual pattern which breaks up the continuity of the striations giving a scale-like effect. The clear cap which the Lizard canary normally carries is not part of the mutation. The clear cap is varigation affixed on its head by selective breeding.The combination of the two mutations can be accomplished with several different matings. My first matings produced many varigated offsprings. The varigated birds were a result of the Lizard's cap. For example, mating a male Lizard to a brown Satinette hen will produce all male and female carriers of Lizard. Only the males will also be carriers of Brown and Satinette. All of these carriers are phenotypically Green. Most of them will be varigated. Only males will be useful for the program of producing Pearls.If not varigated , the hens could be used to introduce new blood to the Lizard stock. Lizard canaries are noted to be weak birds. Other recessive mutations, such as Inos and recessive White canaries, are more vigorous when bred with carriers. I assume the same applies to the Lizard mutation.A Green hen/ carrier of Lizard mated to a normal Lizard will produce 50% Lizards and 50% Green/carriers of Lizard. The Green male I carriers of Lizard, Brown and Satinetre, provided that they are not varigated, will be mated to a Lizard hen. Theoretically, this mating has the probability of producing a Pearl canary hen. In the next year, the Pearl hen can be mated to her father to produce a male Pearl.There is a faster road to produce a Pearl, provided that you have a male Brown Satinette. Mating this Satinette to a Lizard hen will produce 50% Green males/ carriers of Lizard, Brown and Satinette , and 50 % Brown Satinette hens/ carriers of Lizard. This mating produced the ingredients to create the Pearl. In the next year, mating brother with sister will produce the Pearl. Mating a brother with a sister is not as bad as some breeders claim it to be. However, if we are to continue breeding the Pearl canary as a new breed, we must take two or three separate roads. By having two or three unrelated lines, we can improve the breed's quality and have more vigorous birds to work with. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2175</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 10 No. 3 (1983): JUNE-JULY 1983; 38-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2175/2149</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
