<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/429</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-19T03:10:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS: Smuggler Goes to Jail</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In San Diego today, the Honorable Earl B. Gilliam sentencedVirginia Vidrio to a 30-month term of imprisonmentfor her role in a scheme to smuggle over $25,000 worth ofexotic psittacine birds into the United States from Mexico.United States Attorney Peter K. Nunez stated thatVirginia Vidrio, the owner and operator of Vicky's PetShop in Bell, California, a shop which specializes in exoticbirds, was found guilty after a jury trial. Vidrio wasconvicted of one count of conspiracy to smuggle baby yellow-naped Amazon parrots and military macaws; onecount of aiding and abetting the smuggling of twenty babyyellow-naped Amazon parrots; and one count of aiding andabetting the smuggling of three military macaws.According to the evidence introduced by the Governmentat the trial, Vidrio would order the exotic parrots fromsuppliers in Tijuana and then pay" runners" to smuggle thebirds across the border. Vidrio herself was apprehended atthe furt of Entry, San Ysidro, California, on April1981 afterseven yellow-naped parrots were found to be concealedunderneath the rear seat of the automobile which she wasdriving.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/429</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 4 (1988): AUG-SEPT 1988; 50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/429/2619</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
