<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/563</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Red--headed Parrot Finch</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McCulloch, Jane</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Parrot Finches belong to the familyEstrildidae and are distributedthrough a rather small range in theIndo Pacific region. There are 11species of parrot finch, but most ofmy experience has been with theRed-headed Parrot Finch, Erythrurapsittacea, found only in New Caledoniaand neighboring islands in thePacific. New Caledonia has thewarm, moist climate of a tropical rainforest and the plant material is richand varied. The Red-headed ParrotFinch is not a grassland bird, butenjoys a forest habitat where itforages for herbaceous seeds, fruitsand insects.The Red-headed Parrot Finch has abeautiful color scheme with the headand throat being bright red, the bodybright green and the rump and uppertail coverts red also. The female's redparts are usually less extensive andless bright when compared with themale's. The throat color of a breedinghen is a softer red than in the male.The females usually have less red onthe forehead and it does not extendas high on the crown. However,there is a great deal of individual variationin my pairs. I have proven henswith little or no red above the eyeand other proven hens with redextending well above the eye, makingsexing difficult. The young arecolor-banded according to heritagefor this reason.The fledglings are a dull greencolor, but easier to sex than theadults. The males have a smudge ofyellow-orange on the throat whilethe hens are just a lighter green coloron the throat. The age of the birdshas a great deal to do with the successfulsexing of the parrot finch. Ibelieve the hens color up faster thanthe males and at three to four monthsof age, the hens will appear to bebrighter in color. The males, by thistime, will be singing their lovely, longtrills at dusk if there are other parrotfinches within hearing distance toimpress.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/563</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 20-21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/563/546</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
