<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/865</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:17:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Impressions of the AFA's 1994 Convention</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hyde, Graeme</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">InAugustofthis year l wasoneofthreeAu ti·a lian aviculrurists who attendedthe American Federation of Aviculture's20th Annual Convention in Knoxville,Tennessee.As l had attended each of the sevenAustralian AFA conven~ i ons 0 980 to1994) l was looking forward toKn o&amp;gt;.'v ille with grea t anticipation becausesuch events bring together a diverseand inte resting group ofaviculturists. This was certainly a featureof the Kn o&amp;gt;.'V ille conve ntio n.The Australians - Bany Hutchins,Ruby Hutchins, Warwick Re mingtonand l - were most impressed with thewelcome by members of the Tennesseealley Exotic Bird Club upon our arrivalin Knol\'V ill e. This warmth and friendhipwas a highlight of the conventionand certai nly made us feel '·at home" intheThe conve ntion was we ll planned,the range of speake rs were as diver asthey were inte resting, and the theme'·Down Under and Out of Afri ca" was thecatalyst for the sharing of a lot of usefulavicultural info rmation by all rhe speakers.The trade exhibit was, for the Australians,an eye-o pener into the wayavicultureand the pet bird marker is cater dfor in the US. lt enabled us to ee speciesthat are not ava ilable in our own countryand that, in itself, was most interesting.We prefer the American system ofs heduling only o ne sp aker at a time .The Australian system of having twospeakers both speaking at the same time(in different lecture rooms) means thatdelegates cannot always attend theirpreferred lectures.We missed the mid-morning andmid-afternoon coffee breaks that are afeature of Australian conventio nswhich , apart from providing refreshment,enable the mixing and minglingof both delegates and speakers. We observedwith interest rhat most of the conventionoffi cials \Vere women, inAustralia the reverse applies.Contracting the speakers to illu stratethe ir lectures with color slide , and havinga theme for the convention , werenotable aspects of the conve ntion planning.From Australia to Knol\'V ille, Tennessee,is a lo ng way to attend an aviculturalconvention, but it was well wonh the effort involved'(Editor's Note: Craeme Hyde,aLong witb Barry Hutchins and W'arwickRemington, was one of three AustraLiansinvited to speak at Ibis AFAconvention)</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/865</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 1 (1995): JAN-FEB 1995; 46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/865/847</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
