<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/679</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Stories From Red Siskin Project Breeders (The first in a series)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Colwell, Gail Gatewood</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The BeginningIf you had told me a few years agoth at I would be living in the samehouse with a flock of VenezuelanBlack-hooded Red Siskins, I wouldhave told you to dream on! Like manyof you, I have loved birds all my life.My love for birds took the form offeeding wild birds in the winter,donating money to good " birdcauses," and bird-watching. As a fulltimepsychologist, I was never sho11 ofprofessional challenges, and my husbandand I shared a full assortment ofhobbies and social interests. Accordingly,I really didn 't think I had thetime or energy to invest in any additionalbird-related activities.Five years ago, I bought a "pet" parrot... for all the wrong reasons , Imight add. He had a long, pretty tail ;he hopped and danced; he said,"Hello Ricky" in the cutest voice I hadever heard. Thus began my educationin the world of aviculture and birdkeeping.I soon found out what complex,demanding, majestic creaturesthey are. I also began to learn of theabuses and misuses of birds in thename of bird-keeping. My husbandand I began to question the extent towhich it is ethical to cage birds . . .ever.Ironically, our thoughts were followingtwo divergent courses duringthis period of our enlightenment. Wewere increasingly disillusioned with bird-keeping, yet we had acqu iredanother parrot and some canaries.Our bird family now consisted of theoriginal Patagonian Conure, Ricky(the talkat ive, boi terous bird whom Ioften charge with starting this wholething!) ; a Yellow-headed Amazon,Tara (who, at eight years of age,remains the most sweet-tempered parrotI have ever known); and canaries(most were Fife Fancy canaries, plusassorted "mutts"). On one hand, weloved keeping birds; on the other, wehad serious ethical questions aboutthe whole issue. We were in search ofsome kind of resolution of these twopositions.Getting Involved!Enter the AFA! We began readingthe Watchbird in 1990, and it seemedthat there might be kindred souls outthere somewhere. We didn't agreewith eve1ything we saw in the Watchbird,but we agreed with more of itscontents than thuse of other popularbird-keeping magazines by a longshot. Then we encountered some articlesabout the Red Siskin Project.The program gave full recognitio n tothe damage clone to this species bythe pet trade. The project had a plan tocorrect that damage.For those of you who could use abrief overview of the program, I willdescribe it. The project seeks to establisha genetically-diverse captivebreeding population of these beautifullittle birds, with the eventual goal ofreintroduction into protected habitat.A network of breeders across thecountry (and someday, around theworld, perhaps) are now buildingnumbers of these birds, slowly butsu rely. Meanwhile, the project director,Kevin Gorman, is exploring politi- cal, financial, and logistical dynamicsfor obtaining protected habitat. Captive-bred Siskins may someday beused to satisfy bird-keeping demandssuch that smuggling will not be necessary;hence, the pressure will be takenoff the remaining wild birds. It is estimatedthat only a few hundred breedingpairs may be left in their nativehabitat (Venezuela). The project seeksparticipation at several levels, includingfund-raising, program organization,and actual breeding.We were a little nervous about gettinginvolved in the project .. . wewondered if the director would beinterested in relatively inexperiencedaviculturists like us. We decided to bebrave and apply for membership inthe project and let the director decidehow we might best contribute. To ourrelief, Director Kevin Gorman waswarm and encouraging . Kevinexplained to us that pa1ticipation wasneeded at many levels. He firstinvolved us in various organizationaland clerical activities.In 1991 , I accepted the position ofpromotional director. Kevin assuredme that I could be of help to the projectin this way, so I decided to try it.Promotional goals, in general, includedbringing the project to the public'satten tio n, generating funds, andacquiring sponsors for the project'swork. In my tenure as promotionaldirector, we completed a massive mailoutcampaign to bird clubs aroundthe world, acquired various commercialand club sponsorships, and gotsome publicity in high-profile nationalbird magazines. Yvonne Patterson hassince succeeded me as promotionaldirector and has brought national andgrass-roots publicity to the project.The Siskins Are Coming!The next big step came when it wastime for us to have siskins! We hadbeen given specific written and verbalinstructions about preparations fortheir housing and care. Completebreeding instructions were also provided.Through Kevin's networking,we purchased two pairs and weregiven custody of three pairs of projectownedsiskins. We picked up all tenbirds (in a breadbox-sized cardboardbox) one evening at the airport. Wewere terribly nervous as we drovehome. I had the box in my lap, andthe little birds dashed themselvesagainst the box and each other in aterrifying "popcorn-like" fashion.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/679</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 17-18</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/679/662</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
