<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2575</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-16T21:48:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The International Loriidae Society</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, Phyllis K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Remember back to the August 1981 AFA convention held in San Diego, California. At this time, a group of 40 lory enthusiasts decided to form a Lory Society. The time was ripe for the formation of such a club because the last decade had seen unprecedented developments concerning the importation of lories and lorikeets.During the 1970s, the European and American bird markets received an influx of lories from Indonesia and New Guinea. Unfortunately, many of these birds ended up in pet stores and were sold as pets as there were far more lories on the market than could be consumed by dedicated aviculturis ts. Many of the rarely imported species of lories were passed on to the pet trade during this time and, being too widely distributed, comparatively few aviary-bred strains were established. Sadly, other birds perished as the pet owner was unable to devote the time to care for these birds properly.Members of the Lory Society felt it was vital that the maximum use was made of existing Jory stocks and, by forming the society, they would have direct contact between Jory breeders.The fist year of the Lory Society showed promise and at year's end the society had 130 members from 37 states, England, Canada, Australia, five European and one south African country (plus six zoos) with over 1, 200 lories registered on the census. During 1983, the Society showed a decline in activity and limped along until January 1985. At this time, the society was revamped and the members adopted the name "The International Lcriidae Society (ILS)'.' The International Loriidae Society's goals were reaffirmed as follows:1. To the building of selfsustaining captive bred populations of all the Loriidae species possible,2. To disseminate avicultural and scientific information on the family Loriidae to all the members, and other interested parties through the newsletter (which is sent to members four times a year),3. To take an annual census of the captive population of the family Loriidae,4. To assist, where possible, the preservation of the family Loriidae in the wild.Since 1985, the membership has continued to increase; information about breeding lories, housing, diets and diseases affecting lories is published in the quarterly newsletter; the society has an annual meeting of members during AFA's convention; an annual census is taken and results published in the newsletter yearly; and stud books have been set up for many species of lories. As with other societies, articles are always in demand.During 1986, ILS had 60% of their membership reporting on the census indicating 667 pairs of birds in captivity with 576 young being produced. However, in 1987 the census figures were down with one species showing a reduction of 25 pairs in captivity. Did birds die, did members lose interest and not report, did people sell their birds to non-members who did not report, or did the ILS fail to keep the members' interest?Late in 1988, the ILS reorganized with new officers being elected. Fresh ideas emerged and interest again grew in the lory society. With the threat of bird importation coming to a close, ILS is working harder to reach lory owners and obtain husbandry data on all species of lories and lorikeets in captivity and in the wild. We urge participation in the annual census and the stud books, ask that each person raising lories close band all offspring and keep accurate breeding data, and strongly oppose the hybridization of lory species.Dues are $ 12 per year. For further information, contact Sharon Casmier, secretary/treasurer, ILS, 17704 S. Tapps Drive East, Sumner, WA 98390.• </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2575</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 5 (1990): OCT- NOV 1990; 43-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2575/2545</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
