<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2058</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-29T05:29:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From The Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dear Editor:Everywhere today in aviculrure you hear people talking about exotic birds becoming endangered due to man's encroachment into their native habitats. This is a problem and we aviculturists should be concerned. But why are we concerned with only the foreign birds? What about our own native American birds? Why aren't we doing something to protect their future in this country? Already the blue bird population is considerably smaller than it was and the many beautiful buntings are decreasing in numbers also. What are we waiting for!Are we all just sitting back waiting to say of another bird, "Well, we did have it but it has gone to be with the Carolina parakeet. What happened?" If so, I think it is time for the A.FA., the strongest avicultural group in the nation, to start doing something about it before it is too late.Some years ago a program was initiated in England that allowed any aviculrurisr who chose to do so to keep two pairs of each species of native birds. The babies had to be closed banded to distinguish them from the wild caught birds. Many of the captive raised birds are released into the wild and, of course, it is illegal to buy or sell them. This system allows the truly dedicated aviculturist to engage in an altruistic activity that benefits the native birds.Why couldn't the A.FA. Conservation Committee study this idea and make some recommendations to the federal government? I recently visited Missouri and in two weeks didn't see one bluebird. They used to be so plentiful there. Wake up, people! I'd hate to hear someone say, "There used to be a beautiful red bird in this area but now I don't see it anymore. Where has the Virginia cardinal gone?" Remember, extinction is forever.John AgrellaLakeside, California My dear fellow, having grown up in England you probably don't realize how callously the Americans have traditionally treated all native American species. After all, those cowboy and Indian games were not for fun-they were for keeps. If the Americans could endorse a policy that nearly exterminated the native Amen.can humans, how much hope do you hold for the birds?I like your ideas and your deep concern for our native birds and endorse wholeheartedly your thought that the A.FA. Conservation Committee address the problems. I should like to see Frank Todd (or another equally radical and knowledgeable person-if there is one) chair the Conservation Committee. That would guarantee some action for sure. A strong, active Conservation Committee could be one of the A.FA. 'r most important contributions to the world. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2058</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 6 (1981): DEC-JAN 1981; 30-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2058/2029</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
