<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/697</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Diamond Doves Pleasant Additions to any Aviary (Geopalia cuneata)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vigran, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Native to Australia, Diamond Doves(Geopalia cuneata) have become adomesticated species in the U.S. andEurope. Perhaps it is due to theiradaptability in the wild (DiamondDoves live throughout most of Australia)that has made them such a hardyspecies for aviculturists to work with.Diamond Doves can be housed inflights or cages. Cages should be amini'mum of three feet in length toallow for flying room. DiamondDoves can be kept with a variety ofother species such as finches, budgies,cockatiels and grasskeets. In fact,Diamond Doves can be housed withany species that will not harm them.For breeding, Diamond Dove pairsshould be kept separately. Becausethey build such flimsy nests, nests caneasily be destroyed resulting inbroken eggs or loss of babies. MaleDiamond Doves can be aggressive tonests other than their own.Diamond Doves seem to preferopen cup-type nests to woodenbottomed, but can be found nestingalmost anywhere, even in their seedcups. Most Diamond Doves will tolerateyour firming up their nests a bitwhen necessary. They nest off theground anywhere from three feetupward. Once a pair has chosen a site,it is almost impossible to get them tochange it.Two white eggs are laid (rarelythree) and incubation, done by bothmale and female, lasts 15 days. Thechicks should hatch a day or so apart,giving the older chick an advantage atSlllvival.The young fledge in approximately15 days and will usually remain on theground for a day or so. Sometimes theparents will become attentive to onlythe o lder fledged chick, neglectingfeeding the younger one in the nest.Some breeders will either retum ·theolder chick to the nest for a day or soor remove the younger one, placing itbeside its older sibling to ensure itgetting fed.Diamond Doves can survive on theblandest of diets, however it is betterto offer them a well-rounded, healthydiet. A finch mix with red and whitemillet and canary seed should be providedalong with soaked seed, wholewheat bread and greens. Grit shouldbe offered to aid the gizzard in grindingfood and shaved cuttlebone,crushed, baked eggshells and/ orcalcium powder mixed with soft foodshould be provided.Diamond Doves have grey wingssprinkled with white dots resemblingdiamonds. The body feathers are greybrownwith white on the abdomen.Males and females are similar exceptthat the males' eye rings are far morepronounced and a brighter reel, especiallywhen in breeding condition.Upon fledging, young are a dark greybrown.They will receive adult plumageat approximately three to fourmonths of age . Young DiamondDoves can go to nest after six monthsbut it is more desirable to hold themback until they are nine to 12 monthsold to allow for sexual maturing.As with many domesticated species,Diamond Doves can produce yearround in most cases. They can standweather extremes of over 100 F inthe summer and down into the 40's inthe winter. It is best to offer supplementalheat sources such as heatlamps when temperatures drop intothe lower 40's and below.The silver mutation of the DiamondDove is almost as abundant as thenormal and more mutations such asthe white-tailed are cropping up.Diamond Doves are affordablebirds, often available for as little as $10per pair. They are very quiet (emittingonly a gentle cooing) and docile tokeep with other b irds. They are anadded delight to any aviary andremember "diamonds are a girl's bestfri end. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/697</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/697/680</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
