<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4069</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:17:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Puffins in Peril: Preserving the Clowns of the Sea</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dial, Deb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 1 (January 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.National Aquarium Baltimore, MarylandThe National Aquarium, located in Baltimore’s Inner Harbor, Maryland, USA, has been a respected home to many avian species for over 40 years. One of these species, the Atlantic puffin (Fratercula arctica), nestled in the Aquarium’s Sea Cliffs habitat, has been a hallmark species since opening in 1981. The Aquarium’s mission is to inspire the conservation of the world&amp;#x27;s aquatic treasures and the Atlantic puffin is one of those riches in need of protection. Atlantic puffins have diverse habitat needs, skies for open flight, healthy oceans for overwintering and food, along with safe and protected nesting areas.As their name suggests, Atlantic puffins are endemic to the North Atlantic Ocean and they are the only species of puffin found on the East Coast of North America. There are three recognized subspecies of Atlantic puffins: Fratercula arctica arctica, F.a. naumanni and F.a. grabae. The nominate, F. a. arctica, is endemic to Iceland, Norway, Greenland, and the Northeast coast of North America. The most distinct subspecies is F. a. naumanni, which can be found in Greenland and is larger than the other two subspecies. F. a. grabae, the smallest subspecies, can be found in the British Isles, Faroe Islands, France, the English Channel Islands and Norway. (Walker and Meijer, 2021).Over the years, puffin populations have suffered many setbacks and required targeted interventions. Today, the National Aquarium’s commitment to the Atlantic puffin continues and after decades of providing care, we have used our experiences to benefit both the wild populations [AS1] and the welfare of puffins in human care.As a pelagic species, puffins spend the majority of the year on the open ocean and have been observed overwintering in this habitat from August to April. Mature individuals return to land to nest during the breeding season from April to August. Despite the Atlantic puffins[AS2] large range and sizable colonies, there is still not much known about migration during the non-breeding months when puffins return to the sea (Lowther et al, 2020). It is predictable that the puffins are driven by sea surface temperatures and fish patterns (Huettmann, 2000).Natural History From the order Charadriiformes and the family Alcidae, there are four species of puffins: Horned puffin (Fratercula corniculata), Tufted puffin (Fratercula cirrhata), Rhinoceros auklet (Cerorhinca monocerata), and Atlantic puffin (Fratercula arctica).Male Note the black &amp;amp; white bands on the head and chestRhinoceros Auklet Photo by Dick Daniels www.carolinabirds.orgClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4069</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 1 (2022): Watchbird January 2022; 12-18</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4069/4029</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
