<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3487</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-17T17:23:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Super 8 Prizes</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">(1) $800 Gift Certificate for ZuPreem® products donated by ZuPreem®The history of ZuPreem® started with an idea ~ an idea whose time had come and an idea that would change the way we look at the role of nutrition in the lives of all animals. Through vision and innovation, the company has expanded the original family ofZuPreem products to include a complete line of life-staqe diets for exotic birds that includes Embrace® Hand-Feedlnq Formulas, AvianWeaning™ Diet, AvianMaintenance FruitBlend™ and Natural Diets, AvianBreeder™ Diets, and Crunch® Treats. ZuPreem has the same commitment today that it had more than 40 years ago - the same commitment to the welfare of all animals in our worldwide community, the same commitment to state of-the-arts nutrition research and the same commitment to the highest quality standards of manufacturing and quality control. www.zupreem.com(3) Belize Retreat donated by Carolyn and John CarrA four-day Jungle Explorer package for two that includes meals, transfers,guides, fees and taxes (excluding alcoholic beverages and gratuities). A more complete description is available on the website at www.bananabank.com click on Packages and then Jungle Explorer. Airfare is not included. Situated on the peaceful Belize River and central to all of Belize, Banana Bank Belize Jungle Lodge Horseback Adventure is a place where horses roam free and huge iguanas laze in the branches above the bamboo. The land here is surrounded by evidence of both the ancient Maya and a historic logging tradition. Half of the 4,000 acres is pristine primary growth rainforest. The opportunity to encounter and feel the true spirit and atmosphere of this beautiful country is around every curve in the river and each fork of the jungle trail. John and Carolyn Carr, the owners and managers of Banana Bank offer personal and hospitable accomrnodations with infinite activities. There are over 80 horses bred especially for the terrain and climate and they are trained using the Horse Whisperer method. Their quarter-horse mix bloodlines make them suitable for all levels of trail riding.A specialty is Jungle Horseback riding. Also available are day trips lncluding visiting Maya sites, caving, cave tubing, river trips, jungle walks, birding, star gazing, or simply relaxing and enjoying the grounds of the lodge. Banana Bank is a place far from the real world and near to the things you have dreamed of. (4) Stainless Steel Amazon Cagedonated by Carmen Daily-Birdcages By Carmen Choice of Interchangeable Arch or Playpen Top Styles Bar Diameter: 5/32" I 3.96 mmApproximate Inside Dimensions H34"xW23"x Dl 8" Bar Spacing: 1 ~ 1 /4" I 31 .75 mmHeight from floor 60" Includes 3 manzanita perches and 2 feeders. Other options are available which may incur costs. Shipping is included. Birdcages By Carmen is committed to one fundamental concept: create the highest quality environments to enhance the special relationships between exotic birds and their owners. Some unique features of this cage include the feeder system that is made of medlcal-qrade 304 stainless steel. It attaches to the outside of the bird's enclosure to maximize space inside. Special design features prevent birds from overturning their food or water. This also eliminates defecation into feeders, reducing the chance of bacteria-caused illness.The custom stainless steel dishes are easily serviced from outside the cage for your convenience and are dishwasher safe. The uniquely designed one piece apron extends 4~ 1 /2" beyond the perimeter of the cage to catch falling seeds, feathers and other debris, thereby keeping the surrounding area free from messes usually associated with open cages. The exclusive BirdProof Door Latch pops open with the touch of a finger and locks automatically when door is closed. All enclosures have rings specially designed to accommodate hanging toys, such as swings. All cages come with a removable ABS Plastic Tray that is lightweight and easily removed and cleaned. There is a lifetime warranty on all welds and workmanship as well as a guarantee that the cage will never rust. www.animalenvironments.com (5) AICU Brooder donated by Lyon Technologies.The Animal Intensive Care Unit has been a favorite of veterinarian and aviculturists for many years. Lyon also carries an extensive and varied list of replacement parts and supplies for all AICU brooders. Lyon is proud to announce the debut of their new animal intensive care unit. Armed with many of the same features as the acrylic model, the new AICU is made of the highest quality aluminum, making it even more durable and reliable. This brooder includes the dual digital display and the metal cabinet. www.lyonusa.com  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3487</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 33 No. 4 (2006): Number 4  2006; 23-26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3487/3471</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
