<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2637</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-18T20:08:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Blue-crowned Amazon</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McDonald, Mary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">We have had Blue-crowned Amazon ( A mazona f arinosa guatemalae) Parrots at our breeding ranch since 1978 but, until recently, our birds hadn't produced one single egg.In February 1988, we added a beautiful pair of these birds to our collection. That started an era for us.DescriptionThe Blue-crowned Amazon is one of the larger Amazons. Adults measure to 38 centimeters and more, general plumage is green. Forehead and crown bright, light blue; light blue feathers extend down the back, with a yellow stripe at the base of the neck. Lores, superciliary extending down the side of the head, are blue. Pale skin ring around the eyes. Red feathers just above green heavily tinged with black primaries. Under tail coverts green, intermixed with some yellow; bill black with a light streak at the base; feet grey with black nails.The A. Jarinosa guatemalae inhabits the Caribbean Slope from Honduras and north to southern Vera Cruz, in Mexico. The species is a fairly common resident of the area's undistrubed, humid forest of the Peten in northern Guatemala.Large numbers of this genus, but very few of the guatemalae species, have been imported into the United States. Unfortunately, few of the birds have ended up in breeding collections, the majority evidently having been sold as pets.Our AviaryWe housed the pair acquired in 1988 in a suspended pen measuring 3 x 3 x 6 feet, constructed of 16 gauge welded wire, 1/2 inch x 1 inch mesh. A 14 x 14 x 23 inch insulated nest box is attached horizontally to the outside, at the back end of the pen. We use untreated cedar shavings for nesting material.Each of our outdoor breeding pens is a separate unit. The pens are placed amid large oak trees, shade producing plants and bushes, all of which provide privacy. Planted bushes include ligustrum, red tip photinia, loquat, persimmon, all in addition to native growth and ground cover.An automatic sprinkler system simulates a year-round rainforest effect. Our hot Texas summers really require such an arrangement for the safety and contentment of the birds.FeedingFeed for our adult Amazon parrots consists of a quality cockatiel mix, Lake's Parrot Buffet pellets, carrots, fresh corn, apples and some kind of green vegetable.We also prepare sandwiches daily. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2637</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 2 (1991): APR-MAY 1991; 33-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2637/2607</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
