<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/805</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Our First Brotogeris</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wettlaufer, Chris and Tom</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">' 'I think we should go back andget him" is the way it startedfour years ago. My wife Chris and Ihad just left a little Grey-cheeked Parakeeton the perch at a Florida coastalpet store one Sunday and were drivingback home. He was a friendly littledude, chatted with everyone, got onyour finger, paid attention to you,wanted a good home!"I think we should go back and gethim." I turned into a parking lot alongthe road and we talked about wherewe would put him. After all, we didhave an African Grey and a macaw atthe time. "We'll get a little cage andkeep him in the kitchen for a whileand see how he does." A goodanswer. I went back the way we hadcome and, just as the place was closing,we bought "Cheeks" and a cageand headed for home.Four years later, our Grey-cheekedParakeets have bred for three years.We are working on second generationbreeding and have all of the Brotogerisspecies except the Tui, Plain, orYellow-winged (Canary).Chris' Tiny Wings (CfW) AviaryCTW Aviary is set up in two areas:inside and outside. The indoor cageswere custom made and each is 18" x18" x 24". Each contains a toy, a Manzanitabranch (for chewing), a waterbowl, a fresh food bowl and a dryfood bowl. Each cage has a pair ofBrotogeris and a lovebird size nestbox.We house three pairs of Greycheekedand one pair of Orangechinnedinside.There are several different sizes ofcages set up in banks outdoors. Someof the cages are 24" x 24" x 36" andare arranged side by side. These cagesare identical in every respect and areseparated for three-fourths of theirlength with a privacy panel. We used1" x 2" oak for perches and the nestboxesare 10" x 10" x 8". We have asmall, two-compartment dog dish weuse for feeding: fresh on one side, dry on the other. In the front of each cageis the water bowl and each cage has atimed sprinkler.Another section has cages thatmeasure 24" x 36" x 36", side by sideand are identical to the smaller cages(except for size), right down to thesprinklers.There is also a community cagewhich is 36" x 36" x 48". This cage hastwo feeding positions and a largerwater bowl. It also has two nestboxeswith room for two more. For this cage,the sprinkler has a larger spray area.CTW Aviary is located in centralFlorida. For that reason, we can be alittle more experimental with breedingindoors and outdoors. CTW Aviarypresently has a good selection of Brotogerisand can evaluate differentinfluences and how the breedingcycles relate.Population at CTW AviaryWe have been able to add to ourcollection this year a single Greycheeked(paired with one of thisyear's babies will give us five pairs),two White-winged (which gives ustwo pairs and two males) and a singleOrange-chinned (which gives us threepairs). We also have a pair of Cobaltwingedand two pairs of GoldenwingedParakeets. The total Brotogerispopulation is as follows: GreycheekedBrotogeris pyrrhopterus, fivepairs; Orange-chinned Brotogerisjugularis, three pairs; White-wingedBrotogeris versicolorus, two pairs plustwo males; Cobalt-winged Brotogeriscyanoptera, one pair; Golden-wingedBrotogeris chrysopterus, two pairs.We have been successful for threeyears in breeding Brotogeris. This yearwe received our first clutch of Orangechinnedeggs (all infertile). Next year,we expect our second generation ofGrey-cheeked. Last year, one of ourGrey-cheeked pairs gave us a doubleclutch. The hen laid and hatched fivein January-February and laid five eggsand hatched two babies (the rest wereinfertile) in June-July.General CharacteristicsCobalt-winged Parakeets are Chris'favorites. They give the initial appearanceof tiny Amazons. They have avery small but vivid orange spot underthe lower mandible. There is a yellowwash on the front, fading to lightgreen on the crown. The wings aremagnificent. The Cobalt-winged arestocky birds compared to most of theother Brotogeriswe have.Golden-winged Parakeets are myfavorites. They are a dark olive greenwith a black wash to the facialfeathers; the periophthalmic ringreally stands out. The most impressivefeature of the Golden-winged is thesmall, triangular patch of pure goldenfeathers at the bend of the wing. Onlywhen the wings are extended is thegolden patch visible against a darkgreen background.White-winged Parakeets are a littlebit darker than the subspecies B.v.chiriri (Canary-winged). This subspecieshas some white primaryfeathers that are almost invisible untilthe wing is opened. Some of thesecondary feathers show a very subtleyellow wash on white. These birdstend to be a little more territorial and acouple of the males become veryvocal when we change the water andfood bowls.Grey-cheeked are friendly and justtalk up a storm! When there are 10 to15 together at any one time, they canbe very loud. A solitary bird canbecome just as spoiled and just asdemanding as any other largerbird, i.e. macaw or cockatoo, althoughwill remain much more quiet. Themost interesting feature of the Greycheekedis the orange patch under thewing next to the body. This orangepatch tends to peek out at the bend ofthe wing on mature birds.Orange-chinned Parakeets are amiddle green between the Goldenwingedand the Grey-cheeked. Beingsomewhat plain in coloring, they dohave the same type of patch under thewing as the Grey-cheeked except thepatch is a light yellow, not orange.These differ from the rest of the Brotogerishaving ·a medium bronze patchon the outside of the folded wing. Theorange (in Orange-chinned) is visibleas a small spot under the lower mandible.Orange-chinned seem to be"bossy" birds.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/805</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 31-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/805/787</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
