<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3216</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-31T11:10:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">President's Message</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hawley, James C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">When you get to the end of your W rope-tie a knot and hang on!'Life has its ups and downs and I am often reminded about the Peanuts cartoon I once saw in a Sunday newspaper many, many years ago. The first scene had Charlie Brown and Linus leaning on a brick wall with their chins on their baseball gloves. Linus was talking to Charlie Brown and the caption read, "Well Charlie Brown, you win some and you lose some." The next four boxes justshow them still leaning against the brick wall with their chins on their gloves until the last box when Charlie Brown is again talking to Linus and the caption reads, "Yea, wouldn't that be neat!"These last several months have shown a major slowdown in our economy and even a recession moving into global proportions. There's an old saying that I would like to give to you as my suggestion to everyone-"Don't throw the baby (birds) out with the bath water. There will come a day when we will look back at these days and carry on the annoying conversation-"Do you remember when ... ?" and I can one-up you on how hard I had it, I had to trudge three miles, uphill, in the snow, to feed my birds each day, breaking ice in the water bowls with an ax!As an accountant, I find myself advising clients almost every week on some basic economic survival plans:• Avoid unnecessary and excessive debt. • Make wise and frugal purchases.• Try to get the most bang for your buck.Speaking of the "Most Bang For Your Buck," The American Federation of Aviculture's 2009 convention is coming up and I believe this is where you will get the BANG and dollar stretcher! Start planning now to attend the annual convention. Here are some planning ideas:• Set some of your tax refund aside for convention costs.• Set up a monthly fund to pay for your registration and travel.• Have garage sales, 0 R like my granddaughter told me, you can get RICH on eBay.If you plan ahead and plan wisely you can accomplish almost anything you put your mind to! (Oh my gosh! That is what my mom always told me!)Watch for the convention Information and the speaker list. Your planning and struggles to get to the convention will prove to be a very valuable investment! This convention is shaping up to be one of the very best the American Federation of Aviculture has ever had to date. DON'T MISS IT!Again, with my accountant hat on, I have personally lived through several recessions ( and one depression, but that was because I was turning 50) and they are cyclical. They have a beginning and with our resilience they have and end. Things might get tough but that is when the tough get going. Support the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. and I look forward to seeing you in Houston at the convention! </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3216</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 35 No. 4 (2008): Number 4  2008; 5</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3216/3200</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
