<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2131</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-07T19:10:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">1982 Convention Notes</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, Phyllis K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Where were you when the lights went out? Robert Berry, Chairman of the Conservation Committee was standing next to me in the International Ballroom East listening to John Stcodley's lecture on "Incubation and Hand Rearing." AF A's money was well protected during the black-out because our Southeast Regional Vice President, Roger Kenny, sat on the cash boxes.At about 5:50 p.m., Saturday, August 7, all of the lights in the Washingron Hilton and surrounding areas went out. Many of the aviculturists attending our convention were trapped in the subbasement of the hotel listening to the last talks of the day. Speakers went on as if nothing had happened. When bird people start talking about birds, nothing can stop them.The Eight Annual American Federation of Aviculture Convention opened for registration August 3.The board meeting convened at 8:00 a.m., August 4, under President Tom Ireland. One of the first items of business was the counting of ballots by the Nominating Committee to determine the 1982/83 AFA officers.These officers are: President, Tom Ireland; 1st Vice President, Lee Phillips; 2nd Vice President, Don Cavender; Chief Financial Officer, Hubert Morris. A new appointed position was established at the board meeting tided "Legislative Vice President," to be filled by Clifton Witt. Helen Hanson continues as AFA's Executive Secretary in charge of the home office in Redondo Beach, California, and Phyllis Martin was re-appointed Corresponding Secretary.Fifty-five delegates and stare coordinators attended the business meeting. It was pointed our that many of AFA's dreams came true during this past year. During its first year, our Research Committee, headed by Dr. Susan Clubb, accomplished some oursranding results as indicated by the Board's approval of five research gram applications to receive AFA funding totaling $12,380. These research projects are:1. Development and efficacy of a live Budgerigar Fledgling Disease Virus Vaccine for use in Breeder Budgerigars (Melopsittacus undulatus). Principal investigator is Dr. Phil Luken, Dept. of Vet. Microbiology, University of Georgia.2. Seasonal Evaluation of excretory sex steroid hormones in juvenile appraisal of sexual matunty and to sexual identity of immature birds. Principal invesrigaror is Arden Bryan Bercovirz, Ph.D., Avian Physiologist, San Diego Zoo.3. Solid food requirements and water tolerance of Cockatiel chiCks from hatching to fi."ve weeks of age. Principal investigators are C.R. Grau, Ph.D., and T.E. Roudybush, M.S., University of California at Davis, Dept. of Avian Sciences.4. Estimation of the population parameters of the Green-cheeked Amazon (Amazona vindigenalis) tn northeastern Mexico. Principal investigator Jack Clinton-Eitniear of the Vulture Study Group, McAllen, Texas.5. Detection of Chlamydia psittaci infection in exotic birds. Principal investigator isJack Gaskin, DVM, University of Florida, Dept. of Ver. Microbiology.Tom Ireland announced the receipt of donations for continuing these research projects from many aviculrurists attending the convention. Bernie Levine of Pet Farm donated $500 and asked for a matching donation. Drs. Barry Alder and Ira Niedweske matched his donation and additionally pledged to give $500 a year to the research fund; they challenged Mr. Levine to do the same.Another dream come true was the establishment of AF A's goals and guidelines for the Conservation Committee. Chairman Robert Berry is preparing a separate article concerning our conservation program.President Ireland announced that anyone wanting to make donations to either the Conservation Committee Fund or the Research Committee Fund should contact the home office at P.O. Box 1568, Redondo Beach, CA 90278.The Board of Directors approved nine new state coordinators. The updated list can be found in this magazine (page 6 ).The American Federation of Aviculture is one of the most important aviculrural societies in the United States. It has also gained recognition and strength throughout the world. Av icu lrur isrs from South Africa, Sweden, Holland, England, Canada and Puerto Rico attended this convention, a good indication of AF A's popularity.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2131</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 9 No. 5 (1982): OCT-NOV 1982; 38-41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2131/2102</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
