<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3256</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-02T17:36:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">History of the AVY Awards</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he most celebrated, esteemed and highest awards in the history of U.S. aviculture-the AFA AVYs-got their start in 1977 when the American Federation of Aviculture Inc. created an awards system to recognize American aviculturists who have uniquely distinguished themselves in the field of aviculture. Over time, categories expanded until there were bronze, silver and gold awards covering avicultural breeding success and outstanding service from aviculturists in the field. To be presented an AVY was the highest mark of avicultural achievement.The original committee named the AVY awards from the first three letters, "avi," in the word aviculture, which was then modified to "AVY," which we continue to use today. The AVY Awards committee is composed of members of diverse avicultural backgrounds who have achieved or demonstrated avicultural expertise and knowledge, spanning a wide spectrum of aviculture, including zoo species. Committee members are involved in researching, investigating and verifying claims, and in discussion, balloting and voting the results of nominations.Although there have been several leaders of the AVY Awards Committee over the years, two individuals in particular must be mentioned. The first chairman, Roland G. DuBuc, founded the committee-naming the awards "AVYs" -and assigned the numerous categories that we still use today. Beginning in 1982, Dale R. Thompson took the helm for many years, publishing the descriptions and categories of rules in Watchbird and diligently submitting the award winners for publication for all categories between 1982 and 1996. His presentation of awards during banquet festivities were both heartfelt and memorable. For many of us, it was Thompson who came to symbolize the AVYs and who supremely conveyed the importance, dignity and significance these contributions made.The AVY Awards are presented annually during the AFA national convention's August banquet, although it is not mandatory to award all categories every year. Following the convention, an announcement is sent out through AFA in Brief that is distributed to all AF A-affiliated organizations-and in Watchbird-announcing that nominations are open. Nominees for the present year are encouraged to request an application for a specific category; some prior years may also be approved in particular instances.Once a nomination is received, the nominee is forwarded an application, which must be filled out in full with accompanying photographs and other documentation as required, and returned to the chairman by Dec. 31. Nominations for the calendar year are evaluated by the awards committee, decisions are finalized and nominees notified prior to the national convention.AVY Award categories are open to members, and in some instances, other aviculturists or institutions, who have uniquely distinguished themselves in challenging and difficult areas of aviculture.GOLD AVY AWARD-HONOR AWARDThe Gold AVY is a once-in-a-lifetime achievement award and is given to individuals who have made outstanding contributions to the field of aviculture. The award may be given for outstanding breeding success or for service given to the field of aviculture. It is the highest award given by the American Federation of Aviculture.1. The Gold AVY Award is merited for individuals who have made an outstanding contribution to aviculture. The Gold AVY is not solely an achievement award, although achievement may be part of the overall contribution.2. The Gold AVY Award is a once in a lifetime award and may be given posthumously.3. Nominations for the Gold AVY Award must be submitted by an Affiliated Club and not by an individual.4. Nominations for the Gold AVY Award must be for an individual and does not include research institutions, clubs, or organizations, etc.5. Nominees for the Gold AVY Award must be a member of AFA, or a member of an AFA Affiliated Club.6. Nominations must be as detailed as possible in order to provide enough information to aid the work of the Award Committee.7. Nominations must be submitted by Dec. 31 to be awarded at the AFA convention the following year. SILVER AVY AWARDSCATEGORY I. Most Progress for the Establishment of an Individual Species or Group of Related Birds.This category recognizes aviculturists who have made the effort to successfully breed an individual species or related group of birds on a consistent basis. Success must be achieved with a minimum of two pairs of birds, or through the second generation if involving a single species. The Awards Committee will judge whether establishment is achieved. Birds with shorter reproductive life spans (such as finches), will need greater numbers produced than birds that have longer reproductive life spans (such as parrots). The difficulty of each species to reproduce offspring will be taken into consideration by the committee.CATEGORY II. Breeding a Significant or Highly Difficult SpeciesBreeding a significant or highly difficult species reflects the obvious use of sound management techniques. This category eliminates chance breedings and must be well documented.CATEGORY III. Progress in Establishing New Mutations in the United StatesThis category demonstrates achievement in establishing a new mutation that has not yet been established in the United States. To qualify, offspring visible for the mutation must be bred, and demonstrate self-sufficiency, through the second generation. Birds that are not weaned before nomination deadline (due to late hatching dates in that calendar year), should be nominated the following year after self-sufficiency has been proven.CATEGORY rv. Progress in Show StandardsThis category covers birds for which there are written show standards and show classifications. An exhibitor's bird must have won three or more national level shows (may include annual specialty/large regional shows), judged by three or more certified panel judges, with a bird bred by the exhibitor. All wins must be achieved by a single entry wearing a closed, coded leg band with a published show report record of the recorded win. The Awards Committee will determine the inclusion of annual specialty/regional shows based on the number of entries and exhibitors. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3256</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 38 No. 3 (2011): Number 3 2011; 14-22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3256/3240</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
