<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2308</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-07T16:46:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Introduction to the Psittacula Family (Asian Parakeets)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perry, Fred</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perry, Lyrae</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Psittacula family is commonly referred to as the Asian parakeets, and comprise some of the most elegantly dressed birds of the psittacines. Their range is throughout India, Southern Asia, Indonesia, parts of Africa, and Malaysia. They are forest dwellers as a rule, but some do prefer the semi-open country at the edges of forests. They are known to eat various fruits, seeds, legumes, berries, blossoms and "bugs" endemic to their areas. They are however, opportunistic, and soon learn to take advantage of cultivated crops and orchards. They all have the long gradated tail, characteristic of parakeets.These birds make very pleasant aviary subjects, and are generally very prolific breeders as well. The breeding and maintenance of these birds is not much different from one family member to the next. The care needed is basically the same as for other tropical and sub-tropical birds. Almost everyone who has ever had birds has encountered or kept at least one member of this beautiful family. Very few aviculturists, though, are aware that the Psittacula family comprises so many members. There is a fair amount of diversity in the color patterns, which can be somewhat misleading, but closer examination reveals only slight differences, and affirms taxonomic classifications. In addition, the personality traits, courtship displays, etc., of each are only slightly different.The Asian parakeets are spring breeders, and the breeding season usually starts with the ringnecks and Alexandrines in late January and early February. The rest of the family follows suit through the spring, culminating with the Malabars in late March or April. The courtship displays are all quite similar and are very interesting to watch. Having a "headache" most of the year, the hens rule the roost, with the males showing good sense and staying out of the way, for the hens are not to be trifled with and have on occasion been known to kill. With the advent of the breeding season, and consequent change in attitude on the part of the females, the males work up the courage to approach, display, feed, and finally mate with the hens.In our breeding operation we use two sizes of nest boxes. They are both the "grandfather clock" style. For the majority of Asian parakeets, a9" x9" x24" deep box is used. For larger parakeets, such ad Derbyans and Alexandrines, we use a 12" x 12" x 24", or 30" deep box. The sizes may seem small to some, but it has been our experience that the smaller box is more readily accepted, and is adequate to hold even a large clutch of babies.In approximately two to three weeks, two to six eggs are laid (depending on species) at intervals of one about every other day. Incubation is started with the laying of the second egg. If the parents are given an adequate supply of soft foods, they are all excellent parents, and will generally raise the whole clutch without difficulty. There are those who successfully raise babies on a diet limited to seed, but a greater success and consistency can be obtained with a more varied diet. Indian Ringnecked ParakeetThe most familiar and prolific member of the Psittacula family is the Indian ringneck. They are inhabitants of India, the Middle East and Singapore, and are somewhat larger than a cockatiel. The body color is a beautiful shade of green. Males have a black chin and neck ring below which is a rosepink collar. They are sometimes referred to as the "rose-ringed parakeet." Hens lack the neck rings altogether.The bird we commonly refer to as the Indian ringneck is really one of two subspecies: P.k. borealis, which occurs throughout Northern India along the Himalayan foothills, and parts of Nepal, Burma, and West Pakistan, or P.k. manillensis, which has a slightly more restricted range through the Indian peninsula, Sri Lanka (formerly Ceylon), and was introduced in Singapore many years ago. Both of these subspecies have been introduced to various other islands as well.For the beginner, looking for his first pair of' 'real birds'', the Indian ringneck is hard to beat. It is easily bred, and is extremely hardy. It is the perfect 'step-up' from cockatiels and budeies. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2308</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 2 (1985): APR-MAY 1985; 22-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2308/2282</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
