<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/684</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding Red Shining Parrots</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rinke, Dieter</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The islands of the tropical PacificOcean have always captured theimagination of the European andAmerican visitors, and are still the subjectof daydreams about turquoiseblue lagoons, coconut palms, whitesandy beaches -just paradise. Thisparadise is home to some of the mostbeautiful and spectacular birds, whichare almost unknown in our civilizedcountries. So little is know about thesplendid Silktail (Lamprolia victoriae),the gorgeous Flame Dove (Ptilinopusvictor), the peculiar ToothbilledPigeon (Didunculus strigirostris),or the unique Cagou (Rhyno- chetus jubatus).Some of the most beautiful parrotslive on these legendary islands. Thefirst among them is the UltramarineLorikeet (Vini ultramarina) whosearray of blue colors rivals the tones ofthe most spectacular lagoons of itsisland home. Another gem from theislands is the Red Shining Parrot (Prosopeiatabuensis), feathered in darkburgundy red, while the wings andthe tail shine in the brightest blue andgreen colors imaginable.But paradise has its problems, andwith these situations the situation ofmany species of island creatures has changed dramatically. Hunting, introducedpredators and habitat destructionhas resulted in the extinctionof birds the extent of which is unmatchedin other parts of the world. Anumber of birds which have survivedthis wave of destruction are nowfacing a very uncertain future.In 1989, the Brehm Fund for InternationalBird Conservation initiated aconservation program for endangeredPacific Island species, the Brehm FundSouth Seas Expedition, based in theKingdom of Tonga. This programincludes island surveys, translocationof threatened species, captive breeding,and education. Among the specieswhich receive special attentionwithin this program is the Red ShiningParrot (called Koki in the islands)which is threatened by loss of habitat,and potentially by trade. The Koki hasbecome the .flagship species for wildlifeconse1vation in Tonga. A flock hasbeen established in captivity and nowI am reporting about their successesafter two breeding seasons.The Captive FlockThe captive flock of Red ShiningParrots was established since the endof the wild parrots' breeding season in1989. Most of the captive birds werereceived from people on 'Eua, theonly Tongan Island where the RedShining Parrot occurs in the wild. Considerablenumbers of young parrotsare taken from nests every year andkept as pets in tiny wire cages. Most ofthem die after a short period of time. Some are eaten and their feathers areused to decorate traditional mats.We visited villages in October, 1989and 1990, and collected most of thecaptive birds. Only a few peoplerefused to give us their parrots, andthese birds were kept under betterconditions than those which we couldobtain. Some farmers use traps, baitedwith coconuts, on their plantationsyear round. They capture BandedRails (Gallirallus philippensis), PurpleSwamphens (Porphyria porphyria),feral chickens and, occasionallyparrots. Instead of eating these birdsimmediately, some were offered to us.From this our captive flock slowlyincreased to 30 birds.All of these parrots were put into alarge aviary with side-quarters. Theyacclimatized very well and I observedvery little aggression. Most newcomerswere also integrated into theflock without problems. The mostaggressive birds were those whichhad been in captivity for more thanone year (mostly under bad conditions)before we obtained them. Theydid not integrate into the flock verywell and did not establish bonds withother parrots.The aviary also housed four PurpleSwamphens and three Pacific GreyDucks (Anas superciliosa). Some ofthe parrots "played" with these birds,"diving down" on them and chasingthem around in the aviary. The handraisedbirds which had been takenfrom nests remained tame, and flewtowards the visitors who fed themwith berries and peanuts.Aviary Design and DietThe idea to build a complex aviarywhere the birds can choose either tojoin the flock or separate from otherparrots (which parrots do in the wildduring their breeding seasons)resulted from my field studies of RedShining Parrots on the Tongan islandof 'Eua. Other field studies of parrotsalso had an important input, as well asthe often frustrating results of parrotbreeders with so-called aggressivespecies. I had not heard nor readabout a successful natural breeding ofthe Red Shining Parrot in captivity.The young birds had to be handraisedbecause their fathers becametoo aggressive, attacking the newbornchicks (and even the hens).This happens in many parrot species.My hypothesis was that if the par-rots had the choice between flock andbreeding territory, the aggression ofthe male would not be directedtowards the mate (and the chicks). Asa result, the birds should then successfullybreed and rear their own chicks.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/684</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 27-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/684/667</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
