<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2854</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-12-31T15:28:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">1st National American Cockatiel Society Show</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reed, Nancy A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A. C. S. drew an entry of 1 18 Cockatiels at their first club show which was held in conjunction with the National Cage Bird Show in Atlanta, GA., Nov. 16-19, 1978, (total entry over 1200 birds). Max Kennedy (Texas), who has served as our first President since the formation of A.C.S. in 1977, was the Cockatiel Division's judge.This entry was the largest turnout ever of Cockatiels in a show in the U.S. We feel it not only a vote of confidence for A.C.S. and the National Cage Bird Show, but an indication of the growing popularity of the Cockatiel in America today.The following list of the top 10 winning Cockatiels illustrates the distances that many exhibitors traveled in order to support A.C.S. &amp;amp; N.C.B.S.l. Normal hen-Nancy Reed, Windsor, CT2. Normal cock- Wayne Smithson, Geneseo, IL3. Pied cock- Wayne Smithson, Geneseo, IL4. Pied cock - Ralph Bowman, Des Moines, Iowa5. Cinnamon cock - Nancy Reed, Windsor, CT6. Cinnamon cock- Richard Baer, Groveport, Ohio7. Lutino cock - Norma Dee, Calif.8. Split Pied cock- Earl Courts, Lee's Summit, MO9. Pearl cock- Earl Courts, Lee's Summit, MOIO. Pearl hen -Nancy Reed, Windsor, CTBest Opposite Sex: Normal cock - Wayne Smithson (above)Best Young Bred by Exhibitor: Pied cock- Wayne Smithson (above)Best Cock 1978 A.C.S. Banded &amp;amp; Bred by Exhibitor: Cinnamon cock - Richard Baer (above)Best Hen 1978 A.C.S. Banded &amp;amp; Bred by Exhibitor: Cinnamon hen - Conrad Meinert, Warsaw, Ind. At the A.C.S. annual meeting, also held at the show, finalization of the Cockatiel Show Cage Standard was made. Briefly:The dimensions will be 17'' high x 18" wide x IO'' deep with a removable roll top chrome front, and two ¥.! '' dowel perches placed perpendicular to front of cage. Exterior of cage will be painted a black gloss, the interior a light blue semi-gloss (Sherwin Williams brand paint: "Dainty Blue" 48966X. An alternative: Pittsburgh Paint: "Blueberry Frost" P2693).An appropriate seed mix will cover floor of cage, and removable water containers (tubes or bottles) are to be used in order that they may detached during judging period.More detailed information is given in...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2854</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 2 (1979): APR-MAY 1979; 30-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2854/2838</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
