<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/678</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE:The Decisions Are Ours</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Where will all the lovebirds presentlybeing hatched in captivity findsuitable homes? What about thehundreds of pairs of Nanday Conuresproducing babies across the U.S.remnantsof thousands of importedNandays during the '70s and '80s?Who will take care of all the Mitreds,the Cherry-headed, the importedBlue-fronted, and disgruntled Blueand Golds? As hobby and smallbreeder production rises dramaticallyacross America, as our aviculturematures and our health practicesimprove, we must look to where andhow we are going to keep the thousandsof captive-bred baby psittacineswe successfully raise. What speciesmake the best long term pets? Whatspecies are most in demand? Thesequestions are forcing themselves tothe forefront of the parrot breeder/ petstore coalition.Hundreds of wild-caught, escapedand excess parrots end up living in theAmerican wilds. Certainly Florida,California and Hawaii can boast significantnumbers of feral psittacinesliving in remote areas and backyards,scavaging off of fruits, flowers, seedsand greenery. But what about Illinois,Tennessee, New York, Louisiana,Oregon? As aviculturists and parrotlovers, we must begin to sort out ourfeelings about wild flocks of parrotsliving in our areas. It is inevitable, withthe hundreds of thousands of importedhookbills, that some wouldescape and begin breeding. It is alsoinevitable that local, state and federalagencies will get involved in this situation.We must think ahead and beready with imaginative ideas, beliefs and policies.Others of these surplus parrots arecheaply offered for sale and may beshuffled from one hapless pet ownerto another as dysfunctional, terrorized,even mean birds. City newspapersare teeming with ads foruntrained or untrainable Goffin'sCockatoos, African Grays, OrangewingedAmazons and assorted conures.Many customers call us beggingto find a good home for theseunwanted psittacines. But with thehandfed market expanding, there arefew good homes. Some of these speciesend up as cheap added breedersin lackluster aviaries with little naturalenvironment. Unfortunately, I seemany parrots given quality of care relativeto their value and cost price.Picture this: a small-time NewMexico breeder puts together severalhundred dollars to purchase a six-birdgroup of scmffy, wild-caught, traumatizedGreat-billed Parrots from adubious impo1t station. Unable to adequatelyprovide for the nervous groupof parrots, the breeder leaves them ina temporary holding flight the firstwinter hoping to discover their bonding.All six birds freeze their feet onthe metal pipe perches and are lost.This is a crime. It also demonstratesthe side to American avicultureagainst which we are all fighting.The rule is this; if we are not able togive state-of-the-art, humane, conscientiouscare to the living creatureswe presume to keep and breed, we donot deserve to own them.What we are talking about here isthe natural choice. The choice to domore than build cages with a perch, a nestbox, a food and water dish. Thechoice to make our psittacine environmentsmore than clean and sterile -tooffer more to our pets and breedersthan a sameness of food, the boredomof routine, the wire of a cage too smallto allow flight, or the trimmed wingsof a baby fledgling never taught toland, hover, or flap and hop.So, as we obviously cannot all bringour parrots out into nature, the logicalalternative is to bring nature to ourparrots. In some cases this is incrediblyeasy -like introducing rocks,stumps, logs, greenery and flowersinto the birds' cages. In other cases thesimplest of necessities present a problem.Take sunlight for instance. Iwould no sooner keep a valuable psittacineaway from daily sunlight than Iwould myself. Admittedly in southernstates this is not a big difficulty, buthundreds of indoor aviaries across theU.S. house psittacines that seldom, ifever, feel a direct ray of sunshineupon their feathers. Skylights orremovable roof panels should be afirst consideration in any aviary. I havebeen using indoor lighting with parrotsfor over eight years; I still do notbelieve it incites hookbills to the kindof activity that true sunlight does.What about rain? Here we can supplysprinkler systems and give ourbirds regular showers. Good enough.Yet the natural rain experience for aparrot is when low pressure moves in,skies gray, wind whips and the dropsbegin. To be alert to this means turningon sprinklers when the day iscloudy, overcast or raining outside.Better yet, allow aviaries portions ofscreened roof where parrots may have access to true outside weather.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/678</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 14-16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/678/661</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
