<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2491</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-13T19:58:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in Action ... News &amp; Views</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Phillips, Lee</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Christman, Chris</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">With the recent adjournment of the 99th Congress, House of Representatives bill 4535 passed into oblivion. This bill was introduced on April 9, 1986 by Representative Charles Rose (D. NC. 7th District) and had picked up 32 additional sponsors before adjournment. There is every reason to believe that the bill will be reintroduced in the next session.HR-"1535 would have amended section 19 of the Animal Welfare Act by adding the following thereto:"Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, any person may commence a civil action on his own behalf or on behalf of any animal protected by this Act to compel any person or persons charged with the duty by statute or regulation to enforce the provisions of the Act to execute such duty"Thus the bill would permit any person to institute a civil lawsuit to compel the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) to enforce the Animal Welfare Act against anyone alledged to be violating the Act and since suit could be brought on behalf of any animal protected by the Act, this would give animals a legal right of access to the judicial system of our country for the first time. If passed, this bill could have led to the filing of hundreds of frivolous, nuisance suits against APHIS and could conceivably jeopardize anyone from rancher and farmer to pet owner, and the subsequent wasting of AP HIS resources to investigate and defend its actions.The bill was referred to the House Committee on Agriculture which twice requested comments from the U.S. Department of Agriculture and twice received unfavorable comments.Listed below are the names of the additional sponsors of this legislation: Rod Chandler, (R. Wash. 8th); Joe Moakley, (D. Mass. 9th); Barbara Boxer (D. Calif. 6th): Robert C. Smith (R. NH lst), William G. Whitehurst (R. VA 2nd); Patricia Schroeder (D. Colo. 1st); Tom Lamos (D. Calif. I lth), Sala Burton (D. Calif. 5th); ParrenJ. Mitchell (D. MD 7th); Frank Horton (R. NY 29th): RobertJ. Mrazek (D. NY 3rd); Matthew G. Martinez (D. Calif. 30th); Thomas J. Manton (D. 1',ry 9th); Brian). Donnelly (D. Mass. 11th); Howard C. Nielson (R. Utah 3rd); Robert G. Torricelli (D. NJ 9th); Andrew Jacobs, Jr. (D. Ind. 10th); Bruce A. Morrison (D. CT 3rd); Joe Kolter (D. Penn. 4th); Matthew J. Rinaldo (R. NJ 7th); Ted Weiss (D. NY 17th); Robert A. Borski (D. PA 3rd);JamesJ. Howard (D. NJ 3rd); Edward). Markey (D. Mass. 7th); Bill Hendon (R. NC !Ith); Mervyn M. Dyrnally (D. Calif. 31st); Ronald V. Dellums (D. Calif. 8th);John Conyers.jr. (D. Mich. lst); Helen Delich Bentley (R. MD 2nd); Newt Gingrich (R. GA 6th); Edolphus Towns (D. NY I lth); Benjamin A. Gilman (R. NY 22nd); Glenn M. Anderson (D. Calif. 32nd).While some of these legislators undoubtedly will not return to Congress, I urge each of you to contact those in your state who survive the election and make your views known to them. They may be addressed at House of Representatives, Washington, D.C. 20515.The animal welfare program administered by USDA's APHIS has received funding in the amount of 55,878,000 for the enforcement of the Animal Welfare Act, an increase of Sl ,250,000 over last year.Going abroad? The Fish and Wildlife Sen ice of the U.S.Department of the Interior in cooperation with the World Wildlife Fund - U.S. has developed a new brochure alerting travelers to the pitfalls of buying wildlife and wildlife products abroad. "Buyer Beware!" describes the animal and plant products that are most commonly sold in foreign countries and whose importation into the United States is illegal. It also explains the Federal and international laws and treaties under which the Fish and Wildlife Service seeks to stem the growing trade in illegal products and to promote the conservation of the world's endangered wildlife.Because of the complexity of regulations governing wildlife importations, "Buyer Beware!" advises travelers with specific questions to contact the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Sen-ice or the World \X'ildlife Fund well in advance of their trip to obtain more detailed information.Single copies of "Buyer Beware!" are available free from the U.S.Fish and Wildlife Service, Publications Unit, Room 148. Mammie Building, 1717 H Street NW, Washington, D.C. 202-JO. •  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2491</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 6 (1986): DEC 1986- JAN 1987; 40-42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2491/2463</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
