<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4117</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:18:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA 48th Annual Conference Recap</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferragamo, Concetta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 4 (October/November 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Recap of AFA’s 48th Annual Educational ConferenceThe 48th annual AFA Educational Conference and Bird Expo was a wonderful success. With COVID19 variants still lingering, we weren’t quite sure if we would have a good turn out or not, but we most definitely did. Like-minded bird lovers from all over the United States, along with some of our international friends, joined together for this fun filled educational experience in Herndon, Virginia just outside of Washington DC. It is always wonderful to hear so many different people talk about howJames, Dr. Dan Lebbin, Cassie Malina, Jenna Meade, Rob Milko, Adrianne Mock, Hildegard Niemann, Dr. Rainer Niemann, Mindy Patterson, Jack Pine, Debbie Schweikardt, Daniel Sigmon, Robin Sullivan, Kelley Taylor, Jafet Velez-Valentin, Buddy Waskey, Jade Welch, and Jamie Whittaker. Dorothy Paterson (Laney Rickman’s sister) pulled off an incredible “Blues Bash” for conservation awareness of the Blue-throated macaws through the Nido Adoptivo Nest Box Project at the Bird Endowment in Bolivia and the Prevention Protocol to Protectthey met - what turns into live -time friendships among our AFA membership. NY AFA State Coordinator, Suzanna Dodd stated that she has been, “looking forward to seeing my AFA friends for months.” When Suzanna said that out loud, others chimed in and talked about their own experiences and how they look forward to seeing friends in person at the conferences.As always, AFA pulls together amazing speakers who deliver impressive presentations. Currant AFA President, Mary Ellen LePage launched the conference with her president’s message. Mary Ellen then introduced, this year’s Keynote speaker who is a past AFA president, current Regional Director and author, Tom Marshall. The following speakers captivated the attendees’ attention, covering topics about rehoming birds, behaviors, medical updates, legislative awareness, nutrition, breeding/hormonal cycles, conservation, holistic approaches to behaviors, history of keeping birds, training birds, free-flight training, microchipping, building bird enclosures, breeding education and saving aviculture. Thank you to our spectacular 2022 presenters, Josee Bermingham, April Blazich, Dr. Frank Blazich Jr, Kashmir Csaky, Steve Duncan, Dr. Stephen Fronefield, Taylor Hains, Bennett Hennessey, SteveClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4117</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 4 (2022): Watchbird October/November 2022; 10-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4117/4077</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
