<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/728</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Those Loveable Lovebirds ... Problems in the Nest Box</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Casey, Judie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">When you have obtained a pair oflovebirds and want to set them up tobreed, there are a few things that canhappen in the nest to be aware of.Lovebirds build their own nest frommaterials you supply. Their favorite ispalm leaves. The birds will shred the leaves into thin pieces. Females tuckthe pieces into their rump feathers andunder their wings. This is carried tothe nest box where she will build hernest. Some nests are quite elaborate with a deep tunnel and an entrancethat is covered on top. They will continueto build the nest as long as thematerial is available, sometimes evenif eggs have been laid or babieshatched.If palm leaves are not available,there are some other things you cantry. Some birds will use fresh cornhusks, Bird of Paradise leaves or sometypes of bamboo. Make sure anythingyou give your birds is free of insecticidesand is not poisonous.When the female starts to lay hereggs, it is helpful to keep track ofdates the eggs are laid to estimatedates of hatch. I use index cardsstapled to the nest box, but a calendaris easy when you don't have a largenumber of birds.The hen will lay an egg every otherday. Eggs will hatch 19 to 21 daysfrom the date of incubation. Sometimesthe hen doesn't start incubatinguntil two or three eggs have been laid.Make a note of the date she starts sittingall the time.Babies will hatch one every otherday if the hen started sitting with thefirst egg. If she didn't, two or threebabies can hatch at the same time. Ifthe hen has laid five of six eggs andthey all hatch, the last may be verysmall compared to the first hatched.Check them from time to time to see ifthey are being fed and don't wind upon the bottom of the pile of babies.If you have other lovebirds withbabies, you can switch them so sizesare more even. Try not to overburdenany pair with too many babies. Mostof the stress in breeding is in raisingthe babies. If you don't have otherbabies to switch with, when youcheck the babies put the smallest oneson top of the larger ones. If they stilldon't get fed, wait for the parents tofeed, then remove the larger ones.When the parents feed again, they willonly have the smaller ones to feed.After they have been fed, the largerbabies can be put back. Always keepbabies removed from the nest niceand warm.Keep your nest boxes as clean anddry as you can without disturbing theparents too much. It is helpful to keepsome of the nesting material that falls to the bottom of the cage. This can belaid under the babies for fresh beddingwithout disturbing the nest itself.Lice and mites can be another problemin the nest. To discourage them,we put Sevin powder in our boxesbefore the birds start building theirnests. We also use Eucalyptus leavesin the boxes. Boxes should be thoroughlycleaned and disinfected aftereach clutch, then fresh powderand/ or leaves put in them. If you findbabies or parents with lice or mites,there are sprays that can help. Spraybabies and parents, keeping sprayaway from eyes and mouth. Spray canbe used in the nest but don't get thebedding wet. Powder is better as longas babies are in the nest.Some birds will nest in warmerweather. When babies start to get pinfeathers, sometimes parents will pickthem. This only seems to happen inthe heat, but there is a chance thatparents could do this anytime. Not allparents do this, and sometimes parentswho have never picked babieswill do so in extreme heat. It seemsthere is no definite reason why. Thereare, however, many opinions. If thishappens, we use a bitter spray on thebabies. Most times parents don't likethe bitter taste and will stop. You mayneed to apply the spray several times.Normally, the babies' feathers willgrow back with no permanentdamage.When babies leave the nest, parentswill continue to feed them for abouttwo weeks until they are eating ontheir own. I don't remove babies untilthey have been out three weeks. Bythis time they are sure to be eating ontheir own. If you have more than onenest of babies ready to leave theirparents, most times they can behoused in a cage together. Youngbirds will normally get along together.No matter what we do or try, there isalways a chance of losing babies inthe nest, and most often if has nothingto do with anything we have done.Don't let any of these things discourageyou. Some things must be left tonature, especially when we have doneall we can. We are rewarded when wehave a cage of fat, healthy babies. It'sa wonderful sight. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/728</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 29-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/728/711</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
