<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1155</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:31:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A vi culture: An Underestimated Conservation Tool?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Desborough, Laurella</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Historical records of the development of human civilization indicate that aviculture-the keeping and breeding of birds in captivity-has been practiced for thousands of years. Ancient Indian and Eastern manuscripts depict Indian Ring-necked Parrots (Psittacula k. kramen) and African Grey Parrots (Psittacus erithacus) being kept as pets and relate stories of the "remarkable talking ability" of these birds. The ancient Chinese often kept singing birds such as Pekin Robins (Leiothri:x: lutea) as caged birds. Archaeologists report that Mesa-American cultures kept and even bred macaws in captivity for the production of feathers to be used for trade purposes and ceremonial uses. The present day domestic chicken, derived from the captive breeding of the Red Jungle Fowl (Gallus gal/us) in ancient times, is seldom recognized as a direct and positive result of aviculture.Traditionally birds have been kept in captivity for a variety of reasonsutility purposes, aesthetic appreciation, as companion animals or as sources of amusement or study of their interesting arid unusual behaviors. Indeed, the study and keeping of birds in captivity has contributed much to man's understanding of nature and the world around us-a Darwin's Finch ( Geospiza magnirostris) and the concept of evolution, the Graylag Goose (Anser anser) and Konrad Lorenz's studies into the understanding of animal behavior, and the use of the domesticated Homing Pigeon ( Columba livia) as one of the earliest developed forms of "rapid communication." The keeping and breeding of birds in captivity is not a new concept and the practice of aviculture as a human endeavor has a lengthy established history. Although seldom acknowledged, aviculture has, in many ways, had a tremendously positive impact on mankind and the quality of life as we know it today.Aviculture Offers BenefitsYou are no doubt wondering what this has to do with CITES and endangered species? A lot, both directly and indirectly. While aviculture is not a truly recognized science, aviculture offers a wealth of benefits to the sci- entific and conservation communities. To the scientific community in generating knowledge, information and understanding, the very fundamental quest of all science. And to the conservation community in providing basic and fundamental understanding of avian requirements under controlled conditions including many useful insights, technologies and other benefits to in situ efforts for threatened or endangered species. Established avicultural protocols and husbandry techniques can provide direct benefits to the long term support of wild populations. How? Direct Benefits to ConservationFirst, the establishment of long term self-sustaining captive populations can provide a positive contribution to the global conservation effort in assuring a readily available supply of captive bred avian specimens for the international trade. In this context, captive breeding can dramatically reduce pressures on wild populations. The international trade has been identified as one of the primary factors negatively impacting wild populations of a number of species, particularly parrots.Second, the establishment of long term self-sustaining captive populations can provide a source of captive bred specimens to augment wild populations. While this conservation strategy remains in its infancy and there are many hurdles that must be overcome to make this a real and viable applied concept, the use of captive bred specimens to replenish or rebuild wild populations has already been done successfully-the Peregrine Falcon (Falco peregrinus anatum), the Whooping Crane ( Grus americana), and the California Condor ( Gymnogyps californianus). More can be done in this area if this concept is effectively and comprehensively studied, refined and developed. Ill-fated release programs to date, have more often than not, been the result of ill-fated planning and lack understanding with virtually no input or support from the avicultural community. To categorically dismiss the potential contributions from the avicultural community in establishing long term sustaining captive populations to this end, is not in the interest of a broad based conservation arsenal. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1155</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 3 (1997): MAY-JUNE 1997; CITES 1-2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1155/1134</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
