<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2851</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-07T21:34:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Quarantine and Care of Newly Acquired Birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harrison, Greg J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To properly care for newly acquired birds, and to protect an already established collection, one needs to quarantine, evaluate, and condition the new birds before introducing them into the aviary.Unfortunately, neglect of this principle has come into recognition recently with the catastrophic Joss of several United States collections of birds.All legal birds coming into the country have already been through a 30 day quarantine under the supervision of the United States Department of Agriculture before they are released for distribution. This time period was developed to protect the poultry industry from exposure to Newcastle· s disease. Other diseases might also become evident during this time. However. just because a bird survives this first 30 day period does not mean that it is free from all disease and in healthy condition. In fact, it is often the "quiet" disease (the one which the bird is carrying but is not showing any symptoms of) that actually causes these disasters. Further quarantine by the aviculturist is recommended as top priority when receiving new birds.Since many people are unsure as to what a quarantine entails, perhaps we could discuss a few of the basic principles as set forth in the U.S.D.A. handbooks for quarantine stations, and see how they can be adapted for use on a smaller scale.Basic principles of the U.S.D.A. quarantine include:I. All birds in and all birds out at the same time.2. Supervised by a veterinarian.3. Located at least ~ mile from any other birds.4. Building made of materials to withstand constant cleaning and disinfecting (possibly metal or some other impervious surface). It should also be double screened. 5. Prevent over-crowding6. Proper ventilation (Use of laminarflow air movement)7. Vermin-proof feed storage area8. Separate area for necropsy9. Separate room for washingequipment10. Shower located at entrance withclothes storage area.11. Insect and pest control supplies.12. Adequate water.13. Provisions for incineration of waste.14. Have power cleaning and disinfectant equipment.15. Sufficient stock of disinfectant.  Operational Procedures1. Personnel - access to the facility shall be granted only to persons working at the facility or approved by the veterinarian. All personnel granted access to the bird area shall:a. Wear clean protective clothing and footwear.b. Change clothing and footwear when soiled or contaminated.c. Shower when entering and leaving bird-holding and necropsy areas.2. All psittacine birds shall receive treatment as a precautionary measure against omithosis, in accordance with guidelines of USPHS.3. The facility shall be disinfected between each load of birds.4. It is preferred to have a single bird per cage.5. All birds shall be assumed infected. 6. Cages are screened to avoid birds having contact with stool.7. Cleaning cages:a. First bird is transferred to a clean cage.b. Cage is then placed in live steam or quaternary ammonium chloride solution for at least 30 minutes; then cage is thoroughly scrubbed in hot water and carefully rinsed in clear running water.8. Equipment:Vessels used for preparing the drug-feed mixture and for feeding must be of incorrosive material, such as plastic, heavy glass or stainless steel. These must be kept scrupulously clean.Keeping in mind the above principles, one can adapt their own program. We have a two-step method for new birds at our research facility.Step. I. Birds are held in an enclosed building with laminar flow air movement for the first IO days. Here they are conditioned and given physical examinations, including laboratory work; they are endoscoped, placed on preventative medication and observed closely. Each bird has an individual cage. Our diet is introduced, and the dropping and amount of food being consumed is monitored. Step II. For the next 3-4 weeks, the birds are held in open wire cages, hung under a large shade tree. They are caged together as they will be in the future (pairs, etc.). There is a separate employee responsible for each step of the quarantine.We have developed an outline to follow in evaluating each bird's health and I have included it here. You might reproduce it and use it to check out each new bird that is added to your collection.[ have repeated the outline, but have included specific notations on what to look for in the way of abnormalities, etc. to assist you in establishing a routine.I am also including suggestions in evaluating the aviary as a whole, as well as a possible example of a health certificate to be included with the bird if he is sold or otherwise transferred.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2851</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 2 (1979): APR-MAY 1979; 24-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2851/2835</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
