<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/929</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE: Lorikeet Food Reference List</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Editor's Note: every situation is differentbut the author's birds have enjoyedthese dietary items with no ill effects.Be sure that all natural foods are freeof potentially harmful chemicals.applepearbananapapayagrapefigapricotberriesmangoFRESH FRUITpeachguavaplumpomegranatekiwipersimmonmelon (seeds too!)cherry (de-pit?)citrus (high acid!)DRIED FRUIT(soak overnight to decrease sugar/useliquid for nectar)prunes papayabanana pineapple (high sugar)fig cranberryapricot raisins (high iron level)(Note: many fruits are dried with sulfur)carrotcob cornbeetssquashpumpkinbeanschardgreensVEGETABLESpotatoyamsproutscabbagecucumberbroccolicelery (calming agent)milletfinch mixNUTS &amp;amp;SEEDScanaryparakeet mixsesame anisecumin poppyamaranth quinoisafflower sunflower Oarge lories/(limit quantity) limit quantity)dill hemprapewalnutpecanpeanutmacadamiathistlecoconutalmondfilbertHEALTH FOOD &amp;amp; MISC.honeyprotein shakesamazakebee pollencheeseunsaltedcrackersmeal wormsfruit wormscuttlebonespirulinagranolamaltmaple syrupwhole wheat breadsoy milksmoothiessoaked breadnutritional yeast(adults only)corn wormsveggie juiceswheat germbaby formulacream of wheategg (well cooked)FRUIT &amp;amp; VEGGIE JUICEapple papayaapricot carrotgrape pineapple-coconutV-8 prune (droppings stain)pear citrus (high acid)celeryFLOWERS (especially buds)dandelions cosmospetunia geraniummarigold orchidnasturtium chrysanthemumpansies wildflowers (weeds)sunflower daisylegumes fruit blossomsimpatiens bird seed flowersherbs rose hipsasters chamomilehibiscusADDffiONAL NOTES:1) Lory powder is a main staple food;but all our lories prefer it in nectarform; if water is used, powder will settleand surface becomes thin andweak; we mix powder with qualityfruit juices to prevent settling; papaya,apricot, pineapple-coconut are bestand last longest; apple and orangesour quickly. If your lory runs to thewater dish with dry powder to createhis own nectar he is trying to tellyou something!!!2) In lory feeding, the single most valuabletool is the blender; any and allnutritional foods from sprouts tomulberries can be made into a deliciousnectar in the blender with theaddition of juice, lory powder,molasses, etc.3) Lory diets loaded with sucrose, dextrose,fructose and such sweetenerhave a tendency to make pets hyperactive.Try cooked grains, soakedbreads, rice, beans and veggies freshor juiced.4) Lorikeet metabolism is rapid andheat producing; summer temperaturesare more dangerous than wintercools for most species; a water dishlarge enough to climb into is a must!5) All lory nutrition for captive speciesis still in its infancy; wide variety andextra effort to train your birds ishighly recommended; avoid fallinginto feeding ruts.6) And finally, after mixing up yourown scrumptious blended lory nectar- don't forget to lick the spoon!</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/929</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 5 (1995): SEPT-OCT 1995; 34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/929/910</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
