<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1029</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-10-21T04:39:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Interview With Dr. Luis Baptista</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buckley, Stash</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buckley, Carol Anne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Introduction to Dr. Luis BaptistaMr. Luis Baptista is not a ~ household name among the avicultural set, however, among the ormthologists and researchers world wide, he inspires great respect and credibility. Undoubtedly, Derek Goodwin's hook, Estrildid Finches of the l'(lorld (1982) is well known as the finch aviculturists' "bible." Less known is Dr. Baptista's great contributions to this work.Indeed, we were only dimly aware of his standing in behavioral research when we phoned him several years ago on a question relating to finch behavior. We quickly developed a telephone rapport, and upon hearing of our behavioral observation on video tape, Dr. Baptista grew more and more intrigued. I-le said that on an upcoming trip to Washington D.C. he would like to swing by our place and see some of our videos. We were thrilled.Sure enough, the day of his visit arrived and, upon seeing our video log hooks, he said that we had a goldmine of valuable, previously undocumented (hut, of course, reported) behaviors and vocalizations (of special interest to him). \Y/e distinctly remember that he wanted to see the triangular head display of the Violet-eared Waxhill Uraegintbus granatina. So. of course, we edited it up on the monitor. Dr. Baptista was obviously glad to see that the birds were not just small clots in a huge screen. The behaviors were easily observed and at very close range. \Y/e spent the greater part of the afternoon and evening watching our documentations of finch behavior.Indeed, we must say that Baptista was me perfect houseguest. It was summer time and when we asked him to make himself more comfortable and take his shoes off, sure enough, he did. Being a connoisseur of fine wine, he had brought along a bottle of excellent white wine, and over a dinner of poached salmon, we discussed birds into the night.That was several years ago and we are now proud to consider Dr. Baptista not just a mentor, hut a true friend. He has shown us what to look for in bird behavior, and without his guidance we would not he recording the behaviors we are today, many of which were previously unknown.We suppose the thing that most impressed us about Luis Baptista, is his accessibility. If he does not return our calls promptly, then we can suppose that he is out of the department, if not out of the country. This was once confirmed when we received a postcard from him mailed from Vienna at the summer palace of Emperor Franz Josef. True to form, Baptista commented that the food was excellent and the wine divine. We cannot tell you how many times he has returned our calls from airport phones to answer a question of interpretation of finch behavior.Dr. Baptista is the acadernic's academic-a person who is always willing to listen and learn, despite the fact that he himself is a walking treasure trove of information on a wide variety of subjects. We certainly are not of his standing in avicultural and ornithological circles hut he always takes time to listen to us and Lake us seriously. He has made us feel very comfortable.Following is a short interview we conducted in the hope that you may more fully understand what this remarkable man is all about.Buckley: We know you have been interested in all birds for a long time now, but what prompted this interest originally, especially your interest in estrildid finches'Baptista: My interest in birds began early. My father kept chickens and ducks on our farm. By my eighth birthday my brother, Gaspar, bought me a pair of Budgies and my father added a Strawberry Finch to the menagerie. I heard the finch's flute-like song and was hooked forever.Buckley: We know that in addition to your responsibilities as head of the Department of Ornithology and Mammalogy at the California Academy of Sciences, you are currently working on the dove book for the Birds of the World series.We are glad that you can use some of our input on vocalizations and behavior of estrildid finches for your upcoming book on that subject-an update of Goodwin's Estrildid Finches of the World Many books have come and gone since Goodwin's work but we feel this updated version is the one finch aviculturists have been waiting for. Can you tell us a little about the book and when it can be expected in the book shops?Baptista: The hook is co-authored by Joe Forshaw, Peter Slater, and myself Every species of estrildid will he illustrated in Slater's magnificent plates. Do you know that Slater won an important award for his plates? Hopefully, the hook will he finished within three years.Buckley: On the subject of books, what else do you have to your credit and how might aviculturists obtain them?Baptista: I have co-authored a college textbook with the late professor Carl Wilkie. It is called Tbe Life of Birds, fourth edition, and is available from Saunders College Publishing.Buckley: You have been to New Guinea to do field research on mannikins (Lonchura sp.). Could you share some anecdotes about this experience and other field work in which you have participated?</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1029</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 3 (1996): MAY-JUNE 1996; 50-51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1029/1009</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
