<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/733</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the editor's desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">For those aviculturists who aremutation fanciers, a very interestingletter was received by the Watchbirdmagazine editors in response to Tomand Karen Nemerovsky's article ontheir recent achievement towards twodifferent mutations of the QuakerParakeet (August/ September 1992).john Connan from South Africa hasproduced a mutation similar to theNemerovsky's cinnamon Quaker, onlyhis appears to have a darker basecoloration. He calls this mutation acinnamon. Mr. Connan has gone onestep further and crossed his mutationwith a blue Quaker and the new doublemutation is indeed beautiful. Thefollowing is an excerpt from his letterthat also includes some aviculturaltechniques in breeding this species.Dale R. Thompson, editor. . . I bought some b lue and splitQuake r Pa rakeets in 1988. In theirsecond season with me, a chick washatched with red or amber eyes. Onfeathering, the bird turned out to be alight yellow bird with a lime green tint. It was even yellower on the belly andvery light on the thmat. The flightswere light brown. This brought me tothe conclusion that there was a fairchance that the bird was in fact a cinnamon!And it appeared to be a hen.On this assumption, I mated thisyoungster to an unrelated blue cockbird. My assumption that it was a henproved correct. This pair successfullyproduced a green cock split to blueand also split to - dare r hope -cinnamon!In the meantime, the original pair(split cock and blue hen) was successfulagain and produced two red-eyedcinnamon chicks. Cock parent birdwas mated to a blue hen and this timeproduced two red-eyed cinnamonchicks, both hens split to blue. Wherethe hen from the first pairing had a66% chance of being split to blue, Inow had two definitely split to bluecinnamon hens .My next step was to take the doublesplit cock bred out of the first cinnamonand mate him to one of the cinnamonsplit to blue hens. Both hadbeen bred away for one generation, which to me is acceptable geneticallyspeaking.In the very next nest of five eggs,four chicks hatched with red eyes.Two had a yellowish down and twohad the smoky down similar to that ofa blue chick. I could scarcely containmyself while waiting for the feathersto break through. Eventually, bingo,two light blue chicks," with brownflights - cinnamonblue.The birds are quite exquisite, alovely soft powder blue with light grayunderbelly and almost white throat. Ihave not had them sexed as I do notfeel the slight risk necessary. They willshow me their sex by their actionsbefore the time I want to mate themfor the coming season. I find themajority are prepared to breed at oneyear of age.I breed them in a cockatiel type ofnest box, giving them a few bits ofdried alfalfa stalks to stimulate thebreeding hormones. Their normalcolony-type of stick nest is unsightlyand unsuitable, as it is virtually impossibleto do any type of nest inspection.This aspect is very important to me asone must know what is happening inthe nest!John M. ConnanMarydale, South AfricaeThank you fromMatthew VriendsI would like very much to thank theliterally hundreds of bird friends whoshowered me with get-well wishesand flowers (my hospital room lookedlike a flower shop in less than twodays!) during my six-day stay in JewishHospital of Cincinnati after triplebypass heart surgery in February ofthis year. My heartfelt thanks (fromindeed a heart now well repaired!) goto my wife Lucia and daughter Tanya,who were with me all the time, alsomy brother Cornelius, who came allthe way from Holland, and assisted usfor over a month! Thanks, brother!I further like to extend my thanks and appreciation to my surgeon Dr.Victor Schmelzer, and my cardiologistDr. Donald L. Wayne, who were (andstill are!) brilliant and caring, and whobecame good friends overnight. Ithank and highly endorse the efficiencyof all the some 60 or so peoplefrom the Jewish Hospital in Cincinnatithat may have served me during myhospitalization - they all wereextremely competent, caring, andwell-trained to carry their function!I am particularly appreciative to thedozens upon dozens of you whoprayed for me and showed so muchconcern, especially (just to name afew) my publisher Barroa's and hiseditor and my friend, Don Reis,Michele Earle-Bridges, my illustrator,and my good friends and colleaguesof LIM Animal Farms. Thanks for themany who visited while I was in thehospital (especially Mr. and Mrs. RobKaegi and Dr. Rob Dahlhausen), andto those who made (often many) telephonecalls to me, in particular MargeMaguire and husband, of Capital districtCage Bird Club, Albany- andwhile you may not have found mealways overly effervescent, and full ofconversation (especially the first fewdays!), remember that a talk couldcreate a cough, and a cough can becompared to having a baby. Let meexplain: the most important itemgiven to me after surgery was a littlered, heart-shaped foam pillow. I wastold that when I got ready to cough (Ihad to cough every other hour!), holdit over your chest and squeeze. It wasnot necessary to tell me twice, thesqueezing part I mean. We all haveheard women talk about childbirth,and I would challenge a pain tolerencetest for the delivery of a baby,and the price of a cough. Of course,during the operation the chest bonewas sawed in two, the chest openedwith expanding devices, the heartplaced in ice, a heart/lung machineattached to do the function of theheart, while the repairs are made tothe heart. The heart then is placedback and the chest cavity sewntogether again and wired; consequently the slightest movementresulted in very noticeable pain, butwhen it was time to cough or tosneeze the pain was multiplied ahundredfold!Thank God, it is all over. I'm doingexcellently, am up and about, and fullof joie de vivre! So, again, my dearfriends, I would like to thank all ofyou for your kind support and attention!God bless you all!Matthew M. VriendsPleasant Plain, Ohio •David . .. We'll Miss Youby Mike DeSart, OregonWe'll miss your good advice freelygiven to anyone you thought neededhelp and your offers to help others inneed. We'll miss your contributions toaviculture such as starting the InglebrookCage Company and running itfor many years. We'll miss your articlesand letters in bird magazines andyour thank you notes or calls whensomething was done for you. We'llmiss your presence at many of thebird functions in our area, as well asup and down the west coast. We'llmiss your concern for the many problembirds you took in and cared forthat others had given up on orcouldn't financially take care of. We'llmiss your calls for help with someinformation you had misplaced or forgottensuch as a phone number orhow to get from one place to anotherin the city, yet you could call a greatmany of your 200 or so birds by name.David, the one word that best startsto describe you is congenial, but ittakes what follows just to try and finishyour description: an aviculturist, aphotographer, an entrepreneur, abusinessman, a proud man, a salesman,a gentle man, a promoter, agood friend, and most of all ... a manwho loved his birds and cared forthem to the best of his ability.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/733</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 37-38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/733/716</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
