<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1291</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:34:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Coucals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Holland, Glen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">from a bottle - a loud descending ''Doo-doo-doo-doo." Management My experience with Coucals is based on one African species - the Burchell's, Centropus burchelli, but in discussion with staff at Perth Zoo where they breed the Pheasant-tailed Coucal, Centropus pbasianus, the captive management seems to differ little between species. In aviculture these birds can be likened to giant shrikes. They feed on insects, particularly grasshoppers, reptiles, frogs, small birds, nestlings, and mice. Small prey is swallowed whole and larger prey is held in the foot and tom apart with the beak. Coucals are aggressive and cannot be mixed with smaller species of softbills or seedeaters. They are best kept with larger softbills with a similar nature, aturally they are found in dense thickets, wetlands, tall grasslands, and riverine vegetation. Coucals are also located in gardens with plenty of dense shrubs and hedges. Sexes are alike and they are found either singly or in pairs which aggressively defend their territories against others of their own kind. Their territories are maintained largely through their calls which have been likened to water running such as Grey Hombills and Longtailed Shrikes. Their aviary should include clumps of tall grass and a few clumps of reeds such as napier fodder or Phragmites and Typha (bullrush) which ideally should be planted around a shallow pan of water. Scattered clumps of dense shrubs and will also be utilized by the birds. They have favorite perches in the aviary where they will sit and sun themselves in the early morning. The odd exposed dead tree stump will provide ideal sunning and viewing opportunities. While soaking up the sun, the head and neck feathers are puffed out and the wings drooped. Their flight consists of a few quick wing beats and then a glide. Coucals do bathe but, unlike other birds, they simply walk through the water until their plumage is wet. They are relatively hardy birds which can withstand cold and wet weather for short periods but in severe climates which experience temperatures near freezing for extended periods, coucals will require additional shelter and warmth. As the sexes are alike, the birds should be surgically sexed. Diet In captivity they are best fed on 70% substitute foods such as minced chicken, pets mince, ox heart, and 30% natural food such as crickets, mealworms, mice and various insects. This natural food is particularly necessary if breeding is desired. Breeding In courtship there is no display, but the male approaches the female with food which he gives her and copulation takes place shortly thereafter. The nest is a ball-shaped structure and is constructed of thick blades of grass and twigs, then lined with leaves. It is placed in a dense shrub or creeper. At the Johannesburg Zoo I saw a nest which had been built in a thick clump of grass and was placed about 50 cm (19.5 inches) above the ground. Both sexes incubate the 3-5 white eggs for 16 days. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1291</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 2 (1999): MARCH-APRIL 1999; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1291/1270</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
