<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2925</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-12T15:48:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Visits - Kai Juhl</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It is always exciting to see the varied ways aviculturists cope with the harsh winter climates of the mid-west and northern states. Those of us fortunate enough to live in the warmer environments of the sunbelt states have the luxury of housing our collections outdoors year round at a minimum cost for facilities.Our less fortunate cousins residing in colder climates are generally forced to keep their birds indoors at least part of the year. This requirement tends to limit the size of a collection or drastically inflate the cost of providing adequate facilities.Some aviculturists do quite well under winter conditions, one of whom is Kai Juhl of Glenview, Illinois. Kai is a native of Southern Jutland in Denmark, who moved to the Chicago area at the age of eighteen. Not long thereafter he met and married Jan and they now have three fine children.Kai's interest in birds began while he was a young lad in Denmark. By the time he was ten he was successfully breeding Pigeons in a coop that hung from the wall of his apartment house (Europeans are very sympathetic towards aviculturists ).When Kai came to Illinois he brought with him his bird fancier's enthusiasm, which incidentally Jan has also managed to catch. He purchased his present home with the intention of building "a place of my own, where I can do what I want."The Juhl collection is surprisingly large and broad ranging. There are pheasants and waterfowl, canaries and parrots, finches and quail. Many of these species are wintered outdoors. It may not seem surprising to see pheasants and geese strolling in the snow, but how about a Princess of Wales frolicking about with obvious delight!The main breeding complex consists of a combination indoor/outdoor set-up. A rectangular building, whose indoor flights exit off a central aisleway , is climate controlled on cold winter nights, when the birds are shut inside. During the day the birds are given access to adjoining outdoor flights. This facility is devoted to Psittacine birds, which include Princess of Wales, Red-rumps, .Bourkes, Scarlet-chested and Turquisine Parrakeets.Other outdoor flights are separated from the main complex and house pheasants, quail, and waterfowl. There are several finch flights, which are occupied during the warmer months.During the day the waterfowl are frequently allowed to roam free in the yard.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2925</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 1 (1978): FEB-MAR 1978; 38-40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2925/2909</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
