<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1437</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-13T21:14:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Costa Rica, the Jewel of Central America</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hutcheson, Toby</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Costa Rica, a shaky little country, that lies between Panama and Nicaragua in Central America, is a bird lovers paradise. No larger than West Virginia, Costa Rica boasts an avifauna of more than 830 species, more than that of all the United States and Canada combined. However, like most countries of the world, Costa Rica has some bird and animal species that are not faring too well in the modern world. Such brings me to the story of an outstanding aviculturist, doing his part, and then some, to restore some of Costa Rica's native fauna.Fifteen kilometers from the capital city of San Jose, in the town of Alajuela, is a jewel in avicultural excellence. This facility is dedicated to the breeding and preserving of Costa Rica's native fauna, and the educating of Costa Rican natives as to the importance of preserving its wildlife. This incredible facility is locally known as Zoo Ave.Former Canadian, Dennis Janik, owns and operates this non-profit facility. He began by establishing a business in Texas. Profits from the business were used to acquire the property and build most of the existing aviaries. After several years Janik sold the business and made the final move to Costa Rica.Janik insists this is a wildlife conservation, breeding, and education project, not an Eco-Tourism project. He is dedicated to breeding and reestablishing wild populations of Costa Rica's birds and animals, into areas where they formerly existed.Today Zoo Ave. is funded by gate fees, donations, and money from janik's own savings. The Costa Rican government has made no effort to acknowledge janik's facility or his efforts on behalf of Costa Rica. The Costa Rican government may view Zoo Ave. as a competitor to its National Zoo Simon Bolivar, located in the heart of San Jose. In truth, there is no comparison of the two facilities. Zoo Ave., although only seven years old, has an incredible track record of breeding success. Simian Bolivar has no apparent breeding program. Zoo Ave. has 750 more birds and animals than the National Zoo, and is by far cleaner and better kept than the National Zoo. Although the Costa Rican government has not supported Zoo Ave., the Costa Rican media has supported Janik and his efforts.Dennis Janik first located a private collection of birds in Costa Rica, and acquired this collection before the collectors death. This collection included a large group of Scarlet Macaws Ara Macao. Zoo Ave. now has over 60 Scarlet Macaws in their breeding program.A recent wildlife study by the wildlife department of Universidad Nacional, in Heredia, shows that each wild Scarlet Macaw was worth $500,000.00 U.S. in terms of how much tourism revenue the birds would generate over the course of their lifetimes. Janik tries to educate native Costa Ricans as to the benefits of macaws and other wildlife to the Costa Rican people. Zoo Ave. estimates that in the next 10 years the zoo will produce between 150-200 Scarlet Macaws for release into the wild. Ten to 15 of their progeny are kept for future breeding purposes. All other birds produced will be released, and an attempt made to reestablish them (in significant numbers) in a part of the country where they have vanished as long as 100 years ago.Many of the birds and primates held at Zoo Ave., were formerly kept as pets, many in deplorable conditions by Costa Rican nationals. These animals are now kept in large enclosures with grass, trees, and others of their own species. Zoo Ave. has worked successfully with numerous types of injured and orphaned animals. Zoo Ave. has successfully rescued, rehabilitated, and released many different types of birds and animals including porcupines, Coati Mundi, turtles, caiman, foxes, iguanas, Raccoons, anteaters, sloths, falcons, and many other types of birds. Some injured and orphaned animals, due to their particular injury, cannot be released back into the wild. However, these animals remain in the zoo. They are set up in breeding situations where they have the opportunity to produce healthy young that may be released in the future.Zoo Ave. cares for over 80 species and has already successfully bred over half of these. They have already successfully released Finsch's Conures, Crested Guans, chachalacas, Ruddy Ground Doves, and others into the wild. It is interesting to note that Zoo Ave. houses some blue mutation Finsch's Conures Aratinga .finschi that were donated to the zoo by some local residents. However, the zoo shows no interest in breeding these for release into the wild.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1437</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 4 (1998): JULY-AUG 1998; 46-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1437/1414</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
