<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/599</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cage breeding the Red--cheeked Cordon Bleu (or how I raised Cordon Bleus in spite of myself!)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rishman, Grant</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">When breeding wild species of birds, there are certain procedures that, if followed, will give a better chance of success. Probably the most important are to know the natural environment and diet of the birds. The Red-cheeked Cordon Bleu (Uraeginth us bengalus) is truly a bird of the African tropics. Its natural distribution is from Senegal on the west coast, eastwards to Ethiopia and then south down as far as Zambia. It is found inhabiting semi-arid thorn scrub and cultivated areas near villages. It may be found in very arid country if there is surface water available. The diet is varied but the young are usually fed on green seeds and termites. Now that we have covered their natural environment, let's bring the birds into captivity and see what we have learned from this limited information. We can make the following assumptions: they are particularly susceptible to low temperatures and damp, requiring careful acclimation before they become tough and resilient to our northern hemisphere weather. Even when acclimatized they should not be exposed to temperatures below 60°F for any prolonged period of time. They do not need a dense forest and probably feel happier with just a little cover that will afford them some privacy and security. Being found near villages they are not particularly shy of human beings. The diet fed to the young would indicate that this species breeds after the rainy season. This is one of the most popular of all African waxbills and a description is probably not necessary. However, in case there are any'' parrot people" who are thinking of converting, the description is as follows: four and three quarter inches Jong; bill silvery pink edged with black; forehead, neck, back and wings soft reddish brown; face, throat, flanks and tail sky-blue; lower breast and abdomen pinkish buff; cheek patch crimson; legs and feet horn colored. The hen differs from the male in having the blue areas paler and less extensive and she totally lacks the cheek patch. Their diet in captivity should include a selection of mixed millets with the addition of small canary seed and some of the ''high fat" seeds (e.g. maw, niger, etc.). Green seeding grasses are always popular and should be offered as often as possible. Millet sprays and soaked seed are valuable additions and fresh corn, greenfood, and various fruits are often appreciated. Livefood is essential to keep waxbills fit, mealworrns and their pupae are ideal and may be varied with fruit flies, ants, waxmoth larva, etc. I also offer a small dish con- taining grit; crushed, baked eggshells and shaved cuttlebone. When breeding the birds will also accept a fine grade insectivorous food and eggfood. On alternate days I sprinkle a good vitamin/mineral supplement (I use Superpreen) or nectar powder on the softfood. I have bred this species regularly for three or four years but it is the start of the 1992 breeding season about which I specifically want to give details. If nothing else, it proves that if birds are ready to breed they will raise their family despite any assistance that man attempts to give! The birds in question are a wild caught pair that I "rescued" from a local pet store. They have been in captivity for about four years. This pair is housed in a double breeding cage 48" x 15" x 18" high. Small cedar boughs were attached inside the wire to give some privacy. A wicker nest was filled to just below the opening with fine hay and the birds were given sisal teasings (cut in two inched lengths from a ball of sisal string) to finish the nest construction. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/599</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 5 (1992): OCT-NOV 1992; 69-71</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/599/582</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
