<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2949</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-08T05:05:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Mixed Waterbird Exhibits</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Muller, Kerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Risser, Arthur C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">More than ever before people are keeping birds in captivity, and the number engaging in this activity is increasing at a surprising rate. Aviculture has never been more popular. Although many aviculturists are primarily concerned with aviaries that are functional and do all they can to promote the best breeding results, many keep birds for their aesthetic values. Waterfowl in particular lend themselves to extremely attractive landscaping in the appearance of the pools, lawns and aquatic vegetation that provide a home for the various species of ducks, geese and swans.A good deal of literature has been published on keeping waterfowl in captivity, and on the various aspects of landscaping to enhance their beauty. However it is seldom that any thought is given to including other types of aquatic or semiaquatic birds in the exhibit. With the great number of bird dealers now active in the United States, many other species of birds are often available that would greatly increase the aesthetic value of almost any well landscaped aquatic exhibit. These fall very generally into the following categories:A. Flamingos.B. Coots, moorhens, gallinules and rails.C. Long-legged waders:Ibis, spoonbills, herons, egrets, and relatives.D. Short-legged waders, shorebirds:Stilts, avocets, plovers, oystercatchers, curlews, godwits (and other sandpipers), jacanas.E. Cranes, sunbitterns.All of these birds have been kept for many years in most zoos and many have successfully reproduced in captivity. They can be mixed with waterfowl in large areas. Outlined here are considerations which must be given when an exhibit is planned.FlamingosTwo species of flamingos are occasionally available on dealers' price lists. These are the Caribbean Flamingo, Phoenicopterus ruber ruber and the Chilean Flamingo, P. chilensis (or P.r. chilensis], They have often been housed with small species of waterfowl and will live compatibly with most other birds. Flamingos have long, thin legs which can be broken relatively easily, and if broken cannot be repaired. They should not be housed with large, aggressive swans or geese. Any horizontal barriers such as branches, etc., that they could trip on should be removed from their exhibit. They require a flat lawn area for resting and display, and a pool area, with gently sloping nonslippery sides, for bathing and breeding. One portion of the pool should be up to three feet deep. Fresh water should be introduced regularly. For breeding, at least 10 pairs are required for they are a communal species and require group display stimulation. They require a muddy area near the pool for their communal cone-shaped mud nests, and a flat lawn display area no less than 40' x 60'. Only one species should be kept as they will hybridize if kept together.flamingos can withstand considerable cold if they have access to water that does not freeze. However, in very cold climates they are usually provided with a heated shelter and pool. Suggested diets for the species discussed here can be found in the appendix at the end.Coots, moorhens, swamphens, gallinules, rails etc.The American Coot, Fulica americana, is a very common species in most of the United States. The Common Coot, F. atra, is equally so in Europe. Most waterfowl breeders with large ponds have coots come in as wild birds, and if natural aquatic vegetation occurs in the exhibit, they may breed there. There are a wide variety of swamphen, waterhen and rail species. Most are difficult to keep in an exhibit area and may make attempts to escape. Even when pinioned or wing clipped they can easily climb a wire fence. For this reason they are usually best kept in an enclosed aviary. The larger species will eat eggs, small ducklings and may be aggressive to teal and other small duck species. The smaller rails, such as the African Black Crake, Limnocorax flavirostra or the Lateralis crakes are delightful in an enclosed aviary, and will often reproduce readily.Long-legged Waders (Ibis, spoonbills).There are several species in this group which may be desirable. The larger ones such as the Sacred Ibis or Straw-necked Ibis, can be aggressive to small waterfowl and even prey on baby ducks. On the other hand, the Scarlet Ibis, Eudocimus ruber, or the American White Ibis, E. a/bus, are smaller and will live peaceably with most waterfowl. Although they have been wing clipped or pinioned in open exhibits, they do best and reproduce if kept in an enclosed exhibit where they can fly and set up a colony of stick platform nests in trees or large shrubs. They require protection in very cold weather.Herons, Egrets, Bitterns, and Relatives.There are several species represented in this large family but most are not suitable for housing with waterfowl or other small birds. Most herons, bitterns, etc., will kill ducklings and harrass small ducks. They all require a covered aviary and can...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2949</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 3 (1978): JUNE-JULY 1978; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2949/2933</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
