<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2029</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-26T05:21:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">hand taming your parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vigran, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">When you first obtain your parrot, place him in the area which is going to be his permanent home. Give him food and fresh water and talk to him softly but otherwise leave him alone for a few days. Don't try to play with him and don't let loud action or play occur directly around him. Just leave him alone to get used to his new surroundings. All parrots need to know that their cage is their castle. Every-one needs a place that they can call their own, even birds. It is his cage and his territory and you should not destroy that security.When you are ready to work with your parrot everyday, make sure that his wings have been clipped properly, so that he cannot fly away from you. Let the parrot come out of his cage on his own free will. Don't force him when he is not yet tame and not used to being handled. Some birds come out almost immediately once the door is left open, others take days or weeks to feel secure enough to leave their happy home. If the bird does seem to be timid, leave him alone, maybe even leave the room for a while so he isn't afraid to leave his cage because of your presence. Once he has left his cage let him wander about the top and sides of his cage. Make sure that there is nothing close within his reach that he could get into trouble with, nor anything harmful, or anything that you do not want destroyed. Parrots are quite mischievous and if they feel like it, will chew on anything. On this first trip out of the cage don't force anything on your bird. Eventually, probably within a short period of time, he will go back in his cage. If he fails to return within a given length of time, offer a treat. Usually most parrots can be convinced to return inside when offered one of their favorite treats.Now on to the second stage. The length of time it takes the bird to leave his cage should be a great deal shorter. He remembers that there wasn't anything scary about being out and actually it may have been fun. So let him come out, again on his own. Maybe leave him a toy or something to investigate and play with on top of his cage. Once again don't push him, just let him enjoy himself and return to the inside of his cage on his own (you can tempt him with a treat if necessary).Now, if the bird seems quite comfortable with playing on top of his cage, it is time to start working, but very slowly. Let him out of his cage and let him play for a Little while. Take a perch (very similar if not identical to the perch in his cage) and move it towards him (down low so that it is lower than the bird, so as to not frighten it). Direct the perch lengthwise toward the belly region. Some birds will be terribly frightened by this and others will not. If the bird is frightened he will probably try to fly away from the perch - be patient - just keep moving it toward him slowly. Try to push up, gently under the belly so that he places his feet on the perch. Once this has been accomplished just hold the parrot steady in that position, for a few minutes. Let him down on top of his cage again. Repeat this process the next day - but do not overdo it and intimidate him. Then let him go back into his cage, tempting him if you must with some kind of treat once again.The second perch lesson usually comes easier, however once in a while there are parrots who become stubborn and don't want to cooperate, just keep your patience and work slowly with him.Once the parrot seems completely comfortable with sitting on the perch you can begin to lift him up and move around the room a bit. If the bird flys off just go over and slowly lift him back on to the perch, start walking around again. when you're ready for him to go back into his cage, this time you can place him directly from the training perch into his cage. Let him climb off in his own fashion. Remember, that the more time you spend working with your bird the better trained he will become.Once the parrot is completely comfortable with moving about on the perch you can start working him onto your hand. At this time make sure that your bird is well manicured with no long sharp nails. When the parrot is first getting used to your hand he will cling on tight and even short nails will dig in deep into your skin. Pick him up Nancy finger taming a mealy Amazon.with the perch and then transfer him onto your hand in a fashion that will be easy for him to climb onto. Try not to be shy, the bird can sense your insecurity and it will inturn make him insecure. If your parrot should try and bite you, (remember that most parrots use their beak for balance and will touch with their beak first, before climbing onto an object), or does bite you, then quickly either flick his beak or tap it with your forefinger. Don't hit your bird, don't hurt him, just let him know that you are the boss and that he is not going to get away with intimidating you. Then proceed to working him onto your hand again. Once he is on, follow the same method as you did with the perch. Just let him rest there for a few minutes and then put him down on his cage again. Do this a few times and let him become secure with it. Then you can start moving about the room with him on your hand.So now you have done it, your bird is hand tame. Where do you go from here? Well, the things your parrot can learn to do are endless, so it really depends upon your personal preference. Some people like to have their pet parrot ride around on their shoulder, I have a friend who has a macaw which rides around on the handle of the wheelbarrow while he is working out in the yard. Parrots can learn to pick up things, move things from one place to another, retrieve, and the list goes on and on. Just remember that whatever you want your bird to learn, it must be done with patience. Use common sense and always move slowly whenever you're trying to teach him something new.Your parrot can be your best friend and companion. Keep him healthy with a good variety of food, fresh water daily, and lots of things to entertain him. If he is happy he will always be willing to learn and share with you. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2029</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 4 (1981): AUG-SEPT 1981; 28-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2029/2000</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
