<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/282</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:17:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">On December 10, 1986, the American Federation ofAviculture proposed the establishment of a legitimized selfsustainingpopulation of thick-billed parrots in the UnitedStates. The proposal is presently under consideration by theU.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and AFA has great hopes for itsadoption. The proposal on AFA's part came mainly inresponse to the uncertain status of thick-bills held in captivityin the United States, some of which quite obviouslyhad entered this country illegally and some of which arelegitimate "pre-Act" birds or their offspring. The followingis the first portion of the proposal. Due to its length the fullproposal will be published in parts in consecutive issues ofthe Watchbird. The purpose for publishing this proposal isto demonstrate AFA's keen interest and concern for conservationprograms which it feels are, in light of the situation intoday's world of disappearing habitats and killing of avianspecies as pests, synonymous with aviculture and necessaryin order to ensure the survival of many avian species. AFAsincerely appreciates the interest of the U.S . Fish andWildlife Service in reviewing this program. Needless to say,there are n umerous legal and technical issues which willneed to be resolved if and before such a program could beadopted and implemented. While some of these issues aredifficult ones, AFA is committed to using its energy to findtheir solution. This proposal not only offers the opportunityto create a consortium for the breeding of an endangeredspecies and a vehicle for prevention of illicit trade in thosespecies, but also presents the unique opportunity for reestablishingand sustaining a psittacine species in the wild inthe United States which, according to all reports, is currentlyextinct in that range. The leadership of AFA is extremelyoptimistic that this proposal could be one of the foremostpsittacine conservation projects in the history of the UnitedStates.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/282</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 14 No. 3 (1987): JUNE-JULY 1987; 29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/282/271</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
