<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/604</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Funds 3 Projects: Ocellated Turkey, Hornbill and Halfmoon Conure</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Marais, Eugene R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionThe Southern Ground Hornbill(SGH) and its northern congenor, theAbyssinian Ground Hornbill B. abyssinicus(AGH), are the largest andmost carnivoro us h o rn b ills in the world. These birds inhabit woodedsavanna and steppe, spending mostof the day walking around in searchof small prey animals but taking totrees and rocky outcrops to rest andnest.The SGH is widely distributed inthe moist savanna of Africa south ofthe equator with a total range ofabout 4.5 million sq. km of whichless than 2% extends into SouthAfrica. Outside the limits of SouthAfrica it is not recorded as havingdeclined in its range, but within thecountry over the last fifty years hasdisappeared from about 70% of itsoriginal distribution (Cyrus &amp;amp; Robson1980, Vernon 1986, Tarboton et al.1987). Only land that is provided forgame reserves, forestry or tribal landssupport populations of the birds.They occur in small groups varyingfrom 2 to 11 individuals. In theKruger National Park (KNP), 98% ofthe SGH population are groups ofthis size, 72% are groups of three tofive and 2% is solitary (Kemp 1990).Groups occupy territory of about100 sq. km per group. A number ofreasons have been suggested as contributingto this decline includingdense human settlement, felling oftrees in savanna, forestation of grasslands,direct persecution and indirectpoisoning.Breeding ProgramWith the current status of the SGHin South Africa in mind, an attemptwas made to establish a breedingprogram at the National ZoologicalGardens (NZG). On the suggestion ofDr. Alan Kemp of the TransvaalMuseum, it was decided to harvestsecond hatched chicks, which die ofstarvation in nature. This was agreedto by the National Parks Board and,since the mid-1980s, a handful ofchicks have been harvested in theKNP. Unfortunately only a few havebeen successfully reared. Fortunatelya few adult birds have been acquiredand currently the NZG has two malesand two females, with the strongpossibility of an additional threebirds from Zimbabwe. Two otherinstitutions, namely Umgeni RiverBird Park (URBP) and World of Birdsat Hout Bay, are also currently veryinterested in being part of the jointeffort in breeding the SGH. The URBPcurrently has an adult female.During 1990 a breeding unit wasconstructed at the NZG covering anarea of about 400m of natural bush ina quiet corner of the zoo. The birdshave settled down extremely welland during July 1991 started to excavatea nesting area in a stoney ridge.In the KNP, adult turnover hasbeen estimated at 1.5% per annum,groups fledge on average one chickevery 9.3 years which attain maturityat about six years of age (Kemp1990). With this slow reproductiverate, it is of great importance toestablish as many breeding groups aspossible, thus maximizing production.Both species of ground hornbillhave been bred repeatedly in captivity(e.g. Olney 1985). Observationson captive breeding of the AGH suggestthat captive propagation can farexceed that in the wild, by rearingboth hatchlings and by removingfledglings to produce rapid andrepeated relaying (Penny 1975). </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/604</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 8-10</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/604/587</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
