<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/776</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-13T16:17:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding Spectacled Parrotlets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Robert W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of the seven species of parrotlets they are sexually dimorphic and can in the genus Forpus, the Spec be sexed around three weeks of age. tacled Parrotlets Forpus conspicillatus The males are predominantly are certainly the most brilliantly col- emerald-green with magnificent blueored. Being less than five inches in violet plumage on the wings, rump length and weighing approximately and a ring of feathers completely 25 grams, they are also one of the encircling the eye. This eye ring smallest. As with all Forpus parrotlets, resembles the appearance of glasses or spectacles, giving them their name. The females are lighter green with yellow feathers between the eyes above the nostrils. They have no blue coloring but have a ring of emerald green feathers around the eye. In the wild, they are found in eastern Panama as well as northern and central Columbia. In addition, there are at least two known subspecies of Spectacled Parrotlets. The Forpus conspicillatus metae male has a brighter yellow head, cheeks and under parts and the eye ring is reduced to a thin line of blueviolet feathers above the eye. The female's general plumage is much more yellow than in the nominate species. They range from the eastern Andes of central Columbia to western Venezuela. In Forpus conspicillatus caucae, both the males and females have a heavy, large beak. Although the males have lighter blue-violet on the wings, rump and eye ring than the nominate species, the females' plumage is the same. They are native to southwestern Columbia. Another Forpus parrotlet found in the Patia valley of Columbia was named Forpus conspicillatus pallescens. Since no specimens exist in museums nor has any description ever been published, there is dispute as to whether it is a true...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/776</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 3 (1994): MAY-JUN 1994; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/776/759</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
