<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1194</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Nest Boxes for Indian Ring-ecked Parakeets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vanderhoof, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he Indian Ring-necked Parakeets, being early breeders, need to have their nest boxes cleaned and made ready very early in the season. This can be as early as November or at least by the first of the year.Over the years, I have experimented with a variety of sizes and shapes of nest boxes for these birds. Regardless of the species, curiosity as to finding the "perfect" nest box seemed to have gotten the best of me each Spring. In every case, the changes were to the smaller rather than larger. By smaller, I mean diameter not necessarily depth. With lories, caiques, Australian parakeets or the Asiatics, I have witnessed the acceptance of small enclosures over larger nests in the majority of cases when given a choice.In addition to the size of the actual box, the entrance hole is an important factor. Again, I have watched as birds have chewed the opening to their preference. Obviously, if this opening to their nest is too large, they are unable to "personalize" it without making it even larger than they possibly wish. Therefore, I use screws to attach a plate over the larger-than-necessary hole. This plate consists of a piece of wood that is thinner than the box material so that the birds may readily chew it as they so choose. The opening in this plate is purposely a bit smaller than the size of the bird's body. I feel that the desire to chew this opening is an important aspect to their courtship. I'm not ·stating that they won't go to nest successfully without this opportunity, but rather it may enhance the progress towards accomplishing the ultimate goal of producing young.Presently, the nest boxes I use (as do a few other breeders) measure 9.5in. W x 9.Sin.W x 30 in. H. The top and bottom are attached by screws for easy removal in cleaning. Inside the box, located 4in. below the entrance hole, there is a shelf running horizontally across the front. This allows for youngsters to stand and look out for a day or two before taking off for that maiden voyage. This shelf idea is not mine, I received it from Gene Hall who has proficiently raised Ringnecks, as well as many other species, longer than I've been alive.This particular design size and configuration has satisfied all of the Ringnecks in my collection so far. Until such time as another improvement results in greater success, I have no reason to "fix what isn't broken."Obviously, this is only one persons opinion, resulting from some experimentation. I will hasten to add that when a pair of birds, including Ringnecked parakeets, is ready to go to work, they will usually use whatever accommodation is available as they put into practice their God-given instinct to procreate. + </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1194</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 5 (1997): SEPT-OCT 1997; 12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1194/1173</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
