<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3891</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-17T03:14:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Future of the Thick-billed Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Marshall, Tom</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In 1949, Aldo Leopold—widely acknowledged as the father of wildlife conservation in America—wrote in the highly acclaimed A Sand County Almanac that he had discovered the noumenon of the Sierra Madre in the Thick-billed Parrot. (Noumenon is a philosophical term referring to the intangible essence of material things—the “something” without which a thing would seem lifeless.)
Leopold wrote:
“He (the Thick-billed Parrot) is a discovery only because so few have visited his haunts. Once there, only the deaf and blind could fail to perceive his role in the mountain life and landscape. Indeed, you have hardly finished breakfast before the chattering flocks leave their roosts to perform a sort of morning drill in the high reaches of the dawn. Like squadrons of cranes, they wheel and spiral, loudly debating with each other the question whether this new day creeping slowly over the canyons is bluer and more golden than its predecessors, or less so. The vote being a draw, they repair by separate companies to the high mesas for their breakfast of pine seed—on the half shell. They have not seen you.”
[For the full article and images, please continue to the PDF]</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3891</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 52 No. 2 (2025): AFA Watchbird Fall/Winter 2025; 44-47</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
