<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/731</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Keeping and Breeding Bee-eaters</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">de Ruiter, Maarten</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bee-eaters (Family - Meropidae) areimported quite frequently into Europe. The African species of bee-eaters are themost commonly offered. Privateaviculturists rarely acquire and breedthe bee-eaters because this group ofbirds have a reputation as being "difficult"to keep and reproduce. I feel thatbee-eaters are as easy to keep as manyother softbills when the followingpoints are taken into account. DietBee-eaters are insectivorous and it isdifficult to feed them a diet other thanlive food. The species I have beeninvolved with were fed mealwormsand crickets in large volume. Theywere also given a mixture of insectfoodand then strips of beef whichwere occasionally eaten by accident.Other food items given to these birdswere spiders, wax-moths, grasshoppers,flies and, of course, bees.HousingBee-eaters are tropical birds andmust be kept in heated enclosuresduring the winter in very cold elimatedareas.Nesting HabitsLike motmots and many kingfishers,bee-eaters nest in earthen walls. If oneis planning to breed these birds, anearthen or mud wall or bank must firstbe constructed.In Walsrode Birdpark in the northernpart of Germany, I was privilegedto care for several species of motmots.These included the European (Meropsapiaster), White-throated (M. albicollis),Little (M. pusillus), Cinnamonchested(M. oreobates) and Black (M.gularis) bee-eaters. Three of thesespecies made breeding attempts whileI was there.The first was the European Beeeater.It is the northern-most speciesand its breeding grounds are mainly insouthern Europe. In the northerncountries like Germany and the Netherlands, only a few successfulbreedings are accomplished. At Walsrodea colony of six birds was kept ina large European free-flight aviary.This exhibit also housed Europeanrollers, avocets and ruffs. We constructedan artificial nesting wall especiallyfor the bee-eater. Although theylaid eggs, no successful breedingstook place. Because the wild population of European Bee-eaters goessouth during the winter months, weremoved the captive colony from thefree-flight and housed them in heatedenclosures.The Little Bee-eaters were also keptin a colony of six birds. Being an Africanspecies, they were housed in anaviary in the Tropical Hall. This enclosuremeasured 6m x 3m x 2.2m high(19-1/2 ft X 10ft X 7-1/4 ft high). Theyshared this enclosure with a pair ofSuperb Sunbirds and a group of Kittlitz'sSand Plovers. In the back of theenclosure a 6m x 1m x 1.5m high (12ftx 3-1/4 ft x 5 ft high) artificial wall wasconstructed in which were placed severalnesting pipes. Two pairs of LittleBee-eaters made use of these nestsbut after about a week threw theirincubated eggs out of the nest. Thereforesuccess was not achieved.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/731</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 35-36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/731/714</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
