<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1761</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-13T14:58:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Guide To Macaws as Pet and Aviary Birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jordan, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A Guide to Macaws as Aviary &amp;amp; Pet Birds is a welcome surprise - one is not accustomed to finding so much material in one book. And the amount of color is impressive - indeed, the book contains about 250 plus photographs (so many that l lost count) with many a full page photos, including one for each extant species. Even if you don't read, this book is a joy because of the fantastic photos.There is a very interesting introduction that briefly touches on the number of species and something about the current status of each in the wild and in captivity - this information is greatly expanded, bird by bird, in the SPECIES section. Also in the introduction is an account of the history, mythology, and legend of the macaws. It shows how important the macaws have been to the native peoples over the centuries. Lndeed, in some cases, the macaw achieved "holy" status and was revered as a "Sun God." Although these pages were among my favorites, the majority of you practical people will, no doubt, derive more "hands on" information from the rest of the book.The book is organized into three main sections, MACAWS IN TllE AVIARY; MACAWS AS PETS AND COMPANIONS; and SPECIES. A look at part of the table of contents is in order:Section I: Macaws in the Aviary -Choosing Good Breeding Stock-Quarantine-Handling Macaws - Restraint and Transportation-Aviary Design and Construction-Nutrition-Breeding-Artificial Incubation-Handrearing from Day One-Weaning-Diseases and Disorders Common to MacawsAbove are the subheads, each of which is broken down into great detail with loads of information. For example, under "Breeding" you'll find this further break down:There is nothing about "macaws in the aviary" omitted. You can get started as soon as you absorb Section I.• Sex Determination • Pairing Birds for Breeding • Mate Compatability • Egg Laying and Parent Incubation • Infertility • Parent Rearing • Hand Rearing • Record Keeping • Positive Identification •Artificial Insemination - is it Possible? ·A Note on Hybridization.Section 2: Macaws as Pets and Companions-Preparing for Your New Pet Macaw-Housing Your Pet Macaw-Feeding Your Pet Macaw-Illness and Disease of Pel Macaws-Behavioural Problems in Pet MacawsAnd each of the above subheads has full explanations of the specific subjects. You'll know how to feed and house your pet macaw after reading this section- and a lot more besides.Section 3: SpeciesEvery known species of macaw is listed under this section with a full range of information including:Species Name • Other Names • Description • Average Length • Weight Range • Approximate Breeding Age • Average Clutch Size- Average Incubation Period •Average Fledging Age • Aviculture and Status in Capivity • Distribution and Status in the Wild • Regional Variations • Captive Mutations• Author's Comments.The book was edited and published in Australia and has been converted to the British/Aussie awkward spellings but don't let that throw you-Rick Jordan is a first class American aviculturist with enormous experience. All that experience comes...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1761</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 30 No. 4 (2003): Fourth Quarter 2003; 33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1761/1736</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
