<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1785</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:14:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">PEKIN ROBINS... Infmmation on their Care and Breeding</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Karsten, Peter</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he following notes have been prepared to assist participants in the Pekin Robin breeding consortium. Additional information is available for the breeding of food insects. Notes on ailments and treatment are still in preparation. Findings in this essay are based on three years of breeding Pekin Robins with 17 nesting and 27 successfully raised offspring.Biological ConsiderationsThe Pekin Robin (Leiotbrix lutea) also called Red-billed Leiothrix, Chinese or Japanese Nightingale belongs to the Order of Passeriforrnes (perching birds) Family of Timaliidae, the babblers. The Pekin Robin is a typical soft-bill bird in the context of aviculture and requires corresponding diets and care differing from seed eaters, such as finches, sparrows, quails, cloves and psittacines (parrot family members often referred to as hook-bills by bird fanciers).Pekin Robins have been popular cage birds for close to 100 years. They are very colorful, fine singers, active and hardy, long lived birds which do well in captivity. Their cheerful behavior and intelligence make them delightful birds to own. The species is long lived with records approaching 20 years in captivity.Birds, mammals, and reptiles are at times grouped according to their predominant food intake, for example: carnivores (meat eaters), herbivores (plant eaters), insectivores (feeding on insects, spiders and other arthropods), frugivores (fruit eaters), nectarivores (feeding on nectar) and omnivores Cf eecling on a mixture of several food groups). Pekin Robins lean towards the insectivore and fru-givore group, but consume constituents of other food groups as well.This becomes an important point of consideration to accommodate the dietary and behavioral needs of the birds and the daily care routine. Pekin Robins must have a varied diet with live insect supplements, particularly for the breeding of this species. Pekin Robins can be observed picking up "finch" seeds, however these are not suitable as a source of essential nutrients. Pekin Robins can not shell seeds and do not have a crop like seed-eaters to aid pre-digestion, or a very muscular stomach, partially filled with grit, to break down the seeds to digest them effectively. A Pekin Robin may pick up some seeds, hut passes them through for the most pan and would in time starve to death, unable to digest them. Plants count on this by luring soft-bill birds to their colorful fruits to ingest the fruit, but then to pass out the seeds, unharmed, for dispersal to produce new plants elsewhere. Germinated seeds are on the other hand a more suitable food source.Another consideration is the species' natural way of food gathering as an insectivore and to an extent as a frugivore. lt requires constant search for insects and ripe fruit within a habitat of great diversity in plant and animal species and habitat form. Pekin Robins live in the underbrush of mountain forests with small clearings and creeks. They will also visit cultivated lands such as gardens and fruit plantation to search for food. Their natural behavior results in relatively long periods of food gathering interrupted with short rest periods.To accommodate this and to enjoy observing their fascinating behavior we must provide them with larger enclosures with a simulated bush habitat. Pekin Robins and most other soft-hill birds usually make a pitiful display in barren, small conventional cages. Their need for activity causes them to display, and unfortunately to acquire, stereotypical behavior, by going through a short, constantly repeated routine of movements. In addition, they often damage their otherwise splendid plumage, which they keep in immaculate condition in a suitable environment.Pekin Robins live on the southern slopes of the western Himalayan mountains to the east of China. They can be found in mountain forests to an elevations of 2700 m, which makes this species relatively hardy for an "exotic" cage bird. Pekin Robins can tolerate subfreezing temperatures. provided they have been conditioned to the proper sequence of seasonal changes and that they have a large, partially covered and wind protected enclosure. They must always have access to unfrozen food and water. Birds could perish if they do not have water and food available to them for more than 24 hoursIdeally the outside aviary is connected to an indoor shelter with temperatures above freezing. The food is offered in this space to habituate the birds to come inside so that they can be locked in if particularly windy, wet and cold weather is predicted. Cold weather causes additional stress to a bird in marginal condition, during molt, following a demanding breeding season, and, of course while fighting any form of illness. There is no incentive to establish durability records. The author routinely brings the birds into protected shelter if outside temperatures drop below freezing. Nonetheless, the climatic tolerance allows us to create a well planted, unheated outdoor habitat for the birds, less expensive to construct and maintain than environments for other exotic bird species.The creation of a close to nature aviary habitat can be looked at as an art form in itself, one that is aesthetically rewarding, educational, entertaining to the observer, and highly beneficial to the well-being of the birds. A natural well planted environment of sufficient size makes regular cleaning and maintenance a small task since the proportioned amount of space per bird is relatively great. This is important as it eliminates disturbances during the nesting period.Establishment of a Breeding Pair111e sexual differences in the plumage and body are very slight. They may be obvious to the owner and experienced aviculturist, but not on first sight. Sexing this species by their appearance alone is not reliable.Generally the male has a distinct white edge on the two extend- eel upper tail coverts, which look like shorter tail feathers. The female has a relatively finer line or no white edge marking on these feathers. One must be careful not to draw conclusions if the white markings are not visible. The particular feathers may have fallen out. They seem to be not as strongly seated as the true tail feathers and birds which have been in transit may have lost them. Furthermore, some females show rather prominent white markings.Pekin Robin keepers use another appearance clue, which is the facial patch of whitish gray around the eye region. It is more distinct in the male and stands out when looked at from a distance, while it is less defined in margins in the female. This only works if one is quite familiar with the images or if both sexes can be seen side by side. Beyond this the male is slightly more colorful.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1785</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 2 (2002): Second Quarter 2002; 56-68</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1785/1760</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
