<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3204</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-30T12:46:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">2011 AFA Convention Speakers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Keynote Address: Dr. Susan Clubb: 'The Past, Present and Future of Aviculture and the Pet Bird Industry" Fran Andersen• Lineolated Parakeets: A Breeder's Perspective On Maximizing Pet PotentialAlycia Antheunisse• The Perfect Match: Ensuring The Right Parrot For The Right PersonEric Antheunisse• Parrot Breeding For The American Pet TradeJohanna "Jeleen" Briscoe, DVM, Dipl.ABVP (Avian)• The Animal Welfare ActAnd How Regulations Could Affect YouSusan L. Clubb, DVM, Dipl. ABVP(Avian) Keynote: The Past, Present And Future OfAviculture And The Pet Bird Industry• Parrot Relinquishment In The United States Jason Crean• Using DNA To Identify A Species• Mutations: How They Get From One Generation To AnotherKashmir Csaky• Understanding Reinforcement And Punishment:Why Does My Parrot Still Do That?Steve Duncan• Nursery Management For Rearing Psittacines• Wild Parrots Of Southern California Dann Dunst - ,• GalliformesM. Scott Echols, DVM, Dipl. ABVP (Avian)• Using Nutritional Supplements To Manage Avian Diseases• What Are We Really Feeding Our Birds?Walt Frey, PhD• Breeding And Keeping The Red-vented Cockatoo -A Model For Successful And Fun AvicultureJames D. Gilardi, PhD• World Parrot Trust - The Flyfree CampaignSharman Hoppes, DVM, Dipl. ABVP (Avian), • When A Dilated Proventriculus Is Not POD1-. Annette Howard•· • Exhibition Of Parrots And Finches• "Jewels In Aviculture" -African Rnches Hildegard "Hilla" Niemann• Beauty Lies In The Eyes Of The BeholderRainer Niemann, PhDJ • From The Wild Into Our Homes f/ Rebecca O'Connor Falconry, Conservation, And The Future Lyrae Perry• Eat Or Be Eaten - The Business Of BirdsMatthias Reinschmidt, PhD• Breeding Rare MacawsAt The Loro Parque Fundaci6nLinda Rubin• The Ethology Of Australian Parrot Flocks And Captive BehaviorsChris Shank; Living With Companion Free Flying CockatoosRobin Shewokis' • Enriched And Organized ... What A Concept!• Addressing Behavioral Issues.,1 With Enrichment Strategies5.,. Nancy Speedr • The CaiqueIan Tizard, BVMS, PhD, ACVM• Update On Progress On Avian Bomavirus And Proventricular Dilatation Disease~ • The Scarlet Macaw Genome ProjectMargrethe Warden• Lories In American AvicultureLeslie Woods, DVM, PhD, DACVP• A Survey Of Avian Diseases Seen At The California Animal Health And Food Safety Laboratory System; Case Studies </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3204</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 37 No. 4 (2010): Number 4  2010; 24</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3204/3188</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
