<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/729</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Ring That is a ]ewell</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hall, Gene</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Well, you started out with budgiesand in time moved up to cockatiels.Where does the avicultural trail leadme now, you ask. You feel ready tomove up to the "big birds". Which oneyou ask. There is a solution to youryearning that has a "ring" to go with it.Psittacula krameri manillensis. Now,what the heck is that? It is a beautiful,graceful bird commonly known as anIndian Ring-necked Parakeet that willprovide you with joy and a challenge.In some parts of the world it isreferred to as a Rose-ringed Parakeet.It occurs in central Africa, Afghanistan,Burma and India. The Africanform differs slightly in size and colorand is not seen very often. The onethat is raised in great numbers comesto us with an Indian background. Insize, it is somewhat larger than thecockatiel and has a very long, slendertail. The body is a bright green incolor, accented with the upper mandiblea deep red and the lower mandibleblack. The adult male has whatcould be described as a black moustachestarting with the black lowermandible and extending partiallyaround the neck. This is connectedaround the back of the neck by a ringof rose. The hen, while not a timidsort, allows her mate to be the gaudy one and thus goes without the ring.It is quite easy then to determine thesex of specimens when they becomeadults entering their third year. If youacquire younger specimens, insist thattheir sex be determined by one of themany methods available. Checkingthe pelvic area as well as other visualinspections is at best only half right.Their plumage is smooth and even,the tail long and graceful and they set·the perch in an upright manner. Theyare easily available and not expensive.Now really, aren't you just a little interestedby now? Okay, let's move on. Asyou become involved with them, youdiscover that they also come in othercolors that occur in captive breeding.A bright yellow lutino with red eyes, alovely blue and a snow white albinowithout the ring on the neck. Sure,these will cost more but they will providea challenge for you in the future.Assuming you have learned your geneticsin the budgies and cockatiels,you are ready to apply the same ruleshere.While the males don't acquire thering-neck coloration until about the27th month, they often will raiseyoung in the spring of their secondyear. Ring-necked Parakeets are one of the first to go to nest each year. Insouthern California, they often lay inJanuary. They seem to quit when theweather becomes warm. With anextended cool spring, they will oftenraise two clutches of three or fouryoung. Success has been achieved bycolony breeding; however, it has been my experience that more youngstersare produced when pairs are housedseparately. I am presently using a nestbox that is 12" x 12" x 32" high. Sixinches of dampened pine shavings areplaced in the nest in December.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/729</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 31-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/729/712</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
