<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/507</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-08T05:03:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">American Zoo Consortium Papua New Guinea Project Report</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, Ron</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Risser, Arthur C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">''Wonders from a celestial paradise.. best known for their extraordin·ary courtship plumage ... birds ofparadise allied with the relativelydrab, short-plumbed 'architects' and'artists' - the bower birds haveinspired fascination since their discoveryby Europeans in 1522."Thomas Gillard wrote these eloquentphrases in his book Birds ofParadise, 1964, which bringstogether many scientific expeditions,a true labor of love, searching for thesecrets of these birds. A total of 2,500books and scientific papers have beenwritten about these inspiring birds;still, little is known about breeding,ecology, parental care and evengeographical distribution of somespecies. There are 4 3 known speciesof birds of paradise, 33 found inPapua New Guinea, 12 of which areendemic.New Guinea, the second largestisland in the world, is divided politicallyinto two countries. The westernhalf, Irian Jaya, is governed by Indonesia.The eastern half, Papua NewGuinea, became independent fromAustralian rule in 1975. The Melanesianpeople have literally developedfrom the stone age to the electronicera in two decades. Birds of paradiseare woven culturally into the socioeconomicstatus of the over 700tribes throughout the island. Today,birds of paradise are still an importantaspect of their lives and rituals. Singsings (ceremonial festivals) bringtogether the diverse tribes, and clansmenare fully decorated in ornateheaddress, displaying plumes frombirds of paradise and other speciessuch as...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/507</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 4 (1989): AUG-SEPT 1989; 18-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/507/491</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
