<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/607</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE: Two Polytelis as Pets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Amongst the Australian parakeets,the Princess of Wales and the RockPebbler have a reputation for peacefulpersonality and trust of humanswhich has allowed them to carve outa distinctive niche in the Americanpet market.Even in the wild where especiallythe Princess can be elusive and difficultto spot, reports confirm thatthese species may indulge in entertainingantics only a stone's throw from human workers or campsites.As captive-reared, hand-fed babies;these long-tailed clowns can be considered"sleepers" in the pet trade.They are attractive, quiet, nondestructiveand non-aggressive additionsto any home or aviary; and infact may become avian companionsto single cockatiels, budgies, pyrrhuraconures or gentle, small parrots.There is a growing trend in the petbird trade across the U.S. these days.It is a move toward keeping hand-fedpsittacines in full-flight natural environmentsin the home-be it an aviary,bird room, greenhouse or outdoorsummer walk-in cage. Many times thechoice of avian species for theseenvironments are those hookbillswhich acquire an independent attitudeafter weaning and demand littlehands-on affection from theirowners. They are often kept in unrelatedpairs and may breed, literally,in full view of their keepers.As these parrots do not fit any ofthe "cuddle-bunny" categories, theyallow the pet owner freedom fromresponsibility for providing fulltouch and petting input for the birdand freedom to have an expandedcollection of psittacines without neglectingany single pet. Princess ofWales and Rock Pebbler Parakeets fitdelightfully into this category of aviculturalpet.Princess of Wales, commonlycalled Princess Parakeets, are sleek,pastel packages of avian personalitywhich will naturally pitty-pat aroundthe floor curiously peering into everycorner and sampling bits of grit,spilled seed or fluff. In fact, many ofthem seem to prefer hanging outwith the doves on the ground of amixed aviary. They delight in grassbundles, picked flowers, greens andseeds offered in flat pie pans, logs,crumbly material, and driftwood playitems encourage them to activelyexplore and taste, though most seemto chew little. After such a journeyaround their grounds, capped off bya playful bobbing and mumbling totheir reflection in a stainless seedcup, one will spot them drowsilytucking their head behind a wing andsettling in for a nap - while the restof the aviary parrots scream and carryon around them. Sometimes I worrythat the Princess Parakeets are notfeeling well because they seem tofluff their feathers and doze often andat the oddest times.In the living room, our two pets,Hansel and Gretel, would have amorning run around legs of furniturepicking at tufts of carpet or the like.They sometimes will hop or jump-flapabout as if chasing their tails, utteringlittle squeals of delight. Desert birdsby nature, Princess tend to avoidexcessive bathing; some must bechased around with a spray bottle fora weekly bath. Lyrae Perry, a notedSouthern California Australian parakeetbreeder, observed that youngPrincess will use a water dish forquick dips, but that adults preferoverhead misting systems whichthey use, wings spread, much likecockatiels. "Even the breeder Princessare friendly," she emphasized,"though they do not like beingtouched with hands. They prefer topay a visit, beg for a nice goody andbe on their way."There are exceptions, of course.Male Princess are often bolder andmore demanding of attention fromtheir owners, flying to arms andshoulders for a nuzzle as if to ask"what entertainment do you offerme now?" Males ar-e also the moreconsistent vocalizers, having attractivevarieties of whistles, clicks, andtweets to go with a tiny computerlikevoice. The learning of wordsseems to depend upon each individualparrot's bond to its owner and theamount of training, much as withmale cockatiels. The non-verbal communicationlevel is high, however.Males will often greet their ownerwith a flurry of bobbing and noisemakingmuch akin to their joyfulcourting dance- tiny foreheadfeathers fluffed, eye pupils flashing,feet prancing back and forth sidewayson the perch.Such displays, along with theirextremely keen flight skills, makethese Australians a joy to watchwhen given plenty of room toactively maneuver. Their intelligentdirect flying habits make them perfectparrots to negotiate inside takeoffsand landings without stumblingor crashing into glass windows andunstable perch spots.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/607</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 18-20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/607/590</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
