<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1693</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:15:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Start to Indian Ringnecks in the Pet Market</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Powell, Gwen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Whether you are going to attempt to breed your own pet, purchase young unproven birds, or purchase a proven pair, there are many things you should consider. Only you can answer the following questions because the answers depend on your own circumstances:• Where are you going to house your breeders?• Do you have sufficient room?• Is the temperature suitable year round?• Will there be too much noise?• Is the area easy to keep clean?• Is the area secure to keep the birds in and the predators out?• What can you afford? Can you afford the:• Cost of proper housing?• Cost of proper food?• Cost of vet bills?• Cost of daily time?• Initial cost of the birds?• Where will you acquire your stock?• How will you market the birds you do not keep?My Story and How it Might Relate to YouMy knowledge of bird breeding was very limited when I bought my first pair of Indian Ringneck Parakeets. I really wasn't interested in breeding birds. I just wanted a blue male Ringneck as a tame pet - one that would hopefully talk. This desire was based solely on a picture I had seen in a book. I was your typical potential bird client. After raising a few batches of love birds, I believed that any parrot hand raised properly could make a great pet. The Indian Ringnecks were the right size range I wanted and I was attracted to their sleek beauty. I did not really care if I acquired a Plum-head, Alexandrian, or Indian Ringneck. I jut knew I wanted to hand raise the bird myself and did not want to purchase through a pet store. Why do I even bring this into the discussion? Because I want to highlight how a breeder responds to potential buyers makes a huge impact on the success of selling into the pet market.During the weeks I spent calling breeders listed in the back of Bird Talk, I also spent time scouring book stores and libraries (pre-internet access). The common theme was that the libraries had very limited texts with none devoted to Psittacula and book stores had even less. Only one breeder I called explained the difference between the species. She also explained what she had available. None of the breeders tried to call me back when I left a message even when I said to call collect and gave hours I would be available. Needless to say, the breeder who took the time with me has remained a good friend. Our bird breeding relationship has been beneficial to us both over the years. This all occurred 16 years ago.Now that I am the breeder, I try to be patient and remember my ignorance and frustration purchasing my first bird. I use this knowledge to better serve the people who are my prospective clients.Since a blue baby was outside my set budget at the time, I agreed to buy three green babies. During my time searching for my bird, I also found other people who wanted a hand raised Indian Ringneck for a pet. The breeder I purchased these babies from also offered me an older proven pair for a very reasonable price. She explained that they could produce the blue baby I wanted and they could pay for themselves in the first breeding season. I did not jump on the offer; I told her I would get back to her. What were my answers to the questions I raised earlier?My family thought it would be a fine idea as long as I remembered this was a hobby and not a business. The moment I try to make a hobby into a business, I am miserable.My husband and kids went to work building an aviary of my design. I read all I could find at the library. It had flaws but it was safe for the birds and never caused a problem in the 10 years I used it. It could house one pair of breeding ringnecks. It was six feet high, six feet long, four feet wide with a safety area for me to enter, check the nest box and feed the birds without disturbing them. It had adequate shelter from heat and rain for southern California.The breeder was stunned when I called her and asked when would be a convenient time to pick up the birds. She took the time to give me as much information as possible to ensure that the birds would be taken care of properly. The blue cock was the son of her first blue Indian Ringneck and the hen was green/blue. Even though it was late in the breeding season they gave me two green babies that first year. All five of the babies I raised that year became great pets. All talked in their first year although the one I kept, Mr. Toad, gave up talking at about three-years-old.But Mr. Toad is a "bullet proof' pet. He doesn't get upset when he is ignored for long periods. He is not very messy as far as birds go. He loves people - everyone. Mr. Toad will not bite a human even when I take him to kindergarten classes and the five-year-olds pull his long tail. He is the perfect example of a bird you want to keep around to demonstrate the best qualities of a pet Ringneck. He sells birds for me. Everyone wants a "Mr. Toad." </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1693</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 1 (2002): Fourth Quarter 2001; 58-61</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1693/1670</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
