<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/933</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question #1: My cockatiel pass- Question #2: It has been suggestedes whole, undigested seeds in the to me by several aviculturists to add astool. I have not changed his seed brand smaU amount of Nolvasan® to theand he otherwise seems fine. Why drinking water of my birds. Is there anydoes this happen and what do I need benefit that you know of in doing so?to do about it? It is even a problem? Can it be harmful?M. Cartwright, CA. S. Robinson. New York, NY.Answer#1: The presence of whole Answer #1: The addition ofseeds in the stool is never normal and Nolvasan® (chlorhexidine) to drinksuggestsa problem with either the ing water has been suggested by manyproventriculus (glandular stomach) or as a method of controlling unwanted bacventriculus(gizzard) where seeds are soft- teria and yeast from building up in theened and crushed. Causes of proven- drinking water. The primary benefit intricular and ventricular disease include doing so is to the seller and the manbacterialinfections (gram negative ufacturer of the product. Used accordEnterobactermegabacteria and spiro- ing to the directions, chlorhexidinechetes), fungal infections, parasites would not be harmful. However, there(giardia and roundworms), proven- is no substitute for proper sanitation.tricular dilatation syndrome (also known Clean, scrub, and sanitize water and foodas PDS or Macaw Wasting Disease) containers daily. If tap water is used asand rarely cancer. A thorough physical your source of drinking water, let theexam including fecal cultures, radi- water flow for one minute before usingographs, and possibly surgical biopsy, to clear stale water from the pipe.may be needed to determine the cause. James M. Harris, DVM.Nicole VanDerHeyden, DVM Dipl. Oakland, CA.ABVP. Indianapolis, IN. Answer #2: The addition ofAnswer #2: The passing of whole and N ol vasan ® or one of the genericundigested seed in the feces is gener- chlorhexidine products to the drinkingally an indication of hypermotility of the water of birds, is thought to decrease thegastrointestinal tract in which the seed number of bacteria and prevent theis passed so quickly through the gas- occurrence of the yeast Candida albicanstrointestinal tract that there is no time in birds. Whether this actually works atfor digestion to take place. Abnormalities the small amounts that are added to thein the crop in which food storage time drinking water, is fairly unlikely. Whenis altered can also be associated with it is used at small amounts it is not harmpassingwhole undigested seed. ful to birds, but once again the benePancreaticinsufficiency can be a cause fit is extremely questionable. A numberas well. of aviculturists through the years haveSince all of the above mentioned added chlorhexidine to handfeedingconditions can be harmful to the bird, formulas in an effort to reduce theit is advisable to have your bird exam- possibility of Candida overgrown inined by an avian veterinarian to deter- babies. As the amount of chlorhexidinemine the severity of the problem. that is added varies with the hand-Robert B. Altman, DVM Dip!. ABVP. feeder, it is anecdotely thought to be ofFranklin Square, NY. benefit in some situations. ThroughAnswer #3: The passage of undi- cleaning and rising water bowls with agested seed in the stool is not a normal solution such as bleach, is a betterfinding. I strongly recommend that the method than the use of chlorhexidinebird go to a veterinarian with special in the drinking water.interest in avian medicine and have a Amy B. Worell, DVM Dipl. ABVP. Westmedical assessment and workup. Be sure Hills, CA.to collect fresh feces and bring them toyour appointment so that they can bechecked.James M. Harris, DVM.Oakland, CA.Question #3: Could you pleaseexplain all of the diagnostic tests that canbe performed with a bird's droppings?M. Judge, NM.Answer #1: Bird droppings, a mixtureof both urinary tract and digestivetract waste can have great diagnosticvalue. The feces can be checked for theova (eggs) of intestinal worms and fora variety of gastrointestinal parasites. Theorganism that is responsible for psittacosis(Parrot Fever) can be screened forand isolated in culture from feces if itis present. Pathogenic (disease producing)bacteria can be cultured fromthe stool as well as yeast. Blood, whichcan be the result of a variety of insultsfrom tumors to infections to toxic substances,can be detected from fecalanalysis.The color of the droppings is anindicator of health and disease. Changein color may indicate infection, liver disease,or pancreatic dysfunction. Changein consistency is also significant. The liquidportion (urine) with its associateduric acid crystals (the white powderymaterial) can also be analyzed. Tests andcultures for renal (kidney) functionand disease can be done as well. Bloodin the droppings is significant and maysignal tumors or heavy metal poisoning.Testing the droppings is a most usefulnon invasive procedure.James M. Harris, DVM.Oakland, CA.Answer #3: The droppings of abird originate from both the urinary systemand the gastrointestinal or digestivesystem. The cloaca, the common sac inwhich the droppings are depositedprior to their release from the body, alsois the endpoint for the reproductive systemand its products, as well.A large variety of diagnostic testingcan be performed on the droppings ofa bird. A partial list is included here.• Fecal parasite examination- determinesthe presence or absence ofinternal parasites (worms) andprotozoa (single celled organisms)that can parasitize a bird's body.• Cultures and gram stains - determinethe presence of bacteria,fungi, and yeast in the intestinaltract. These organisms can eitherbe part of the normal flora (bacteria),opportunistic organisms, orpathogens.• Fecal acid fast - can identify thepassing of the causative organismof avian tuberculosis, Mycobacteriumavium.• Urinalysis - from the urine partof a bird's dropping an analysis ofthe urine can be performed. This</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/933</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 5 (1995): SEPT-OCT 1995; 44-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/933/914</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
