<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3016</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-16T09:58:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Forces Gather</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ollson, Mickey</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A giant step towards organization among responsible zoological groups to oppose harmful legislation occurred on Jan. 10, 1977 at a meeting in Washington, D.C. The following organizations and representatives were presc .• c.Mr. George Steele, Zoological Action Committee.Mr. Bob Wagner, Executive Secretary, American Association of Zoological Parks and Aquariums.Dr. Gordon Hubbell, President,A.ALP.A.Mr. Bill Braker, Legislative Committee Chairman, A.A.Z.P.A.Mr. Frank Powell, President, Sea World. Mr. Mickey Ollson, Director, American Game Bird Breeders Federation and First Vice President, American Federation of A vi culture.Mr. Cliff Witt, Legislative Liaison, American Federation of Aviculture.Mrs. Lee Thompson, American Pheasant and Waterfowl Society.Mr. Roland J. Gibbs, Circus Fans Association of America.Mr. Jerome Sowalsky, Corporate Counsel, Ringling Bros. Barnum and Bailey. Mr. Virgil Wilder, Imperial Shrine Circus Committee.Mr. Tom Wilds, National Congress of Animal Trainers and Breeders, lnc.Mr. Bill Warren, A.A.Z.P.A. Education and Information Fund.This meeting, called jointly by AAZP A and ZooAct, was for members of the responsible zoological community to exchange views, discuss areas of common concern and interest, and hopefully to explore means to prevent or defeat detrimental legislation in the future. Among the items discussed were the Endangered Species Act of 1973, Injurious wildlife proposals, Marine Mammal legislation, the Federal Zoological Control Board proposal, the so called Steiger Bill, H.R. 15151 and other matters of importance to zoological parks, aquariums, circus, aviculturists and game breeders.As a result of this meeting it became ever clearer that more and more harmful legislation is a real possibility unless the above groups organize sufficiently to combat its passage and implementation. The legislation would severely hamper aviculture and game breeding as well as zoos and aquariums and circuses.Despite the possible harmful legislation on the horizon it is most encouraging to see the various responsible zoological organizations meeting together to form a united front to stop or soften the possible laws. I feel very strongly that by working together and joining forces with other groups in the zoological community we as aviculturists and game breeders will be heard more strongly and this united effort will become a force which can stop the ill conceived legislation that threatens us all. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3016</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 1 (1977): FEB-MAR 1977; 15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3016/3000</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
