<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4020</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Hawk-headed Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Marshall, Tom</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 2 (April/May 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.The Hawkheaded Parrot, the only member of the genus Deroptyus, has long produced considerable anxiety among many taxonomists and naturalists concerning its relationship with other members of the parrot family.Rosemary Low has stated in several of her numerous publications that. “Anyone with experience of keeping and breeding Pyrrhura conures can have few doubts regarding the close relationship of the Hawk - head Parrot to Pyrrhura.” She further states, “that it differs only in its larger size, correspondingly louder voice and in its ornamental ruff. In behavior, it resembles Pyrrhura in every way. ” I myself, see a scalloping pattern on the front of some Pyrrhura conures as a similar type configuration on Hawk -heads, that visually might make onebegin to see the possibility of a relationship between the two species ( Deroptyus and Pyrrhura). However, science has shown us that similar characteristics and behaviors, which are perhaps evolutionary and adaptive in nature, don’t necessarily indicate any close relationship between different species.Back in 1982, I wrote an article for Bird Talk magazine that speculated on the hypothesis that caique ’s closest relatives among all parrots of South America might be the Hawk - headed Parrot, also like Caiques - a single genus. I reported that several ornithologists see a relationship between Hawk -heads and some conures based on the bone structure of their skulls. However, my superficial and limited observations, led me to consider that Caiques might be closely related to the Hawk -headed Parrot. Hawk -heads and Caiques populatesome of the same area in northern South America; they have identical shades of green coloration on their backs; and they have somewhat similar vocalization patterns. In trying to describe the vocal repertoire of Hawk-heads, which includes a variety of chattering, high -pitched squealing, whistling sounds, some musical in nature, Tony Juniper and Mike Parr, authors of PARROTS: A Guide to Parrots of the World have also indicated some calls resemble Black - headed Caiques.Anecdotal observations and my deductions are not at all scientific, but there are now recent studies that indicate that my hunches might have some validity. Dr. John C. McMichael in his definitive work, Caiques: Their Care, Breeding and Some Natural History reported in 2010 that recent karyotype studies indicate that there are three main groups of parrots in the Americas. Caiques share a group that includes macaws and conures. These findings also state, “From the known nuclear and mitochondrial DNA sequences, the most closely related genus to theClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4020</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 2 (2024): Watchbird April/May 2024; 8-10</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4020/3980</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
