<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3250</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-02T17:36:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Message to the Membership</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Speed, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Iwas awed and somewhat intimidated when I attended my first convention as a delegate in 1995. I knew I wanted to be more involved and later found the courage to write Robert Berry (then president) and list ways I thought I could be of service. It is now my responsibility as your newly inducted president to inspire each of you to become more involved.How can we be certain we will have a future in aviculture? I believe we must have a passion for the future and must have the courage to reach out and share it with others. Since its inception in 1974, AFA has courageously shared that passion through education, conservation and legislative awareness.One way members can contribute is to tell others about AFA and encourage them to join us. Share our mission statement and the methods by which we strive to touch every aspect of aviculture. As an individual member, you have more power and ability to contribute than you may realize. You have a wealth of contacts-your friends, your clients, your veterinarian's office, employees at your pet store and fellow bird lovers attending bird-related events.Your contacts could also include those involved in rehoming and sanctuary, where the ultimate goal is to place birds in situations that will fit the birds' needs, including homes or breeding situations.Our membership numbers could double in a very short time. There is genuine strength in numbers when there is a strong and strategic alliance among the membership. AFA also serves the avian community in areas of disaster relief We are at the forefront when natural disasters occur, assisting when emergencies arise that may escalate to endanger the safety and well being of our birds.We have a real challenge ahead of us. If you believe in our mission statement and what we seek to accomplish, join us-For a Future With Birds! </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3250</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 38 No. 3 (2011): Number 3 2011; 4</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3250/3234</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
