<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3079</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-18T08:43:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Emerald Toucanet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Emerald Toucanet [Aulacorphynchus prasinus) is one of the smallest members of the family Rhamphastidae, approximately 12-14 inches in length. It is almost entirely green with the exception of a small maroon patch on the rump, a white patch just below the eye, and the reddish-brown tipped tail feathers. The beak is two toned - yellow upper mandible and maroon-brown lower mandible. Sexes are nearly alike, distinguished only by bill length. The female has a short, nearly straight bill measuring approximately 2~ inches in length, whereas the male's bill is approximately one inch longer and is slightly decurved. The female at Walnut Acres has a bluish green breast as opposed to the male's green.The Emerald Toucanet inhabits the sub-tropical cloud forests and wooded foothills of mountainous southern Mexico, Central America and the Andes of Venezuela, Columbia, Ecuador, and Peru from an elevation of 4000' to 8000'. It is a close relative of the Crimsom-rumped Toucanet (A. haematopygus) which has been bred in captivity a number of generations (Watchbird, Vol II, No. 2, April 1975). The Emerald Toucanet occurs in small flocks during the non-breeding season. During the breeding season individuals pair off to nest in tree cavities, most frequently the nests of large and mediumsized woodpeckers. The Emerald will take over both abandoned and active nests, driving the current occupants away. They then may slightly widen the entrance hole, as they begin to lay their clutch of three to four white eggs.Both male and female take part in incubation during the day, though only the female incubates at night. Young remain in the nest approximately six weeks and are brooded by the hen at night. They are fed a diet of berries, fruit containing undigestable pits or seeds, insects, and the eggs and young of other birds. Emerald Toucanets are known to be great nest robbers.Emerald Toucanets are not frequently seen in captivity, especially in private collections. Approximately 16 months ago I was able to' acquire a true pair, which are set up in an aviary measuring 16' x 16' x 9'. They are fed a diet of Gaines dry dog kibble, fruit cocktail (rinsed and drained), diced fresh Papaya, and fresh water containing HeadstartPoultry Vitamins.Towards the end of May 1977 a nest log, provided by Dale Thompson, measuring six feet in length and one foot in diameter was placed in the rear of the flight. Within two weeks the pair were observed entering and leaving the nest log, which has been occupied previously by woodpeckers at the Los Angeles Zoo (Mr. Thompson had loaned his log to the zoo during his employment at that facility.)Approximately three weeks after the birds were first seen in the nest, faint noises began to erninate from the nest cavity. Five days thereafter the noises ceased and it was presumed the young had perished. The adults were not observed near the nest again until mid-July, when a second nest was begun. (It is not known exactly when these birds began to lay, incubate, or feed young since the nest cannot be inspected short of destroying the log entirely.) </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3079</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 5 (1977): OCT- NOV 1977; 16-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3079/3063</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
