<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1691</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:15:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BUILDING ATTACHED AVIARIES</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Banas, Norma</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AppearanceP robably the most overlooked aspect of building an aviary, especially one that is attached to the house, is to make it fit the design of your home.People tend to buy or build aviaries because they look nice or are easy to buy or build. Once built and attached, they often stick out as an add-on rather than become an enhancement to the main building. So, before you start, look at your house and consider such points as: type and slant of roof, composition of the building, overall design of the building. For example, if you have a ranch style home with long lines, consider making the aviary also of long slim lines that parallel the house rather than jutting out from it.If you have a basic rectangular home consider an extension at one end that gives you a finished L shape. If you have a fancy structure with archways, columns and large windows, consider an aviary of great height with arched design as well. If you plan to convert a patio, screen enclosure, or garage consider how the interior design of the aviary will fit with the interior of your home. If you have a second story consider building in front of windows on both levels. Consider how placement extending from specific rooms or windows will affect the view and the entry into the aviary. If you place an aviary on an upper deck you should consider both exterior design and interior compatibility. Plan the shape and overall size on graph paper attaching it in various ways to the outline of your home and consider the overall effect this addition will have on the total finished appearance. Consideration of location and design compatibility with your existing facility is a prime factor in planning an attached aviary.Another consideration is the type of birds you plan to place in the aviary.Know your birds' needs; do they need long flight space vs. tall climbing or perching space? Are they ground birds that need a natural substrate or do they hang in branches and need a tall tree? Do they need seclusion or prefer to be where life is busy and active?Exposure and Weather ConsiderationsFacing south or southwest is the best exposure for weather. However, there are other considerations. Probably one of the most important is where you will get the most enjoyment from watching the birds. Placement in front of a window where you can sit and watch is most desirable for pets while a secluded solid wall would be better for breeders. Other placement considerations are: location in relation to your neighbors and to traffic and the privacy needs of the species you are keeping vs. their need to be near you and be the center of attention.A balance of shade vs. filtered sun must be consider.ed. Draft must be prevented and can be done by natural placement against the house and aided by the addition of Plexiglas panels that can be hooked to the aviary and removed if not needed. Placement also is selected by whether you wish to enter the aviary from the house or from the outside.If you live in a climate that does not permit birds to be outdoors all year round, build partially into a room and have the rest outside through a doorway or window. That way, in cold weather the birds can be completely sheltered and warm. Remember that birds can take cold as long as there is no draft and as long as they are acclimated by being out all year around. ConstructionMost people and many companies build aviaries with a wood frame. We are very opposed to this practice for several important reasons: wood can harbor bugs and bacteria, it will eventually rot and it can be chewed by all of the larger birds. There are two easy alternatives to wood. Most expensive but a strong building material is aluminum framing put up by a screen enclosure company. The aluminum frame can then have screening placed as the top layer and appropriate wire cloth or heavy duty wire screwed to the underside of the frame. This layered effect gives good protection to your birds.However, if you live in raccoon country, the raccoons may tear the screening in an attempt to get to the aviary. If you are planning to build the aviary for macaws or cock- atoos, the wire must be screwed to the top of the frame so that the birds cannot get to the screws.Wire used should be galvanized after weld. Gauge depends upon the birds and will range from 16 for smaller birds to 10-gauge for strong birds. A Hyacinth Macaw will need 4 gauge. Hog rings or ferrules should be stainless steel so that they do not rust. Screws and washers should be stainless for the same reason. This costs more initially but will pay off in the end in a better and more long lasting product.Wire spacing should not be larger than 1/2 inch x 1 inch, or for larger birds, 1/2 inch x 3 inch to prevent predators from gaining entry with body or hand. In some cases where raccoons are prevalent, a finer wire covering the bottom wire may be needed to prevent predators from pulling birds through at night. Even if you build your aviary on the ground, place wire on the bottom and securely fasten it to all sides to prevent intrusion from animals that can dig under the aviary.The simple way to build an aviary is wire without a frame. A 14-gauge or stronger wire can be used without any framing and is strong, easy to put together, and can be expanded easily at a future date.Hog ring all sides and top and bottom together. The method of attachment to the house will depend upon where you are attaching. If entry is to the inside, attachment to the wall of your main structure is done directly to the wall of the house. If entry is from the outside, a safety door should be added to the aviary. Cut your doorway out after the cage is set up. Then cut a piece of wire that is at least three inches larger on all sides. If you do not have a safety section, it is preferable to make the doorway low so that you must duck to get inside. A simple safety feature would be an extra piece of wire that hangs down in front of the door on the inside of the cage. With an inside-the-house entry, this type safety can be made of attractive wire or mesh wire. The idea is to prevent a startled bird from flying past you to the outside as you enter.Doors should have closers that cannot be opened by the birds and that hold the door tightly to the cage. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1691</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 1 (2002): Fourth Quarter 2001; 52-54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1691/1668</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
