<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4074</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:17:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Kakapo Conservation Genome Study</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boyd, Janice</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 1 (January 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Kakapo Conservation Helped by Genomics StudyNew Zealand was one of the last landmasses colonized by humans. Following Polynesian colonization circa 1360 CE and European colonization in the 1800s, and the resulting overhunting and introduction of mammalian predators, New Zealand experienced major extinction events of endemic species. The kakapo (Strigops habroptilus), an endemic flightless parrot, was widespread before human arri-remaining kakapo population. A high quality, chromosome-level reference genome was sequenced by the Vertebrate Genomes Project (VGP), and an additional 35 modern genomes were sequenced from the Stewart Island population and 14 genomes from the extinct mainland population (13 historical birds collected between 1847 and 1924). Stewart Island was isolated from the mainland about 10,000 years ago. Surprisingly, the present-day island kakapo were found to have a reduced number of harmful alleles (i.e., genes) compared to the (extinct) mainland individuals. Population genetics theory would expect the isolated island population would have experienced increased inbreeding compared with the mainland population and the increased inbreeding would have concentrated the level of harmful mutations. However, it appears that some of these damaging alleles were purged over the thousands of years by...Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4074</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 1 (2022): Watchbird January 2022; 24-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4074/4034</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
