<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/630</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Raising Canaries</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vigran, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Traditionally, Valentine's Day hasbeen the time for canary fanciers toset up their birds. Canaries, domesticatedsince the early nineteenth century,have remained spring seasonbreeders, as they go through a heavymolt in the summer. Young birdsstart showing their maturity in thefall; males start bellowing out fullsongs which were only inconsistentwarbles just after weaning. Femalesstart flitting about looking for nestingmaterial to carry to a potential nestingsite.Generally, canaries raise youngbest when caged as pairs. Many fancierswill utilize one male with morethan one hen, thus leaving the familyrearing duties to the hen alone. Colonybreeding, for the most part, leadsto disappointment and heartache asmales fight and hens destroy othernests while trying to work on theirown.Canaries build nests in open, cuptypecontainers. Often a liner is usedto provide a good, sturdy base. Driedgrasses, ripped burlap and cottonstring can be offered for nest building.The hen will often sit in the nestduring the building time, appearingto check for necessary adjustments.Three to six eggs are laid, the averagebeing three to four in larger types(such as Yorkshires or Norwich) andfour to five in the smaller types (suchas Glosters or Fifes). Most breederswill remove each new egg laid andreplace it with a plastic "dummy"egg until the clutch is completed. Inthis way, the babies all hatch aroundthe same time (13 to 14 days later)and have equal chance at survival.The eggs are blue with brown mottledspots and usually the last egg laidwill differ in coloration with lessmottling.Eggs and sometimes babies can betransferred to other hens for fosteringwhen necessary or when onlysmall, fertile clutches appear.Young canaries grow quickly andone great pleasure is to watch theirdevelopment in the open-type nest.Usually, for the first week or so, thehen sits tight allowing the male tofeed her and she, in turn, the young.Some hens will get off to feed ontheir own and many males will hopon to keep eggs or babies warm.After the first week the hen willspend more time off the nest and theyoung can be more readily observed.Depending upon the type, youngcanaries should be close-bandedbetween five to seven days of age.Some hens may try to remove thesebright objects from their nests, sosome breeders smoke the bands tomake them less shiny (before puttingthem on, of course!).The young will start climbing ontothe edges of the nest at about 18 to19 days and will take to fledging at 21days of age, sometimes returning tothe nest at night.It is at this stage that the hen maybecome anxious to go back to nest. Asecond nest should be provided witha lot of extra nesting material. If themale has been with the hen, he canbe partitioned off with the young,while the hen gets her nest ready.During this time the male should beallowed to visit with the hen forshort periods to ensure fertilizationof the new eggs, and then returned tofeed his weaning chicks.If fledglings are left in with theirmother, there is a fairly good chancethat she will pull feathers from themto add to her nest, especially fromthe lighter colored babies (yellow orwhite).Canaries can easily and successfullyraise two to three clutches per seasondepending on the number ofbabies per clutch and whether thehen has been left to feed the youngon her own.Their diet should consist of a goodcanary mix offering canary seed,small millet, rape and a little nigerseed. In preparation of nesting, hensshould be offered calcium in theform of cuttlebone, mineral blocks,dried, cooked eggshells and/or liquidminerals added to the water, or powdered,mixed in soaked seed or softfood.Some breeders start offering eggfood andjor other soft foods such aswhole wheat bread, corn bread orvegetables as the hen is preparing hernest, thus encouraging her by lettingher know there is plenty of goodfood to rear a family. These richfoods should be limited during herincubation, since she is so inactiveduring this time. A day or two beforethe eggs are due to hatch, thesefoods should be increased to ensurefeeding when babies appear. Greenfoods can also be offered, such asromaine lettuce or kale.When babies fledge, a low, flat dishof soft food can be offered on thebottom of the cage, to encourage thebabies to eat on their own. Anotheruseful tool for weaning is spray millet,as babies are curious about thisand will pick at it.Young males can often be identifiedat this early age, as they will tryto sing, letting out a funny little warble.A plastic open band in a particularcolor (such as blue) can be placedon these birds for identification.These birds should be confirmed,however, when they are older, i.e.six to eight months.Canaries love to bathe and shouldbe offered bath water several times aweek in warmer weather to encouragepreening and help them throughthe molt period. Hens like to bathejust before eggs are due to hatch andthis will increase moisture for hatching.Remember to check water oftenand/or offer drinking water in a tube,which won't be all splashed out bythe end of the day.Whether you prefer specializedsong, fancy colors, crests, tall andthin or chunky birds, or even funnylookinghunch-backed birds, canariesare a delight for every bird fancierand breeder. These small gems of thebird world will worm their way intoany heart.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/630</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/630/613</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
