<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2606</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-17T16:23:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Avicultural Society of Australia Commemorates its 50th Year with Issue of Avi-Index</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Tuesday, August 7, 1990 was an historic day in the history of the Avicultural Society of Australia when Graeme Phipps, Senior Curator of Birds, Tarango Zoo, Sydney, launched the society's latest publication, Aui-Tndex, at the society's monthly meeting. This 72 page paperback book is unique to the avicultural world. It is a comprehensive index to the ASA's monthly journal, Australian Aviculture.Aui-Tn dex, a selected index of Australian Aviculture over 43 years, covers the period of January 1947 to December 1989 (Volume 1, No. 1 to Volume 43, No. 12), a unique period of innovation and change in aviculture in this country.Compiled by Charles Hibbert and Ken Kleesh, two long-standing members of our society, the index, in their words: " ... resulted from the inescapable conclusion that a vast amount of useful and important information lay hidden and untapped in past editions of Australian Auiculture"The Avi-lndex contains an incredible 3,318 articles (including cross-referencing) which have been carefully placed in 35 separate chapters ranging from "Aviaries" to "Lorikeets," from "People in Aviculture" to "Diseases, Ailments and Treatments'.' Each chapter is divided into six columns: (1) subject, (2) article, (3) author, (4) journal, (5) page, (6) N. The symbol "N" indicates the number of photocopied pages that would be required to obtain the article.Twenty-six illustrations have been sprinkled throughout the text and these, together with the easy-to-read layout, make the Avi-lndex a publication suitable for browsing through, or be used in the intended manner, as a reference tool to Australian Aviculture. The concept of an Avi-Index to Australian Aviculture was suggested to the society by Graeme Phipps - himself a long-time member of the society. It was fitting, therefore, that he was invited to write the foreword to this splendid publication - a modern day world first for an avicultural society in the Englsh-speaking world.As an essential extension of the Index, the society has established a photocopying service so that anyone, anywhere in the world, can order articles they require. Robert Trott, the society's archivist, is in charge of this innovative and important activity. Every copy of the Aui-Index contains an order form for articles required by photocopy.Every serious aviculturist, especially those who want information on specific subjects, should obtain a copy of this publication. All writers of avicultural articles, and all who speak at avicultural meetings, would benefit from owning a copy. Indeed, all who are active in aviculture should have a copy on their bookshelf.Copies of Avi-Index are only $ 10 each, which includes postage anywhere in the world (overseas air mail additional $2). Send your order with money to: Ian Grant, Book Steward, ASA, 24 2 Civic Parade, Altona, Victoria 3018, Ausrralta. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2606</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 6 (1990): DEC 1990- JAN 1991; 62-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2606/2576</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
