<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/499</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">the fledging of an evening grossbeak</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mackie, Ron</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Edit01·'s ote: Here we have anarticle that very simply expresses theessence of man's love for natur-e, andnature's response.While it is illegal to confine wildbirds, aving a fledgling from almostcertain death and nurturing it tomaturity and then turning it loose inthe wild is another matter. A fledglingfallen from the nest is rarely raisedsuccessfully. A baby bird, perhaps threeweeks old and feathered , depends on adiet of wild food not easy to provide.Imprinting of such a yo ungster hasalready taken place with the parentbirds. The chick is a wild creature. Onthe other hand, a chick newly hatchedout of the egg has not been adjusted toa diet nor has imprinting taken place. Itcan be fed an artificial diet andimprinting can take place with ahuman pla ying the role model ofparent.This is the sto ry of how Mr . SamClark of Country Club Acres, Oakhurst,California, successfully raised such afeatherles chick, saw it grow to maturity,and, most remarkably, aw it live tohave a family of its own.One spring day, Mrs. Clark's atten-tion was arrested by the persistentbarking of one of her beagles. The dogwas under a white oak nuzzling somethingwith its nose. This turned out tobe an ugly blob of flesh less than twoinches long with two round bulges foreyes. It was obviously somethingnewly hatched from an egg and fallenfrom a nest in the tree above. This littlebody, entirely featherless, looked muchlike a newborn mouse. Mrs. Clarkcupped it in her hands to warm it andtook it into the house and put it in amall box filled with cotton wool. Sheimmediately called a veterinarian. Shewas advised to feed the bird pureedbaby food such as Liver by picking up atiny morsel of the food with a toothpickand placing the food in the bird'sthroat. Likewise, water could besupplied with an eye-dropper.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/499</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 56-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/499/483</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
