<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/308</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:17:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Unusual Hybrids</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Silva, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The four of us were sitting in NewOrleans' famous Arnaud's Restaurant.Across from me was Theo Pagel, Jr.; tomy left his father, Theo Pagel, thefamous German lorikeet expert; and tomy right, Paul Roth, a Swiss ornithologistwho now lives in northern Braziland whose specialty is parrots. Ourdiscussion centered on parrots, thensuddenly it turned to hybrids. Wfthhesitation I explained having seen avery unusual, indeed almost incredulous,cross in Australia- the offspringof a male rainbow lorikeet (Trichoglossushaematodus moluccanus) anda female king parrot (Alisterus scapularis).I expected Pagel to react the sameway I did when first hearing of the bird- my eyebrows raised, facial expressionclearly showing that I did not believethe cross was possible, and then askingthe person telling me the story if theyhad been drinking - but he did not;in his soft-spoken words, he relatedanother peculiar happening: the rearingof hybrids between a macaw (Ara spp.)and Pionites or caique. These two birdsare as separate from each other as the lorikeet and king.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/308</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 14 No. 4 (1987): AUG-SEPT 1987; 36-38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/308/296</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
