<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1004</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:20:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pyrrhura Conures:   Status in Aviculture</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jordan, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">GENERAL the genus Pyrrhura is comprised of 18 different species and 29 subspecific forms. They are all New World birds and range from as far north as Costa Rica, in Central America, southward to northern Argentina. TI1e majority of the species being concentrated in the north-central region of the South American continent. Joseph Forshaw in Parrots of the World (3rd rev. edition, 1989) states the following with regard to this genus: "Pyrrhura Conures are small to medium sized birds with long graduated tails. The bill is rather broad and there is a notch in the upper mandible. The naked cere is prominent, and in many species there is a very prominent ring of bare skin around the eye. In the skull there is a complete orbital ring. Sexual dimorphism is absent and young birds mostly resemble adults." STATUS Deforestation is a major problem in many countries of South America, having a detrimental affect on many species of Pyrrbura conures. Several species are already listed as endangered and control of these species is strictly controlled by the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species (CITES). It is interesting to note that many of the species listed as Threatened or Endangered originate in Brazil which has prohibited their export for over 30 years. This fact seems to imply that other pressures within the habitat itself are the major contributing factors to the decline of these species and mat trade had little to do with the dwindling numbers in the wild. Many Pyrrhura conures frequent isolated areas pf the South American rain forest. Accessibility is a major contributing factor for the lack of information about these birds. A new species, the El Oro Conure Pyrrhura orcesi was not even discovered or recorded until 1985, demonstrating how little is known of the members of this genus or their habitat. rain forest. Accessibility is a major contributing factor for the lack of information about these birds. A new species, the El Oro Conure Pyrrhura orcesi was not even discovered or recorded until 1985, demonstrating how little is known of the members of this genus or their habitat. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1004</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 2 (1996): MARCH-APRIL 1996; 8-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1004/984</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
