<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/690</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">President's MessageMost of you are aware that the regulations are being draftedas required to implement the Exotic Bird Conservation Act of1992. Currently, only CITES listed (I, II, III) species that wereimported during 1991 have been allowed entry, at their 1991levels. Non-CITES species are allowed without restriction,with only a few exceptions.A number of AFA special committees have been establishedto provide input as to the new regulations. AFA wantsreasonable, workable guidelines for certification of foreignbreeding facilities and breeding consortiums as well as an"Approved List" that actually reflects the current status ofspecies as indicated by reliable data, not opinion. While manythink of this bill as an • • ending," it is actually only a"beginning." The act will require continual monitoring.Oh, the care free days of the seventies when we had no bill,and what seemed an endless variety of birds at reasonableprices to choose from. Aviculture has changed. Those days areno more. The irresponsible importation of birds in unthinkablenumbers and the historic lack of any United States policyregarding same created a ploughed head attitude into anatmosphere of lawsuits to protect lobsters from the trauma ofthe cookpot (CITES had always relied upon but it seldomactually worked). Many individuals believe that human life isconsidered equal in value to that of the other animals that shareour planet. Of course, it's speculative as to what aviculture willlook like in the next ten or 20 years. Certainly, the next fewyears will determine whether a number of species continue tobe represented in captivity.The current economic "slowdown" will undoubtedly play amajor part with individuals and their decisions as to whatspecies to work with in a captive environment. It isunfortunate, but a fact of life, that a large portion ofaviculturists must derive some revenue from their birds. Thisactivity is a double edged sword. First, species representationwill be dictated by the pet value of the species. Few people willchoose to breed species that bring a low sales price. Second,aviculturists are selling a large portion of the offspring theyproduce. Given the lack of imports, selling all your progenyleaves you in an awkward position when you need newbreeding stock. Finding good breeding stock will be increasinglymore difficult. As they say, '• If they are such goodbreeders, why are you selling them?" Many aviculturists havecreated a compromise situation where their "bread and butter"birds are domesticated species, principally cockatiels, so Jessreliance is made upon selling the offspring of their more rarespecies. Another situation that has the potential to maintain anumber of species is that of the bird club breeding consortium. Clubs around the country are devoting energy to establishingspecies through intraclub breeding loans. The common denominatorto all programs is that the breeding effort must bemanaged to maximize genetic variability.With the coming implementation of the exotic bird act, AFAis readying itself to meet the challenge of managing nondomesticatedspecies populations. A full array of open andclosed bands is now available from our business office in anyquantity. Our Red Siskin program is serving as an effectivemodel as to what can be achieved within the aviculturalcommunity. Finally, we hope to have a full-time employee,within the coming months, who will devote total energy toassisting clubs with consortiums and enhancing AFA's ownefforts. The bottom line is, however, that interest in maintaininga large number of species in captivity must come from theaviculturists themselves. I suggest that every member take acritical look at his/her collection and answer the followingquestions:1. Are you maintaining unpaired specimens of nondomesticatedspecies?2. Are you selling all the progeny from certain pairs ofnon-domesticated species?3. Do you band or micro-chip progeny and maintaingenealogical infonnation permanently?Finally, is there a species that you feel should be receivingmore concentrated attention from the avicultural community?I'd like to hear from you. Please seriously consider droppingme a note by writing: AFA, 999 E. Basse Road, Suite 180-164,San Antonio, TX 78209 or telephone (210) 828-5306. I'mlooking forward to hearing from you. •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/690</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 50-55</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/690/673</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
