<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2891</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-09T18:14:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Code of Ethics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The following code of ethics has been adopted by the A. F.A. to serve as a guide. It is not necessarily rigid or fixed in concrete. The code of ethics can be flexible and designed to deal with whatever problems may arise in the bird world.If you are convinced that elements of this code have been or are being violated you are invited to send your evidence to Ethics Committee Chairperson, Ruth Hannessian in care of the home office, P.O. Box 327. El Cajon, Ca., 92022.A.F.A. CODE OF ETHICS POLICY &amp;amp; PROCEDURESI. It is considered unethical to:A. Be involved in the smuggling of birds or to purchase birds known by the buyer to have been smuggled.B. Be involved in the theft of birds or to purchase birds known by the buyer to have been stolen.C. Be actively or passively involved in the inhumane treatment of birds.0. Be involved in fraudulent business practices:I. Accepting money for birds the seller does not deliver.2. Knowingly selling diseased or deficient birds.E. Be involved in other violations of the law such as:I. The interstate shipment of endangered species without permit.Il. It is the policy of the A.F.A. to:A. Have the Ethics Committee investigate, at its discretion. all complaints forwarded to it.B. Require documented proof of a conviction prior to publication which must contain at least:I . A copy of the complaint.2. A copy of the docket.3. A copy of the judgement.C. Have the Ethics Committee present to the Board of Directors of A.F.A. the result of its' investigation and recommendations for A.F.A. action.D. Have the Board of Directors of A.F.A. determine appropriate disciplinary action. ill. Investigation Procedures.A. Receive complaints from our members and respond to the complaint immediately with a form letter acknowledging receipt of the complaint.B. Check out the complaint if several complaints have been received about the same individual. Local delegates may be called upon to assist in the investigation.IV. Disciplinary Action.A. Write an opinion letter to the complaintant after the investigation.B. If the investigation reveals unethical conduct. write a letter to the person suspected of unethical conduct asking for an explanation of such behavior.C. If we do not receive a satisfactory explanation from the individual and we have some hard evidence, tum the evidence over to the government agency responsible for such violations of law.D. If the person is a member of A.F.A. or an advertiser in the "Watchbird", write a letter of warning stating that they will be expelled or refused ad space unless they can satisfy the Ethics Committee's request for an explanation or request for assurances that such conduct will not reoccur.E. Disqualify or expel from advertising and/or membership any applicant or member who has been convicted of violation of any state or federal law concerning the importation, interstate shipment, possession or humane treatment of any avian species.F. Publish in the "Watchbird" such information as pertains to the conviction of any individual or individuals who have been convicted of violation any of the aforementioned laws upon receipt of documented proof of such conviction.(See Section II, Subsection B). </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2891</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 4 (1979): AUG-SEPT 1979; 37-38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2891/2875</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
