<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/794</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-13T16:20:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Identifying Forpus Parrotlets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Robert W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Eorpus parrotlets comprise one of he world's smallest genera of parrots. Often confused with species from the genus Brotogeris, they are more closely related to the genus Amazona. There are seven species of these parrotlets: Green-rumped, Pacific, Blue-winged, Spectacled, Mexican, Sclater's (Dusky-billed) and Yellow-faced. Many of these have more than one subspecies. They are primarily found in Columbia, Brazil, Venezuela, Equador, Peru, Argentina, Bolivia, Paraguay, Guyana and various Caribbean islands. The Mexican Parrotlet is the only species not found in South America but is native to northwestern Mexico and the Tres Marias Islands. All species of parrotlets are sexually dimorphic. Females are generally green with various shades of yellow whereas males have beautiful blue coloring on their wings, rumps and heads. Identification of the male of a species is based upon the particular shade of blue he possesses. The females are more difficult to identify so attention must be paid to small details such as subtle changes in the shades of yellow and green feathers. Identification of parrotlet species is simplified by the process of elimination. Pacific, Green-rumped and Spectacled Parrotlets all have horn-colored beaks and legs. Yellow-faced also have horn-colored beaks and legs, but their beaks contain a thin black line which runs the length of the beak from cere to tip. Mexican and Bluewinged Parrotlets have gray beaks and legs, but Mexican hens' beaks do not tum gray until they are in breeding condition. The upper beak is gray in Sclater's, the lower is horn-colored and their legs are gray. The Pacific or Celestial Parrotlet Forpus coelestis is the most wellknown and popular species of parrotlet in aviculture. They are approximately five inches in length and weigh around 30 grams. In the wild, they are found from western Equador to north- western Peru. The males have a cobalt-blue streak of feathers extending backward from the eye as well as cobalt-blue on the rump and wings. Many females also have an eye streak but it is light turquoise or emerald green. They also have dark green backs and wings with light green feathers on the face. Occasionally, Pacific hens will have a blue rump but normally it is emerald green. Interestingly, the rump color is not cobaltblue as in the males but deep turquoise. These hens often pass this trait on to their daughters. While there are no known subspecies of Pacific Parrotlets, many breeders believe these birds could be an unrecognized subspecies. Pacific Parrotlets are certainly the most fearless as well as curious of the Forpus species. They are also extremely territorial, especially the females. They should be kept either alone or not more than one pair to a cage. If given a chance, they will also attack much larger birds. Handfed babies make wonderful pets if placed in a home right after weaning and handled regularly. Being highly intelligent, they can be taught to do tricks. Both males and females can learn to talk, however, they will never have the vocal abilities of their larger Amazon cousins. Female Pacifies tend to be more dominant than the males. As with most parrots, domesticallyraised pairs are much easier to breed than imports. Indeed, it is not unusual for a pair to begin setting up housekeeping at six or seven months but they should not be allowed to breed until one year of age. Another common species, Greenrumped Parrotlets Forpus passerinus are the smallest, weighing around 22 grams. They are native to Guyana and have a delicate, streamlined body with a small beak in proportion to their heads. Predominantly apple-green, the females have a patch of yellow feathers between their eyes, above their nostrils. The males have bright, western Peru. The males have a cobalt-blue streak of feathers extending backward from the eye as well as cobalt-blue on the rump and wings. Many females also have an eye streak but it is light turquoise or emerald green. They also have dark green backs and wings with light green feathers on the face. Occasionally, Pacific hens will have a blue rump but normally it is emerald green. Interestingly, the rump color is not cobaltblue as in the males but deep turquoise. These hens often pass this trait on to their daughters. While there are no known subspecies of Pacific Parrotlets, many breeders believe these birds could be an unrecognized subspecies. Pacific Parrotlets are certainly the most fearless as well as curious of the Forpus species. They are also extremely territorial, especially the females. They should be kept either alone or not more than one pair to a cage. If given a chance, they will also attack much larger birds. Handfed babies make wonderful pets if placed in a home right after weaning and handled regularly. Being highly intelligent, they can be taught to do tricks. Both males and females can learn to talk, however, they will never have the vocal abilities of their larger Amazon cousins. Female Pacifies tend to be more dominant than the males. As with most parrots, domesticallyraised pairs are much easier to breed than imports. Indeed, it is not unusual for a pair to begin setting up housekeeping at six or seven months but they should not be allowed to breed until one year of age. Another common species, Greenrumped Parrotlets Forpus passerinus are the smallest, weighing around 22 grams. They are native to Guyana and have a delicate, streamlined body with a small beak in proportion to their heads. Predominantly apple-green, the females have a patch of yellow feathers between their eyes, above their nostrils. The males have bright, cobalt-blue on their primary wing feathers while the secondaries are turquoise. They are the only species of parrotlet which lacks blue on the rump. They are sweet, gentle birds which make exceptional pets. There are four subspecies of Green-rumped. Forpus passerinus uiridissimus is found on the islands of Trinidad and Jamaica as well as northern Venezuela to northern Columbia. The males are darker forest green and have a deeper shade of blue than the nominate species. There is no difference between the females. While not as aggressive as Pacifies, this subspecies is much more bold than the species found in Guyana. This subspecies is rather common in aviculture. Forpus passerinus cyanophanes, native to northern Columbia, has more dark blue feathers on the upper wing which forms a patch of color that can be seen when the wing is folded. The female is indistinguishable from p. passerinus. Forpus passerinus cyanochlorus is found only near the upper Branco River in northern Brazil. In this subspecies, the male is very similar to the nominate. It is the females who differ in their overall plumage which is much more yellow especially on the rump and underparts. Forpus passerinus deliciosus is native to northern Brazil along the banks of the Amazon. The males are the only subspecies of Green-rumped to have their rump feathers tinged with light blue. Females have more yellow feathers between the eyes than p. passerinus. This is another subspecies which may be found in aviculture although not as frequently as the nominate species or viridissimus. Mexican Parrotlets Forpus xantbopterygius are found in northwestern Mexico. They are one of the larger species of parrotlet with an average weight of 40 grams. The males have brilliant bright turquoise on the rump and wings. Females have dark...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/794</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 3 (1994): MAY-JUN 1994; 55-59</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/794/776</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
