<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2310</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-07T16:46:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Nestmates Anonymous</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clear, Val</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A new and greatly needed service will be provided subscribers in future issues of the Watchbird.In every part of the country there is a solitary bird languishing alone in a breeding cage, dreaming of a mate, while in another place there is an equally lonely bird of the opposite sex with the same dream. Through the Education and Media Services Committee we propose to put these two discouraged birds in touch. Each month we will carry a list of mates being sought by subscribers. Here is how it works.An owner who is looking for a mate for a bird sends the following:English name of the speciesLatin name of the species, if known Sex of missing birdName, address and phone number of ownerOne dollar (cash or check) for up to four birdsFull confidentiality will be maintained. No name, address or phone number will be published; only the species and sex will be Listed.A reader who has the bird being sought will send the following to the address below (not to Watchbird):Name and sex of speciesName, address and phone number of reader One dollar for each bird sought (for forwarding costs)The purpose is to provide a service, not to produce revenue, but there are costs involved and the minimal charge of a dollar is expected to cover them. Any surplus will be used by the AFA for appropriate purposes. All personal services are contributed without remuneration.Preparing the lists and forwarding will be done by Ms. Cathy Grosse, 3120 Epworth Avenue, Cincinnati, Ohio 4 5 2 11. All correspondence should be addressed to her, not to Watchbird. Obviously, neither American Federation of Aviculture, Watchbird, the Committee nor Ms. Grosse can assume any responsibility for transactions resulting from this service. This brokerage is performed without screening, so anyone utilizing it should exercise the usual precautions in such situations.Where duplicate listings are received, responses will be alternated among the searchers. The Committee reserves the right to make adjustments in this new project as experience indicates. Readers are urged to send listings immediately so as to get into the next issue of Watchbird. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2310</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 2 (1985): APR-MAY 1985; 40-41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2310/2284</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
