<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2576</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-16T21:48:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">New Book "Lories and Lorikeets in Aviculture"</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"Lories and Lorikeets in Aviculture" book by John VanderhoofThis upcoming lory book is due around Christmas of this year. This large format (9" x 12 ") book will be around 80 pages in length and deals mainly with those lory and lorikeet species now found in captivity. The author has maintained and reproduced up to 30 species and subspecies of lories and lorikeets for many years. He was the first to manufacture, test, and perfect a dry lory diet that can also be used as a nectar. This book came about primarily as a request from many people who asked about the proper identification of the family Loriidae and as an answer to numerous questions regarding their maintenance and breeding. This book will be interesting reading for most bird enthusiasts, but it is mainly written for those aviculturists interested in propagating this group of birds. There are several chapters at the beginning of the book that deal with aviary and cage design, nestbox size and design, diet flexibility, proper pairing, fostering of eggs and babies, medical, anatomy and other pertinent information.The main portion of the book gives information on each separate species. This includes their size, call, diet, incubation, nesting, sexual difference if any, distribution in the wild, their pet quality and other general information that is specific to the species.The most outstanding quality and certainly the most notable are the full page paintings which accompany each species. There are 34 species that are done with watercolors. These illustrations are second to none and all are originals painted by Gamini Ratnavira, one of the finest wildlife artists in the country today. Exquisite likenesses of those species of Loriidae now found in aviculture are painted with all natural backgrounds.Several books on lories and lorikeets are presently available but they mainly deal with history and early breedings of given species. John Vanderhoof's Lories and Lorikeets in Aviculture fills a need for lory lovers with up-to-date avicultural information on this beautiful group of parrots. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2576</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 5 (1990): OCT- NOV 1990; 45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2576/2546</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
