<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2581</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-16T21:48:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">In Memory of Clark Bavin</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lilienthal, Gary P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It was with great sadness that AFA learned of the recent passing of Clark R. Bavin, Chief of the Division of Law Enforcement of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, Department of the Interior. Over the years, Clark had many dealings with AFA and its representatives in areas of mutual concern to aviculture and the Fish and Wildlife Service. Many of Clark's decisions were extremely difficult when it came to dealing with exotic avian species and, in every case, he attempted to understand the meaning and ramifications of his department's actions as they affected aviculture and exhibited a willingness to listen and understand the concerns of the aviculturists. In several instances, Clark and his staff sought the input of AFA representatives as to matters affecting aviculture. AFA's last contact with Clark was at the U.S. State Department at the March 1990 briefing on the Recommendations of the Cooperative Working Group on the Bird Trade at which time Clark committed his Department's efforts to the realizations of the Recommendations of the Cooperative Working Group. The avicultural community's condolences go to Clark's family and his associates at the Divison of Law Enforcement in Washington. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2581</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 5 (1990): OCT- NOV 1990; 58</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2581/2551</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
