<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/518</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">An Alaskan Tragedy</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bauman, James R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The pigeon guillemot flapped hisway into the air and flew inchesabove the surface of the water nearBligh Reef. He was small as shorebirds go - drab and awkward. Hewasn't really going anywhere but theurge to mate and have chicks hadgiven him a vibrant energy. As hemoved along, he didn 't notice whenthe translucent emerald water justbelow changed to the viscous blackcolor of death . The small, reddishorange webbed feet reached downtowards the surface, but instead of anawkward splash the sound was morelike a rock striking very wet mud.Immediately panic struck. The littlebird tried at full speed to push withhis feet and become airborne again ,and gather enough wind beneath hiswings to pull clear of this lethal goo.With his heart pounding he fell back.He could no longer see, his eyes nowcovered by this substance so tenaciousit would not blink away. Hischest heaved as he sucked in the fatalgasses which caused the vessels of hislungs and airsacs to burst, and finallyto cause the heart to stop beating .With his death the little guillemot hadbecome one of the early statistics inthe largest oil spill in United Stateshistory.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/518</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 4 (1989): AUG-SEPT 1989; 58-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/518/502</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
