<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1198</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T02:55:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Does the World's Rarest Macaw Hybridize?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Waugh, David R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Recent news from Brazilian wildlife agency IBAMA suggests that the Spix's Macaw Cyanopsuta spixii, the world's most threatened parrot species, has hybridized in the wild state. Given that there is only one known individual left in the wild, a male; which under the circumstances has opted to form a pair with a female Illiger's Macaw Ara maracana, at least the potential for this to happen is not surprising. There are no written records of confirmed hybrids between the Spix's Macaw and other species, either in captivity or the wild, but now there comes confirmation that an egg taken from the nest of this mixed pair contained an emhryo.The egg was one of a clutch of three that were removed from the nest of the mixed pair in December 1996 by biologists of the Spix's Macaw Recovery Project, financed by the Laro Parque Fundaci6n. The Committee for the Recovery of the Spix's Macaw(CPRAA) had authorized an experimental transfer of wild Illiger's Macaws eggs to the nest of the mixed pair with the purpose to determine the incubating and rearing capabilities of the pair as a preliminary to the possible transfer of Spix's Macaw eggs from the 40- strong captive population. Although intensively observed, the mixed pair had never been known to hatch their own eggs, the principal supposition being that these were infertile, although it had not been possible to remove eggs from the nesting cavity until the experimental transfer last year.Microscopical analysis of the eggs at University of Sao Paolo showed no embryonic development in two of them, hut the third had a well-formed embryo approximately 24mm long, with the head forming a third of the total length. In this embryo the beak was present, the wings well-developed and traces of the dorsal feather tracts visible. Its stage of development was equivalent to stages 32 to 34 of chicken embryo development which means seven or eight days of incubation and a total approximate age of 10 or 11 days. The embryo DNA was too degraded for direct study, but can still be studied through amplification techniques for comparison with Illiger's Macaw DNA when samples are collected from the same region.Until the DNA study is done we still do not know if the embryo is truly a hybrid or the result of a "sneaky mating" between the female Illiger's Macaw and a male...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1198</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 5 (1997): SEPT-OCT 1997; 16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1198/1177</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
