<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/709</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Red--browed Amazon Parrot: Chronicles of a Paradise Lost? (Amazona dufresniana rhodocorytha)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reillo, Paul R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As tropical avifaunas have becomeincreasingly imperiled through humanactivities, the imperative for conservationpractices in aviculture hasbecome increasingly clear. Firstbreedingsand subsequent propagationof rare species are important firststeps toward maintaining captive populations,from which natural populatioHsmay ultimately be restored.Recent limited conservation successeswith psittacines like the Puerto RicanAmazon (Snyder, et al., 1987) and theThick-billed Parrot (Beissinger andSnyder, 1991) are testimony to the efficacyof aviculture in preserving certaintaxa. Sadly, for others the hope of rescueis fleeting, and the prospect forrecovery of natural populations evenin the distant future is essentially nil.For these desperate species, captiveculture has taken on a sobering newlight- occasional breeding successesmay be all that stem the inevitable tideof extinction. It is with this perspectivethat we report the first successfulNorth American breeding of the RedbrowedAmazon Parrot (Amazonadufresniana rhodocorytha) in eightyears.DescriptionThe Red-browed (a.k.a. Red-toppedor Red-crowned) Amazon is a largeAmazon, 35 to 40 em in length and450 to 650 g in adult weight. The obviousfeature of the species is the redforehead and crown, which fadestoward the nape to a reddish-purpletinged with blue. As with its nominatespecies, the Blue-cheeked Amazon(A.d. dufresniana), the lares areyellow-orange with cheeks and neckblue. Other distinguishing featuresinclude a horn-colored upper mandiblethat becomes pink at the base, anorange-brown iris and grey legs.Further details of plumage can be found in Forshaw (1989) and Stoodleyand Stoodley 0990).Natural HistoryOnce a common parrot in southeasternBrazil (Pinto, 1935), the Redbrowis now altogether extinct acrossmost of its original range due todeforestation and human encroachment(Forshaw, 1989). Remnant populationsare very locally -distributed infragmented forests between Alagoasand Rio de Janeiro, although it isdoubtful that any birds survive in thelatter state (Low, 1984; 1986). WithinEspirito Santo it is known only fromthe Sooretama Reserve and MontePascoal National Park and adjacentareas (Ridgely, 1981). Habitat preferencesvary seasonally, and extend from humid lowland forests to montaneforests to estuarine mangroves,where they may be associated withOrange-wing Amazons (A. amazonica)during winter foraging trips.Red-brows prefer to roost and feed inthe tops of primary forest trees, and atone time were found in large flocks inthe forest canopy. Pinto 0935)described raucous congregations· along the banks of the Gongogy Rivernear Boa Nova, Bahia where birdscould be heard each morning; thesepopulations have been extinct for atleast 12 years (Ridgely, 1981) andprobably much longer. AvicultureThe first captive breeding of A.d. rhodocorytha occurred in Peterbor- ough, England in 1980 (Mann, 1982).The first - and prior to this writing -only documented, captive b reedingsuccess in the USA was by RamonNoegel in 1984 (Noegel, 1984). Theentire collection, including offspringand adult birds compiled from varioussources prior to the 1984 breeding,was purchased jointly by Dr. JohnVaughn (Rare Species Conservatory,Florida) and Mr. Charles Osterbrink(Night Flight Farms, Mississippi) in1988. To our knowledge, this representsthe only significant collection ofRed-brows in the United States (ISISBird Abstract, 30 June 1992), comprisingthree adult males and seven adultfemales, plus the progeny describedhere. An additional adult pair that wasconfiscated by the U.S. Fish and WildlifeService in 1982 and main~ained atMiami Metrozoo has been loaned toThe Rare Species Conservatoty to beincluded in our breeding program. Other birds have been rumored tobe in private collections for years,although only a single male, currentlyoutside our collectio n, has been verified.Hence, as of this writing, thereexist 12 adult birds in our program,four of which are males. As a founderpopulation for genetic diversity, this iscertainly a bare minimum. Ironically,the last bird to be fledged in the U.S.in 1984 is the mother of the babiesdescribed here, which, maternally,represent second-generation domestics.HusbandryThe breeding pair is housed in a 4' x5' x 12' suspended cage made from1"x 1", 14-gauge galvanized wiremesh. The nest box measures 1' x 1' x2' and is made from 3/ 4" plywoodlined with galvanized flashingthrought. The box is hung from thetop center rear of the flight, with thelongest dimension in a vertical aspect,the entrance hole near the top of thebox. The only access to the box isfrom a hinged flap-style door at theback near the bottom. Since Redbrowsat our aviaty have never usedthe box except for sitting eggs, thebox is inspected only weekly duringthe non-breeding months and is lefton the cage yea r-ro und. Soft pineshavings are changed monthly (minimum)during the breeding season andas required during the fall and wintermonths.Diet consists of a mixture of varioustypes of sunflower seeds, parrot mix,Zupreem monkey biscuits and freshfruits and vegetables offered once aday, with seeds constituting roughly30% of the daily ration by volume .Spray millet is offered weekly. Nekton-S vitamin supplement (NektonProdukte,7530 Pforzheim, West Germany)is dissolved in the drinkingwater which is provided fresh eachday. Food and water bowls arewashed and disinfected daily.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/709</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 34-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/709/692</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
