<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4066</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:17:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Understanding Problems with Your Parrot’s Beak</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roset, Kimberly</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 1 (January 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Understanding Problems with Your Parrot’s BeakAnatomy Overview The psittacine beak is one of the parrot’s most recognizable and distinct characteristics. The entire beak is known as the rostrum and can be divided into the upper beak (maxillary rostrum) and lower beak (mandibular rostrum). It consists of bone and internal tissues covered by a thin layer of keratin similar to our fingernails. This keratin layer is what we are able to see, and the upper portion is referred to as the rhinotheca while the lower portion is called the gnathotheca. Movement of the beak also makes parrots very unique in the bird world. They can use their beaks to do everything from climbing, cracking nuts, preening feathers, and even carefully peeling the skin off a grape. Unlike many other birds, parrots have independent control of the upper and lower beak which is controlled by numerous bones, muscles, and joints. This complexity can lead to problems if...Common Conditions Developmental Abnormalities Many birds develop abnormal beak alignment during incubation and the resulting beak deformities are often apparent soon after hatching. These present most often as a scissor or elongation of the upper or lower beak. The portions of the beak that do not meet properly will result in keratin overgrowth. If caught early enough, there are surgical procedures that can offer some improvement but most of these birds will need corrective shaping throughout their lives. Any arthritic changes or imbalance in the joints controlling the movement of the beak can also create an abnormal wear pattern. While both of these cases will need intermittent trimming, adding environmental enrichment which promotes wear can help maintain the normal function of the beak.Young cockatoo with a congenital scissorTrauma Numerous hazards exist in the environment which can result in injuries to the beak. The most common causes occur from falls, toys, or other birds in the household. Many of these injuries are minor but often painful for the parrot. The most common beak trauma is a chip on the tip of the beak after an unsuccessful flight attempt. These injuries can be difficult to see so evaluation of even minor bleeding should be done to make sure the bird can continue to eat appropriately and the pain is controlled. Some of the most severe beak traumas occur when there is an unfavorable interaction between 2 birds in the household .Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4066</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 1 (2022): Watchbird January 2022; 6-8</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4066/4026</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
