<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2460</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T21:50:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I believe in ghosts. I can't help it. The late Joe DeAguiar bas appeared to me several times recently regarding the career of the APA. Many of you won't remember Joe but be was one of the APA's most ardent supporters as well as one of its sternest critics.Joe bad a dream for the APA that projected well into the future. He saw a great glass and steel home office building set on a large tract of land planted and tended as a bird sanctuary. He saw a huge, well-oiled organization working with the precision of a Swiss watch. Joe saw the APA in its ideal, ultimate form and be talked to people about it.But Joe was not a mere dreamer. He knew the APA bad to begin small and move one step at a time toward the ultimate goal. He also warned that the path was narrow and easily lost. He prophetically pointed out several stumbling blocks that, indeed, the APA has stumbled over.In bis practical way, however (Joe was an astute businessman), be tried to point out what be felt were appropriate steps for the APA to take. His first thought was to establish a home office (the APA bad no office for several years). He actually found a piece of property with a suitable house on it and proposed the APA buy the thing. It would serve as a home office location and also as an investment. From this point in time we can look back and see what a great investment the property would have been had we bought it.As a businessman, DeAguiar recognized the value of professionals. He always advocated a home office and a small, well-paid core of professionals to run the business of the APA. After all, the APA (if I recall correctly) turns over something near a half million dollars annually. That is not a backyard bird club. The APA has a plethora of everyday business transactions that involve paying and receiving payments from an assortment of individuals, agencies, and businesses. It functions as a small company contracting with various vendors for materials and services.The APA is also set up as a not-forprofit organization. This means that much of its energy must be supplied by volunteer help. Joe was astute enough to know that 29 committees and around 150 volunteer board members would not, could not, pull together as one big team. Communications alone were, he felt, enough to confound such a bulky, scattered group. It was Joe DeAguiar, I believe, who first suggested a home office and the office of executive director. Hind sight, folks, is 20/20. All the times I met with Joe to discuss the APA, I realize now, I never understood what he was saying. Now, several years after his death, I've run across well researched studies and documents that point out in black and white most of the tbingsJoe wanted for the organization. Joe was right. The APA, however, bas been very slow shifting its huge organizational bulk towards the functional form that Joe recognized as correct and standard for non-profit outfits.But, I am happy to report to Joe's ghost, the APA bas actually made noticeable progress. About three years ago, then-President Lee Phillips took a special interest in the home office. She reorganized the personnel roster and kept in very close touch with the office activities. Under Phillips' leadership the APA began to use more effectively the executive committee, a smallish group of APA officers who have been able to consult together when necessary and make immediate decisions. This has been a great help in handling the everyday affairs of the APA. Phillips, like Joe DeAguiar, also recognized the value of a small core of paid professional help. When the Watchbird, for example, was not serving the organization as well as she thought it might, she was the one who called special meetings and ultimately authorized additional professional help.When Jennings came aboard as president, one of the first things he did was create the office of executive director. Joe's ghost will clap his hands when be learns that. For years and years everyone bas agreed with Denguiar's concept of the APA being coordinated and uplifted by a professional executive director. We all talked about it but did nothing until Jennings took the bold step and actually hired a professional to fill the long-awaited position.So the APA is, slowly but surely, evolving from the small roomful of bird club enthusiasts into a more sophisticated organization that can better serve American aviculture. It is developing organizational concepts and offices that are in closer harmony with the basic principles for non-profit organizations.But enough of this. I prefer not to write on this organizational theme. Other subjects are so much more fun. But in this case, what spurs me on is that I believe the APA is at the point where it can mushroom into a truly great organization but most of you folks think the AFA is a mere magazine. Jn fact, the APA is a very complex organization that has a number of goals and accomplishments aside from the best auicultural magazine going In the next few editorials f'/l try to touch on the AF'4, the organization, and show how it is put together and how the various offices and parts interface. You paid your money and you really deserve to know.In the meanwhile, thefollowingfew letters are included for your perusal. Ed.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2460</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 4 (1986): AUG-SEPT 1986; 52-55</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2460/2433</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
