<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1504</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:52:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">This Issue</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A zoogeographical region is, dear readers, an area defined to a great extent by the kind of animals (birds, in our case) within it. The Watchmrd series focusing on such regions begins here with Australia, Tasmania, and New Zealand - a zoogeographical region of great significance to aviculture.Fittingly, the first regional article (after my prelude) is titled "100 Years of A viculture - an Australian Perspective" by Graeme Hyde. Hyde is the perfect person to write such an article as he is one of the few who can actually remember most of those 100 years (just kidding, Graeme - I know you have forgotten some of them). He has edited Australian Aviculture for many, many, many years and has a very good feel for the history he writes of.Next comes Glen Holland's description of his family vacation through the southern part of Australia. The wild birds he reports on are a wish list for many of us. Holland is a first class aviculturist we'll meet again.Then we have a press release about Tbe Swift Parakeet, an excellent and colorful book about this rare and wonderful bird. The plethora of color photos (real eye candy) are almost all by noted wildlife photographer, Cyril Laubscher. Read this press release and take advantage of the remarkable off er it contains.Susie Christian then tells of her personal affair with a Rosejbreasted Cockatoo - one of the favorite birds from Australia.And if you have been told that Gouldian Finches still try to operate on the Australian seasonal calendar, be sure to read the short piece Peggy Dalrymple has written. She has many years experience with Australian finches and willingly shares her knowledge.Page 35 brings us to Joseph Forshaw's outstanding article on one of my personal favorites - the Goldenshouldered Parakeet. Forshaw is a world class ornithologist and aviculturist whom you all know from the extraordinary bird books he has written. You parrot people will love this article.On page 45 Dr. Matthew Vriends, another prolific and knowledgeable writer, treats us to an overview of the five most popular Australian Grass Parakeets, my first parrots after the Budgies.Then we meet Glen Holland again, this time at work. His job involves captive breeding New Zealand's endangered birds for conservation. He deals with some very interesting birds and techniques. A fascinating article.Still in New Zealand, we have Jim Chou's article on a beautiful pied mutation of the Red-fronted Kakariki.This barely scratches the surface of our first region but don't worry, we'll return to in due time.In addition to the above "regional" material, we have a lot of articles that will educate and entertain you. There is also some new Organizational material you'll be interested in. Check the newly formatted table of contents for the selection.Enjoy this journal - and we'll see you next issue in South America. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1504</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 2 (2000): March-April 2000; 5-8</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1504/1481</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
