<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3848</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-04-14T23:29:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Message from the President</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Whittaker, Jamie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I certainly have some big shos to fill. Nancy Speed may look petite, but she has a big heart and a strong spirit. SHe has been a big presence in AFA for many years; and I am glad to know that she is still looking over my shoulder as past president. The new Board of Directors represents all areas of aviculture and all species of birds. Tere are certain to be rough waters ahead, but with your support, we will continue to do everything we can to keep birds in our homes and in our lives now and in the future.Chicago was a great experience! The hotel was great; and the zoo trips were interesting. I heard that some people even got to kiss a giraffe! The speakers were interesting and educational. The vendor hall and the raffle were fun. The Lory League Bird Show had a record number of entries including birds that have almost disappeared from aviculture. Have you ever seen a Barraband Parakeet (Polytelis swainsonii) or a Sierra Parakeet (Psilopsiagon aymara)? If you went to the Lory League Bird Show in Chicago, you would have had that opportunity.Speaking of birds at AFA, Bilbo, the Curl-crested aracari (Pteroglossus beauharnaesii), was at the registation desk helping Carol Woodson greet attendees. Luna, the Golden conure, was the perfect hostess. You never knew what shoulder...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-04-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3848</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 42 No. 3 &amp; 4 (2015): Vol 42, No 3 &amp; 4 (2015); 4</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3848/3818</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
