<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3062</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-13T15:42:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Crowned Pigeons</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lint, Kenton C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Giants of the pigeon family are those members of a small but distinctive group of crowned pigeons found in more remote forests of New Guinea and neighboring islands. Three species and three sub-species have been well described. The largest form measures 33 in. (70 cm.) in length and weighs 8 to IO pounds - the size of a small turkey hen. All are greyblue and maroon in color with contrasting patches of white or gray on the wings or tip of the tail.The Crowned Pigeons, genus Goura, as a group differ from all other pigeons. They have reticulated scales on their legs, sixteen tail feathers, no oil gland and no gall bladder. The most striking feature is the erect, laterally compressed fan-shaped crest, the feathers of which have long and separated barbs which give them an attractive lace-like appearance. Unfortunately, these same filmy plumes once were prized in the millinery trade, under the name of "goura" feathers from the generic name of the group.Their behavior pattern is similar to other forms adapted to ground and forest dwelling, and like the green fruit pigeons of the genus Treron, they also show the up and down movement of the tail when excited or disturbed.The male's voice is a deep booming coo in the breeding season, similar to the drumming of an Emu to attract females in a given territory. I have observed the bowing display many times with the tail spread and erected, partly opened wings and stamping of feet in front of desirable females. In the pre-copulatory display, the female responds by crouching, running beneath the male and holding her bill close to his and making short hissing calls. When she is submissive, the male mounts and copulation is completed.The purpose of this article is to share my experiences in the successful raising of Crowned Pigeons in captivity. Far too many individuals and aviculturists keep birds rather than raise them. Hundreds of Crowned Pigeons have been imported into the United States and Eurasia in the last ten years. How many pairs raised one or two chicks consistently') Very few aviculturists have taken the time to study the breeding behavior and life history of this interesting group of pigeons.Although Crowned Pigeons are members of the pigeon family Columbidae, which has 285 species, they are a specialized group and can not be treated in the same manner as the common members of foreign pigeons and doves usually seen in public or private aviaries. They need special security, special aviaries, special nests, and special feeding for adults and chicks if propagation is to be successful.ARTIFICIAL INCUBATION. Artificial incubation of eggs is not recommended for Crowned Pigeons. After thirty-six years of experience in rearing these birds, I find that the parents will do a much better job in incubating, brooding and feeding the nestling, if only given the opportunity.SECURITY: Cover, Landscaping.Most pigeons and doves are timid birds and are easily frightened by cats, owls, hawks or rats. Untame birds rocket upward, in the manner of partridges, when they are startled, and should be given as much security as possible. To provide this security I would suggest that the entire top of the aviary be covered with corrugated fiberglass panels, plywood panels or palm fronds. In New Guinea and in their natural environment, Crowned Pigeons live in rich rain forest habitats with very little sunshine penetrating their natural homes.Good-sized trees, eucalyptus, acacia, orange, lemon, guava or fig trees may be...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3062</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 4 (1977): AUG-SEPT 1977; 6-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3062/3046</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
