<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/862</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:17:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Syringe Feeding of Baby African Greys</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Beech, Bob &amp; Marie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">At Beech's Nest Bird Ranch our AfricanGrey ba bi ~s are handfed from timeof hatch using catheter-tip syringes. Forthe first 24-48 hours we u e a l ee syringe,graduating in size to 3cc, 12cc,35cc and 60cc as the babies grow in size .By the time a baby is about two weeksold it is being fed with a 60cc syringewhich has a tip about one inch long.Syringe feeding allows the baby's foodto directly enter the crop, eliminatingmany problems associated with spoonfeeding, most conunonly aspiration.We have found that African Greys areve1y particular about the tempe rature ofthe ir food. We feed at 1 05" F. The easeand speed of the syringe allows the foodto be given at a constant temperature.We experience virtually no problemswith the birds spitting back food, whichthey almost always will do if their food istoo cool.An additional plus to syringe feedingis that it ve1y closely emulates a parentbird's beak e ntering the mouth of itsbaby.Each baby i fed with a clean syringe .All syringes and feeding utensils are easilyrinsed and kept in a disinfectant solutionbetween uses. This is an efficientway to eliminate the transference ofbacteria.Our babies are fed exclusivelyKaytee Hand Feeding Formula and allbreeders are fed exclusive ly Kaytee pe llets.We have experienced ve1y satisfactoryresults using the combination ofKaytee food and syringe feeding. Weare proud to say that our babies' growthrate and overall health are excellent.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/862</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 1 (1995): JAN-FEB 1995; 39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/862/844</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
