<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3393</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-01-21T02:17:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Notes from the AFA Red Siskin Project</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Castaner, Ron</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Did you have a chance to attend the 2005 AFA Convention at the Radisson Hotel Downtown Miami? If not, you missed a great time. Therewere many representatives and vendors, great ratte table, many new friends to meet, and many old friends to catch up with.There were knowledgeable speakers from around the USA and abroad giving us the most informative and very interesting lectures with great slide presentations, for the purpose of promoting avian conservation and avian care of our feathered friends, large and small.As the AFA South Florida State Coordinator, I'vebeen involved with the Red Siskin Project for a few years, and I've dedicated much of my time at speaking engagements around Florida promoting the Red Siskin Project. It was a pleasure to be a part of the AFA Red Siskin Project during the 2005 Convention;I answered many questions about the project. Wehad a great ratte table and slide presentation for the public to see and hear. We made available a DVD and a CD slide show featuring the Red Siskin which are available for any individual or club. Some State Coordinators have used the DVD and CD as a tool when visiting clubs around the State during their visits and speaking engagements. Other items available include Red Siskin Project polo shirts and a CD containing articles about the AFA Red Siskin Project, bird husbandry and breeding consortiums .. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .With regulations becoming tighter, breeders of any bird are going to be learning how to apply for permits; this is one of the federal requirements now mandatory when purchasing Red Siskins across state lines. All those who hold Captive Breeding Permits are required to De yearly reports. Get involved and be aware .. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .AFA's Red Siskin Project now has a partnership with the Prospect Park Zoo, which is located in the Bronx, NY. They have just acquired their captive breeding permit, and now need to acquire Red Siskins to pair up with their loaned birds from the project. The birds are currently on exhibit to raise awareness and help to expand the Red Siskin gene pool............................................The Red Siskin Project would like to thank the following:DThe members and oft.cers of Aviary &amp;amp; Cage Bird Society of Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, who donated a total of $1,000 to the Red Siskin Project.DThe members and oft.cers of Treasure Coast Exotic Bird Club of Stuart, Florida, for their many years of supporting the Red Siskin Project. They donated a pair of Gouldian Finches, including a basket and cages for the AFA Red Siskin Project ratte table this year.DSteve Applebaum, owner of Just Exotic Birds of Lake Park, Florida, for donating a pair of Shaftail Finches and cage for the AFA Red Siskin Project.DRolando Hurtado for his continued support of the AFA Red Siskin Project...........................................Please visit our Web site at: http:/home.earthlink. net--redsiskinproject • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-01-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3393</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 32 No. 2 (2005): Number 2  2005; 54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3393/3377</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
