<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1178</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-12-31T14:55:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Psittacula Sightings: Bits'n Pieces</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perry, Fred</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perry, Lyrae</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Summer and early fall is the time of year when Psittaculids are not actively engaged in procreation. It is an excellent time to review breeding records, expectations, and set new goals for future pairings. Now is the time to clean and repair nest boxes, aviaries and replace perches. Disinfect and test incubation and brooding equipment and repair or replace as needed. Most importantly, it is the time to acquire new birds and begin the process of pairing your breeders for the coming season.In this issue we've included some of our aviary management practices and other miscellaneous information to help the next breeding season get off to a good start.Breeding Season-CycleAsian parakeets are complex creatures with a specific pairing and breeding cycle that has been quite successful for thousands of years. In captivity, most species breed only in the spring. The pairing process begins sometime in August or September depending on where you live in the U.S.A.. Climate changes, rainfall, barometric pressure, health, maturity and all the other factors known only to the birds dictate the exact timing. Male birds begin courting and pair bonds are formed over a course of several weeks. Once the bonds have been formed, the pairs stake out territory (their aviary) and begin working the nest box. The pair bond will last for the current breeding season only. It ends shortly after the babies are weaned by the parents, or when the last babies have been pulled in for handfeeding. The bond is completely broken when the annual molt begins. Compatible pairs can be left together for the balance of the year with no problem. If you wish to pair your birds differently for the next season, the time to make the changes is right after the molt.Proper Pairing of Asian ParakeetsThe frantic phone calls begin in January and continue through February and sometimes as late as March ... "I need a mature three year old male for my hen" or " My hen just died and I need a mature one for this season." If the caller is lucky enough to find a mature bird at the last minute, the bird is usually thrown into an aviary with no regard to compatibility, often with disastrous results.For example, it's extremely foolhardy to put a replacement male into an aviary with a hen who has lost her mate suddenly during the breeding season. The new male is regarded as an intruder, not a fill-in mate. Even though her original mate is gone, the hen will continue to defend the territory until the season ends. The hen may tear the new male apart--literally. If he isn't killed, he may starve to death because she won't let him near the food.As with all strangers, proper introductions can go a long way toward promoting romance. Putting new pairs together is best done during the summer giving them ample time to become acquainted. The proper introduction period is about two to three months prior to the start of breeding season. Shorter introduction periods can work, but it depends on the individual birds. Several pairs of the same species can be placed in a large aviary for the annual pairing process. Ideally, each bird will be able to choose its own mate from a group. When they get to choose, success is nearly always guaranteed.Eight Indian Ring-necked sized birds will be comfortable in an aviary that measures four feet wide, eight feet high, and· ten feet long. Four Alexandrines or Derbyans can fit in the same space. Mixing species in flights is not recommended, ever. As the breeding season draws near, you'll see birds begin to pair off. They'll sit close to each other, drive away other birds, and males may begin feeding the hens.Watch to see which birds have bonded. Pull those birds out and place them in their own breeding aviary which has already been prepared, nest box hung etc. Pull out and set up the remaining pairs in this same manner. The birds paired in this manner, (the ones allowed to choose their own mates), usually begin nesting... </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1178</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 4 (1997): JULY-AUGUST 1997; 32-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1178/1157</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
