<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/715</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thorpe, Jean</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There is Work to be DoneMy husband, Paul, and I retired to Florida to enjoy the sun,sand, and leisurely lifestyle of retirement. It was a radicalchange from working and Jiving in New York state. We boughta cockatiel, which sparked our interest in birds. Shortlythereafter, we joined a local avian club affording us theopportunity to meet other bird lovers and began to acquire anovice degree of knowledge about birds. Gradually weexpanded our family of feathered friends and became submergedin the world of aviculture; thus ending the leisurelylifestyle.During the past ten years we have been involved with birds,there have been many a vi cultural advances in research, feedingprograms, avian medicine, and most notably legislation.Government agencies on local, state and federal levels are alltaking a serious look at various aspects of bird ownership,breeding, and transporting. Recently, federal legislation waspassed that will greatly affect our breeding programs byimposing restrictions on various species being imported andrequiring breeding accountability. The mechanics for administeringthis legislation are not yet in place, but will be shortly. Inaddition to current federal legislation, we can surely expect thatfurther regulations will be generated to govern our activities.I believe it is now time for avian clubs to take a serious lookat their purpose and re-think their responsibilities to theindustry, the membership and, most importantly, the birds.There are professional organizations that establish and maintainoperating standards; thus are regulated from within. Ipropose that avian clubs establish and maintain a set ofstandards for membership.Initially, a group from your club, or group of clubs in an area,would set forth written standards for bird owners and breeders.This should include minimum cage requirements, feedingprograms, record keeping, isolation, incubation, baby careprocedures, banding, sanitation, and safety requirements.Where State avian federations exist, it may be possible tosolicit their help in order to establish uniformity for all clubswithin the state.All current members and new applicants would be requiredto submit to a membership team's inspection to certify thatsta?dards are being met, with reinspections on an annual basisto J~sure that these standards are being maintained in order toretam club membership. Once the team feels that birds arebeing ade~uately taken. care of, certification of membershipand comphan~e can be Issued. Persons not meeting standardswould be advised of the deficiencies and given a time frame inwhich to co~ect the pr?blems and re-apply. Naturally, ownersof a~ _occasJ.onal pet b1rd wou.ld fall into a separate categoryrequmng ~mque st~dards .. This program would require a paidmembership comnuttee With funds being obtained from a It may very well become necessary to take such steps in thenear future, so starting now could be very advantageous.Primate breeders are currently subjected to inspections fromoutside, therefore, it is not improbable to assume that aviariesmay become subjected to similar regulations. Clubs that setprecedents by establishing standards will be in a viableposition to negotiate with other agencies and to cope with theoutcome.This is an ambitious program and one that would require alot of work and money, but would constitute a valuableaccomplishment in the avian field, one that would earn therespect of local, state and federal officials. Such a programwould be educational for the bird owners and definitelybeneficial to the birds. Club membership should be an earnedprivilege.All of your members will not be willing to participate in thisprogram. Therefore, a "Friends" program should be in placeto continue generating the necessary revenue to run the club.Friends could continue to enjoy club activities in the samemanner as today. The primary difference might possibly betheir inability to purchase or sell birds depending upon theextent of future regulations that may be imposed on aviculture.The regulations being imposed on the avian industry areprimarily for the purposes of insuring humane treatment ofbirds and preserving endangered species. We have all seenconditions that are less than desirable. Ultimately, those of uswho Jove birds want the best for them. Clubs are in the bestposition to reach the majority of bird owners. Therefore, itshould be our responsibility to act as role models by settingprecedence. Is there a better way to advance our cause andtruly protect our interests?•</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/715</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 50-54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/715/698</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
