<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3886</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-17T03:14:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Perspectives on The Future of Pionus Parrots in American Aviculture (part 2 of 2)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sargent, Mark</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Species History in U.S. Aviculture and Current Status (Additions to Part 1)
Plum-crowned (P. tumultuosus)
Despite limitations in the available Plum-crowned stock, the PBA was able to successfully produce a few clutches from a single pair in California. Unfortunately, nearly all of the young produced by this pair succumbed to aspergillosis, either prior to or shortly after fledging.
Over time, the foundation stock of Plum-crowned parrots in American aviculture steadily declined. The remaining population became heavily skewed, with far fewer females than males. This imbalance led to a severe genetic bottleneck. With no additional imports and no surviving offspring from the original consortium to sustain breeding, the species could no longer be propagated in captivity.
As a result, the Plum-crowned—along with Messena’s—has effectively been lost from American aviculture, as no viable breeding populations remain.

Dusky (P. fuscus)
First bred in aviculture: 1983 — Ramon Nogel and Greg Moss, USA
Dusky Pionus were imported in small numbers, primarily from Guyana. These birds proved difficult to maintain, as they were more prone to stress and generally higher-strung than other Pionus species. Many early imports died without any clear physical cause, even after necropsy.
It wasn’t until 1983 that the first successful breeding occurred, achieved by Ramon Nogel and Greg Moss at Life Fellowship in Seffner, Florida. This milestone highlights both the challenges and the relatively recent establishment of this species in aviculture—marking it as a true American avicultural success.
With their beautiful pastel violet coloration and distinctive, almost falcon-like appearance, Dusky Pionus became a point of interest among aviculturists. However, demand from the general public has remained limited, raising concerns that the species could face a future genetic bottleneck.

Factors in the Current Pet Bird Market (Continued from Part 1)
In addition to Pionus species, there has been a noticeable decline in the variety of small- to medium-sized parrots and parakeets offered by large pet retail chains.
Species such as small macaws (e.g., yellow-collared), Poicephalus parrots (including Senegals, Red-bellied, and Meyer’s), as well as others like Brotogerus and parakeets such as Bourke’s and lineolated parakeets, are becoming less available. These birds are often well-suited for modern living situations due to their manageable size, quieter vocalizations, and adaptability to apartment or condominium life.
Despite offering many of the same desirable companion qualities as the more commonly marketed “standard” parrot species, these birds are increasingly underrepresented in the current pet trade.
 
[For the full article and image, please continue to the PDF]</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3886</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 52 No. 2 (2025): AFA Watchbird Fall/Winter 2025; 20-29</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
