<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/219</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:56:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Blue Mountain Lorikeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Risser, Arthur C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Lories and lorikeets are small to themedium sized parrots whose brushshapedtongues are uniquely adapted tofeeding on nectar and pollen. Birds ofthe genus Trichoglossus have long beenpopular as aviary birds but have presentedtaxonomic problems because oftheir wide distribution and the closeresemblance of some forms. As a groupthese Rainbow lories, as they are sometimescalled, are distributed among manyof the Indonesian islands, east throughNew Guinea and the adjacent islands tothe Solomon Islands, New Hebrides, NewCaledonia and the Royal Islands, andalong northern and eastern Australia,including Tasmania. Currently there aretwenty or twenty-one recognized subspeciesof Trichoglossus haematodus,although in the literature there has beensome argument as to the validity ofsome of these subspecies. (See, forexample, Rosemary Low's article in theNov/Dec 1974 and- B. Sayers, April/June 1975 issues of Aviculture Magazine.)Some aviculturists and authorschoose to drop the scientific name,haematodus, and refer to the Rainbowlories only by their subspecific name.Thus, Swainson's or Blue Mountainlorikeet, Trichoglossus haematodus moluccanusis sometimes seen as simplyTrichoglossus moluccanus.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/219</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 3 No. 6 (1976): DEC-JAN 1977; 5-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/219/210</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
