<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4015</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Golden Eagle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Darden, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 1 (January/February 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.By Jennifer Darden Write for Birds Meet Rory, a Golden Eagle who was critically injured when hit by a moving vehicle. He spent three days on oxygen, coughing up blood and fighting to survive. Thanks to Winged Freedom Raptor Hospital, look where he is now! He ’s quite the feathered nomad, as they estimate he has migrated 1500 miles since being released back in early April, according to River Valley Raptors and Raptor Resource Project who backpacked him with a GPS tracking unit.wingedfreedomrh.com Of the over 60 species of eagles found around the world, the Golden Eagle has the largest home range. They inhabit four continents in the northern hemisphere, including North America. An upland predator that hunts mammals, Golden Eagles are primarily found in the western half of North America in the mountains and desert southwest. However, recent observations of the past 25 years have changed their understanding of these incredible raptors and redrawn their range maps in North America. Researchers now know that migratory populations spend the winter months in portions ofthe eastern United States. The National Eagle Center - The Golden Eagle Project - in its 20th year nationaleaglecenter.org The National Eagle Center encapsulates a world in which the iconic power and presence of eagles are known, respected, advocated for and protected. Located in Wabasha, Minnesota, they ’re home to several non -releasable Bald Eagles and a nesting place for hundreds of other winter visitors. They offer education, awareness and research through field trips, habitat tours, eagle cams and exhibits.Twenty years is an important milestone for a project, both from a longevity and a data set standpoint. Because of the work and dedication from hundreds of volunteers over the past two decades, understanding North America&amp;#x27;s other native eagle species has changed and improved.Ongoing research is dedicated to better understanding the presence of Golden Eagles in the eastern United States. Migratory Golden Eagles come to the region each winter from their nesting territory upwards of 2,000 miles away in northern Canada, just below the Arctic Circle. Every January on the third Saturday, the Project conducts its annual Golden Eagle Survey. Volunteer surveyors (citizen scientists) spread out over portions of southeastern Minnesota, southwestern Wisconsin, northeastern Iowa, and northwestern Illinois tocount Golden Eagles observed. Results are reported and analyzed to develop a better understanding of these migratory eagles and are featured on their website. Rory the Golden Eagle Conservation Installing GPS Tracker These eagles settle into the bluff lands of the Driftless Area during the winter. The Driftless Area is a 15,000 square mile region of western Wisconsin, the corners of southeastern Minnesota, northeastern Iowa, and northwestern Illinois that was not flattened by the glacial ice sheets during the last Ice Age. The geographyClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4015</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 1 (2024): Watchbird January/February 2024; 24-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4015/3975</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
