<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/863</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:17:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Finch Videography</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buckley, Stash</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Arelatively new aspect of avicultureis the ability of the averagebirdkeeper to document and record birdbehavior - a realm once rese1ved exclusivelyfor the scientist and researcher.With the constant advances in videotechnology and the blurring of lines betweenconsumer and professionalequipment, it is now possible fo r the averageperson to afford and make professionalvideos. In our experience, birdswhich are frightened by a 35mm cameraremain at ease, canying on their normalactivities, in the presence of a small camcorder.!Iowever, when setting out tobuy equipment, one is suddenly caughtin the dilemma of deciding in which ofthe various formats to invest. If you donor choose wisely from the beginning,you may be stuck with a dying format orone that is inadequate for your purposes.The formats available are VI-IS , SVHS,Smm, and Hi-8mm. Beta and UMaticare professional formats, but wee liminate them due to the prohibitivecost and the bulky size of the equipment.VHS is the standard consumer formatand the o ne you are probably most familiarwith, as it is the most likely thekind of VCR you have connected to yourtelevision. We discou rage the birdvideographer from investing in this fo rmat,as it delivers only about 225lines ofresolution and deteriorates quickly aftero nly a few generations. The VI IS camcorderson the market contain o nl y o neCCO (charged coupling device). Bygenerations we mean the process ofmaking a copy of the ta pe from the o riginal,then a copy of tl1at copy, etc. A CCOis responsible for the capturing of thelight and turning it into magnetic signals.S-VHS (Super VHS), 8mm, and Hi-8provide about 400 lines of resolutio n,which makes these good formats inwhich to invest. Smm was meant to bethe standard of the indust1y. However,many companies in Japan broke awayfrom this in favor of their own particularformat. lli-8 is an improvement overregular 8mm, providing better picturequality. Our first video "BreedingFi11cbes- Parts 1 and 2 "was shot entirelyon 8mm. 'Tbe Cuban Melodious"ancl''E1y1bura - The Parrot Finches" wereshot with a mix of both 8mm and Hi-8."The Red Strawberry Finch "was shot almostentirely on Hi-8.The choice you really have to make,then , is between S-Vl IS and I li-8 equipment,as both offer you high resolution,acceptable loss of quality gene ration aftergeneration, and the availability ofprofessional equipment. They also otlerwhat is now known as '' pro-sumer"equipment - a crossover between consumerand professional. Also important,both of these formats provide you withprofessional tape formulations, as you donot want to play back that once-In-a-lifetimeshot to discover it is little more than asmudge. Make sure you use true professionaltape, which is generally not availablethrough consumer retailers. So becautious if your local retailer sells you"professio nal" tape. Just because it saysprofessional on the box does not necessarilymake it so. Generally the true professionaltape is available to only those in thetrade. Make it a point to seek out thosesources which will sell to the pros as wellas to the "pro-sumers"who are serious andwilling to buy in quantity.!!ere is where other crite ria have tobe taken into account. If you plan onmaking and releasing your own videos,another factor becomes important -the narration track. Jf you choose SVHS,:tft:er you have edited your mastervideo with the footage in the seque nceyou desire you will have to record theaudio narration separately, probably onaudio tape, synchronize that with yourvideo, and record yet another generationwith the narration mixed with themaster, resulting in a third gene rationvideo.With each subsequent generation you will naturally lose some quality.You now see the majorf1aw of the S-VHSformat. Another drawback is the size ofthe camcorder equipment. Most ofthese are large shoulder-mount models.As anyone who has worked with smallbirds knows, it is very difficult to look inconspicuouswith a large growth onyour shoulder. The manufacturers of SVHShave countered this problem withthe introduction of S-VHS-C. The drawbackhere, however, is the smaller cassettesprovide shorter running times- adefinite drawback if you are recordingthat once-in-a-lifetime nest-building orchick-feeding sequence.Hi-8, on the other hand, is a miniaturizedformat, the videocassettes beingabout the size of a standard audio cassette,and provides the same standardrecording time as S-VHS- two hours.Also, the smaller size ofthe camcorder isa real plus, enabling you to movequickly and effortlessly between cageswith a hand-held model.Here is where the term "pro-sumer"really comes into use. What basicallyseparates consumer from professionalcamcorders is the number of CCD's. Professionalmodels contain three- one foreach of the primary colors of the spectrum.Consumer models contain only one. BothS-VHS and Hi-8 have hand-held modelsthat contain three CCD's, giving you a superiorpicture and one of broadcast-qualityresolution.Since we have already eliminated thelarge shoulder-mount models for ourpurposes, the choice comes down to ahand-held 3 CCD S-VHS or a hand-held3 CCD Hi-8. The S-VHS models currentlyavailable have fewer pixels,which determine sharpness of pictures,than the Hi-8 model, which leads us tothe crux of the matter. And the winneryouguessed it - it's a Sony Handicammodel CCD VX 3 - lightweight, small,professional quality. This is the camcorderwe currently use in our video production.Now for the bonus on the Hi-8 format:it provides an additional audio track(digital, no less). When youhaveyourfinalvideo footage edited up, you simplyplay back the master on your editingdeck and over-dub your narration ontothe PCM track. This way you saved anadditional generation and you can easilycorrect or augment your narration.Now that you are delighted that youhave the answer to your video dilemma,here is the Hi-8 drawback. Due to thesmall size of the cassette, it is much more susceptible to wear and tear than S-VHS.After producing a Hi-8 master, we makean S-VHS sub-master and, from this, werun off the VHS copies. The major loss ofquality occurs when you start makingyour VHS copies.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/863</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 1 (1995): JAN-FEB 1995; 40-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/863/845</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
