<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1647</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:50:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Hanging Parrot and Fig Parrot National Conservatory</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he newest organization in the avicultural community, is also one of the most dedicated and enthusiastic about their birds and their goals. The Hanging and Fig Parrot National Conservatory was founded by Ron Kasper on December 6. 2000. In a little over a month, they had more than 20 members from around the world including many internationally known aviculturists and its membership continues to grow by leaps and bounds.As with many new organizations these days, the Hanging and Fig Parrot National Conservatory primarily communicates with its members on the Internet. A members only newsgroup has been set up for members to find birds, exchange information and compare notes.Mission Statement• We are a not for profit organization of aviculturists who are dedicated to the national preservation of all species of Hanging Parrots and Fig Parrots through maintenance, breeding, sharing of information, public education, and cooperation with approved zoological gardens made possible through our national conservatory.• Associate members cooperate with charter members for propagation of the species and to strengthen bloodlines of birds. International cooperation is invited. We are not a resource for the sale of birds.• We support many avian organizations and especially encourage members to join and become active including the American Federation of Aviculture, World Parrot Trust, and the International Lori Journal.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1647</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 2 (2001): MAR-APR 2001; 52</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1647/1624</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
