<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2648</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-19T21:07:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Australian Cockatoos</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sindel, Stan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Editor's Note: Stan Sindel is a noted and well-respected aviculturist from Sydney, Australia. He presented two papers at the 1985 national AFA convention in San Francisco, California, one of which was Australian Cockatoos. This article deals with the Australian cockatoos found in their natural habitat and in Australian aviculture. Mr. Sindel is the author of the book, "Australian Lorikeets."We have eleven species and many subspecies of cockatoos in Australia.Two of these subspecies are quite distinct. For avicultural purposes, I shall deal with them as separate species; they are the White-tailed Black Cockatoo and the Western Long-billed Corella.When one considers there are only 18 species of cockatoos in the world, it is clear that the Australian cockatoo family is very well represented. One or more species of cockatoo may be seen in every form of habitat found over the entire continent.The Palm Cockatoo, Gang Gang and Galah are monotypic; that is, they are the only member of their genus. The cockatiel is the only member of its entire sub-family ( Calo psi ttaci ni).Some of the species, such as Sulphur-crested Cockatoos, Galahs and Short-billed Corellas, now exist in almost plague proportions particularly in some of the farming areas. The clearing of land for grazing and the development of permanent water for stock purposes, particularly in the more arid areas, has helped these three species to extend their range and expand their numbers. The population explosions that have resulted put these birds in jeopardy. The birds now suffer from massive extermination efforts in the farming districts.All species are still surviving well in the wild with the exception of the Major Mitchell Cockatoo. That species still exists in reasonable numbers. The species is suffering from the side effects of poisoning and general persecution by the farmers. While the farmers' depopulation efforts are directed at the Sulphur-crested Cockatoos and the Galahs that inhabit the same areas, the Major Mitchell species suffers as well. The Long-billed Corella is also in a vulnerable position. The vulnerability is due to the species' limited range, which extends into the grain growing areas. The numbers of Long-billed Corellas are high, but constant persecution due to its habit of damaging crops, places the species at great risk.I have been fortunate enough to have observed all species and most subspecies in the wild. Even so, as a native Australian, I am still thrilled by the sight of black cockatoos, Major Mitchell Cockatoos and Gang Gangs in their natural habitat.Over the last 20 years, I have bred all the non-black species of Australian cockatoos, with the exception of the Sulphur-crested Cockatoo. I have never kept the Palm or the black cockatoos. All the avicultural information on the black cockatoos is given by Mr. Bob Lynn of Sydney, Australia. I consider Mr. Lynn to be the greatest aviculturist in Australia today. He keeps only black cockatoos, and in specializing in this family I believe he chose one of the most difficult of avicultural subjects.He has bred all species including the Palm Cockatoo and the Yellowtailed Black Cockatoo for the first time in aviculture, in the world. Australian aviculturists do not consider a hand-reared bird to be a first breeding. To achieve a first breeding award, the youngster must be reared to independence by the parents.DietsCockatoos represent such a diverse family that diets must, of necessity, vary considerably. In general, a basic mixed seed diet of sunflower, canary, maize, sorghum, safflower, wheat and millet may be fed to all species, with the exception of the Galah. The Galah is very subject to obesity. I feed those birds only the basic diet of white millet and sorghum, and even these seeds should be fed in limited quantities.All cockatoos enjoy, and should be given, sprouted seeds (particularly sunflower and maize), sweet corn, wholemeal bread, raw peanuts, various fruits and vegetables, a variety of green foods, table scrap bones such as chop bones, chicken bones, and the like. One can add, on occasion, a little raw meat (particularly for Gang Gangs and black cockatoos), plain cake, biscuits and dog kibble.Bob Lynn attributes some of his success with the black cockatoos to feeding them Casurina cones. He also feeds his black cockatoos Banksia, Hakea and pine cones.Bob Lynn and I have both found that baby cockatoos being reared by the parents often suffer from calcium deficiencies. We have overcome such deficiencies by feeding a calcium supplement on the sprouted seeds.Feeding a good balanced diet to cockatoos is one thing, getting them to eat that balanced diet is another. Perseverance and cunning is needed to get some individual birds to eat what you know they should eat. Bob Lynn dusts all his sunflower seeds with a mineral and vitamin supplement and he feels this is having a desired effect.When hand rearing cockatoos, I feed a mixture of two parts "Farex" baby food, one part chicken starter pellets and one part egg and biscuit canary rearing food, together with calcium, mineral and vitamin supplements. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2648</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 1 (1990): FEB-MAR 1990; 19-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2648/2629</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
