<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/772</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:01:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Wild Geese</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elgas, Bob</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Brant Family Within the brant family are five well defined species. As is the case with true geese, they enjoy wide distribution throughout the northern hemisphere. The five species consist of Canada geese, the true Brant, the Barnacle Goose, Red-breasted Goose, and the Hawaiian or Nene Goose. The Canada Goose is certainly the best known of all North American species. It is found throughout much of North America where at least 11 subspecific races have been recognized. These range in size from the very large Giant Canada Goose, which has been recorded with weights in excess of 20 pounds, to the tiny Cackling and Aleutian Canada Geese weighing as little as three or four pounds. All races of Canada Geese are marked alike. The head and neck is black with the familiar white cheek patch. As is true with all members of the brant family, feet and bills are black. The body color ranges from gray to brown, depending upon sub-species and, as is true with most geese, the pigmentation is darker on the back than on the underside. During recent years, certain races of Canada Geese have enjoyed a substantial increase in population. This is largely as a result of their capability to adapt to an environment which has a close proximity to humans. As an example, they are fond of golf courses, where they are frequently encountered in substantial numbers. The tender green grasses and waterways are much to their liking, and they don't hesitate to partake of an inviting environment. The true Brant are represented by four sub-species. These are the Atlantic Brant, the Pacific or Black Brant, the little known Laurence's Brant and the Russian Brant. Brant are unique among geese in that they are almost exclusively marine in habit. Other than when they come ashore during the nesting season, almost their entire life is spent upon salt water. They feed upon marine vegetation, especially The Brant Family Within the brant family are five well defined species. As is the case with true geese, they enjoy wide distribution throughout the northern hemisphere. The five species consist of Canada geese, the true Brant, the Barnacle Goose, Red-breasted Goose, and the Hawaiian or Nene Goose. The Canada Goose is certainly the best known of all North American species. It is found throughout much of North America where at least 11 subspecific races have been recognized. These range in size from the very large Giant Canada Goose, which has been recorded with weights in excess of 20 pounds, to the tiny Cackling and Aleutian Canada Geese weighing as little as three or four pounds. All races of Canada Geese are marked alike. The head and neck is black with the familiar white cheek patch. As is true with all members of the brant family, feet and bills are black. The body color ranges from gray to brown, depending upon sub-species and, as is true with most geese, the pigmentation is darker on the back than on the underside. During recent years, certain races of Canada Geese have enjoyed a substantial increase in population. This is largely as a result of their capability to adapt to an environment which has a close proximity to humans. As an example, they are fond of golf courses, where they are frequently encountered in substantial numbers. The tender green grasses and waterways are much to their liking, and they don't hesitate to partake of an inviting environment. The true Brant are represented by four sub-species. These are the Atlantic Brant, the Pacific or Black Brant, the little known Laurence's Brant and the Russian Brant. Brant are unique among geese in that they are almost exclusively marine in habit. Other than when they come ashore during the nesting season, almost their entire life is spent upon salt water. They feed upon marine vegetation, especially eel grass, which is a great favorite. In captivity, they graze on green grass and adapt to a terrestrial environment exactly like other geese. Brant are small, weighing three to four pounds. General plumage color is black and white. Although they are not brightly colored, they are dainty and graceful and pleasing in appearance. The Barnacle Goose is medium to small. It breeds in Iceland and Spitzbergen and winters on the west coast of Europe, especially in Scotland and the British Isles. They are largely black and white with a substantial patch of white on the head and face. The name Barnacle Goose originated in a most unusual way. They were described long ago before bird migration was known. Observers of that time only knew the geese disappeared in the fall and re-appeared the following spring. The disappearance in the fall was explained by the possibility that the population simply disappeared and perhaps died. This did not explain the re-appearance in the spring until an enterprising observer of the time "discovered" that geese were produced by Barnacle trees! Barnacle trees, it was explained, produced barnacle shells. As these shells matured and ripened, they would split open allowing the contents to be released. Those contents that fell upon the ground came to naught. However, the contents that fell upon the water would develop and become Barnacle Geese, thus the species was able to perpetuate itself. Verification of this remarkable phenomenon was authenticated by eye witness accounts, including sketches and drawings of the actual event. It was not until much later, as bird migration became known, that it was realized Barnacle Geese actually spent their summers and reared their young in Iceland and Spitzbergen and returned to their winter home in Britain and Europe with the arrival of the fall. Old tales can die hard, and the story of Barnacle trees is still remembered today. The name Barnacle Goose has endured and, perhaps - just perhaps - maybe a few Barnacle Geese, indeed, do still come from Barnacle trees. One of the most beautiful of all waterfowl is the tiny Red-breasted Goose of Russia. As is true with others of the clan, there is considerable black and white feathering. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/772</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 2 (1994): MAR-APR 1994; 55-59</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/772/755</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
