<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2969</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-14T09:52:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Convention, Dallas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clause, Sharon F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The fourth annual convention of the American Federation of Aviculture was co-hosted by the Dallas Cage Bird Society and the Fort Worth Bird Club. Fifty delegates, state coordinators, and officers gathered in the North Park Inn convention center in Dallas, Texas, to conduct the business meeting August 23rd. One of the decisions made was to hold board meetings every two months rather than monthly with two of them to be held outside of California. Another - the 1979 convention to be held in Florida!With official business out of the way, delegates joined other aviculturists enjoying the convention.Dr. Raymond Jerome, Convention Chairman, assisted by Joe De Aguiar, Steering Committee Chairman, arranged an informative series of lectures on a diversity of topics ranging from "progress during the last twenty years in aviculture" to "pending legislation". An innovation was the inclusion of a "hands-on" workshops in avian r photography (Steve Clause), avian firstaid (Greg Harrison, D.V.M.), and bird slide presentations (Dr. Rainer Erhart).The Saturday evening banquet was preceded by the AF A raffel conducted by Joe de Aguiar. Ray Berwick, noted bird trainer, discussed techniques used to train Fred (Baretta's cockatoo) and other avian performers. He also mentioned his project to train "seeing-eye" Macaws for the blind! The highlight of the banquet was the presentation of A VY Awards by Roland Dubuc, followed by the installation of officers for 1979: Dr. Richard Baer - President, Lee Horton - 1st VicePresident, Joseph de Aguiar - 2nd VicePresident, Helen Hanson - Secretary, Janice Pritchard - Chief Financial.Officer , Joe McLaughlin - Membership, Sharon Clause - Corresponding Secretary.On Sunday, two zoo trips - one to each of the host cities - were featured. Sunday also marked the day of the veterinarian seminar - another AF A innovation. This special scientific seminar carried approved continuing education credit for those veterinarians in attendance! The evening workshops featured laparoscopy, artificial insemination, and examples of chromosomal sexing and parasitism. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2969</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 4 (1978): AUG-SEPT 1978; 21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2969/2953</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
