<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/660</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Birds of Africa</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Publishers: Academic PressPrice: $140.25 per volume (sevenvolumes are planned)Editors: Leslie Brown, Emil Urban,Kenneth Newman (Vol. 1). Subsequentvolumes edited by C. Hila1y Fq,Stuart Keith and Emil Urban.Collectors and readers of ornithologicalbooks have undoubtedly seen a number of series begun but not completed.Nothing frustrates one morethan to invest several hundred dollarsin volumes one and two of a four volumeset only to discover that the lasttwo volumes will not be produced.Fortunately for those with an interestin African birds this is not the casewith The Birds of Africa. Volume onewas published in 1982 and containedOstriches to Falcons. Of interest toaviculturists are the accounts of penguins,storks, flamingoes and waterfowl.Number two in this series wasavailable in 1986 and covered Gamebirdsto Pigeons. Number three, publishedin 1988, was devoted to Parrotsto Woodpeckers and finally volumethree in 1992 tackled the first 312 ofthe roughly 1,200 passerine specieson the continent and outlying islands.While it has been ten years since thefirst volume was available, it appearsthat with only three volumes remaininga series will actually be producedthat provides all the volumes necessaqto complete its topical area!As with most comprehensive, hardboundbooks, this series is an investmentof significant mag nitude. Toobtain the first four volumes will "setyou back" approximately $600.00.Another attribute of the "series" conceptis that of constant price increases.This set has already spanned a decadeso it seems reasonable that later volumesare increased by $20.00. Giventhe cost and difficulty of securingmany African species for captivebreeding, the purchase would justifyitself if it contributed, even in a smallway, to your successfully breeding ormaintaining one pair of birds. Nevertheless,I have noted numerous singlevolumes on the shelves of aviculturists.Undoubtedly they purchased onlythose volumes that contained speciesthey were interested in. While Iencourage you to consider purchasingthe series (one never knows, you maychange your interest and experiencedifficulty obtaining new volumes) Ihave included a listing of the contentsof each volume.The overall approach to species presentationis rather straight forward.Each species is discussed in terms ofits range and status followed by adetailed description of the bird includingimmature and young, field characters,voice, general behavior, food andbreeding biology. Reference is madeto the various color plates that illustrateeach species.While books do exist that deal withthe birds of north, east and southAfrica, this series also includes westAfrica. Given that a number of finchesare exported from west Africa, lack ofa good handbook has contributed toour inability to breed these species.Unfortunately, the three remainingvolumes will cover the remaining 888passerines of Africa including thefinches!Volume 1 ContentsOrder Struthioniformes, Procellariiformes,Sphenisciformes, Pellecaniformes,Ciconiiformes, Phoenicopteriformes,Anseriformes, Falconiformes.Volume 2 ContentsOrder Galliformes, Gmiformes, Pterocliformes,Columbiformes.Volume 3 ContentsOrder Psittaciformes, Musophagiformes,Cuculiformes, Strigiformes,Camprimulgiformes, Apodiformes,Coraciiformes, Piciformes.Volume 4 ContentsOrder Passeriformes including thefollowing families: Broadbills, Pittas,Larks, Swallows and Martins, Wagtails,Cuckoo-shrikes, Bulbuls, Waxwings,Dippers, Wrens, Accentors,Thmshes (to chats).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/660</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 16-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/660/643</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
