<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2157</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T03:20:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Operation Brown Pelican-an Update</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Woerpel, Richard W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Since Charlene Beane 's excellent initial article (''Brown Pelicans Maimed ... ". Vol. IX, No. 6, The A.F.A. Watchbird) on the mutilation of California Brown Pelicans, a lot has happened and a lot hasn't happened.Sixteen pelicans (all juvenile birds) currently reside at Crown Valley Animal Hospital in Laguna Niguel, California. Four have been successfully "fitted" with beak prostheses. Of the twelve remaining birds, we hope to surgically apply prostheses to all of them, although several may not be able to benefit from such surgery because so little of their upper beaks remain. Three other mutilated juvenile Brown Pelicans have been humanely euthanized at different times because of the severity of their wounds when presented to veterinarians for examination and one lost its struggle to live shortly after Fish and Game wardens presented it to Crown Valley Animal Hospital because of excessive hemorrhage.The most dramatic development with Operation Brown Pelican has been the development of a new surgical method of attachment of the upper beak prosthesis. We are confident that this new surgical procedure will offer the birds their best chance to be returned to the wild and maximize their survival potential.Shortly after the first surgery ("Pinocchio" on 10-z4-82), Dr. Greg Crose, an aero space engineer with PDA Engineering of Santa Ana, Ca., contacted head surgeon Dr. Robert Rooks to offer his assistance in exploring a different method of attachment of the prosthesis which he hoped would be bio-rnechanicall y superior to the first procedure. His unselfish efforts with Dr. Rooks and those of Dr. Crose 's co-workers were fruitful. Successful surgeries employing this new procedure with his personal guidance were performed on "Rusty'; "Kathy Lee', and "Jamie" (11-16-82), although still in captivity. The next surgery is scheduled for 1-9-83.Sadly, no progress has been reported by officials of California Fish and Game and...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2157</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 10 No. 1 (1983): FEB-MARCH 1983; 41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2157/2131</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
