<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/995</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Lord Derby's Beautiful Parakeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, Edye</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I once had the pleasure of owning andcaring for a pair ofDerbyan Parakeets.My experiences with this speciesstarted back in 1988 when it proveddifficult to locate a pair of these not-socommonAsian beauties. I contacted avery knowledgeable breeder of Asianbirds in Florida, but with males beingharder to come by, I had to settle for a.year old male with a mature three yearold hen . None the less .... I had mypair!In February of 1989, the pair wasshipped to their new home in Ohio.Basement living seemed inappropriatefor such elegant birds, however, itwas the best Ohio and I could offer. Theywere somewhat flightly after their tripand a visit to the vet, but they'd beenhandfed birds and were quick to settledown.They were housed in a 4 x 4 x 8 ft.suspended flight made of 1 x 2 in., 14gauge welded wire . The double floorprovided a grate over the bottom floorthat lined newspapers. Note: Derbyansshould not be housed in anything lesssturdy than 14 gauge wire due to theirgreat beak strength.Perches were made from naturalbranches of various handwoods. I havecut, cleaned &amp;amp; weathered more 4 ft.branches for this pair over the pastfive years than most birds go throughin a lifetime! . These guys loved tochew! All kidding aside, I catered to thisneed because I thought it not onlyprovided entertainment but was alsomentally stimulating as well as excellentbeak exercise. Hanging appletreelogs proved to be my pair's favorite roostingspot each night. These 6 in. thick logswere suspended from the cage top,one on each side of one end of the flight.A heavy wire was run through anaugerdrilled hole, half-way down andthrough the middle of each log.Humidity was controlled at around700/o and lighting was provided from twoVita Lights suspended over the flight aswell as other fluorescent lighting inthe basement. Two separate timersstaggered on/off lighting 1/2 hour apartto simulate dusk/dawn. Summer monthsran 15 hours of light daily from 6:30AM-9:30PM. Winter months were set for13 hours of light daily from 7:00AM- 8:00PM.This pair was not very demonstrativein their affections with each other. ..living up to their Asian reputation of notbeing very cuddly. I never saw thempreen each other but they did livepeacefully together with the extent ofdisagreements being who could "stealthe-peanut" away from the other. Beingtrue water-lovers .. . bickering regularlybroke out each morning over whocould get closest to the stream of waterfrom the garden-sprayer. Since thefemale was the bossiest. .. she usuallywon the water and the peanut!Being only seasonal breeders leftmuch time to enjoy other nicities of lifesuch as toys! They loved swings of allkinds. A variety of acrylic, leather, hardwooden, whole nuts, and hard rubber'kong' type toys were all considered"safe" choices. Caution was in orderbecause of their great beak strength ...and new toys were always monitored.The Derbyans were easy to feedbecause they were not picky eaters.Separate containers of pellets, parrot seed(half standard/ half Fiesta Parrot), millet(loose or spray), and clean water wereavailable at all times. The 8 ft. long cageallowed flying space and kept this pairphysically trim and they were allowedall the seed they wanted. A container ofsoftfood was also served daily. Thiswas made in quanity, frozen, thaweduntil warm and served. It consisted ofa variety of cooked beans, rice, pasta,raisins, wheat, oats, barley, walnuts,shelled pine-nuts, par-cooked sweetpotatoes, cut up dried apricots, a largebag of frozen mixed vegetables, cranberriesin season, and anything else thatfreezes well. This standard mix wasserved daily and topped off with severalitems that did not freeze well... suchas fresh dark greens, fresh fruits, cheeses,etc. This pair's all-time favorites werefresh celery (high in sodium), sproutedsunflower seeds (especially whenfeeding babies), corn-on-the-cob, andpieces of Oscar Meyer brand hotdogs.An avian vitamin was sprinkled onsoftfood several times a week. Cuttlebone ·pieces were also given several times aweek unless the hen was laying ... thenit was offered daily.Although not mature until threeyears of age, pair feeding, copulation,and egg laying began that ftrst year... withthe hen three and the male only one.I'm sure the hen being mature stimulatedthe male's interest in courtship at sucha young age. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/995</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 1 (1996): JAN-FEB 1996; 57-58</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/995/975</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
