<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2909</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-10T17:00:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">1979 AFA Photo Contest Winners</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The 1979 Photo Contest produced many spectacular photos. All enrrees were displayed at the convention exhibit hall of the Diplomat Hotel, Hollywood, Florida. The committee chairman handling the work load this year was Ron DeVolder, with Steve Clause, Ted Grochowski, Jr., and Dan Manin serving as judges. The judges studied, debated, meditated and finally emerged with the list of winners which were announced at the Saturday evening convention banquet, August 25th. On these two pages and this issue's front and back covers you see all the winning enrrees. It is hoped that Margaret Perry will forgive us for showing her Diamond Sparrow in black and white. That beautiful photo is in the works as a future Watchbird color front cover. The other two winning color slides shown here in black and white will also appear in full color in later issues of the Watchbird.When the Watchbird art director studied all the entrees, it was clear that the list of winners were deserving, but there were still quite a few beautiful photos that merited reproduction. Throughout the future issues, you will see the fine work of the other enrrees that have been selected for publication. Their names are: G.W. Pillsbury, Norfold, VA., Renee Lapperuque, La Jolla, CA., Harold Hanson III, Redondo Beach, CA., E. Trent Swigert, Jackson, MS., Gary Lilienthal, Boston, MA., Colleen E. Rumph, Hacienda Hts., CA., Jack Leslie, Whittier, CA., Manuel Iglesias, Jacksonville, FL., Patricia Witman, Escondido, CA. COLOR PRINTS1st place - DIAMOND SPARROW by Margaret Elaine Perry, Wichita, KN2nd place - KEEL-BILLED TOUCANby Karen King, Delray Beach, FL See front cover3rd place - TOCO TOUCANby John Mott, Green Bay, WI TRANSPARENCIES1st place - OWL FINCHESby Margaret Elaine Perry, Wichita, KN2nd place - BABY COCKATOOSby Frank Nothaft, Medford, NY See back cover3rd place - GREY CRESTED ZEBRA FINCH MALE by Margaret Elaine Perry, Wichita, KN </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2909</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 5 (1979): OCT- NOV 1979; 37-40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2909/2893</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
