<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/569</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sun Seed Is anOfficial Sponsor ofAmericanFederation of AvicultureThe Sun Seed Company, Inc., of Bowling Green, Ohio hasbeen named an official sponsor of the American Federation ofAviculture and will dedicate a portion of its company profits tothe AFA's work in the bird industry.In a joint announcement by Sun Seed President Les Gondaand AFA President Jack Clinton-Eitniear, the sponsorship ishailed as ''an important step toward promoting a new level ofeducation and awareness in this very significant field."• • This is another way of underscoring our position as a companyof bird owners for bird owners," Gonda says, ''and we'reproud to take this step forward."In addition to its continuing educational programs for boththe industry and the general public, Clinton-Eitniear says theAFA plans to expand the number of AFA breeding consortiumsand to encourage its affiliated clubs to choose a species andbegin a breeding consortium as well. Such programs will allowfuture aviculturists and pet owners access to variety of geneticallydiversified species.In a related step, Sun Seed has donated 250 pounds of birdseed to the AFA to assist in a program of releasing some 60Amazon parrots back into the Mexican wilds after they wereconfiscated on the Mexican side of the Texas-Mexico border assmugglers were attempting to bring them into this countryillegally.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/569</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 43-44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/569/552</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
