<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4052</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:18:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Aviculture Around the World</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Silva, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 2 (July 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.When Covid-19 first struck, I was in Europe visiting aviaries and gathering information for a book on Amazons that was to follow my recent Macaws in Field and Aviary. That trip had taken me across the continent. Months before I had been in Asia. For the next year, travel was complicated by the Covid-19 outbreak but as soon as the pandemic died down, I was back on the plane, traveling to South Africa and the Middle East. My avicultural perspective is thus global.My view of aviculture was solidified in a visit to India in 2015. The general perception was that aviculture in India was in its infancy and that a trip there would be worthless. I persisted and went. What I saw left me in awe. Indians were passionate about aviculture, were breeding species ranging from Red and Blue Lories (Eos histrio) to Palm Cockatoos (Probosciger aterrimus), had a good grasp of avicultural fundamentals and the average age of the Indian aviculturist was 25 years. Anil Garg showed me that there were collections in existence that equaled the best in the US or Europe. Indian aviculture had evolved on its own with little input from the US and Europe because when they sought assistance, they were ignored.Five years ago, the general opinion in the US and Europe was that bird keeping would disappear. Interest was declining, the fancy was not attracting younger people, and prices were so low that many breeders were unable to cover their operating costs with the young they produced. I never subscribed to this thinking. My view was that this telescopic perspective did not reflect the status of aviculture. I based this opinion on my discussions with people, but I had no concrete evidence.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4052</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 2 (2022): Watchbird July 2022; 4-5</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4052/4012</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
