<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/503</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breedig Red Fronted Macaws</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hollingshead, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hollingshead, Cindy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In March of 1984 my husband Johnand I bought our first pair of redfronted macaws. We set them up in a3' x 3' x 6' cage with an 18" x 18" x24" wooden nest box. This pair hadbeen in a holding cage for over a yearwith about 50 other sexed red fronts.It was noted by the keeper that theyhad pair bonded together on theirown, and he advised us to set themup as soon as possible. The red frontswere very compatible. We saw thebirds sitting closely together on theperch, eating together and preeningeach other.In 1984 we were feeding the birds adiet of boiled corn, beans and dogfood kibble, with some cut up fruitsand vegetables. Since then we havechanged our diet to 50% cookedracing pigeon mix, 25% Leach largehookbill mix and 25% fruits and vegetables.Our fruit and vegetable mixconsists of carrots, broccoli, celery,apples, pears, and two or three differentkinds of melons. At varying timesover the last few years we have addeda few changes such as sprouted beansand seeds.The birds were set up in an indoorcage and were placed on the end of arow to give them a little more privacy.These birds were a little shyer thansome of our other pairs and seemedto do better when left alone. Our birdbuildings are not heated but are insulatedand cooled during the summerwith a swamp cooler. The lights inthe buildings are on timers. Weincrease the amount of light startingin January, and towards the end of fallwe decrease the amount of light togive the birds a natural rest period.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/503</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 4 (1989): AUG-SEPT 1989; 6-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/503/487</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
