<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/631</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The White--winged Powder Blue Mutation of the Crimson (Pennant's) Rosella</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Part/Editor's Note: The authors wishto remain anonymous so sent thearticle through editor Dale Thompson.If there are any questionsregarding either Part I or Part II,they should be directed to DaleThompson at the AFA Home Officeaddress.Since 1970 when the blue mutationof the Pennant's Rosella firstappeared in West Germany, manychanges have developed. The firstbreedings of this mutation resulted ina color change where the normalcrimson red color on the chest, headand back was replaced with a silver,white coloration. As with any mutation,through selective breeding overseveral generations this mutationimproved in size and color. An April/May 1981 AFA Watchbird articleexplains the genetic probabilities ofthis blue mutation.In 1979, Josef Dexler, a WestGerman aviculturalist, acquired fourpairs of the blue mutation Pennants.Each pair consisted of one blue birdand one split-to-blue mate. In his firstbreeding season with these birds,Herr Dexler successfully reproducedoffspring from all four pairs. Thisprovided him with a good source ofbirds for future line breeding.Through a careful selection process,Herr Dexler's second generationbreeding resulted in producing somefemale offspring which contained ablue colored back that replaced thesilver, white coloration found inearlier generations.These blue-backed females weresubsequently bred to split-to-bluemates. This combination produced apowder blue color which occurred in12.5% of the time in either male orfemale birds.Although Herr Dexler normallyprefers to breed his mutations with asplit bird to ensure greater size, in1986 he opted to breed a powderblue male with a powder blue mate.The following year this pair producedan all powder blue bird whichhad white wing feathers. In addition,two other pairs of powder bluefemales mated to split-to-blue malesproduced several offspring that weresplit-to-blue Pennant's Rosellas (normalred coloration) but also hadwhite wing feathers. In 1988 threemore powder blue white-wingedPennant's Rosellas were bred fromtwo pairs ofJosefDexler's birds.With each generation, the powderblue coloration on the back andchest, and the white primary wingfeathers became more prominent. Inaddition, small white patchesappeared on the head and rumpareas. Only future breedings of thispowder blue, white-winged mutationwill determine the genetic probabilitiesand characteristics of thismutation.In addition to the blue Pennant'sRosella mutation there are the yellowand white mutations. The yellowmutation is a recessive mutation, thesame as the blue mutation.Part IIGenetics of the White-wingedBlue Pennant's RosellaThe powder blue and white wingcharacters in Pennant's Rosellas arevery interesting to say the least. Thered Pennant's split to powder bluewhich have green in their matureplumage probably are also split towhite-wing.An excellent mating would be thePennant's which are red-green splitto powder blue and white-wing withthe powder blue, white-wing Pennant's.This should produce goodstrong birds . The following areexpected results of such a cross.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/631</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 35-36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/631/614</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
