<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3887</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-17T03:14:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Helping to Save Birds in the Wild</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jordan, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">“When the last individual of a race of living beings breathes no more, another heaven and another earth must pass before such a one can be again.”– American Naturalist William Beebe, The Bird: Its Form and Function
We live in a time when species are going extinct faster than in any other time in recent history. Our generation,and that of our children, must identify the factors that are contributing to the decline and eventualdemise of species around us. The only way to influence these factors is to educate the next generationand arm them with the tools necessary to slow or stop the destruction that is taking place now. If we fail,the magnificent diversity that we ourselves experienced in our lifetime will be diminished.
The American Federation of Aviculture Inc. (AFA) has had an eye on avian conservation for over fifty years.Members have contributed to the AFA conservation fund enabling the organization to assist biologists toevaluate and assist species in need. The list of programs and species supported by the AFA in the past isimpressive.
Below is a partial list of projects supported by the AFA and its contributing members.
- Bees and Nesting Cavity Removal Research. Caroline Estathion- Investigation of Wild Parrot complete blood counts and causes of death in the Tambopata Region- Wildlife Conservation Society-Scarlet Macaw Chick Survivability Research-Guatemala- Prevention protocol to protect parrot nest boxes from colonization by Africanized honey bees-Lear’s Macaw Corn Subsidy project, Brazil-Mexican Amazon Nesting and Survey Project with Loro Parque and others-The Tambopata nest box project-The Red-fronted macaw conservation project (Asociacion Armonia, Bolivia);-Project Abbotti, conservation of the recently rediscovered Abbotti’s cockatoo (Indonesian parrot project/ project Birdwatch);-The Spix’s macaw project, captive propagation in Brazil;-Nesting ecology of the Slender-billed conure;-Proventricular dilatation disease research (Schubot Exotic Bird Health Center, Texas A&amp;amp;M University);-Puerto Rican parrot (PRP) research and reintroduction;-A joint project with the Loro Parque Foundation in Tenerife, Canary Islands, Spain on artificial nest boxesfor the Cuban conure.-Scarlet macaw conservation, release, and monitoring program, Chajul,Mexico
[For the full article and image, please continue to the PDF]</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3887</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 52 No. 2 (2025): AFA Watchbird Fall/Winter 2025; 30-32</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
