<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/807</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Red Siskin Project Items Available</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Patterson, Yvonne I.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">~e AF A's Red Siskin Project is rais- 1 'i~g monies for isoenzyme analysiskits (see May/ June 1994 Watchbirdanicle on page 12. In this same article,a VCR tape of Professor Smith andAntonio Rivero 's presentations atSiskin Summit '93 was offered. Theydiscussed faunal preserves the Venezuelangovernment is providing forprotection of the few Red Siskins leftin the wild. They also provided valuableinformation on food sou rces,habitat, nesting and trapping of thewild Red Siskins. This tape alsoincludes a nice production of the RSP ,detailing aspects of the project. This 2-hour video sells for $22.95 , which includes shipping costs.The March/ April 1994 Watchbirdissue, page 60, showed two pieces ofartwork which were donated to theproject. Signed and numbered printsare now being offered for sale.Jay Fullmer's "Red Siskins on aPringamosa Plant" sell for $25 for ablack and white signed and numberedprint, or $50 for a hand-painted print.This is a very clean piece of artworkwith nice detail. Prices include shippingand handling charges.Mark Wade's colorful "Siskin Family"portrait sells unmarred for 15.Matted prints sell for $20 and $25,depending upon the number of mats which have been cut. These pricesinclude shipping and h a ndlingcharges.T-shirts are $15 total, which includesshipping and h a ndling costs. Bo thT -shirts are 50/ 50 meaning they willhave minimal shrinkage. One T-shirtd esign fea tures the United Sta tes( " hatched he re") and Venezu e la("released here"), with a pair of RedSiskins (order RS/ hatch) . The newdesign T-shirt has three Red Siskins ona branch , a pair and a juvenile (orderRS/ wild). This design describes theendangerment status of Red Siskins inthe wild and our project goals.All items are in limited qua ntities.Please make checks in U.S. d ollarspayable to the AFA-RSP and ma il toRSP Promo tio ns, 10735 E. 40 Hig hway,Independe nce, MO 64055. Forthose who wo uld like to ma ke atax-deductible contributio n, pleasefo rward your check to the ab oveaddress.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/807</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 39-40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/807/789</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
