<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/669</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Basement Aviaries</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Karg, Randy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Being a parrot breeder-hobbyist inthe midlands, I am presented with acold hard fact of life - winter in Iowacan be frigid! Iowa's weather has alsosolved my problem of where to housemy African parrots. The majority ofhomes in the Midwest have a cellar toseek shelter in the event of a tornado.Many breeders have opted to turntheir basement into an aviary.As my collection of parrots grew, Irealized I was going to have to enlargemy parrot room. Figuring the cost ofan additional building (including heating,cooling, and a water supply) thethought of converting a recent additionto my basement became veryappealing. My father and I came upwith a working plan of action. Theroom to be converted measured 24 x14 feet. Our first step was to cover thefloor braces and electrical wiring. Chipboard was used instead of plywood asa cost savings measure. Trap doorsmade electrical junction boxes accessiblein case of rewiring needs or anemergency; also most building codesrequire an easy access to the junctionboxes. The room was painted white toreflect light.The next task was to design newcages to fit my needs as well as myfeathered friends. I started from thebottom working up, utilizing as muchspace as possible, while minimizingclean up chores. Cage floor dimensionsfor the smaller Poicephalus are the same as two double unfoldednewspapers overlapped, 21" high x21" wide x 36" long. Multiple layers ofnewspapers under each cage makescleanup as easy as pulling off the toplayer. A minimum amount of time isspent bothering nesting pairs. Threecages are stacked in a shelf designedto suspend each enclosure above thewaste and debris.The larger cages were designedaround the width of a large roll of craftpaper. The cages measure 3' wide x 3'high x 7' long, with the far endenlarged 4' to accommodate a nestbox to provide privacy for nestinghens - in other words, a large Lshape.Metal conduit was adapted andfastened to each cage to support thelarge rolls of craft paper. The paper isthen pulled along the bottom length ofthe cage and cut. It actually looks likea large paper towel dispenser. Thelarge cages are hung two high by wiresuspended from the floor joists above.Each cage is separated by sheet metalto prevent waste dropping to thelower cage. Food and water are easilyaccessible due to a flip-up design Icopied thanks to the Watchbird's visitto Joe and Marge Longo in Washington.A large door is provided in caseany bird needs to be caught for examsor other purposes.Heating the basement has been amajor advantage to undergroundbreeding. All heat ducts have beenclosed off to the bird room. Temperaturesoutside have dipped well belowzero with the aviary maintaining anaverage 60°F due to the heated roomsabove. A major ice storm a few yearsback caused power outages for threedays. The house temperature droppedto 20°F because outside it was 5°below zero! I stayed downstairs withthe birds as the basement temperatureleveled off at 50°F and maintained thistemperature during the power failure.Low humidity in the winter monthsdoes not appear to affect egg hatchability,therefore, I have chosen not touse a humidifier. High humidity, onthe other hand, did present some problems. The summer monthsunderground can be very muggy.I do use a dehumidifier during thistime. The humidity was causingdampness and mold buildup on thecage floors.One advantage of basement breedingis the control of the lighting scheduleto fit the keeper's need. I am workingthe graveyard shift so this meansaltering the lighting for the birds togive them the best care. When achange in the birds' light schedule isadjusted, I attempt to increase (ordecrease) in a fifteen minute changeper day. Night lights are very importantduring the birds' sleeping hoursfor obvious reasons. Lighting is controlledby an inexpensive computerhook up. The lights are an arrangementof rows of fluorescent lights.Night lights are low wattage incandescentlight bulbs.Disadvantages to basement birdkeeping include poor air quality andthe dust accumulation from the Africanparrots. Since my operation is asmall business, I do not have the luxuryof an elaborate air exchange system.I presently use an exhaust fan circulatingcontinuously. I also use anordinary room fan with a furnace filterover the intake. This traps a surprisingamount of bird dust and smallfeathers. I have yet to find an air purifierthat can handle bird dust. As ofthis writing, I have gone through threesystems, the last one costing $300.00- the motor burnt up a couple ofweeks ago. I am also concerned aboutthe outbreak of an airborne disease inthe basement bird room. A highlycontagious incident would be verydetrimental to the flock. An AA V veterinarianis a must to maintain contactconcerning the prevention of such anoutbreak and to keep your flock in thebest condition.Lack of sunshine seems to effect theAfrican parrot's eye color. This hasbeen an on-going discussion in TheAfrican Parrot Society and a firmanswer has yet to be resolved. Poicephalusbred in outdoor aviariesappear to develop the colored eyering in a shorter amount of time.We have a lot to learn about thewants and needs of our featheredresponsibilities. It is our duty to providethe best environment that we aviculturistscan in the different climatesand surroundings in which we forceour birds to live.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/669</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/669/652</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
