<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2495</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-13T19:58:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Captive Propagation and Management of the Guinea Turaco</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heston, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">TaxonomySo distinctive are turacos in general form and plumage pigmentation, it is not surprising that they were at one time collectively considered to be the sole representatives of the now nonexistent order, Musophagiformes. Since, attempts to "lump" them with other well established taxonomic groups have been interesting. Turacos have been associated with the Galliformes (pheasants, quail, etc.) on the basis they were found to be a potential host tO some of the same ectoparasites. Not being qualified in the field of coevolutionary aspects of host-parasite relationships, I would not attempt to contest the basis of that criteria; however, from a more contemporary taxonomic, or systematic viewpoint, to classify this group of birds on that basis alone seems a hasty decision, and inherently wide open to debate - and in time debated it was. Today, primarily due to anatomic resemblances to the non-parasitic cuckoos, and positive affinities in egg proteins, turacos now comprise the family Musophagidae, within the order Cuculiformes (cuckoos, anis, roadrunners, etc.).RangeThere are about 20 known species of turacos and many subspecies, all of which are indigenous to various regions of Africa south of the Sahara Desert. Some species have a widely distributed range; some are found at astonishingly high elevations, even in non-equitorial regions; and as may be expected with isolated varienrs such as subspecies and races, some species have a cornparatively small and restricted range.Morphology and Natural HistoryWhen it comes to obsession and bias with respect to favorite bird groups, aviculturists can be the epitome. Yet, if it is possible to set aside personal preferences and evaluate the fantastic variety of birds found throughout the world, we would find that each species is a uniquely adapted creature reflecting the selective pressures of every conceivable habitat and niche. Likewise, to suggest that turacos are the most interesting animal that ever bore feathers, would lack perspective. Even so, there are some traits, both subtle and otherwise, that are unique only to this family of birds. For a start, turacos are · 'semizygodacrylous" - a term that refers to a condition in which the outer toe (#4) is reversible. This means that with a quick adjustment of this outer toe, their feet can assume a zygodactylous position like parrots, woodpeckers, toucans, etc. (two toes forward and two back); or, as with most other species, three toes forward and one back. When observing these birds, even in captivity, it becomes obvious why this trait is so important with respect to maneuverability. This instantaneous option of toe position proves invaluable for the efficient negotiation of the natural randomness of their forest habitat. They are extremely well adapted for running along the length of branches, instantly reversing stationary direction, hopping, and making brief flights through a barrage of dense foliage. lt is this characteristic, along with their relatively long tail (a general characteristic of the cuckoo family), that enables these birds to be true masters of the forest canopy.During short flights, the conspicuously bright red "flash patterns" located on the primary flight feathers are a striking feature. Along with distinctive call notes, it is believed that at least one of the useful purposes of this characteristic may be to help individuals in loosely scattered groups maintain orientation to one another in thick vegetation. Such flash patterns (usually white or bright yellow in other species of birds) may also serve to confuse potential predators that may approach coo close for comfort, inducing them co take sudden flight. On many occasions I have seen nesting turacos swell up and display this red wing patch to unwanted intruders. I rather doubt its true effectiveness against an able and determined predator in the wild, as this tactic can be regarded as no more than a ridiculous but courageous bluff from a creature whose only real effective strategy for survival is to take flight from the situation.The pigments found in the turaco's plumage are remarkable and found nowhere else in the animal kingdom. As a general chemical group, the pigments are fat soluble lipochromes known as porphyrins. Turacin, a copper base pigment, is responsible for the red flash pattern on the wings, and it is an oxidized form of this chemical, turacoverdin, that produces the soft green of the contour, or body plumage. Green plumage in other species of birds is produced primarily by an inreracting combination of melanins, xanthins, and structural aspects of the feathers that are perceived as blue.Members of the genus Tauraco are so similar in form and behavior, variation in the crest and facial markings appear to be the only obvious distinctive features between species. Like others of its genus, the Guinea turaco is about 17 or 18 inches in length, it has a breast and mantle of green; and the secondary flight feathers, wing coverts, and tail feathers are all a glossy, deep bluepurple. With this sort of coloration, these birds become virtually invisible in dense green foliage. Currently I am maintaining a pair in a small but densely planted flight, and even though the exhibit is only 4 feet deep, it is still difficult to point them out among the dense bamboo, ferns, and nandenas. In my opinion, a functional display that reflects basic aspects of an animal's natural history is most interesting and aesthetically pleasing. At least more so than exhibits based mainly on only color and expense. This species sports a green crest, and if the light is right, a light brush of red is visible on the tip. On the cheek there is a trapezoidal patch of white in front of the eye, a small patch of black below this that extends back under the eye a bit, then another patch of white extends further towards the back of the head. Also, as with many other species, there is a red. wattle-like ring around the eye. It is only the subtle difference in dimension of these black and white markings that render this bird distinguishable from two other subspecies: T'p. bu/Joni and Tp. zenderi. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2495</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 6 (1986): DEC 1986- JAN 1987; 46-51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2495/2467</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
