<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2035</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-26T05:21:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Spring AFA Board Meeting</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Last May on Saturday the sixteenth the A.F.A. quarterly meeting of the Board of Directors was held at the Sheraton National Hotel in Arlington, Virginia. The minutes of that meeting have already been sent out. These couple of paragraphs are just to bring to your attention the really good job so many of our members do in their A.F.A. duties.The meeting was sponsored by the Na- tional Capitol Bird Club and Tom Marshall was the chief organizer. The meeting covered the normal A.F.A. business (which can be found in the minutes) and there were three excellent guest speakers. Dave Orlean from the Wildlife Section, U.S. Department of Justice explained how his agency was responsible for enforcing the federal laws regulating birds and other animals. Most of the convicted crooks listed in the last Watchbird were nailed by the Justice Department.Dave Goodman from the U.S.D.A./ APHIS service gave an update on Newcastle and answered questions regarding bird imports and quarantine. Dr. Mallinson, now with the University of Maryland Agriculture Extension Service, explained a program whereby private aviculturists can work with state governments on a volunteer basis to monitor and control pet bird health problems. His idea has merit. If we keep our act clean, the government won't have to clean it up for us.When the meeting adjourned many members and delegates went on to dinner on the town while some of the outof-towners were taken on a tour of the nation's capitol city. Much credit should be given to Tom Marshall, Cliff Witt and the National Capitol Bird Club for hosting such an excellent meeting. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2035</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 4 (1981): AUG-SEPT 1981; 42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2035/2006</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
