<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2031</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-26T05:21:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Air Freight Costs Relief in Sight?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brown, Ron</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">History:Of late, the aviculturist has been feeling the pinch of air freight rates when shipping birds or other animals. One horror story after another has crossed my desk regarding the unusually high prices that air carriers are demanding these days. Some of you, no doubt, will remember when air freight charges ranged from $15. 00 to $2 5. 00 coast to coast. They have now risen to as much as $60. 00 to $100. 00 or more. One fact that many aviculturists seem to be unaware of is that in October of 1978 the United States government deregulated the airlines, permitting them to increase their rates to the maximum charge the consumer would tolerate.Current Developments:On 20 May 1981 in Stouffer's Inn in Denver, Colorado the I.W.W.A. (International Wild Waterfowl Association) chaired a meeting that hosted cargo or marketing representatives from eight major airlines. This monumental meeting was principally orchestrated by Joe de Sarro (I.W.W.A.) and Barron Collier, II (l.W.W.A.). Many wildlife hobbyists and pet organizations were represented as well as some private businessmen. The goal of this meeting was to present to these airlines the dilemma confronting us and to seek prompt solutions.All problems regarding air freight should be brought instantly to the attention of the airline in question by addressing a letter of complaint to its manager of cargo sales. Please forward a copy of the letter to me for the A.F.A. files.There is no prompt, simple solution to this problem but the airlines are at least aware now that there is a problem. Whereas they have traditionally been unavailable to us, they are now open to correspondence and suggestions. The airline representatives in attendance agreed that air freight rates must decrease in the future.A follow up meeting will be held in September of this year in Minneapolis. It is encouraging to have representatives of many different bird and pet organizations working together in such perfect harmony. Hopefully, this accord will set the stage for further interaction amongst all such groups.On another tack, but in the same vein, the American Pigeon Fancier's Council is pursuing the possibility of shipping birds via the U.S. postal system. One way or the other the problem of outrageous shipping costs will be solved.Airlines represented at the meeting on 20 May 1981:1) Terry Stoepel , Manager-Cargo Sales BRANIFF INTERNATIONALWorld HeadquartersDallas-Ft. Worth Airport Dallas, TX 752612) John Zembeck, Director System Cargo, Sales &amp;amp; Service FRONTIER AIRLINES8250 Smith Road Denver, CO 802073) Frank Supple, Manager Cargo Sales Support EASTERN AIRLINESMiami International Airport Miami, FL 331484) David N. Barnes, Manager Cargo SalesTRANSWORLD AIRLINES (TWA)P.O. Box 20447 Kansas City, MO 641955) Vic Gedminas, Manager Freight Services WESTERN AIRLINES8100 Smith Road Denver, CO 802076) Bill WilliamsCONTINENT AL AIRLINESLos Angeles, CA International Airport1-(213)-646-62457) Edward M. GerrityDistrict Marketing Manager DELTA AIRLINES7555 E. Hampden Avenue, Suite 605 Denver, CO 80231 8) Bill R. FrazierDistrict Sales Manager REPUBLIC AIRLINES3333 Quebec Street. Suite 4090 Denver, CO 80207Organizations and private concerns present at the meeting on 20 May 1981:I) American Federation of Aviculcure Ron Brown2) American Game Bird Breeder's Federation Angus Hebb, Arlan &amp;amp; Loretta Vaughn3) American Pheasant &amp;amp; Waterfowl Society Vance Grannis, Lloyd &amp;amp; Bev Ure, Bruce D. Bergbom4) American Rabbit Breeder's Assoc.Dwight &amp;amp; Jan Fitzgerald 5) Bang-A-Way Gun Club &amp;amp; Kennels Ray E. Olson6) Colorado Homing Pigeon ClubLynn &amp;amp; Tim Buehler7) Denver Zoo-Ed Schrnirt8) Halbach Poultry Farm-Harold Halbach9) Illinois Game &amp;amp; Pet Breeders-Craig Hendee10) International Wild Waterfowl Assn.Warren Hancock11) Macfarlane Pheasant Farm-Jim Adamson12) Minnesota Pheasant and Waterfowl SocietyVance Grannis13) Sea World-Scon Drieschman14) Stromberg Pets Unlimited- Loyd Stromberg15) Wisconsin Bird and Game Breeders Mary Popple </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2031</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 4 (1981): AUG-SEPT 1981; 32-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2031/2002</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
