<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4106</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:20:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Losses - Carolina Parakeet and the Passenger Pigeon: Vanished Birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schroeder, Dick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (January 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Boom! One shot was all it took from 14 year old Press Southworth’s 12 gauge shotgun. Boom and the last passenger pigeon, Ectopistes migratorius, to ever be seen in the wild, was dead. It happened on a farm in Pike County Ohio on March 24th, 1900. Of course at the time no one realized that young master Southworth’s bird was the last, but there was never another seen in the wild.found in the same tree. The nesting colonies could cover over 800 square miles. They generally laid 1 egg on a nest of loose twigs. The chick was tended by both parents, and would leave the nest before it was able to fly. After a few days they would be able to fend for themselves as well as take flight.The last nesting colony was reported in the Great Lakes region in the early 1890’s. The last bird seen in Wisconsin was shot in 1899, just a year before Southworth’s bird in Ohio.That last wild passenger pigeon still survives today in the Ohio Historical Society. It has been named Buttons because the woman who prepared the specimen used black shoe buttons for the eyes.Their decline was first noted in the 1850’s; they were gone 50 years later. It seems almost impossible that such a thing could occur, but we know that it did. They were considered an agricultural pest, descending on cornfields and feeding on the kernels. The fact that they were tasty didn’t help matters. The young squabs were easy prey for hunters who forced them from their nest by setting fire to the trees. Adults were killed in huge numbers. A market hunter near Petoskey, Michigan, earned $60,000 in 1878 by killing over three million birds from a colony, packing them in barrels and shipping them to markets in the East.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4106</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 1 (2023): Watchbird January 2023; 20-22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4106/4066</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
