<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1653</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:51:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">WING TIPS Aloe for Bird keepers... Avian Pharmacy in a Leaf</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Swicegood, Carolyn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A llopathic medicine is barely a century old, but the practice of using plant remedies such as Aloe iera can be traced back to ancient civilizations. Aloe oera, a succulent member of the lily and onion family, was used to treat a variety of health problems. There is a valuable lesson in this ancient wisdom for aviculturists who prefer using natural preventive remedies and treatments for their birds whenever feasible. Aloe uera, also known as the "burn plant," possesses powerful healing properties that are beneficial to both birds and their caregivers.There are hundreds of species of Aloe but Aloe Barbadensis (still commonly known as Aloe vera - which term we will use here) is the species most frequently used for healing. It contains a wound hormone that accelerates healing of injured surfaces such as skin, nails, and feathers. Aloe vera has proven to be beneficial as a topical treatment for minor wounds and burns. When taken internally, it improves immune function, detoxifies, and promotes general healing. Scientists have found that Aloe vera gel is useful as an astringent, an anti-inflammatory agent, a natural antibiotic, a coagulating agent, and a pain inhibitor. No other plant can claim as many healing properties as Aloe oera, which truly is a "pharmacy in a leaf."Aloe vera can be useful to bird- keepers in the following ways:"It promotes the healing of wounds and prevents infection."It is a safe and natural analgesic."Aloe spray discourages feather destruction."It stimulates the immune system making it an effective preventive remedy."It can be used as a coagulating agent for the treatment of broken nails and blood feathers."Aloe detoxifying formula can save lives when conventional treatments fail.Aloe for Healing WoundsThe prevention of infections that sometimes result from skin wounds is important to a bird's health. Aviculturists should consider the natural medicinal benefits that Aloe vera provides as a remedy for such abrasions. Aloe penetrates all the skin layers, which helps to account for its healing properties when treating burns, cuts, scrapes, abrasions, and other skin problems. It draws infection out of wounds as it helps to regenerate healthy tissue. Aloe contains fatty acids that have anti-inflammatory properties, as well as the wound healing hormones, Auxins and Gibberellins. Aloe vera also has antibacterial, antiviral, and antifungal properties that are effective defenses against a broad range of microbes. The Aloe vera plant produces at least six antiseptic agents: lupeol, salicylic acid, urea nitrogen, cinnamonic acid, phenols, and sulphur. All of these are recognized as antiseptics because they kill or control molds and other fungi, as well as bacteria and viruses.Extensive research since the 1930s has shown that Aloe vera gel has the ability not only to heal wounds, but also to treat ulcers and burns by putting a protective coating on the affected areas and speeding up the rate of healing.Aloe as an AnalgesicIt seems to be a well-kept secret that Aloe vera is an effective pain killer. The lupeol, salicylic acid and magnesium in Aloe have strong analgesic properties with no known side effects, making it helpful to both birds and their caregivers. Aloe spray is an excellent analgesic for birds because it does not require hands-on application. Tame birds might allow the owner to apply Aloe gel or other medications directly to their wounds, but hirds that are not so tame or hirds that are upset can he treated more easily with Aloe spray. Consequently, Aloe is one of the most valuable items in the Avian first aid kit. George's Aloe Spray by Warren Laboratories is available in many health food stores in a reusable eightounce spray pump bottle for ahout $5.00. You can easily make your own spray by purchasing additive-free, steam-distilled Aloe juice (not gel) and an inexpensive spray bottle. Steam-distilled Aloe does not require dilution or refrigeration and will stay fresh for months.All birds bite and all birdkeepers eventually are bitten. The only effective painkiller for a crushing hite is Aloe vera gel. To treat a bird bite on a finger, fill a rubber finger cot with Aloe gel and wear it on the finger for as long as the pain-killing benefits are needed. Five minutes usually is sufficient to stop the pain, but it can be used for as long as needed. Aloe also helps to coagulate blood in injured tissue and minimize swelling and bruising. If you have older Aloe vera plants with large leaves, you also can cut open a leaf and wrap it around an injured finger. To treat bite wounds on other parts of the body, spread a generous amount of Aloe vera gel on the wound as often as needed to control pain. Aloe preparations are sold in pharmacies, supermarkets, and department stores. Read labels and look for the highest Aloe content with the fewest additives. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1653</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 3 (2001): Third Quarter 2001; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1653/1630</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
