<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/501</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A.F.A. visits . . . Mickey Ollson,s Wildlife World Zoo</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Some of us are satisfied with ourpet bird, deriving infinite joy from itsantics and affection for us. Othersfind the pleasures of pet bird ownershiplead to an interest in raisingbirds. These people we call aviculturists.Some aviculturists acquire moderatecollections of birds, whileothers establish very large collectionscomprised of many different species.These latter aviculturists usually arelooked upon as professional birdbreeders. Then there is MickeyOllson!Mickey started raising birds as asmall child, when he acquired somefinches, waterfowl, and budgiesunder the encouragement of his parents.He liked other animals as well,especially "zoo types;' and keptsquirrels and a couple of alligators. AsMickey grew up, his interest in animalsbecame more intense, and themenagerie larger.In 1963 Mickey graduated fromArizona State University with a B.S.degree in advertising. He worked acouple years, then began teachingjunior high school in 1965. Thatsame year he acquired five acres inGlendale, a northwest suburb ofPhoenix, and founded Ollson's RareBird Farm. By the early 1970s,Mickey had earned an internationalreputation as an aviculturist with acollection of over 135 species of birdsof which he bred over a hundred.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/501</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 59-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/501/485</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
