<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1568</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:54:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Bearded Barbet (Lybius dubius)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Callaghan, Eric</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Foreword: A few details regarding the climate in Ireland.The Irish climate is officially described as "maritime," moderated by prevailing southwesterly winds. As a result, there are no great climatic extremes, with mild winter temperatures and cool summers. Rainfall is abundant. The east coast, where I live, is the driest area, having an annual rainfall of about 30 inches (250 centimeters), spread throughout the year, although late spring and autumn (fall) tend to be relatively dry. Average monthly temperatures vary from a low of 8C ( 46F) in January to 20C (68F) in July. Over the last few years we have experienced little or no snow and only a few nights of frost (average minimum temperature in January being IC (34F). Unfortunately, we do not receive extended periods of sunshine, an average of two hours per day in January, rising to seven hours in May and June. Daylength varies from about 6-7 hours in Nov/Dec to over 18 hours in June.All this has implications for birdkeeping.While there is no need for elaborate, heated shelters for most species, some require extended lighting, especially the smaller species. The period of winter darkness is just too long without access to food, especially as it will be cold at the same time. Nonetheless, it does mean that many species can have access to outside flights throughout the year, with only the minimum of shelter facilities.The Bearded BarbetIn July 1997 I found four Bearded Barbets (Lybius dubius) offered for sale in a dealer's premises. This is a large barbet, basically black and red in colour, with the mid-to-lower back white. The flanks are creamy white. It has a large, grooved, yellow bill with two "teeth" on each side. The bare skin around the eyes is also yellow. The species is native to West and Central Africa, where it is to be found in tall trees at the edges of open woodlands, wooded grasslands and cultivation, and in small isolated forest patches or clumps of second growth on old plantations (Fry et al. 1988).The birds were in good condition, just a little rough in feather, although one had a badly dropped wing and was unable to fly. One bird appeared to be slightly larger than the others, with a slightly heavier bill, and while all would respond to being watched by flicking their tails from side to side, this was the only one to accompany it with a "caw" vocalization. At the time I was unaware that these birds could be sexed visually, but suspected this bird to be a male. I bought all four birds and later discovered that females can be recognized by the presence of a few black spots on the flanks (Fry et al. 1988). These spots can be seen without handling the bird and confirmed that I had indeed one cock and three hens. I decided to keep the birds together for as long as possible, as the species is supposed to be a co-operative breeder in the wild, albeit in natural family groups.AccommodationAfter an initial few days in a cage, I moved the birds to an outdoor aviary not shared with any other species. This is one of a series of flights, with flights on either side. The rear is enclosed as is the rear half of the roof, and there is a solid partition on one side. The aviary on that side houses a trio of immature Cape Parrots (Poicephalus robustus suahelicus), while there is a number of small passerines in the aviary on the other side. The aviary measures 8 feet deep x 5 feet wide x 6 feet high (approx. 2.4m x 1.5m x 1.8m). There was some dry heather hanging at the back of the aviary, a flowering currant bush planted at one side and a large abutilon near the front, trimmed to just below the roof. The aviary was furnished with a section of rotten silver birch and a wooden nest box 2ft 6in high and 6in square (approx. 76cm x 15cm square). There was a feeding tray near the front and a water dish was placed on a pine log approximately 3 feet (91.Scm) high. All birds roosted together in the box from the first night. The intention was to take the birds indoors as the weather deteriorated but this has never been necessary and they have now successfully passed three winters in the aviary. After a couple of weeks in the aviary, the birds' plumage had greatly improved and the bird with the dropped wing had recovered to a degree that enabled it to fly again. The wing is now only very slightly displaced. Unfortunately the birds are not ringed, making it difficult to distinguish individuals. This has restricted the amount of behavioral information that could be obtained, especially as they have remained quite shy and will not do anything other than sit on a perch if they are aware of being observed.FeedingThe basic diet is a mixture of chopped fruits: banana, apple, pear, tomato, grapes, kiwi fruit, melon, peach, plum and occasionally tinned fruits. All fruits were chopped to a size suitable for swallowing whole, while half a pomegranate or half an orange would be eaten out by the birds. Berries, such as blackberries, raspberries and elderberries were always refused. Initially the fruit was mixed with a commercial softfood to increase the protein content, but the birds were reluctant to take it. Later it was coated with a dry baby cereal, which was readily taken. Once a week, a vitamin/mineral mix is added to the fruit. A dish of home-made softfood is always available and this is sometimes eaten, but usually not until the fruit is finished. Initially, the birds readily ate mealworms, but later lost interest, until breeding commenced. Crickets were always refused. On this diet the birds have retained their red colour, without the need of supplements. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1568</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 5 (2000): Sept-Oct 2000; 14-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1568/1545</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
