<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3534</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-10T22:17:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">President’s Message</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hawley Jr., Jim C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Have you ever thought, maybe even out loud, "How can I find out more about this or that?" In the last few years everyone I talk to says, "Go online ~ the lnternetl That's where all the answers are." Well, maybe I am still just a little old school, but have you noticed how many experts there are on the internet with very impressive websites?Everybody seems to have become super smart overnight. Oh the power of the spin (website) and the absolute power of the printed wordl At this point I would like to suggest that you consider your choices and your sources of knowledge. We used to esteem and measure knowledge by experience, longevity and success. There are many great and credible websites out there, but can you tell the difference between the credible ones and the websites that just look great and have partial or misleading information?Don't despair ~ hope is here. The American Federation of Aviculture has and will continue to follow our mission statement, "The mission and purpose of AFA is promote the advancement of aviculture through educational programs that enable better husbandry, management, and living conditions for exotic birds; promote avian research and censervation of exotic birds; keep our members aware of legislative issues that affect aviculture and aviculturists and keep leqislators aware of the need for fair and equitable regulations. The goal of AFA is to insure lone-term, self-sustaininq populations of exotic birds both in captivity and in the wild:'Our 34th Annual Convention "Celebration of Birds" will be held in St Louis, Missouri. We will have credible and proven speakers, specialists from the many areas of aviculture and much, much more. Not only do we offer our annual convention, and have for 34 years, we now have certification available under our Fundamentals of Aviculture course Level I and soon to offer Level II (in the works as I write this). For furthering your education in aviculture, I highly recommend taking the AFA Fundamentals of Aviculture course. You are really missing out if you haven't yet and if you have, recommend it to a friendl Plus for our Girl Scouts of America friends, we have the Aviculture Badge Program (don't forget the grassroots).This summer when you attend this year's convention in St. Louiis... </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3534</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 34 No. 4 (2007): Number 4  2007; 5</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3534/3518</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
