<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2856</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-07T21:34:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA 5th Annual Convention</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This year's convention is sponsored by Gold Coast Exotic Bird Club.The dates will be August 22nd thru the 26th, at the Diplomat Hotel, in Hollywood, Florida. What more could you ask for Florida, a beautiful hotel, waterfront views (see accompaning photos) and lots of bird talk and education.We have an ambitious group of workers this year, led by Dr. Ronald Harris. Tom Ireland, chairman of the program, has enlarged the very popular workshops to include many diverse subjects. These workshops will be repeated three or four times daily so you can participate easily. They will be made up of small groups of 10-15 people, subjects to include:Photography of Birds Dan MartinLove Birds Cliff WittFirst Aid for Birds .. Dr. Gregg HarrisonCockatiels Nancy ReedGenetics Manuel IglesiaHand Feeding Ruby StormBreedingAustralian Finches . . . Peggy CochranThe Isolet Concept U.S.D.A.Care and Nutritionof Pet Birds Dr. Ted La FeberDisease Control Dr. David GrahamBreeding theBrush Turkey Charles CookSpotting Disease dunngQuarantine . . . . . . . Bernard LevineMutations H. GregoryRemember our Convention is an event where you learn and enjoy. Major Lectures will be on many subjects and at least two will run at the same time so if a subject is not of interest you have an alternative. Also, other events such as the workshops will be available. With this concept we hope to have something of interest for you every hour of every day during the convention, no matter what your specialty may be in aviculture.The following is only a part of the impressive list of major speakers, much more will be added as confirmations are made:Pitfalls of A viculture Bob BerryCaptive Breedingof Amazons . . . . . . . . . Ramon Noegel Avian Parasitology .. Dr. Robert Altman Lories and Lorikeets ... Dr. Ray Jerome Larger Australian Psittacines . Gene HallAvian Nutrition Dr. Gregg HarrisonLove Birds Today Lee HortonAviary Construction and Land-scaping .. Russ Snyder &amp;amp; Jim Thomas First Breeding of the Emerald Toucanette and Aerial Toucan .... Jerry Jennings Color Varieties in theBudgerigar Charles SchafferPheasants . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . Mary Dom Avian BacterialDisease Dr. Susan LancasterExposure to this event is bound to be rewarding and certainly you will return home better informed as an aviculturist.I have just been informed that the A.F.A. Florida Clubs are also organizing three or four different tours, some bird orientated some not. This way members of your family or your guests can also visit other sites around Florida.Dr. Gregg Harrison, Chairman of the Veterinary Seminars, is also scheduling an important list of speakers. This event will take place all day Sunday. The Veterinary Seminar includes to date:Radiology Clinical Lab ... Chuck Galvin Drugs, Antibiotics, Anesthesiologyand surgery Michel BushRespiratory Disease and RadiologyClinical Lab Robert AltmanCommon Problems withBirds And Nutrition .. Gregg Harrison Pathology andUse in Diagnosis B. GrahamFrom the information given to me to date, with more to be added, this year's convention is certainly going to be the event- to Top Them AU!!!I thank all those working so hard to make this event the best A.F.A. Convention ever!  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2856</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 2 (1979): APR-MAY 1979; 34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2856/2840</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
