<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4182</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-12T15:11:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Visit to Loro Parque 2018</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sargent, Mark</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 46 Number 1 (2019).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.TX CONGRESO INTERNACIONAL “®* sobre PAPAGAYOS 24 - 27 SEPTIEMBRE 2018Every four years I look forward with much anticipation, to the International Parrot Conference, held every four years, in Tenerife, Spain. Why? Because it is like no other parrot conference you will ever experience! What’s not to love - the opportunity to see so many diverse parrot species (some so rare that I had only seen them in photos previously); to meet and hear top-rated speakers with current information from all over the world; a first-class convention program and events from start to finish; and, all held on the scenic tropical island of Tenerife in the Canary Islands. This was my 9th Conference at Loro Parque – I haven’t missed one since 1986. The XI International Conference on Parrots was held September 24 through 27, 2018 and boasted representatives from 47 countries.Every four years I look forward with much anticipation, tothe International Parrot Conference, held every four years, in Tenerife, Spain. Why? Because it is like no other parrot conference you will ever experience! What’s not to love - the opportunity to see so many diverse parrot species (some sorare that I had only seen them in photos previously); to meet and hear top-rated speakers with current information Alemania India ME 53 . Germany hnvadi: from all over the world; a first-class convention program abia Saudi eae: . Sai &amp;quot; ie Ms and events from start to finish; and, all held on the scenic ;&amp;#x27; Israel amtropical island of Tenerife in the Canary Islands. This was Pustralia he ee&amp;gt; : Australia ia Ms my 9th Conference at Loro Parque - I haven&amp;#x27;t missed one Austria Japon oClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4182</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 46 No. 1 (2019): Watchbird 2019; 38-44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4182/4142</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
