<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/304</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:17:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The U.S. portion of the "Puerto Rican Parrot Project" at the ElYunque Rain Forest Station in Puerto Rico has recently beenplaced under the directorship of Miss Kelly Brock. Kelly is doingsome very good things with the project. After Dr. Jose Vivalde(Director of the project for the Puerto Rican Dept. of NaturalResources) and I had discussed the situation with Kelly in depth,she has been able to convince the U.S. government wildlife officialsto allow her to move the parrots from completely enclosedhousing quarters into outside cages which are half covered and halfexposed to the open air, rain and sunshine. There are also goodindications that, when a location is found, the birds will be movedto a lower and drier location in the park. I personally believe thatthe constant high humidity and cool temperatures of the presentlocation are primarily responsible for the decreased number ofeggs hatched in recent years. The physiology of the growingembryo within the egg is interesting. The embryo must expel largeamounts of metabolic water, as vapor, through the eggshell duringits growth. If the outside humidity is too high, there is not a sufficientdifferential water vapor concentration gradient between theinside and outside of the shell for this exchange to take place andthe embryo dies.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/304</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 14 No. 4 (1987): AUG-SEPT 1987; 29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/304/293</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
