<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/736</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">FISH &amp; WILDLIFE Facts: Traveling Abroad With Your Pet Bird</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Wild Bird Conservation Act of1992, which became effective onOctober 23, 1992, is a significant newstep in international conservationefforts to protect exotic wild birds subjectto trade. The Act focuses on birdspecies listed in the Appendices to theConvention on International Trade inEndangered Species (CITES). Sincemost exotic pet birds, including allparrots, cockatoos, and macaws, arespecies listed under CITES, most areaffected by the Act.The Service recently issued regulationsimplementing the Act that providefor permits to allow foreign travelwith your pet bird (domestic traveland sales are not affected). If you planto take your pet bird with you on foreigntravel, or your residence hasbeen outside the United States for ayear and you plan to travel to theUnited States with a pet bird, you willneed to have a permit before youtravel.These new regulations are in additionto any other existing requirementsof CITES, the EndangeredSpecies Act, and other applicable statutes.If you are unsure whether theseregulations apply to you, contact theU.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Officeof Management Authority, at theaddress provided.Leaving the United StatesWith Your Pet BirdTo ensure that you will be allowedto bring your pet bird back into theUnited States from travel abroad, youwill need to take the following stepsbefore you leave:1. Obtain a valid permit from theOffice of Management Authority.Applications for permits must bereceived in that office at least 60 daysin advance of anticipated travel.2. Have your permit validated by aFish and Wildlife Service inspectorbefore you leave the United States.(Instructions will be provided on thepermit.) 3. Take a copy of your validated permitwith you. This copy must be presentedwhen you re-enter the UnitedStates with your pet.4. Find out whether the country(ies)you plan to visit have additionalimport and export requirements andrestrictions. At a minimum, for CITESlisted birds, a re-export certificatefrom the country(ies) visited will berequired. The address of the CITESpermit issuing authority in the country(ies) you will be visiting is availablefrom the Office of ManagementAuthority.There are no restrictions on thelength of time you may travel abroador on the number of birds you maytake with you.Traveling to the United StatesWith Your Pet BirdIndividuals who have resided out- side the United States continuously forat least one year may import a maximumof two pet birds per person, peryear, if all applicable requirementshave been met prior to their arrival inthe United States. Following are thesteps you need to take before youleave for the United States: 1. Obtain a valid permit from theOffice of Management Authority.Applications for permits must bereceived in that office at least 60 daysin advance of anticipated travel.2. Obtain documented evidence thatyou have resided outside the UnitedStates continuously for a minimum ofone year.3. Obtain documented evidence thateach bird was acquired legally.4. Obtain all necessary permits fromthe country(ies) of expott.Note: The Act restricts the numberof pet birds individuals may importinto the United States annually tofewer than are otherwise allowableunder CITES. However, under certainconditions, this restriction does notapply to certain captive-bred birds.For information on whether therestriction applies to your pet bird(s),contact the Office of ManagementAuthority.Applications andAdditional InformationPermit applications (Form 3-200)and any other information you mayneed are available from the Office ofManagement Authority, 4401 N. FairfaxDrive, Room 420, Arlington, VA22203, phone 1-800-358-2104 or (703)358-2093, and Fax (703) 358-2281.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/736</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 45-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/736/719</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
