<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3759</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-08-06T18:55:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Insects.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McMichael. PhD, John C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There are numerous reports about wild parrots eating insects, but very few indicate the insect species. Some of those that do are listed in Table 1. Most reports just state that they take insects and that is that. I suspect that most parrots, just like my caiques (Pionites spp.), are very fond of insects as food and insects likely comprise one of the most important sources of protein for wild parrots. Our domestic chickens and turkeys have a requirement for essential amino acids and parrots likely do too. These amino acids are usually more readily available from the proteins synthesized by animals than from those synthesized by plants. While wild parrots do not eat large animals, except perhaps some occasional carrion, they sometimes eat snails, spiders and small crustaceans. But insects are likely the main source of animal protein. Some parrots, such as the wild Meyer's parrots (Poicephalus meyeri), that are well known to need insects in their diet and switch to a predominately insect larva diet during the breeding season when they are rearing chicks (10, 57). This may be the case for breeding cockatiels, budgerigars and Quaker parakeets in the wild too (3, 29). However, I suspect the only time most pet parrot owners provide a live insect is when they inadvertently feed the flour moth larvae present in infested...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3759</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 43 No. 1 &amp; 2 (2016): Special Double Issue; 50-60</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3759/3734</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
