<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3055</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-17T17:41:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Canary Calendar</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nierenberg, Charlotte</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">SCHEDULE FROM HATCHING TO MOULTINGCOLOR FOODREST &amp;amp; RECUPERATION"Tapering off' operations should come as a welcome relief to both breeder and birds at this time of the year.Breeders are tired of preparing egg food, performing necessary extra chores and staying so close to home during the season. More important, the birds are ready for a well-earned rest!For those who breed on a pair-to-pair basis, that is, whenboth the cock and hen raise their babies, the parents should be separated when the last clutch of babies is about 10-12 days old. This will preclude further coition and resultant fertile eggs. The more "eager feeder" should remain with the young (preferably the cock) and the mate removed to a nearby cage. If the hen lays another clutch of eggs after that, her infertile eggs may be tossed without regret as soon as she completes her laying cycle. INCREASING PRODUCTION NEXT YEARUnderstandably, a large commercial breeder wants as much produce and profit as possible during a breeding season. A basic hobbyist, however, is closer to his birds and values the individual hen who is a good breeder and mother. Since most creatures who mature quickly have comparatively short life spans, limiting the canary hen to two nests per season will ensure a longer productive life. This is especially true for a first-year hen and one who raises her babies alone.When a novice gains more experience and sets up a number of hens at the same time, he can still increase his production from one hen while allowing her to raise only two clutches.A hen canary is capable of laying up to four clutches of eggs per season. Laying and incubating does not drain strength - it is the feeding and nurturing the babies for approximately four weeks that does.If the hen lays infertile eggs, she may be allowed to try until she produces. Sometimes a change of mate will help.Any clutch of eggs (from the first to the third) may be removed and transferred or distributed to other hens who lay at the same time. The first hen may then be recycled to produce more eggs.If the hen hatches only one or two babies, these can be transferred to another hen who produces an equally small clutch (of the same age). This hen can also be recycled to produce a hopefully larger clutch.If the above procedures of "switching" are followed, the breeder must exercise some precautions. Try to make sure that the foster mothers are reliable feeders. Transfer babies of the same age and size (preferably close to "lights out" time) and put a drop or two of mixed dry baby cereal and water in the crop. Check the transferred babies to make sure they are being fed the next morning. Do not transfer babies to a full nest - four is an average-sized clutch; do not burden another mother hen with six unless she regularly produces and raises that amount. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3055</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 3 (1977): JUNE-JULY 1977; 28-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3055/3039</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
