<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1267</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Convention Corner</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This year the 1998 American Federation of Aviculture is pleased to announce that it will hold its Annual Convention in exciting Baltimore, Maryland. It will be held at the beautiful Omni Inner Harbor Hotel from July 29- August 2, 1998. The Omni is located in the heart of historic Baltimore and just a few blocks from the fun and excitement of Baltimore's Inner Harbor.Baltimore is conveniently located within a short driving distance from many major U.S. cities. It is only 35 miles north of the Nation's Capital, 150 north of Richmond, 100 miles south of Philadelphia, and 185 miles south of New York City. If you plan to arrive by air, the Baltimore-Washington International (BWI) is just a short ride by taxi to the Inner Harbor.This convention promises to be the best ever. With lots of exciting new raffle prizes including baby birds, cages, a diamond ring, artwork, plus many more. The AFA will also have exciting and informative lectures from the best speakers in Aviculture. Don't miss this opportunity to listen to great seminars and shop in our fantastic exhibit hall.There is also lots to see and do while in Baltimore's Inner Harbor. Don't miss on visiting Maryland's premier attraction, the National Aquarium and explore the four corners of the globe-from a frosty Icelandic coast to a misty rain forest, from a spectacular coral reef to the ocean depths and beyond. Be sure to stroll through the lush tropical rain forest - teeming with birds, Golden Tamarins, emerald green iguanas, and dozens of other exotic jungle creatures.After experiencing the magic of the National Aquarium, shop in the newly renovated Harborplace. The Harborplace offers 125 specialty shops as well as scrumptious eateries and outdoor cafes. In addition, Charles Street, Fells Point, and Federal Point provide fun boutiques and unique museums. There is also a Hard Rock Cafe and Planet Hollywood for your enjoyment -- a great way to take a break from the warm summer sun in Baltimore.Did someone say crabs' This is a must for first-time and repeat visitors. Enjoy steamed hard shell crabs, crabcakes, or even raw oysters. Possibly, take one of the ferries across the Harbor to visit a Maritime Community, or catch a panoramic view of the Inner Harbor at the World Trade Center's Observation Level.All of these wonderful attractions are located with in walking distance from the Omni Inner Harbor Hotel. Make your reservations early to attend AFA's most informative and fun convention yet! </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1267</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 2 (1998): MAR-APR 1998; 14-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1267/1246</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
