<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/704</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding of the Blue-rumped Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jordan, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Blue-rumped Parrot (Psittinuscyanurus cyanurus) is a small parrotfrom southwestern Thailand. It is alsofound through Malaysia and on severalof the islands of Indonesia. Psittinusc. cyanurus is the smallest of thethree known sub-species with anadult size approximately the same assome of the larger love birds.It is quite common throughout itsrange. Until quite recently it has beenvery rare in captivity, probably due toan unusually high mortality rate duringimportation, the cause of whichhas never been explained. In the pastthree or four years the shipments ofthis species have consisted of youngbirds and survival rates have increaseddramatically.Sexual dimorphism is marked inmature birds. Males are distinguishedby a pale blue head and red uppermandible whereas the females' headsare brown and the upper mandible isbrownish-red in color. This dimorphismis very similar to that of many ofthe Asian parakeets. As a matter offact, the behavior and physical attributesof the Blue-rumped Parrot aresimilar to many of the Psittacula parakeetsexcept for their lack of a longpointed tail.My original pair and an extra malewere purchased in tl1e late summer of1990. The proven hen is on breedingloan from Ernie Colazzi of Dallas,Texas. All four birds were placed inone cage to allow for pairing with themates of their choice. The pairs establishedthemselves very quickly andthey began to fight amongst eachother within a week. The alpha pairconsisted of the oldest hen and oldestmale. They always perched in thehighest space available and they atebefore the second pair was allowednear the food. After a week, the twopairs were separated. Fighting wasusually between the females, not themales. In many cases the dominatefemale actually fought off both malesalso.Not knowing a whole lot about thisparticular species, I began my breedingtrials by placing both pairs incages that were next to each other.This later proved to be a mistake asthe hens spent several hours a dayfighting through the wire. Cages wereconstructed of one inch by one halfinch, 14 gauge wire. Both cages measuredtwo feet wide by three feet tall bythree feet long. The food was placedat the front of the cage and the nestwas placed at the rear.Nest boxes were designed by myselfand built by a friend, Rob Gibson.They were so1t of an "L" shape with a4" x 4" entrance box nailed on thefront. This entrance box actually stuckinto the cage with the remainder ofthe box extending onto the outside. Inthis manner there was an entrancethat was internal and the hen had toclimb through a four inch hallway,turn right and go down a 12 inch corridorbefore reaching the actual nestquarters at the bottom. I was tJying tosimulate the depth and feel of a hollowbranch rather than that of a treetrunk. The inside measurements of thecorridors were only six inches by sixinches.Neither pair showed any interest inthe nest boxes in the first year. Theyconsumed large quantities of seeds,fruits, figs, berries and branches cutfrom the large ficus trees (Ficus benjiamana)in the yard. Raw sweet cornwas relished as well as most othervegetables and fruits. The seeds wereconsumed as a second choice.In November of 1991, the two pairswere moved to Miami, Florida. Theoriginal cages and nestboxes wereprovided once again. Both pairs wereside by side which seemed to stimulatethe males. Singing was noticed inboth the males and, less frequently,the females.After a few months in Miami, themales began to show aggressiontowards human intervention. Theynever really competed with eachother, only with the feeders or peoplethat came near the cage. When no onewas around they were content to siton their perches and sing to amuse orstimulate the females. Their song consistedof three different whistle tonessung high to low. Their threat posturewas to fly at the front wire, flaring thetail, lifting the wings, dilating the eyesand repeating the whistle tones ina distinct staccato manner. If a pproached,they would return to theperch and continue the tail and wingmovements. After a few weeks thefemale would retreat to the immediateinterior of the nest and observe themale's defense posture. This was thefirst time the female was seen enteringthe nest.In June of 1992 the rains drenchedthe nest box and the interior wassoaked and somewhat muddy. Inearly July, when tl1e rains stopped, theweather turned very hot. At this pointthe nest dried out but the nestingmaterial needed to be changed. OnJuly 11th, I purchased a new bag ofpine shavings to clean the nests thathad been rain soaked. When I openedthe box on July 12th, an egg was in themiddle of the dirty shavings and thehen was standing nearby. I made adecision not to change the nest untilshe appeared to be brooding.On July 14th, the second egg waslaid. The filth in the nest was toomuch for me so I changed the nestingmaterial and replaced the eggs. Thatentire day the hen stayed out of thebox and fought through the wire withthe female Blue-rumped in the nextcage. The fighting continued the nextday and I decided that something hadto be done. I moved the second pairof birds to the other side of the breedingarea where they could not beseen, only heard. The two eggs wereremoved from the nest and placedunder a broody cockatiel. The dirtynesting shavings were removed andreplaced with fresh pine shavings.On July 16th the third egg appearedin the cleaned nest. By this time thehen had returned to her duties in thebox and in the following four dayslaid two more eggs, on July 18th and20th.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/704</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 21-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/704/687</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
