<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/706</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Those Loveable Lovebirds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Casey, Judie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">If lovebirds are your choice, you'llfind that breeding and keeping themis easy, fun and rewarding. Youngsterscan be tamed and handfedbabies make wonderful, loveablepets. They can sometimes learn a fewwords, but are not known to betalkers.Lovebirds are natives of Africa andsome of the offshore islands. Thereare eight species of lovebirds: Peachfaced,Masked, Fischer's, Red-faced,Black-cheeked, Madagascar, Abyssinianand Swindern's. We will be discussingthe Peach-faced specieswhich makes up the majority of ourbreeding stock.First on the list is the type and colorof lovebird you want. Some of thecommon color mutations of thePeach-faced species are: blue andgreen pieds, creams, lutinos, Americancinnamon, mauve and olive.There are many variations of bluesand greens which all have names, butit is very confusing to recognize eachone when you begin. I'm still not sureof all of them.The best way to decide which birdsyou want is to just choose birds youlike. The only way to really learnabout them is to be able to observethem and their habits.Getting a true pair is next and that isnot always easy. We have read aboutand been told so many ways to visuallysex lovebirds but we gave up aftertoo many wrong guesses. The onlysure way we know is by DNA sexingor surgical sexing. This can be expensive,so there aren't many sexed lovebirdsavailable for sale. Usually areputable breeder can be very helpfulin choosing a pair.The following items are some of thebasics from our breeding program.These have been very successful forus and we are happy to pass them onand hope they work for you.We like to set our birds up with onepair to a cage. We put them togetheras youngsters and let them mature together.Our breeding cages are 2' x 3'x 3' and have PVC legs that are easy towash and make the cage light weightto handle. We use 1/2 x 1" 16 gaugewire that is put together with "]" clips.The cage is a "boot" style which has asafety front with a door to access foodand water and another door in the upperfront positioned just a little to theright. This is for catching birds whennecessary. The PVC legs are cut infive foot lengths and attached withwashers and screws. They are positionedon the sides of the cage frontand back so the bottom is about 36"from the floor, making the cage standabout six feet high.Nest boxes are hung with wirehooks on the outside left front. Thecage wire is cut just enough for thebirds to enter through the 2-1/2" holein the box. There are various stylesand sizes for lovebird boxes. We usea regular reverse that is 7" wide x8-1/2" high x 9" long.We put our boxes on the cageswhen we put the birds in. Most lovebirdslike to sleep in a box. This isalso the reason we do not removeboxes except for cleaning. Our birdstake a rest from breeding even if thebox is left up, and seem to do so twoor three times a year. I'm sure thereare those who will disagree but thishas worked for us and the birds seemto be doing fine.At breeding time, we give the birdspalm leaves which they will shred.Hens will tuck pieces in their mmpfeathers and carry them to the nestwhere they weave them into a nest.Some birds get quite elaborate withsmall tunnels.Clutches usually consist of four tosix eggs, but some young hens onlylay three and we have some olderhens that will lay as many as eight.Eggs are laid one every other day andhens will begin to sit seriously afterthe second egg is laid. Hens do all theincubating and usually only come outto eat or drink. Males will also feedthe hen while she sits.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/706</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 27-28</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/706/689</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
