<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3631</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-25T19:27:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Lory League Hookbill Shows at the 2013 AFA Convention Were a Huge Success</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Corwin, Julie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The bird shows this year at AFA had an amazing variety of species and mutations, including several rare species. The exciting number of 318 entries provided a beautiful backdrop of sounds, a splash of color and a wonderful education to those who attended.Shows were hosted by Lory League and Co-Sponsored by Triangle Bird Club of Beaumont, Texas and Kaytee. The local supporting club, Mid Atlantic Cooperative of Breeders &amp;amp; Exhibitors whose members include Josh Maple, Leslie Huegerich, and Wendy Edwards did a fantastic job of reaching out to exhibitors for all the different divisions, provided a wonderful team of volunteers, show benches, secretary books and more.This year's shows boasted 4 different divisions: ALBS-African Love Bird Society, NAPS-North American Parrot Society, NCS-National Cockatiel Society, and SPEE-Society of Parrot Breeders &amp;amp; Exhibitors. There was also a Junior Class for kids age 16 and under to enter their birds for free.Judges did an amazing job of educating the gallery and pointing out specifics for the exhibitors. Exhibition judges are trained to look for the best representation of the species on the bench. They also help to educate the attendees of the shows. The exhibitions hosted by Lory League at the AFA conventions follow the mission statement and purpose of AFA, and bring the love of birds, and the best conditioned birds to the shows. They also give novice exhibitors a chance to have their birds compared and evaluated by the judge.The Judges came from far and wide this year, Jeff Robinson from Texas judged the Junior Class and the NCS Division (Cockatiels). Jim Heffernan from Michigan judged the NAPS Division (Parrots), Joe DeLuca from Ohio judged the SPBE Division (Parrots), and Mike Miller from North Carolina judged the ALBS Division (Lovebirds). I am proud to say that each one of our judges is a current member of AFA. Exhibitors and attendees came from all across the country. Many of the exhibitors are also members of AFA and eligible for the AFA show awards.The number of entries into the show this year was exciting, but also because Raleigh, NC is in the middle of show country. The Junior Class had 6 entries with Exhibitors ages ranging from ages 10 to 16. The ALBS Lovebird Division had 87 entries, NAPS Parrot Division had 92 entries, NCS Cockatiel Division had 84 entries and SPBE Parrot Division had 87 entries. There were several rare species entered in the show this year including a Blue Throated Macaw, Rose Crown Conure, Hoffman's Conure, Yellow Face Cockatiel and a Slaty Black Face Lovebird. The color mutations of the different divisions created a fascinating backdrop on the show bench.Colorful Rosettes, Medallions, Plaques and more were awarded to the top exhibitors.Junior Class-Judged by Jeff Robinson of Texas Ribbons sponsored by AFA4Kidzand Lory League1st Place-Mosiac Green-cheeked Conure -Ariana Mignella2nd Place- Umbrella Cockatoo -- Mackenzie Cameron3rd Place- Female Red-sided Eclectus -Mackenzie Cameron4th Place-Rose-crown Conure --Ariana Mignella5th Place-Yellow American Budgie -- Brandon Huegerich6th Place-Blue American Budgie-Patrick HuegerichSpecial Rosettes for the Junior Class weresponsored by Blue Jungle Parrot Talkative-Umbrella Cockatoo exhibited by Mackenzie CameronAnimated-Mosiac Green-cheeked Conure exhibited by Ariana Mignella Cutest-Rose-crown Conure exhibited by Ariana MignellaYoungest Exhibitor Plaque was awarded to Arianna Mignella-age 10Ariana Mignella stole the show in the Junior Class being awarded the Youngest Exhibitor Award, created and sponsored by GEM Custom Laser-Gary Morgan and Lory League, along with 1st place Ribbon for best in show in the Junior Class, and the special Rosette for the Most Animated in the show, and 4th place for the Rose-crown Conure which also won the Cutest Award.All birds were checked in by Dr. Greg Burkett Greg, DVM AVPB and benched in their appropriate sections, for the Junior Class at 8:30am and the main show divisions to start at 9:00am.NAPS-North American Parrot Society Judged by Jim Heffernan of Michigan -92 entries-15 ExhibitorsAwards sponsored by North American Parrot Society, Gary Morgan of GEM Custom Laser, and Award for Best Lory in Show sponsored by Lory League.1. African Ring neck exhibited by Mike Miller, NC2. Moluccan Cockatoo exhibited by Fran Andersen, Ml3. Lutino Cockatiel exhibited by Josh Maple, NC4. Violet Indian Ring neck Parakeet exhibited by Mike Miller, NC5. Turquoise Pied/Pastel Parrotlet exhibited by RickSkaggs, NC6. Crimson Rosella exhibited by Josh Maple, NC7. Baraband Parakeet exhibited by Mike Miller, NC8. Gray Cockatiel exhibited by Josh Maple, NC9. Clear Gray Indian Ring neck exhibited by Mike Miller,NC10. Normal Gray Cockatiel exhibited by Josh Maple, NCBest Novice-Turquoise Pied Pastel ParrotletRick Skaggs, NCBest Lory -Duyvenbode's Lory exhibited by Marie Crowley, MlAFA Award-Best Bird in Show-Bred, Banded &amp;amp; Exhibited by a Member of AFA-Josh Maple, NC AFA Award-Best Bird in Show, Exhibited by a Member of AFA-Mike Miller, NCNCS Division-National Cockatiel Society Judged by Jeff Robinson of Texas53 Entries- 8 Exhibitors1. Lutino Hen exhibited by Josh Maple, NC2. Cinnamon Hen exhibited by Karl &amp;amp; Leslie Huegerich, NC3. Cinnamon Pied Cock exhibited by Josh Maple,NC4. Normal Cock (AOV) exhibited by Josh Maple, NC5. Normal Cock exhibited by Peggy Armstrong, GA6. Pearl Hen exhibited by Peggy Armstrong, GA7. WF Cinn/Pearl Cock (AOV) exhibited by Josh Maple, NC8. Cinnamon Hen exhibited by Josh Maple, NC9. Cinnamon Cock exhibited by Peggy Armstrong, NC10. Cinnamon Hen exhibited by Josh Maple, NC Best Novice-Normal Cock-Amber Penniston-PAAFA Award-Best Bird in Show-Bred, Banded &amp;amp; Exhibited by a Member of AFA-Josh Maple-NC AFA Award-Best Bird in Show, Exhibited by a Member of AFA-Josh Maple--NCA LBS-African Love Bird Society Judged by Mike Miller of North Carolina - 88 Entries-8 ExhibitorsAwards sponsored by African Love Bird Society, Gary Morgan of GEM Custom Laser, and Lory League 1. Par Blue exhibited by JD Ferrigno, Washingtonville, NY2. Dilute Blue exhibited by Wendy Edwards, Youngsville, NC3. Green Peach Face exhibited by Josh Maple, Garner, NC4. Medium Par Blue exhibited by Carolyn Chamberlain, Summersville, SC5. Green Fischer exhibited by Wendy Edwards, Youngsville, NC6. Black Cheek exhibited by Susan Saylor, Charleston, SC7. Medium Green Opaline exhibited by JD Ferrigno, Washingtonville, NY8. Black Cheek exhibited by Linn a Reusmann, Catalua, GA9. Lutino Opaline exhibited by JD Ferrigo, Washingtonville, NY10. Green Dilute exhibited by Linna Reusmann, Catalua, GA Best Novice-Medium Par Blue-Carolyn Chamberlain-SCBest Unflighted-Green Fischer's-Wendy Edwards-NCAFA Award-Best Bird in Show-Bred, Banded&amp;amp; Exhibited by a Member of AFA-JD FerrignoNYAFA Award-Best Bird in Show-Exhibited by a Member of AFA-JD Ferrigno--NY </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3631</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 40 No. 4 (2013): Number 4  2013; 10-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3631/3614</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
