<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4041</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:16:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cute and Colorful Conures</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jordan, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 3 (April 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Undoubtedly, the members of the parrot family known as “conures”, are some of the most commonly kept birds as both pets or as breeders. This is partly due to their size; most are small birds measuring less than ten inches from their head to the tip of the tail. There are many species of conures, of many genera, but the majority belong to either the Pyrrhura or Aratinga families. A few others belong to monotypic genera or have been reclassified into smaller groups of classification.All members of Pyrrhura conures have been called “the quiet conures” which, in contrast to the members of the Aratinga genus, is basically true. But this quiet nature limits their mimic abilities as well. The smaller Pyrrhura conures are not known for any exceptional speaking ability but they can learn a few words and sounds and there have been exceptional birds that have learned many words and sentences. Members of the genus Aratinga can become good mimics but are often described as “loud” pets! It’s a tradeoff for sure. Quiet birds equal less mimic ability and vice versa. This does not mean that a Pyrrhura will not talk or mimic or that every Aratinga conure will be loud as each bird is an individual and is often shaped by their environment. Despite a mediocre talent for talking, or a loud reputation, all conures are little clowns that exhibit an energetic and inquisitive personality...Most of the species in the Pyrrhura conure group appear rather similar. They are small birds with very pointed tails and most have a necklace of scalloped or pointed feathers around the neck. They are predominantly green on the back and wings with different shades of maroon, red, or rust colors on the abdomens, heads, and faces.All species in the Genus Pyrrhura are listed on the CITES appendices. Most are listed on appendix II and a few are listed on appendix I. This means that as of 1992 US breeders or pet owners cannot import them unless they get a special approved breeding program through the US Fish and Wildlife Service. The results are that the birds we have here now are basically all we will have for breeding stock in the future. Specialists concentrating on conure breeding are needed or we may see several species disappear from US aviculture.The most commonly kept Pyrrhura conuresGreen-cheeked Conure Probably the most commonly kept Pyrrhura conure is the Green-cheeked conure (Pyrrhura molinae). In the 1980s, this species was imported in large numbers and became established in American aviaries rather easily. They were inexpensive as wild-caught birds and adapted to captivity quickly. It is also interesting to note that today there are many color variations (mutations) of this species. This is common among species that adapt well and breed well in captivity. The very first color mutation on record was a cinnamon mutation that appeared naturally through captive breeding in Arizona. As this color became more readily available, a second mutation, which was wild-caught; the yellow-sided mutation, appeared in quarantine stations among groups of normally colored wild-caught birds. In the 1980s it was believed that the yellow-sided mutation was another species and it...Normal Green-cheeked Conure P. molinaecolored birds. Through captive breeding experiments in California and eventually nationwide, it was proven that the yellow-sided conure was, in fact, a sex-linked opaline mutation of the green-cheeked conure (Pyrrhura molinae).Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4041</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 3 (2022): Watchbird April 2022; 12-18</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4041/4001</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
