<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/477</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS: CITES What It Is and How It Functions</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Phillips, Lee</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">CITES is the acronym for the Convention on InternationalTrade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora. It is acomplex treaty between 95 sovereign countries and it relates tointernational trade in animals and plants. It has no jurisdictionin the internal affairs of the parties to the treaty. In our case,once a shipment and its papers are approved for entry into theUnited States, our own U.S. laws take effect. Let me state thatthere has been no proposal to move all Appendix IT psittacinesto Appendix I. That may be proposed for the next meeting ofthe parties to the treaty but at this time no such proposal hasbeen made.International trade was recognized years ago as a major threatto the survival of many wildlife species. In 1963 theInternational Union for Conservation of Nature and NaturalResources (the IUCN) made a formal call for an internationaltreaty regulating trade in wildlife species and, after a wholedecade of drafting, redrafting and consultations with governments,government agencies and non-government agencies, thedraft of the CITES treaty was concluded at a conferenceattended by representatives of 80 countries in Washington, D.C.in March of 1973. The treaty was entered into effect on July 1,1975 upon ratification by ten of its original signatories.Currently 95 countries are party to the treaty.Meetings of the parties to the treaty are held every two yearsand the next meeting, originally scheduled for Jakarta, Indonesia,and now planned for Lausanne, Switzerland, is set forOctober 9 to 20, 1989.CITES functions on the basis of its Appendices. It establishesdifferent requirements for trade in species listed on the threespecies' appendices.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/477</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 2 (1989): APR-MAY 1989; 48-51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/477/462</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
