<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/683</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question #l: I understand thatAfrican Greys need more calcium thanother parrots. Why is this and how canI supply this in the diet if all the birdswill eat is a seed diet?C. Hysell, CaliforniaAnswer #1: It is not that AfricanGrey Parrots need more calcium thanother birds, but rather that AfricanGreys, for some unknown reason,have a high incidence of hypocalcemia.Hypocalcemia is a lower thannormal level of circulating calcium inthe blood. Adequate calcium levelsare necessary for normal muscle functioning.When calcium levels drop tolevels well below normal, the patientexhibits weakness, trembling, seizurelikeactivity and collapse. Seeds aredeficient in calcium. For birds toutilize calcium, vitamin 0 3 must bepresent in adequate amounts. Birdshoused outdoors with sufficient sunlightexposure produce adequate vitamin0 3. Since window glass filters outultraviolet light rays, birds keptindoors need vitamin 0 3 supplementsas well as calcium.Calcium can be provided in a numberof ways. I would implore you tomake the effort to convert your birdsto a more complete and well balanceddiet of pellets, fruits, vegetables andprotein foods. Additional calcium canbe supplied in the form of mineralblocks and cuttlebone for birds tochew on. Calcium can also be addedto the drinking water. NeoCal gluconsyrup, a soluble product used by nursingwomen and available at your localpharmacy, can be added to the bird'sdrinking water at the rate of one teaspoonper four ounces of drinkingwater.James M. Harris, D.V.M.Oakland, CaliforniaAnswer #2: African Grey Parrotsappear to develop signs of calcium deficiency including seizures, fracturesand egg binding in adults andfolding fractures in juveniles, quickerthan other types of parrots on thesame imbalanced diet. Calciumabsorption from the diet requires thepresence of Vitamin Dl and is inhibitedby large amounts of phosphorusand fat in the diet. It is unknown ifGreys require higher quantities of calciumor vitamin 0 3 in their diet thanother parrots, or if they are unable toremove calcium from their boneswhen needed as other parrots aremore able to do. Regardless of whichmechanism is at work, both adult andjuvenile African Greys do not becomecalcium deficient on most commercialpelleted diets containing 0.5 to l.Oo/ocalcium dry weight. Most Greys canbe converted to a commercial pelleteddiet, or a seed diet can be supplementedwith calcium utilizing cuttlebone,mineral blocks or mineral grit(oyster shell), as well as cheese andother dairy products, kale, collards,and other high calcium vegetables.Greys that are already deficient orwho have been unwilling to convertto a balanced diet can be supplementedusing a readily absorbedcalcium product such as Avimin,Neocalglucon or calcium gluconate.These products can be given directlyor added to the drinking water; however,they are expensive when used inthe correct dosage and a better alternativein the long run is to convert thebirds to a balanced diet. Regardless ofwhich calcium product is used, it isimp01tant to supplement with vitamin0 3 and to limit the fat and phosphorusin the diet.Nicole VanDerHeyden, D.V.M.Indianapolis, IndianaAnswer #3: African Greys areseemingly unique in their utilization ofcalcium. As calcium metabolism is afairly complex subject involving potentiallydifferent forms of calcium, vitamin D, and phosphorus, a simpleunderstanding of an apparent calciumdeficiency in an African Grey Parrot isnot readily available.It is thought that African Greysexcrete excessive amounts of calciumthrough their kidneys and, hence, outof the body. This, therefore, rendersthem easily deficient in the amount ofavailable calcium circulating in thebody that is available for sustainingand maintaining the body's normalfunctions. Further, it has been suggestedthat African Greys arc not ableto mobilize (remove) calcium fromtheir bones as readily or efficiently ascan other avian species. AfricanGreys, then, may actually requiremore calcium in their diets as theylose more in their urine!Providing a well rounded and balanceddiet is optimally the idealmethod for ensuring that an AfricanGrey will not develop problemsrelated to low circulating bloodcalcium. Converting these birds to asupplemented pclleted diet should bestrived for. My personal recommendationinvolves converting birds to a freechoice commercially available pelleteddiet that is supplemented with aprotein based soft food mix, such as"Soak and Cook." A variety of fruits,vegetables and other nutritious tablefood can be added to this daily offeredsoft food mixture, as well as drykibbled dog food and a powderedvitamin supplement.The supplemented pelleted dietapproach has worked well in numerousGreys to maintain them in goodnutritional status in both pet andaviary situations. Supplementation ofbreeders prior to and during breedingseason with cuttlebone or mineralblocks should also be considered, asthis recommendation is also applicablein any egg producing birds.Amy B. Worell, D.V.M.West Hills, California </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/683</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 24-26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/683/666</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
