<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/554</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Rewarding Genes on the Show Bench</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Why are certain indiviuals so successfulon the showbench year afteryear, while others are not? Are theyjust luckier than most or are theyusing a special technique, perhaps aset of principles, seemingly concealedas the elusive "secrets" ofbreeding for show?Successful breeders of such popularspecies as budgerigars and canaries,have known for years how tocreate an exhibition line or breedingstud. When listening to accomplishedbreeders whose wins mountdecade upon decade, many admit topaying their dues perhaps in a numberof areas. Such realms may includethe aviary, or birdroom, and theshowbench certainly. And, somesearch through the written accomplishmentsof others' writing in theavicultural literature. But, perhapsmost valuable of all, is the breeder'sown studbook, which may contain ahighly unique and undiscoveredwealth of information.True, there are those who mayhave an occasional win with a magnificentlygroomed, large parrot orwell-conditioned finch. But, whatabout the offspring of those sameindividuals; why do they fall short bythe same panel judges? Afterall, theywere reared from an award winner!The reason may be a simple matter ofbreeding technique and the establishmentof a family line.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/554</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 3 (1992): JUNE-JULY 1992; 49-51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/554/538</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
