<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2918</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-12T15:48:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">African Love Bird Society</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hakman, Marlene</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">he African Love Bird Society was founded in August, 1976, when it became apparent that there was a need for such a specialty society. From a small gathering of about seventy at the home of our cofounders, Lee Horton and Roland Dubuc, we have grown into a very large international society.A major factor in this growth is our Journal Agapornis World, which is published monthly. Through this medium we are able to follow the dictates of our bylaws, which state, "an international nonprofit organization dedicated to the improvement and standardization of all species of Agapornis and their mutations." Our Journal brings to the novice as well as to the expert avicul turist pertinent information to help them through the many trials that occur in this hobby. It is through this Journal that we are able to bring to our members in Texas, Alaska and even New Zealand, the ideas that are discussed at our California based meetings.Through this medium of print we are able to meet such people as Dr. Richard Baer of Ohio, Jim Morris of Indiana, and Rainer Erhart of Michigan, and many more, and share their successes as well as their failures. Their methods are often different than ours because of climate and space but this knowledge is always welcomed by us. For someone like me who lives in a rented apartment I am able to get many good ideas that are not available from our big outdoor hobbyists here in Southern California.We have also been fortunate as a society to have two members, Steve Clause and Dorothea Petrula , both expert photographers, who have made it possible for us to see the many new mutations and the seldom seen rare species through their pictures. This we hope will help us standardize the names of these many mutations and set up a quality standard for show. In conjunction with this the society has established its own closed band, breeding record cards, as well as pedigree cards. We are all learning the importance of their use.Our meetings are on a floating basis.That means that we try to meet in a different part of Southern California every month. Through this method we are able to reach more members, who ordinarily would not be able to attend distant meetings. We are looking for interested aviculturists both novice and expert. It is the expert who can teach the novice. hut it is the novice who can remind the expert of the many pitfalls that must be experienced.So what do we have to offer? A Journal , congenial people, interesting talk, homes and aviaries to visit, and a raffle table totally self-supported by members and friends.The African Love Bird Society can do much to improve the status of lovebird breeding in this country. Your help and support is valuable. Our lovebirds are worth the effort •  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2918</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 1 (1978): FEB-MAR 1978; 16-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2918/2902</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
