<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/843</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Turaco Husbandry at the Houston Zoo</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Plasse, Rochell</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Todd, William ''Trey"</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The endemic African family Musophagidae (or order Musophagiformes) comprises the turacos, plantaineaters and go-away birds, a homogeneous assemblage of some 20 species (with numerous distinct subspecies) traditionally accepted as related to the cuckoos (Cuculiformes). Separation of the three somewhat arbitrary categories is primarily by plumage color: turacos - green (genus Tauraco), plantain-eaters - blue (Musophaga, Corythaeola) and goaway birds - gray (Corythaixoides; Criniferoides, Crinifer). These common names are often, however, used interchangeably in ornithogical/avicultural literature. In this paper the name "turaco" will be used, unless otherwise noted, as a convenient collective for the entire family.For nearly 20 years Houston Zoological Gardens has maintained a successful captive-breeding program for turacos: over 400 specimens of 14 forms (species and/or subspecies) have been raised. In 1981 the American Association of Zoological Parks and Aquaria awarded the zoo its significant achievement award for its turaco breeding program. In subsequent years we have increased our expertise and initiated several research endeavors. This paper presents a brief overview of management practices proven successful at the Houston Zoo, given our climate, facilities and staff; we do not intend them to be the last word in keeping these birds.HousingThe oldest (1930s) breeding cages at Houston Zoo feature a wire-covered exhibit area, a roofed wooden shelter, and measure 7 ft x 15 ft with a height of 10 ft in the shelter and 7 ft in the outside enclosure. Newer cages (off-exhibit) consist of pre-fabricate weld wire or chainlink panels with an attached partial roof of corrugated fiberglass and shadecloth. These units measure 6 ftx 20 ftx8 ft high. Dim night-time illumination is provided where possible to discourage rodent or predator disturbance. Infrared heat lamps are provided in shelters during winter. Off-exhibit cages are covered with fiber-reinforced polyethylene during winter and forced-air heat maintains temperatures above freezing. Birds may be housed side by side, but some visual or physical barriers may be necessary to discourage fighting through the wire.Substrate is "filter sand," which is gravel approximately . 5 to 2 mm in size, allowing rapid drainage and ease of cleaning by raking and sifting. Aviaries are planted as thickly as practical, given the need for public display and/or service. Vegetation provides shade and seclusion and offers escape opportunity should one of the birds attack another (a frequent occurrence with captive turacos; see Behavior). Juvenile birds are often housed for convenience off-exhibit in less stimulating, plant free, concretefloored cages.Turacos are arboreal nesters, but construct flimsy dove-like nests and are best provided with artifical platforms. Wooden produce flats filled with hay were originally used but were replaced by sturdier-built boxes lined with wire mesh to prevent rolling of eggs or leg problems in chicks if hay was displaced. The boxes are secured to the cage or shelter wall 7 to 8 ft above ground. Wicker baskets have occasionally been used and might be more acceptable to newly imported specimens. Some birds may carry token nesting material, but most soon accept artificial arrangements. To encourage shy pairs and to reduce distur- bance from adjacent birds, visual barriers may be placed around nests situated high in aviaries. Following several successful nestings, nests can often be lowered to more accessible levels and barriers removed.Turacos cool themselves by gular fluttering and are heat-tolerant if not unduly stressed: Houston summer temperatures often exceed 95°F with high relative humidity. During hot weather, keepers attempt to complete most cage maintenance by 10:00 a.m. In dry periods soaker hoses over cages provide some cooling.Winter temperatures in Houston only occasionally plunge below freezing and rarely remain there longer than 24 hours. Provided with heat and shelter, turacos remain active and reasonably tolerant of these extremes. During an unusually severe cold snap (100 hours subfreezing) only one turaco in the zoo's collection suffered a frost-bitten toe.DietWild turacos are generally classed as frugivores and may be conveniently divided into two groups: the go-away birds and gray plantain-eaters, and the green turacos and blue plantain-eaters. The former inhabit more arid "acaia" and "savannah scrub" areas and have been reported eating the leaves, flowers, seed pods and buds of acacia, aloes and similar plants as well as termites.Those species living in wetter areas, such as "gallery, lowland and mountain forests," eat fruits, leaves, some insects and occasionally algae or moss. Fruits such as Musanga (fig-like), oil palm, wild dates and podocarpus are reportedly consumed.The complete diets (so far as known) of wild turacos have not been nutritionally analysed, and captive diets are therefore based to a large degree on trial and error. Often diets are chosen because they are easier to prepare, not because they are nutritionally correct. At Houston they have traditionally consisted of a protein source (e.g., cat chow, dog chow), a variety of fruits and vegetables, and greens (see Appendix). Recently these diets have been evaluated by an independent source and may be changed somewhat in the future to improve nutritional value and feeding efficiency.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/843</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 6 (1994): NOV-DEC 1994; 34-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/843/825</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
