<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/570</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The World Parrot Trust</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Low, Rosemary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Conservation organisations andenvironment-related charities beganto emerge as a strong force in thedecade of the '80s. Now we are in the'90s and the impact that they canmake on conservation issues iswidely felt throughout the world, butespecially in the tropics where manyissues are a matter of great urgency.If an area of rainforest is not savedthis year, ten, twenty or thirty speciescould be irrevocably lost toextinction next year. Unfortunately,this is a scenario which is repeatingitself in countless areas of the globe.Throughout the world, bird populationsact like an environmentalbarometer, often giving an earlywarning to the fact that man is damagingthe environment to an unacceptabledegree, and that someaction must be taken to reverse the damage, whether it is due to pollution, destruction ofhabHat or hunting and harvesting of wildlife. Goneare the days when protection of theenvironment was seen as an activityfor groups with an interest in saving acertain species of bird or animal.Now it is recognised that it is the survivalof the human race which is alsoat stake. And with this recognitionalso comes the awareness that everyone of us has a voice which can beheard and which can influence environmentalissues.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/570</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 45-46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/570/553</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
