<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2197</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-15T07:48:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From Pets to Parents (Buffon's macaws)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gale, R. Florence</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Our Buffon's macaws (Ara a. ambigua), Max and Floyd, were brought to the United States from Panama in 1975, by Nathan B. Gale, D.V.M. Natives had removed them from their tree nests at approximately fifty days of age; and subsequently, Dr. Gale took on their parenting until they were about six months old, at which time the two birds came to my sons as pets. Max has since remained in California, while Floyd resided in Utah until the spring of 1981. Max somewhat tamed and warmed to members of the family even to the point of following my son in puppy-like fashion. Floyd, on the other hand, while controllable, was not as friendly.After being reunited in 1981, a fiberglass home was built for them in a partially enclosed area surrounded by plants and complete with a pair of scarlet macaws for neighbors. However, problems with predators necessitated the enclosure of the entire living area. Thus, their 6 ft. by 4 ft. home has steel framework and is enclosed with cyclone fencing, as Max and Floyd enjoy tearing apart anything else. Manzanita branches serve as perches but do require frequent replacing. Max and Floyd moved into their new home in June, 1981.In August, 1981, endoscopies were performed which determined that Max was female and Floyd was male. They were six years old at this time. In January, 1982, we had a barrel prepared as a nest. It is 27 in. long and 15 in. in diameter and was fixed with a welded edge which covered one third of the opening and hung from the top of the cage, resulting in an entrance not easily accessible for viewing. Cedar shavings, peat moss, and potting soil were tried as nesting material; however, we now use only pine and cedar shavings.While cleaning the cage on March 28, 1982, we noticed that the birds were acting out of character. Max, who usually responded quickly to commands refused to move from the food dish. Floyd was quite aggressive, even to the point of trying to bite me. On further investigation, I found one egg in the nest and then recalled that recently they had been more attentive toward each other and had ceased responding to my talking and petting. Then on April 1, another egg was observed.Max spent most of her time in the nest, frequently not even coming out at feeding time. On occasion, Floyd would assist in the nest. Both were very aggressive, ruffling their neck and head feathers while being fed and attacking the spoon and each other while the food was being given. They would follow and attack us when the nest was being checked. They became secretive in their actions if they became aware of being watched and would stop their own activities and view their observer(s). Often Max would come out only for a quick bite to eat and return immediately to her eggs. These eggs were removed after thirtytwo days and were candled; they were determined to be infertile. Each egg was chalk white and resembled a small chicken egg. Egg A measured 5.5 cm. in length, 4.5 cm. in diameter, and 12 cm. in circumference. Egg B measured 4. 6 cm. in length, 3.8 cm. in diameter, and 11.2 cm. in circumference. For six days following the removal of the eggs, the aggressive behavior continued but only toward each other, not toward the feeding spoon or toward me.On April 22, a second clutch started with a second egg arriving on April 24. Again the birds became aggressive; but in addition, they became visibly nervous when people were present. Two weeks later there were four eggs in the nest. Max incubated the eggs throughout with Floyd giving a wing in the evenings.Finally, onJune 19, 1982, twenty-nine days from the observation of the first egg, two eggs hatched. The third and fourth eggs were broken, and it is assumed that they were infertile. For the first ten days, the new hatchlings sound- ed very much like new-born kittens; and they remained huddled together making little sound and lifting their heads only in reaction to the light which was used to observe them.Max and Floyd were attentive parents, assisting in the feeding of Calen (meaning green) and Rudh (meaning bald) as the "kids" were to be named. In seven days they appeared to double in size. Their eyes were partially open by the 19th day and completely open by the 22nd day. Feathers began on the 18th day, and the pin feathers were very noticeable on the 20th day. At one month both chicks had developed tail feathers. At six weeks the primary and secondalry feathers were showing, and the little ones let us know much squawking and raising to their feet. At seven weeks Calen, the larger chick, had well developed wing and forehead feathers and the beginnings of pin feathers on the upper back.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2197</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 10 No. 5 (1983): OCT-NOV 1983; 19-22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2197/2171</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
