<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/481</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Visits ...  The Aviaries of Lynn Hall</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The dove has been the internationalsymbol of peace for as long asanyone can remember and , if numberscount , the more doves , thegreater the tranquility. And tranquilare the aviaries of Lynn Hall, whichare filled with the brilliant colors andresonant sounds of over two dozenspecies of rare doves, pigeons, andfruit pigeons.When one conjures up an image ofa dove, it is often of the mourning orturtle dove - natives of NorthAmerica - in their plain, earth tonecolors. The word " pigeon" moreoften than not evokes the thought ofswarms of birds begging for handoutsat the local park or fast food chain.These duller members of the Columbiformesbelie the incredible beautyand diverse patterns of size and colorfound in so many species, most ofwhich are found in more exotic andfurther reaches of the globe. Some ofthe fruit pigeons easily rival thegaudiest parrot and the surrealisticLady Gouldian finch.Lynn has been a bird fancier fromhis earliest days, when, as the son of awildcatter, the only companions hehad were the birds he kept. Life in theoil business meant never staying inone place very long , as his fathermoved from one drilling site to thenext.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/481</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 2 (1989): APR-MAY 1989; 58-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/481/466</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
