<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/803</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Macaws as Teaching Assistants at the Washington Zoological Park</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Page, Lynne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Everyone who cares about birds isone day driven to become aneducator encouraging others to valuethe wondrous nature of birds, tounderstand the importance of conservationto protect birds in the wild, andto appreciate the needs of birds incaptivity. The Washington ZoologicalPark in Issaquah, Washington, is dedicatedto teaching these very lessons.The instruction is unforgettable,thanks in large part to the zoo'simpressive teaching assistants, themacaws.Unlike many zoos, the WashingtonZoological Park (WZP) is primarily ateaching institution. Every visitorreceives personal attention and guidancefrom the network of docentswho relate information about the animalsand environmental values andanswer questions. This emphasis oneducation is not surprising as the zoowas founded in 1972 as a teachinglaboratory for a neighboring private school. Now the zoo is governed bythe Zoological Society of Washington.Funding is from society memberships,donations, zoo admissions and fundraising.No government funds or taxmoney is received and the staff islargely devoted volunteers.The Director of the WashingtonZoological Park, Peter Rittler, identifiestwo distinct aims within the zoo'smission to increase public knowledgeof psittacines. The first aim is toenhance the public's understandingand appreciation of parrots in the wildas well as the effect of humanity'sactivities on the birds. Visitors to thezoo may arrive never having heard ofthe Hyacinthine Macaw or havingseen only a picture of this largest of all.macaws. Before leaving, they willmeet Payaso, a young Hyacinthinewho loves to be held and may be caught napping with one foot clutchinga few wing feathers as a "securityblanket." Now Payaso's "students"will be touched more deeply whenthey learn that Hyacinthine Macawsare endangered. Perhaps they willeven take specific action to help protectthe species and its habitat.The second aim of the zoo's educationalefforts regarding psittacines is toimprove the care of parrots in captivity,a concern rarely addressed byother zoos. In common with otherzoological institutions, the WashingtonZoological Park does discouragethe keeping of pet parrots. Mr. Rittlerexpresses this view by saying thebirds remain wild animals and, as childrenof the wild, belong in their nativehabitats. The WZP parts companywith most other zoos by going beyondthat fundamental principle to recognizethat parrots have been kept aspets throughout history, are now keptin large numbers, and will continue tobe prized as pets.Believing that all birds, wild andcaptive, deserve a high quality of life,the zoo governors seek to improve thecare of pet birds through education.An exhibit is being built to presentnutritional guidelines for feeding petparrots and to display examples ofminimum housing. By making realisticsuggestions, the zoo staff hopes toencourage pet owners to upgradeeach aspect of their birds' care. Forexample, Mr. Rittler notes it would beineffective to ask every pet owner toprovide the ideal accommodation of alarge aviary for each bird. People whocare about their birds but have underestimatedtheir needs may, however,be motivated by this exhibit to buy aconsiderably larger cage.Four years ago, the zoo realized itcould best accomplish its twoprongededucational mission as topsittacines by specializing in onegenus. Macaws were chosen to representall parrots because of their beautyand intelligence and because peopleunfamiliar with birds easily Jearn toidentify macaws.When the decision to specialize wasmade, other parrots already resided atthe zoo, including African Grey Parrots,a Moluccan Cockatoo, and DoubleYellow-headed Amazons, two ofwhich are of the Tres Marias subspecies.Mr. Rittler vows that all thesebirds have a permanent home at theWZP because "they are as much a partof us as our arms, or legs, or noses."Watc hing him walk through thegrounds, this is easy to believe , aseach parrot reaches out to him for atreat or caress.Director Rittler points out that thisfocus on macaws is highly unusualamong zoos. One reason may be thatsome zoos choose not to maintainbirds well represented in captivity.The WZP collection includes macawscommon as pets (such as the Blue andGold Macaw and Scarlet Macaw) aswell as less common ones (such as theHyaci nthine and Red-fronted). TheWZP's immediate goal is to have allbut the rarest macaws, such as theLear's. Some day Mr. Rittler hopes toinclude even the rarest species in thezoo's collectio n. Currently, the zoohas Hahn's, Illiger's, Yellow-collared,Red-fronted, Military, Blue and Gold,Scarlet, Green-winged , and HyacinthineMacaws. Because the intent is toeducate people about all macaws, andall these species exist in the wild, theview of the zoo's governors is that it isirreleva nt that large populations ofsome of these species exist in captivity.As a res ult, the zoo now has thelargest macaw collection on the WestCoast between the Canadian borderand the San Diego Zoo, and expectsone day to have the most completemacaw collection in the country.Before tha t day comes, the zoo maywell have one of the largest macawsigns in the nation . Soon to beerected, the sign will identify allmacaw species , give a capsuledescription, and state the status in thewild of each species (threatened orendangered, for instance).In regard to the care of captive birds,part of the zoo's teaching is by example.The zoo has a manual setting outin detail the institution's methods formeeting the three basic needs of birdsin captivity: nutrition, sanitation, andactivity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/803</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 22-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/803/785</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
