<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3382</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-01-21T02:17:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Member Shines at the Great American Bird Show</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Great American Bird show was founded in 1986 by Bill Parlee, of the National Finch Society, Dr. Randy Brue and Howard Miller of Kaytee Productstand Dr. Al Decoteau of the Society of Parrot Breeders and Exhibitors. Today, the Great American Bird Show is one of the largest national bird shows in the country with hundreds of exhibitorn competing with thousands of birds. The GreatAmerican Bird show is also the only national show that gives cash prizes in addition to the standard awards.The American Federation of Aviculture has been working to conserve birds and promote the advancement of aviculture. In keeping with both of those principles, AFA gives an award to the Best Bird in Show at the Great American Bird Show that has been Bred and Banded by an exhibitor who is also an AFA member.In 2004, the Great American Bird Show was held in beautiful Tucson, Arizona on October 2, 2004. There were six Divisions including those for the National and American Cockatiel Societies, National Finch &amp;amp; Softbill Society, Society of Parrot Breeders and Exhibitors, two African Love Bird Society Divisions and an American Budgerigar Division.This year's AFA winner for the Best Bird in Show Bred and Banded by an AFA Member was Kari Morton of Colorado. Ms. Morton took First Place in the Parrot Division with a fabulous blue Lineolated Parakeet. This bird also won the Second Best Bird in Show Award. Congratulations Kari, on a job very well done and thank you for supporting showing and the American Federation of Aviculture. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-01-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3382</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 32 No. 2 (2005): Number 2  2005; 5</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3382/3366</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
