<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/693</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Swans</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elgas, Bob</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Distributed worldwide are eightspecies of swans, most of which arefound in the northern hemisphere.Only two, the Black Swan of Australiaand the Black-necked Swan of SouthAmerica, are native to the southernhemisphere. Exclusive of Antarctica,Africa is the only continent to whichswans are not native.The species with which most peopleare familiar is the Mute Swan ofEurope. It is especially well known inBritain where it has been maintainedin parks and estates for hundreds ofyears. It is now considered a semidomesticatedspecies. It is this speciesthat is widely known from early literature,fairy tales and mythology. It isinteresting that they should have beennamed Mute Swans for, while they donot have powerful voices, they are farfrom mute. Their call is comparativelysoft -a rather melodious, mewingcall. Other northern swans havepowerful trumpeting calls so that bycontrast the Mute is much less vocal.Perhaps this might explain the name.All swans are ornamental, beingespecially graceful upon water. This isparticularly true of the Mute. It carriesits wings in a raised, arched positionabove the back, with the neck gracefullycurved -a handsome sightindeed. They are at their best uponwater, where much of their time isspent. Of all swans, the Mute's legs arepositioned further back on the body.As a result, they are less adept uponland where they walk with a somewhatlabored and rolling gait. Mutesare one of the largest of the clan,being equaled or surpassed only bythe Trumpeter of North America,which, indeed, is the largest of theworld's waterfowl.Inaddition to their long history inEurope, Mutes have been maintainedin American collections for manyyears. They breed very well andescaped birds have established themselvesin the wild. They have becomerelatively abundant in eastern areas ofthe United States where they posesome significant problems. In additionto being dominant over native Americanspecies, their feeding habits aredestructive to the ecosystems ofshallow marshland areas.The Black-necked Swan of SouthAmerica and the Black Swan of Australiaare the two representatives ofthe southern hemisphere. Both arehighly ornamental, adjust well to captivity,and are dependable breeders.As the name applies, the Australianswan is entirely black. However, thereis a strong silvery cast to the plumageand the back feathers are curly. Thecurled feathers are unique to the speciesand give it a particularly pleasingappearance. The eyes and bill are red,which is also unique, as other swanshave black eyes and black is the predominantbill color. In all swans, theupper mandible extends all the waythrough the lares area to the eye. TheAustralian swan has an unusually longneck, which it arches gracefully. Italso has the capability to fluff the neckfeathers in a particularly pleasingmanner. The voice is somewhat similarto the Mute's -a soft whistling,mewing call. As one might imagine, the Black- necked Swan's head and full length ofthe neck are black. The body is whiteand the bill has red and blue coloration.There is a sizable knob on theupper mandible, It is the smallest ofthe swans, is very attractive, andcomparatively scarce in aviculturalcollections.South America is the home of anadditional bird, the Coscoroba, whichhas been included in the swan family.It has been included with the swanslargely on the basis of its being a largeall white bird (the wing tips are black).Actually the Coscoroba is much moreclosely aligned with the whistlingducks than the swans. The bill is muchdifferent from that of the swans. Theeye is pale and the legs are long andwell forward, features typical of whis-tling ducks. Especially significant isthe strongly mottled pattern of thedowny young which, again, is similarto downy whistling ducks. Downyyoung of true swans are all silverygray with no pattern. The Coscorobais a form unique unto itself but shouldnot be included with the true swans.In addition to the Mute Swan, thereare five species native to the northernhemisphere. These are the Tmmpeterand Whistling Swans of North America,and the Whooper, Bewick andJankowski swans of Eurasia. Collectively,these five are kno~n as thenorthern swans, and all are similar inappearance and habits. All are purewhite with black feet and bills. Again-the upper mandible extendsthrough the !ores area to the eye, and,exclusive of the Trumpeter, in whichthe !ores area is black, a bright yellowlares patch is characteristic.The extent of the yellow patch variesaccording to species. It is smallestin the Whistler or Tundra Swan andlargest is the Whooper. In the latterform, the yellow extends all the wayfrom the eyelids to well forward of thenostrils so that only about the fo1wardthird of the mandible is black.The Bewick (which incidentally ispronounced "buick") and the Jankowskihave a comparatively smallerarea of yellow than has the Whooper,but decidedly greater than that of theTundra Swan. The differences betweenthe Bewick and Jankowski areso slight that taxonomists now believethey may be a cline of a single species.The name Bewick should prevail.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/693</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 59-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/693/676</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
