<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4027</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">New Ideas about the Evolution of Avian Respiratory Systems</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sigmon, Daniel</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 2 (April/May 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.The unidirectional respiratory system of birds, with its non -expanding tubular lungs, highly distributed air sacks, activated by movement of the keel bone and ribs 1 has long been a marvel to those who were aware of it.Its radical difference from the tidal breathing of so many other animals is a marvel of evolution demonstrating that life exploits widely divergent solutions to the problem of moving oxygen around an organism. The avian system, massively more efficient than our own, was long thought to be an evolutionary adaptation to the needs of flight. Not only does it provide a high - powered boost to oxygen availability, but the air sacs (and hollow bones) create lots of low - density space inside of birds that make them dramatically lighter. More efficiency and lowerweight are the holy grail for airplane design and construction. So it is also for birds. But recent study has raised the possibility that, rather than flight, the respiratory system of birds (and other archosaurs) developed as a response to the severe low oxygenation events in the deep past of earth&amp;#x27;s history. 2 This solution, having given archosaurs an important edge in an oxygen - starved world, primed them to thrive when the oxygen levels rebounded and gave them the amazing option of flight.As I stated earlier, we humans, and other mammals carry within us one solution to a low-oxygen environment. The diaphragm and alveolar lungs. The diaphragm is a much more efficient mechanism than the rib breathing of reptiles and the alveoli add an extra springiness to the tissues that helps with exhale. This was definitely an improvement over the simpler septate lungs of lizards, which are simply small bags surrounded by blood vessels 3, but in the end, our lungs are still tidal mechanisms. That is, they respire by pulling air in and then pushing it back out in a one -to-one fashion. The airthat goes in, comes out with the next exhale, very much like the ocean comes in and goes out with the tide. The big disadvantage to a system like this is that the stale air that remains in the lung at the end of an exhale (there is always some air left behind, otherwise the lung collapses) is then mixed with the fresh new air diluting it a bit before it is processed into the bloodstream. The result is that some of the molecular space in the lung is always occupied by CO2.In birds, the mixing of stale air is never a problem because of the unique structure of the avian lung. The avian lung is a pass -through organ where air is blown over and through a tube lined with zillions of tiny folds that create an enormous surface area of highly vascular tissue through which oxygen can diffuse into the body. Whereas the lungs of other vertebrates do double duty as air handlers and gas exchangers, in birds, these two functions are separated. The keel bone provides the low New Ideas About the Evolution ofClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4027</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 2 (2024): Watchbird April/May 2024; 18-21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4027/3987</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
