<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2620</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-18T16:12:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">"The Thrill of Victory ... "</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reed, Nancy A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Showing a bird is a wonderful extension of just owning a bird. Showing your cockatiel(s) is the best way to judge, through comparison with other birds, just what you have achieved with your own. You can read every book and magazine, but you will never know where you stand until you see other birds ... the best.So you never attended a bird show?At least go to one! Okay, don't take a bird if you feel too new to the situation. (And I will bet you go home wishing you had shown your bird. You saw lots of birds you could have beaten! The very worst that can happen is that you lose to the tune of $1.00 entry fee per bird.) Regardless, you will meet some wonderful people, and will learn a lot!Years ago, cockatiels were grouped with lovebirds, parrots, conures, Australian parakeets, etc. into one overall hookbill division at shows ( comparing apples with oranges). In 1978, the National Cage Bird Show (NCBS) recognized the growing interest in cockatiels and gave the species its own division and prestigious Kellogg trophy. Entries have grown from 30 or 40 cockatiels to 100 or 200 at the NCBS.Each year, the National Cage Bird Show is held in a different area of the United States ( 1991 in Dearborn, Michigan, Nov. 14 - 16). There are many local and regional shows held by the American Cockatiel Society or the National Cockatiel Society that rival such NCBS entries. My point is that showing cockatiels has become "big time" in recent years.Bird shows are not like dog or horse shows where an experienced handler has an advantage over the novice, as he can cleverly hide faults or highlight good qualities in front of the judge. In bird shows, the birds alone are on display, and the judge has little idea which bird may belong to whom.Someone who has only one pet cockatiel need not feel he has no chance against a breeder who can pick and choose his best from many. Your tame cockatiel might automatically sit up there fearlessly on the perch where it can be seen. A breeder can take a 'wild" bird from his stock and, lacking a lot of work, the cockatiel may huddle in a corner of the cage and panic with the judge's every movement. A bird could be the "Secretariat" of aviculture, but unless he struts his stuff, how will the judge ever know? A breeder must all but finger-tame his birds if they are to exhibit the goals he has reached through his breeding.In other words, one's success in breeding does not necessarily mean success in showing. It takes a lot of work to consistently show successfully.ACS and NCS encourage novice exhibitors to show. Each cockatiel division is now subdivided into novice and advanced exhibitors (newcomers need not feel intimidated by initially competing with the "pros"). The best novice birds are eventually put against the advanced winners. But read my lips. It is not uncommon for novice exhibitors to beat the pants off the "pros"!The novice and advanced cockatiel division is each divided into sections:Normals (greys), Pieds, Lutinos, Pearls, Cinnamons, and rare varieties (Whitefaces, Albinos, Silvers, Fallows). Included in these sections are separate classes for splits and crossmutations. ("Splits" in show classifications refer to birds that harbor the gene for Pied and manifest it by a patch of yellow or white feathers usually on the nape of the neck. "Cross-mutations" are birds that visually show two or more mutational colors/markings, for instance: Lutinopearl, Cinnamon-pied, Whitefacepied-pearl, etc.)Each class is subdivided into cocks and hens, young and old (four subclasses). Young cocks and hens must be banded (proof of age). Birds not hatched in the present year or without bands are entered in the "old" cocks and hens classes.Judging begins at the class level with ribbons for first, second, third, and sometimes fourth places. The resulting placements in each class are then regrouped before the judge to be awarded first, second, third, and fourth best in section. Eventually, section winners are again placed on the show bench for the best in cockatiel division judging. Depending on the number of entries, winners can place from first through tenth "Best in Show'.'Realize that a judge can decide that a bird that placed second or third in one class (or section) is better than a first-placed bird of another class (or section). A given class or section may be very strong in quality. It is not uncommon that a bird that won in its section does not even place on the "top ten" divison bench due to superior competition from other sections.I hope I have not totally confused you! Judging procedures are complex if you don't know the system. You will enjoy a show much more if you know what is going on, and can follow the routine. Don't be afraid to ask questions at a show. Bird people love to help fledglings!Bird magazines carry announcements of the upcoming shows. Send for a show catalog from the show or club secretary. Attending shows, talking to exhibitors, and visiting ( or corresponding) with breeders will develop your eye for quality. The more birds you see, the better you can judge your own.Shows run anywhere from one day's duration to three or four days, as with the National Cage Bird Show and the Kaytee Great American Bird Show. If there is a lengthy trip involved, it may be best to arrive the day before, as judging usually starts early in the morning.Early Preparation for Showing About two months before show time, you must finally decide which birds are best and will be ready in time. Disqualify birds that have not at least started to molt; chances are by show time they will either sport half-grown flight feathers or may be missing them completely.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2620</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 1 (1991): FEB-MAR 1991; 27-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2620/2590</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
