<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/557</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-10-21T04:01:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Venezuelan Black-hooded Red Siskin a success story from Las Palmas, Canary Islands</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abbate, G. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Venezuelan Black-hooded Red Siskin has been in demand for more than half a century, perhaps even more so today than when it was crossed with a canary to produce a red factor canary. Furthermore, every red factor color breeder throughout the entire world has or would like to have one or more Venezuelan Blackhooded Red Siskins . In fact, the demand for this species is greater than any other species of birds amongst color breeders. During my extensive travels throughout the world where I visited hundreds of bird fanciers including color breeders, I noticed that every color breeder I visited either had some Venezuelan Black-hooded Red Siskins or they were inquiring as to where and how they could acquire some. Recalling from memory, many years ago I visited a highly reputable and successful red factor breeder in Argentina (I still remember his name, Mr. Iannuzzelli). I also wrote an article detailing that visit. The first thing that he asked me when I entered his birdroom was, ''I would love to get a Red Siskin .... even a first or second cross would help me. I heard that in America many of these birds are plentiful. Can you help me?" My answer to him was, '' Mr. Iannuzzelli, you have such good deep red factor canaries- why would you want a Red Siskin to improve the color of them?" He answered, " I was told if I introduced a Red Siskin into my red factor canaries' blood line I would get a deeper and better red color." If I remember correctly, I told Mr. Iannuzzelli, "I don't think that the Red Siskin would in any way improve your red canaries. It would probably take many many years and I doubt very much if you would achieve any better results." Nevertheless, the Red Siskin is still in great demand today.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/557</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 3 (1992): JUNE-JULY 1992; 59-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/557/541</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
