<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4114</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:18:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Tributes to Dr. Janice Boyd</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aviculture, American Federation of</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 4 (October/November 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Aviculture Loses a Longtime Supporter In MemoriamDr. Janice Boyd passed away on October 27, 2022, after a brief illness. Below are some tributes acknowledging her contributions to aviculture and conservation.Bailey Payne, Texas A&amp;amp;M Foundation Dr. Janice Boyd was four years old when her family moved to Los Alamos, New Mexico, in 1950. While her father worked in the famous Los Alamos National Laboratory, she found her love for nature and wildlife in the foothills of the Rocky Mountains. Years later, she enrolled as an undergrad at the University of Michigan studying physics and mathematics. She wasn’t sure what to do immediately after graduation, so she took a programming job working under Dr. Carl Wunsch, a prominent oceanographer at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. She earned her Ph.D. in oceanography at Texas A&amp;amp;M in 1986 and held a 20-year position at the Naval Research Laboratory in Mississippi. The job was good, but as the years went by, Boyd found herself ready for something new.Dr. Janice Boyd with one of her great green macawsAround the same time, she adopted her first pet parrots. Soon after, she left her federal job behind for a part -time position that would allow her to visit parrot conservation areas in Central and South America. One of those areas was the Tambopata Research Center in Peru, where she first met Dr. Donald “Don” Brightsmith, who would become a long-time colleague, in the early 2000s. Boyd eagerly collaborated with Brightsmith on a few research projects, including a multiyear study that used tracking collars to monitor wild parrots’ migration patterns. “She’s tenacious,” Brightsmith said of Boyd. “Once she gets on a project, she keeps working on it and makes sure that collaborators stay on track until it’s done.”Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4114</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 4 (2022): Watchbird October/November 2022; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4114/4074</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
