<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3081</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-18T08:43:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">World Pheasant Convention</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The World Pheasant Association held its first annual convention in England and France, September 24-25, 1977. The conference drew over three hundred members and guests from seventeen countries including nearlyforty from the U.S.The first day's activities featured lectures, tour of the pheasant collection of Mr. and Mrs. Keith Howman, banquet, address, and auction.On the dais were Mr. Charles Sivelle, president of the American Pheasant and Waterfowl Society, lecturing on Tragopan Pheasants; Dr. Jesus Estudillo Lopez of Mexico City lecturing on the Cracids; and Mr. Richard Bloom of Australia lecturing on the latest developments in new products. Mr. Bloom is the owner of a large veterinary supply house in Australia.Reports on several WP A supported research projects were also presented. Mr. Mirza, WP A project director in Pakistan described the progress WP A was making in the captive propagation and release of native Pakistani species of pheasants. WP A funds have provided the facilities and manpower for this project, with many of the eggs used in incubation being provided by WP A members around the world.Dr. Peter Severinghaus of Cornell University discussed his two year survey of the wild populations of Edward's and Swinhoe Pheasants in Taiwan. Dr. Severinghaus concluded that the Edward's Pheasant is not endangered in the wild It has adapted very well to the disturbed environment created by civilization and appears to have a secure future. The Swinhoe pheasant also was found to exist in far larger numbers than anticipated and is not currently threatened, though it is not in as favorable a condition as the Edward's.The WPA project on artificial insemination in the Brown-Eared Pheasant was reported on by D.D. Wise, DVM, of England. This project attempted to determine the feasibility of artificially inseminating Brown-Eareds as they have had a notorious history of infertility. His work indicated that the Brown-Eared is not infertile. Rather the males simply show little interest in mating.On the morning of the second day, approximately one third of the group departed by air for France to visit Chateau Cleres, home of Dr. Jean Delacour, WPA President. The activities included the celebration of Dr. Delacour's 87th birthday over a sumptious lunch capped with a large birthday cake. After lunch the WP A contingent was invited to tour the magnificent grounds and bird collection.The WP A conference was preceded by a four day tour of large collections in England. Highlights were the pheasants at Daws Hall, Christopher Marler's Flamingo Gardens, Pheasant Trust, Bill Makin's waterfowl collection, Len Hill's Birdland, and the staggering collection of waterfowl at the Wildfowl Trust at Slimbridge.The post convention tour featured collections in France, Belgium, Holland, and Germany, where the curtain was finally dropped at the Birdpark at Walsrode near Hannover. Walsrode is notable in that it features over 1200 different species - all housed under spacious, immaculate conditions.The WPA, thanks to its energetic and gracious Secretary Didy Grahame, put on a splendid once in a lifetime event. The WP A and its enthusiastic officers and members have made remarkable progress in its first two years of existence and some very significant contributions to aviculture.Succeeding issues of the Watchbird will feature articles on the collections visited during the WP A activities. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3081</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 5 (1977): OCT- NOV 1977; 20-21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3081/3065</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
