<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/992</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">It Seems to Me ...</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I hope you noticed that this issue is focusing more on the birds of Asia. Not all of the Asian birds, of course, there are far too many species to touch in just one issue--or even two.But because so many of you are interested in parrots, I call your attention to the two articles on the Red and Blue Lory and the two articles on the Orange-breasted Fig Parrot. These are birds rarely if ever seen in the States and I'm sure you caught the fact that both authors are situated in or near Asia.Pruitt writes on another fig parrot that is rare but at least alive and doing fairly well here in the U.S.A.-the Edwards's (yes, Edwards's with all those s's at the end) Fig Parrot, an extremely beautiful little bird. You'll learn a lot from his writing.Another article that will turn the light on in your oft bewildered brain is the one by Perry wherein he really shows us how to tell Plum-headed Parakeets from Blossom-headed or Slaty-headed. And he's talking about the females. I know several oldtimers who can't tell the males apart, much less the females. You'll bless Perry's clever old head for sharing his simple, foolproof method with us.This issue has a good variety of material. You'll love the interview with Mike Fidler. I liked his tales about field work in southeast Asia, partly, I suppose, because I've done a good bit of traveling there and his stories hit home.The 1996 AFA Convention, to be held in Concord (of which San Francisco is a suburb), will feature an "Asian Birds" theme. The articles in this issue are the first pointers to the con- vention and an alert, if you will, to the wonders of Asian birds.Knowing all this beforehand, and being the dedicated, humble editor that I am (nothing is too good for our readers). I deemed it expedient to venture into the wilds of southeast Asia myself in hopes of getting some good photos and articles for yourenjoyment. (Someone has to do it).I went first to the Philippines where I have many friends and some family and where one of the world's best bird farms is. Naturally, while I was on Luzon. I took the opportunity to visit Antonio deDios again and enjoy his extraordinary bird farm. The next issue of Watchbird will carry a detailed article on the operation, with plenty of photos. The place wobbles the mind.To see the Philippine Eagle Foundation's captive breeding facilities, I went down to Davao on the island of Mindanao, ducked the ongoing civil war and had a wonderful visit with Dr. Roberto "Bopeep" Puentespina, the veterinarian who watches after the captive eagles, and the Deputy Director for Captive Breeding, Domingo 0. Tadena. Wonderful fellows these, and fanatically dedicated to the recovery of the very endangered Philippine Eagle-there are only four known productive nests in the wild. In an upcoming Watchhird you'll get some remarkable stories about this operation.It seemed the right thing to do so I went to Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia to see the birds and wound up, via a cross country venture, in Singapore. This was a mistake as I was headed for Kuching, Borneo, hut I made the best of it and spent an exciting day at Jurong Bird Park. Believe me, gentle reader, this is a Bird Park of the first order. It deserves three or four days of intense bird watching. It is huge. Many of the birds have no idea they are in enclosures. More on this later. I left Singapore hastily, just ahead of the big guy with the cane.All in all, I had a very good trip, with just the right amount of diversion, and without getting caught hy bolo wielding rebels or Singapore cane masters. The mosquitoes gnawed on me a lot (hungry for American food, I suppose) hut I think I avoided malaria this time. The bottom line is that I got a lot of photos and material for Asian bird articles, and all for the benefit of vou.- It seems to me that, for once, CFO Hawley shouldn't have his usual heart attack when I submit the expenses.On another subject, I believe you'll find the opinion pages very interesting this issue. We are finally coming to grips with the concept of conservation biology and the field biologists who conduct it. And, I might add, how it may or may not relate to aviculture. I have a very good feeling about this subject as I hold a lot of hope that aviculturists and conservation biologists are about to stop and listen to one another and hold to the common causes. We'll see.Thanks for being there, and enioy. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/992</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 1 (1996): JAN-FEB 1996; 45-51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/992/972</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
