<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3448</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-01T00:58:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the marvelous Mini-Macaws</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worth, Gail J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Are you enchanted by macaws but can't have the loud noise or provide large breeding aviaries?If so, the marvelous mini-macaws might be just right! These little charmers are increasing in popularity due to their moderate size, impish and precocious personalities, moderate prices, hardiness, and readiness to breed in captivity. Although the minis don't have the flashy colors of the larger macaws, they possess a charm of their own and have many wonderful characteristics to recommend them both as breeding stock and as pets.For the purposes of this article, we will consider any macaw species that averages 50cm (20 inches) or less to be a mini macaw. This would exclude the Spix Macaw (Cyanopsitta spixii) which measures 55cm, but includes the Red-Bellied Macaw (Ara manilata) which measures 50cm. Therefore, the other five species of minis are the Severe (Ara severa) at 46cm, the llliger's (Ara maracana) at 43cm, the BlueHeaded (Ara couloni) at 41 cm, the Yellow-collared (Ara auricollis) at 38cm, and the Red-Shouldered (Ara nobilis) and subspecies (Ara nobilis cuamensis) at 30cm for a total of six species plus one subspecies. Thus all minis are from the Ara genus which is the same genus as the Scarlet (Ara macao) and the Blue &amp;amp; Gold (Ara ararauna) Macaws.All of the mini macaws are native to South America except for the Severe Macaw which can be found in a small area of Panama. The natural range of these species and population density in the range are factors in the relative availability or scarcity in captivity of the species.Red-Bellied MacawThis macaw is physically distinguished by a large maroon splotch on the lower abdomen. Notable also is the dull yellowish color of the bare skin area of the face. Although the natural range of this species is quite extensive and it is apparently numerous within its range, this macaw is not common in captivity.It occurs in most of north-eastern South America including the island of Trinidad, the Guianas (Guyana, Suriname, and La Guyane), Venezuela, and parts of Colombia, Peru, and Brazil. The only country to export it in recent years is Guyana. As an imported bird, the Red-Bellied is nervous and delicate and has not adapted well to captive conditions. Although some breeding successes have been recorded, this species is far from being established in captivity. Thus this is a very worthwhile species with which to work. Hopefully, the domestic-raised offspring will prove hardier than their wild-caught parent stock and will be more prolific breeders. Although it is reported that the hand-fed babies make delightful pets, it is imperative that these domestic birds be sexed and paired for breeding and, in my opinion, should not be sold as pets in the foreseeable future.Severe MacawAlso known as the Chestnut-fronted Macaw, this attractive macaw is generally green with a chestnutbrown forehead and a blue crown. This species is native to eastern Panama through the Guianas and northern Bolivia ana part or tsraz11. 1 ne ~evere was exported from Bolivia for many years and more recently from Guyana. A large number of wild-caught pairs are breeding in captivity and the species is prolific. This macaw is well-established in captivity and many are sold each year as handfed pets. The only drawback to this species is that it has a loud voice compared to most of the other minis.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-01-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3448</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 33 No. 1 (2006): Number 1  2006; 52-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3448/3432</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
