<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4122</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:18:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Hurricane Ian Strikes a Blow to Florida</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Fred</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 4 (October/November 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.How could it be? We Floridians thought we had already seen the worst hurricane but now Ian shows up. As every bird owner was preparing for a hurricane in the Tampa Bay area and further north, Hurricane Ian decided to play a “Charlie” on us and turn at Port Charlotte and destroy Ft. Meyer’s Beach. No matter how prepared you think you are, a hurricane of this size causes massive destruction of all sorts.I think of Dick Muench, who, with his helpers, collected their vast collection of exotic birds and animals from his Periwinkle Park in Sanibel Island and secured them in buildings built to withstand an 11 foot water surge only to have 13 foot waves come in, causing him to lose all of his birds and animals. We try so hard to make sure we’re prepared and have buildings secured to save our birds and yet a hurricane such as Ian comes in to destroy everything. John Meade had built an 80 foot Macaw building years ago to withstand high winds but even it could not withstand the winds of Ian. Fortunately, while the building was destroyed, the birds were all safe.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4122</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 4 (2022): Watchbird October/November 2022; 25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4122/4082</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
