<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/856</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:17:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Handrearing Parrots: Theory and Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jordan, Rick</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It is difficult to sit down and write a comprehensive article on handrearing parrot chicks. One of the biggest problems is the fact that there are so many exceptions to the rules and so many variables that would apply. It might make more sense to write a series of articles dealing with each and every variable as a separate subject. When all of this information is put together into one journal it would serve as a guide to handrearing.Theoretically, handrearing could be an easy task. The keeper need only fill the crop with nutritious food each time it is empty and in a few short weeks, the check would be ready for the weaning process. This is, of course, assuming that the temperature of the brooder was right, the check never became ill during the feeding process, and the food was correct both in temperature and in nutrition. In many cases, this ideal situation is a reality. However, there are times when things do not go according to plan and the entire protocol must be changed.Let's look at the ideal situation as a place to start. An egg in the incubator has pipped and will hatch in the next two days. Now is the time to get supplies ready for the task of handfeeding. A brooder or incubator will be needed to supply heat for the chick. Syringes, feeding tubes, gavage needles or a spoon will suffice as a feeding instrument and some type of handfeeding formula should be on hand. When researching the proper food to feed, always consult with an experienced breeder who has successfully reared the species in question. Most of the powdered instant formulas available today have evolved into good products and can be used on a variety of different species.Once the chick has hatched, it must be kept at a temperature of about 95-97° F for the first week to 10 days. When chicks are very young they do not have the ability to regulate their own bodytemperature and need the addition of heat if they are to survive. Some breeders use an aquarium and a heating pad to provide this heat. My only caution is that most heating pads are not very stable and may get very hot at times. If this pad is against the glass bottom of the aquar - ium, the glass often gets hot enough to scorch the skin of the chicks. It is often better to invest in a brooder made especially for brooding young parrot chicks. They are not as expensive as they used to be and are a lot more predictable than heating pads or light bulbs.A stable environment is very important for the growing chick. If the temperature is allowed to get too hot, the chick may not grow properly. Similarly, of the chick gets too cold, digestion may cease or slow and once again, growth and weight gains will not be normal. To a certain extent, extreme temperature variations can cause illness in the chick. If bacteria are present in the chick, and it is chilled or over heated, the immune system may allow an over growth of this bacteria and the chick will become ill. The first sign of illness is usually "crop stasis" or a slowing or stoppage of the crop motility.The day old chick requires some special treatment. When it is newly hatched, the chick will have a very small crop capacity. As the chick grows, this crop will also grow and the requirement to feed will become less frequent. The first few feeds should be of a very liquid consistency, almost as thin as milk. Feeding thin formula for a few days or a week is wise as it helps the chick to hydrate its body and to get all the organ systems functioning correctly. If formula is fed too thick, it may remain in the crop and the chick could become ill as bacteria establish themselves in the undigested food.The first two weeks oflife are a very labor intensive time for the handfeeder. Many chicks require feeding about every two hours around the clock. In the beginning, some may even empty the crop in an hour or less. Whenever the crop has emptied, it is time to feed again. The more food that passes through the chick's system, the faster it will grow and the easier the rearing process will become. Slowly thicken the formula to the consistency recommended by the manufacturer. If digestion stops, or slows drastically, add a little water to the next feed to assist in digestion until the bird's system can accommodate the new consistency.Although not absolutely necessary, weight data is helpful to monitor the chick's progress. A postal scales can be purchased and the chicks can be weighed each morning to see if they are growing. Generally, chicks should gain weight each and every day during the growing phase. Very small chicks will only gain very small amounts of weight. Do not expect a 10 gram chick to gain 5 or 10 grams each day. If a weight gain is noticed at all, the chick is growing and is probably healthy. At no time should a weight loss be considered normal. If chicks lose weight they are not receiving enough food or are not being fed often enough. Increase the amount and/orthe frequency of feeding. If this does not correct the problem, the formula itself may be in question. Make sure the formula is being made according to the manufacturer's suggestions.Each day, try to increase the amount of food that is being fed to the chick. These increases will not be large amounts. The crop can only take so much food before the formula will spill over into the mouth and possibly cause choking to occur. Always observe the chick after it has been fed. It should resume normal vocalizations within a minute of being fed. If it is having difficulty in breathing or vocalizing, the crop may have been over-filled. Do not be fooled by the chick's solicitation for food. They will continue to solicit more food even when dangerously full. This is a natural mechanism that helps the chick to survive in the nest. Ifthe crop appears to be full and tight, do not feed more food until it has had time to empty.As the chick grows, the crop capacity will grow. After the first week or two, the chick's crop will hold enough food to maintain it for several hours. This means that the crop will not be completely empty for about three to four hours.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/856</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 1 (1995): JAN-FEB 1995; 22-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/856/838</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
