<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/667</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-19T21:57:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Keeping and Breeding the Lilac-breasted Roller</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sweeney, Roger G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As the movement of birds betweendifferent countries becomes increasinglyrestricted, one avicultural groupthat will become increasingly moredifficult to maintain in aviculture willbe softbills. Already, as the number ofspecies imported into the UnitedKingdom (U.K.) has dwindled, a harshspotlight is being cast on some speciesas to whether or not they can be realisticallysustained as a captive populationin future years. This situation hasseen many formerly common speciesbecome scarce and by comparisonsome formerly rare species, with theaid of concentrated avicultural attention,becoming well established. Onespecies which has managed to establishitself in U.K. aviculture duringrecent years is the Lilac-breastedRoller (Coracias caudata).I have long rated birds of the genusCoracias among my personal favorites.Birdworld Bird Park in Farnham,England, currently maintains threespecies from this genus. Out of these itis the Lilac-breasted Roller which wasthe first to breed and has proved to bethe most productive species, the othertwo species which are the European(C. garralus) and the Racquet-tailed(C.spatulata) have not, to date,matched the level of successful breedingthat has been achieved with theformer.The stout, prominent physical postureof rollers make them impressiveaviary birds. Measuring up to 30 em(11-1/ 2 inches) in overall length,they have a stocky, rounded bodywith short, broad wings and tail. Thehead is pronounced as with all theCoraciformes. This bold stature of thebird is enhanced by their preferencefor roosting in a high, prominent position.In the wild they can frequentlybe seen sitting on top of telegraphpoles and are visible from some distance.In captivity a high central perchwill soon be adopted as the regularperching position within an aviary.The call consists of a short series ofchattering notes.In coloration, the Lilac-breasted Rollershares the usual color scheme ofother Coracias species. Various pastelshades of brown, beige and whitecombine over the head and down theback which contrast strikingly againstthe varying shades of light to royalblue which cover much of the wingsand under body in a typical Coraciaspattern. The Lilac-breasted Roller, asits common name suggests, standseasily distinguishable from its closerelatives because of the rich lilac bandacross the lower neck and chest.Fledging birds have exactly the sameplumage patterns as their parents as soon as they leave the nest, althoughthe coloration could be described asbeing softer and not quite as intensein its brightness. The bird in theaccompanying photograph wasamong the first Lilac-breasted Rollersto be reared at Birdworld and is photographedhere at five months of age.The wild distribution of this birdcovers Somalia and Ethiopia througheast and central Africa. Although sporadicallyavailable throughout aviculturalhistory, the Lilac-breasted Rollerhas never been considered to be"commonly kept" and has onlyrecently begun to be consistently bredin reasonable numbers.The husbandry requirements of Coraciasrollers are easily met. Accommodation,in the form of a largeplanted aviary will suit them. In Englandand other temperate countries ofthe world, the additional need of aheated shelter for the winter periodwill be required. Although rollers aregenerally hardy they are particularlyprone to suffering from foot problemsduring periods of cold weatl1er. Highaviaries are much preferred by rollerswho seem to enjoy perching in aprominent position, but only if this isavailable well above human headheight. Aviaries which allow for thenest box to be situated in a high positionalso seem to prove to be muchmore successful. The diet at Birdworldfor rollers consists of equal parts offruit and a meat mix. The fruit segmentof the diet is made up from avariety of seasonally available fruits.The meat mix contains minced oxheart, soaked S.D.S. Zoo pellets and acommercial insectivorous mix. Livefood is supplied daily in the form ofmealworms fed on the main dish andalso locusts and crickets being fed adlib during the summer. If wild-caughtbirds are ever worked with then theregular feeding of a variety of livefoods does, of course, become....</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/667</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 38-41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/667/650</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
