<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2977</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-15T08:02:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Cockatiel</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reed, Nancy A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">General DescriptionNymphicus hollandicus, is lone member of its genus as well as the subfamily Nymphicinae, and one of the smallest Cockatoos in the family Cactuidae, order Psittaciformes, class Aves. Pretty fancy nomenclature for this rather small and somber feathered bird from Australia! In their native land one would be more apt to hear the name "Quarrion" or "Cockatoo Parrot" in reference to this bird we call the "Cockatiel " (our name coming from the Portuguese word "cacatelho" meaning little Cockatoo). In short, a very popular cage-bird by any name!Bearing the more streamlined body and long tail typical of the Australian parakeets, yet having the erectile crest of the Cockatoos, he is considered a possible link between these two families of parrots.On his native continent he inhabits the open country of Australia 's interior; ground feeding on seeding grasses, herbaceous plants and fruits; and congregating near water. Nomadic in habit, flocks will follow the rainfall, which, when most plentiful in the spring (September through December), initiates their breeding season and assures a plentiful supply of food for their young nesting in the hollows of trunks and limbs of trees. A curious trait is observed in the wild as they avoid alighting on live foliaged branches, preferring dead limbs where, as often as not, they perch lengthwise on the branch rather than in typical bird fashion of crosswise to it. I have observed my own birds occasionally taking this characteristic position on the larger perches in their flights.The Cockatiels we see today have all been cage-bred. Many generations have come and gone since their original ancestors were captured from the wild and exported to foreign continents. Jn 1939 Australia put a ban on any further export of their native birds. Had the Cockatiel not proven to be such an eager and generous breeder, fewer people could today have the pleasure of their company.I find it truly descriptive when someone had the imagination to give the Cockatiel its last name "hollandicus ". A Cockie with his bright orange cheek patches does, in fact, look like a Dutch doll whose porcelain cheeks display identical markings. However, a verbal description of any bird is second-rate to a good picture, so I shall be brief, preferring that you .. see" for yourself.The total bird is approximately I I to 13 inches in length, his tapering tail comprising almost half of that measure. His characteristic crest can be raised and lowered at will. His feet are typical of all parrots, having two toes forward, and two back, designed for climbing and grasping. Form follows function also in his hooked bill which is strong and pointed for cracking hard seed coverings (and biting fingers in defense).The original wild Cockariels , what we call "Normals," show sexual dimorphic markings on adult birds, i.e .. males and females sport different colorations. Note the duller cheek patches of the female. lack of yellow mask, and the black-barred yellow lateral tail feathers. The depth of grey varies in individuals. Some approach almost black. which has caused a few breeders to believe they have a new "black" mutation. These birds are only extremes of the original grey. This makes a very striking and handsome bird in contrast with the yellow. white. and orange accents.Although the predominantly grey plumage of the .. Normal" Cockatiel is hardly competition to more colorful. and some downright gaudy parrots. his endearing personality and prolific ways have caused extensive breeding of this species, which in tum has triggered mutations. These mutations have been a boon in increasing even further the popluarity of the Cockatiel - voila, some fancier clother to match his super personality.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2977</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 5 (1978): OCT- NOV 1978; 6-9</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2977/2961</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
