<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2330</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-08T18:07:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dear Sheldon:A responsible competent importer/ distributor uses the quarantine period to free the birds of parasites, bacterias or other insults the birds may have. He should determine if there is a virus at work. He should not sell birds at any price unless and until he knows those birds are strong, clean and healthy. Anyone who sells birds for a living has the tools available to determine if the birds are clean. We can think of no justifiable, moral reason why dealers, at whatever level in the sales chain, choose to unload birds on their customers with no regrets.There will always be a percentage of birds that honestly slip through with undetected problems, but to not address and acknowledge those problems is unconscionable both from the moral and economic aspects.Unfortunately, as long as price is the sole determinant with so many people, this sorry state of affairs will continue for another long time. The recipients of diseased birds can only protect themselves by quarantining new purchases, separately, for a long enough time, properly diagnose the problem and then treat.Quarantine birds should be separated by continents of origin. Pachecos, for instance, is not indiginous to Asia or Africa. (Why do you suppose cockatoos and grays die from Pachecos?) Everyone should have a facility such that this separation is possible. Otherwise, it's simply a matter of time before your number is up and your wipe out is complete.We understand that city real estate is expensive and space is hard to find. We understand how nice and convenient it is to have a large selection at one place. We also understand your needs. However, birds are not hard goods. They need special care and consideration. Most of all - time. Time to be acclimated, checked, "cleaned" if necessary. The fast buck is soon lost. The quick sale you made just died. Your reputation is shot, or if you have the integrity, you replace your customer's loss. Youloseeveryway.SLOWDOWN.It's always the same. An importer "sells" Pachecos, a smuggler "sells" New castle. A dealer passes it all on.Anyone who sells a bad bird after receiving a ''bad'' bird is just as ''bad'' as the person who originally sold it or is just plain ignorant of what it takes to care for birds.If everyone in the business took the time and expense necessary to assure the health of the birds we wouldn't be hearing of all the tragedies year in and year out.It all comes down to greed. If we could do something about illegal birds ... but then that's another subject.Ron LeclairFt. Pierce, Florida Several years ago you published a letter stating that research was being done on the claim that sunflower seed contained a narcotic and was bad for birds. I have never seen this subject referred to again. Can you tell me if there is any research to substantiate or repudiate the claim that safflower seed is wonderful and sunflower seed is very bad for birds?P.A. Myers Although several studies were conducted, I know of no results that condemn sunflower seed. The specific ingredient papaoarin that was said to be in sunflower has never been found despite some valiant efforts to isolate it.For me there is no sunflower-safflower conflict. Both seeds are in my own parrot mix and my wife feeds so sparingly that the birds eat everything they are fed. They are happy, healthy and produce absolutely normal numbers of young.Ed. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2330</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 3 (1985): JUNE-JULY 1985; 40-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2330/2303</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
