<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3093</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T03:17:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Psittacosis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Witt, Clifton R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">At the time of this writing there is an outbreak of psittacosis in the state of Maryland. It was first diagnosed in a Lutino Cockatiel last August and now, in the late Fall, the state department of Public Health is in the process of tracking down perhaps as many as 2000 birds which they will quarantine and treat. The majority of these birds were sold as pets and are now in private homes, so you can see the enormity of the task at hand.This incident points up the need for several things that we as aviculturists should consider. This is not an unusual situation, unfortunately. Psittacosis is being brought to you by the same people who gave you Newcastle - the smugglers. (Remember the tipster's Hotline (301) 436,8061.) Also' we know that psittacosis is coming out of the quarantine stations rather frequently. The responsible quarantine station, upon discovering psittacosis in the station, will hold those birds beyond the required 30 days and continue medicating another 15 days. In these days of Quarantine Station Population Explosion however (up to 48 now) there are stations that, out of necessity or neglect, will ship birds with psittacosis.AF A members can now play an important role in advising state officials on how to treat the birds since these officials usually are not familiar with cage or exotic birds and would prefer to destroy them or prohibit them just to get them out of their bureaucratic hair. Until we as an industry, a community, a consumer group, or whatever we call ourselves work out ways to eliminate or control diseases like ornithosis (psittacosis), we are likely to be called upon to play the role of public relations experts to smooth the feathers of indignant public officials.One of the things that we have and they want is information about birds. To that end I have provided, below, information on how to treat for ornithosis, where to get the medicine, and how to administer it to the birds. Keep it handy because it is very likely you're going to need it.First of all, if the birds will eat Keet Life, a Hartz Mountain product, use it. It's a clean, easy way of treatment that is effective. One AFA member and quarantine station owner reports that he has used Keet Life successfully on birds as large as Rosellas on down to the small psittacines. Even Half Moons have been fed exclusively on Keet Life for 45 days. Larger psittacines, soft bills, and perhaps finches and. canaries (if they won't eat the Keet Life) have to be treated as described below.The following information has been provided by Dr. A. Louis Shor, D.V M., Manager, Poultry Program for American Cyanamid Company, the manufacturer of the medication commonly used by quarantine stations. Dr. Shor, in his cover letter, indicates that Mr. Spencer Carter of American Cyanamid can help in locating the product in your area. He can be reached at (609) 799-0400 in Princeton, NJ. Dr. Shor's instructions are here presented in their entirety....</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3093</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 6 (1977): DEC 1977- JAN 1978; 24-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3093/3077</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
