<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/688</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Catching Escaped Pet Birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cabral, Denise</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">My name is Denise Cabral. I am ~urrentlyPresident of the Boston So_c1etyfor A viculture and Northeast Reg1onalVice President for AF A. Today I willbe telling you about catching escapedbirds including how I got into this,prev~nting most escapes, my criteriafor response, my most successfulmethods, and why I bother.I got into recapturing pet birds during1987, when in the course ofanswering telephone calls referred bythe Massachusetts Audubon Society'stoll-free environmental help line, Ifound I was fielding about 30 calls ayear about escaped cage birds of c:&amp;gt;netype or other. People were callmgAudubon because, after all, they"know about birds". In fact, Audubonis not interested in providing informationabout pet birds, and so begansending callers to the officers of theBoston Society for A viculture.As a new mom, I had a fair amountof time on my hands, and I beganusing my background as both a wildlifebiologist and a bird breeder toinvestigate the situation and developways to recapture non-native escapees.My first successful recapt~1reswere in the fall of 1987, and smcethen, I've personally caught three tofive birds a year, and assisted ownersin 15 to 20 recoveries.How do accidental escapes happen?There are people sitting here whowalk outside with their beloved petson their shoulders, mistakenly surethat their darling will never leavethem. Well, maybe so, but my phonerings many times every year withsomeone in tears on the other end,because of a stray dog or cat, anengine backfire, a horn honking, afirecracker, or a gust of wind. If /had apet I treasured that much, it would bealways wing clipped, and eventhen I'd be super cautious about takingit outside without a cage or carrieraround it. Two feathers and a goodgust of wind is all it takes some birdsto fly off. Until you can fly, don't tak~your bird outside. My guys get the1rsunbaths in secure cages, thank you.There are, of course, many forms oftrue accidents, like windows fallingout things breaking, etc., but there areals~ a lot of "careless accidents", too, like forgetting your pet is on yourshoulder and walking outside, leavingyour pet out of its cage unsupervisedand it chews through a windowscreen,opening the door for ten l~inuteswhile you bring in the grocenes,or putting the bird out for some sun ina cage that isn't wired together ev~rywhere.As I've said, check those wmgclips! If your pet escapes, don'tgive up. Stay with your bird as long asyou can, and use the methods I'lldescribe.As I developed strategies to help lostbirds, I had to develop criteria for thelevel of my personal response. As Ispeak with a caller, I ask them if thebird is theirs. I rarely respond personallyto a location where an owner h~slost their own bird, because theuchance of recapturing it is far greaterthan mine, even with my tricks. Thebird knows them, and they live there,not miles away like I do. In caseswhere a caller has a "parrot" in theiryard, I ask if they have a bird feeder(full of sunflower), try to get a roughidentific-ation of the birds, ask howlong the bird has been comingaround, and generally determine thewillingness of the caller to help. If thebird is a parakeet, lovebird, cockatiel,or obviously competent conure, mychances of recapturing it are laughable,so I suggest a few easy to dothings to the caller and express mywillingness to talk again. In caseswhere the bird is larger, tame, relativelyapproachable, or returns to thearea very regularly, I may be able torecapture the bird if the caller isn'tinterested in trying to. I will usuallymake one fully-equipped visit to thelocation to ID the bird and try to trapit. I must caution anyone who wantsto try to trap lost or loose birds thatyou really need to screen out birdsand callers that you can't help, andthat you either need to charge a smallfee to cover your expenses, or youneed to get gas money from one ofyour local bird clubs. This can_bean expensive and time-consummgproject!So how do I help owners get theirbeloved pets down from 60 feet up?First, I find out what kind of bird it is, and if they can still see it. Again, smallguys are harder to get back, and bigones are easier. If the bird is still insight, I tell the owner to rush back outto it and keep calling it, until a helpercan come back with a picnid It maysound silly, but sitting down in a comfortablechair with a table full of yourpet's favorite people food, that. helikes to share with you, and eatmgright under his nose has proven to benearly irresistible to escaped parrots.Almost every one of the tame parrotsI've helped owners recover has beencaught this way. The keys are that t~ebird's favorite person has to stay Withit, and that person has to eat in front ofit if the bird won't or can't seem tocome down. You have to keep callingthem, and showing them the food,and eating it. Having the bird's owncage and its mate or other bird companionoutside, in a secured cage, ofcourse, may also help. The picnicmethod may also work for tame birdsthat have left their home area. If theowner is calling me days or weeksafter the escape and the bird isn't insight, things are trickier. I first suggestthat they plan to spend the next morningcruising around the area at5:00 a.m. with the windows rolleddown, listening for their bird. As partof their preparation for this, I suggestcalling the police, if they haven'talready, with a description of them,their car and license plate number,their bird and its value, and whenthey'll be driving around. I also suggestputting up 8 1/2 x 11 flyers allover the place, saying "LOST PARROT",giving a general description,their phone number, and offering areward (don't specify how much).Lost ads in the local paper, with thesame format, .are also a good idea.Sometimes adding a sob story to theflyer or ad is a good idea, becausethere are people who will catch birdsand refuse to give them back, because"you must have been an awful personto lose such a wonderful bird". It'speople like this that make me wish ~eall kept photos, audio-tapes and wnttenrecords of our pets, and that wewere all careful to record what theysay, little behavior quirks, physicalmarks, band numbers, etc., and thatwe all micro-chipped them, tattooedthem, or at least taught them our nameand address.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/688</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 45-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/688/671</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
