<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/487</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-14T22:35:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Guam Rail</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Owstoni, Rallus</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Zoo Lowry Park Zoological Garden is perhaps America's newest zoo, having reopened its admission gates to the public on March 5, 1988, after a total reconstruction. The $8 million phase one of the zoo includes an Asian domain, a primate world, a children's village (with petting zoo), and a free flight aviary. The zoo is largely comprised of cageless environments and specializes in theeducational display and breeding of endangered species. Phase two of the zoo, due to open Nov. 1, 1990, will include a further $12 million in new facilities, including a Florida-at -night building, a Florida biome exhibit and an education complex. The Free Flight Aviary The zoo's free flight aviary is an 18,000 square foot, 45' high cable truss structure. It has a concrete perimeter wall foundation and is covered with 1 '' by 1 '' vinyl coated weldmesh. The aviary, although appearing to be one open space, is divided into six separately managed units, providing opportunities for display and breeding of a wide variety of birds. Presently, in these spaces we manage 13 avian orders, comprised of approximately 200 individuals of 60species. The target species emphasized are tropical, neotropical and some...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/487</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 22-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/487/472</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
