<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/666</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-10T22:31:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Common Red,ears Heading for Rarity Status</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hinze, Ian</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of all the birds that have been exported from their country of origin for reasons pertaining to scientific research, museum specimens, zoological exhibits or just plain birdkeeping, it is the waxbills that have suffered most. Imported into western Europe and North America in the tens of thousands over the years, the fact that they have been hitherto so readily available has made captive propagation virtually non-existent. In the past, whenever a species took our fancy, it was a matter of just going out and making a purchase. Not so today! With legislation to curb birdkeeping being clamoured for by prohibitionists worldwide, those in the hobby who have kept birds merely for a rosette embellished egotrip are gradually coming to terms with the fact that they owe a duty to aviculture by way of embarking on serious breeding programs -therebyputting something into the hobby for a change -or getting out altogether; towhich end they will not be missed! Unfortunately, far from taking birdkeeping seriously for altruistic reasons, there is a minority that sees only dollar signs as the end result. This may well prove as fatal to hundreds of presently available species in aviculture as any import ban because in one's pursuit of trying to establish the rarer species, for financial gain or otherwise, those species previously regarded as common will inevitably be neglected. With this in mind, I decided to concentrate on those species of waxbill which I felt were in danger of being overlooked and, after taking stock of the situation, decided to specialize in the red eye-striped species of the genus Estri/da, with particular emphasison the Black-rump or Red-ear (E. troglodytes). This typical, vivacious little waxbill has been kept in British aviaries for decades and is nothing less than a black mark against aviculture. While many consider it immoral to import hummingbirds and other species requiring extreme specialist care, one cannot complain about the hysterical calls for a total ban on bird imports when one considers that the Black-rump, in spite of the ease with which it settles down, is seldom bred in captivity. In my own country, for the whole of 1991, only 28 were registered by the Foreign Bird Federation (a body set up to, among other things, collate breeding data). Hopefully, this article will inspire others to seriously consider its specialization. Around four inches (lOcm) in length, both sexes look alike and the oft-repeated assertion that females are slightly less colorful than their mates is entirely misleading and a most unreliable guide to determining a true pair. That said, once a definite pair has settled down and come into breeding condition the owner may well spot subtle differences in the plumage. This becomes evident, however, through regular study and vigilance and is easy to ascertain once two birds have obviously paired up. In a pet shop, when waxbills tend to be housed in overcrowded cages, plumage differences may be the result of a lack of condition and to choose a true pair from such circumstances is best construed as being pot-luck. The upperparts are light brownish gray with delicate vermiculations on all of the feathers save those on the forehead and wing quills. The eyestripe, from whence the bird derives its alternative name and which doesn't cover the ear at all, is of deep scarlet. The underparts are of grayish fawn washed with pink, lighter around the throat. There is a rosy red patch on the ventral area, while the under tail coverts are white with a pink tinge. Under wing coverts are pale buff. The rump, as one would expect, is black as are the upper tail coverts and tail.The beak is bright red to crimson and  the feet are dark brown to brownish black. Although there are no sub-species there is a great deal of individual variation in color -particularly in the amount of rose red on the underparts and of pink suffusion generally - which again, highlights the uncertainty of obtaining a true pair and calls into question whether other species, regardless of their geographic location, are over sub-specified! Frequenting grassy savannas, scrub and other grassy areas, as well as swamps in its native Africa gives an indication as to its captive feeding requirments. My own birds are supplied regularly with panicum, white and Japanese millet, canary seed, British finch tonic mix, lettuce seed, oystershell and limestone grit and, prior to and during the breeding season, Ce-De egg-food and the seeds of ripe and unripe annual meadow grass (Poa annua), rough meadow grass (Poa trivia/is), narrow-leaved meadow grass (Poa angustffolia), tussock or tufted hair grass (Deschampsia caespitosa), perennial rye-grass (Lolium perenne), cocksfoot (Dactylis glomerata), meadow or common fox-tail (Alopecurus pratensis) and chickweed (Stellaria media). Along with an abundance of livefood, it is these wild seeds that are the catalyst for a successful breeding. From April onwards I collect bundles of wild seeds on the stalk and just throw them on the floor of the birdroom. As soon as I close the door behind me the birds immediately alight upon them and dexterously work their way along and through the stems to partake of the tonic-giving properties enveloped within the fresh seed-heads. A good idea is to pick...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/666</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 34-37</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/666/649</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
