<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1759</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-25T16:00:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Convention Comer '04</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aboumaali, Esther A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Since 1974, the American Federation of Aviculture has been successfully promoting the advancement of aviculture. The AFA Conventions began as a key channel to educate its members and future members. Combining both fun and education, the AFA Conventions feature world-renowned speakers, the latest and newest bird products by diverse avian exhibitors, and networking opportunities. Thirty years later, the AFA Convention is still the major avian event for all who have an interest in birds.Please use the "Early Bird" registration form located on the dust cover of this issue. While you are registering, please make your hotel reservations as well. You can receive the AFA discounted hotel rates if your reservation is made before July 9, 2004. Why wait? Call today! This year, the American Federation of Aviculture is celebrating its 30th anniversary, and the team putting together the Super Drawing, Silent Auction, and raffles has been working overtime to bring some very special and unique items to this convention. We decided to give our members an "early bird" peek at some of the items that have been generously donated this year:The Super Drawing items for 2004 are some of the best we have seen in recent memory:Prize #1: Avian Library. The first item is something different and appropriate for the theme, Evolution of Aviculture. What better way to celebrate the changes and growth we have seen as an avocation than by assembling some of the premier avian books written over the past 50 years:• "The Encyclopedia of Lories and Lorikeets" by Rosemary Low 1998, donated by Dick Schroeder of Cuttlebone Plus, www.cuttleboneplus.com.• "The Large Macaws" by Joanne Abramson, autographed by the author, and donated by Joanne Abramson of Raintree Publications, www.raintreepublications.com.• "Genus Amazona" by John Stoodley 1990, autographed by the author, donated by Kelly Tucker of www.vktucker.com.• "Pionus Parrots" by John Stoodley 1983, donated by Nancy Speed.• "Australian Parrots" by Forshaw 1988, donated by Wanda Elder.• "Parrots in Aviculture" by Rosemary Low 1992, donated by Wanda Elder.• "Parrots, Macaws, and Cockatoos - The Art of Elizabeth Butterworth" by Elizabeth Butterworth 1988.• "Parrots of South America" by Rosemary Low 1972.• "Parrots and Parrot-Like Birds - Diseases of Birds" by the Duke of Bedford and David Coffin, 1954• "Foreign Bird Keeping" by Edward Boosey.• "Parrot Production Incorporating Incubation" by John and Pat Stoodley, 1983.• "Parrots, Cockatoos, and Macaws" by Edward Boosey, 1956.• "The Living Air" by Jean Delacour, 1966.More books are on their way, so watch the website and the next Watchbird for more additions!Prize #2: Fresh Air Purifier - Alpine Air Purification Systems' "Fresh Air" is the top of their line. These "Living Air?" purifiers use unique proprietary radio wave-like ionization along with activated oxygen to purify the air, and is designed for an entire house up to 3,000 square feet. For more information, go to www.freshairliving.com/welder and enter the password GUEST. This item is donated by I Deal Purification Systems with an approximate value of $700.Prize #3: A $500 Gift Certificate toward Gamini Ratnavira Artwork- Gamini Ratnavira, a world renowned tropical wildlife artist, has donated a $500 gift certificate to be used towards any original or lithograph print. You can commission your bird to be painted in its natural environment as well. To see Gamini 's work, please see the example above or go to his website at www.gaminiratnavira.com or contact Lisa or Gamini Ratnavira at 760- 723-9256 or lisa@tfb.com.Prize #4: One Week in Caho San Lucas, Mexico - Seven nights, from Monday, December 6, 2004 to Monday, December 13, 2004 at a gorgeous resort in Cabo San Lucas, Mexico - master suite has two queen size beds and the living room has a queen size pull out couch which sleeps two, sleeps 6 in total. Unit has private balcony, full kitchen, two baths, and master bath has Jacuzzi. This prize includes accommodations-only at the Hacienda Del Mar Vacation Club, which is surrounded by the Jack Nicklaus Signature Ocean Golf Course known as the "Pebble Beach of Baja at Cabo del Sol." Amenities include infinity swimming pools with waterfalls and countless fountains, private beaches, European-style spa and fitness center with stateof-the-art equipment and personal trainers. For more information, go to www.haciendadelmar.com.mx. This fabulous trip, with an approximate value of $6,500, is donated by Dave and Terri Jones ofwww.flockstockandbarrel.com.Prize #5: Rainforest Expeditions Land Trip to Peru - Noted ecotourism organization, Rainforest Expeditions has donated a land trip for (2), six days and five nights, to Peru. This trip, excluding airfare, includes all hotel and lodge accommodations based on double occupancy, all scheduled land and river transportation, all transfers, all scheduled excursions with English-speaking guide services, and meals as specified in the itinerary at www.perunature.com. You will see the world's largest clay lick, visit the canopy tower and oxbow lake at Posada Amazonas, hike to a macaw-nesting colony at Tambopata Research Center, and explore its trail system at leisure with expert naturalist guides.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1759</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 30 No. 4 (2003): Fourth Quarter 2003; 26-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1759/1734</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
