<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2750</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-26T17:00:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Gouldian Finch: Aviculture and Reproduction</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leli, Ubaldo</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Although I am not a large-scale breeder and exhibitor of finches, I have accepted the invitation of the editor to write this article on the management and breeding of the Gouldian Finch with great pleasure. This is because the information on breeding, foster parenting, artificial incubation and, particularly, handrearing from egg of this species is also relevant for many other species of finches, including the most demanding of the waxbills.This article focuses on the biology, management and breeding of the Lady Gould Finch (Chloebia gouldiae). The special problems presented to the aviculturist by the frequent failure of Gouldian parents to incubate and/ or raise their offspring is, as we will see later, not completely negative, but may, under certain circumstances, carry positive consequences for the husbandry of this species.Biology of the Gouldian FinchMany books and innumerable articles cover the biology of the heterogeneous bird compound called finches. Here I will restrict myself to the description of the specific aspects of the Gouldian Finch's biology that will help the aviculturist to draw conclusions that can be extended safely to the management of other species kept in captivity.What is a Gouldian finch?For the aviculturist, finches are birds that eat totally or in part a seed diet. They can be subdivided into ''European finches" and ''exotic finches". Examples of the first group are the Canary and the Goldfinch; and of the second, the waxbills and the grassfinches. The ways these groups of finches hull their seeds differ. The Fringillidae use a central crest in the lower side of their upper jaw, rubbing it against the edges of the lower jaw; whereas the Estrildidae, for example, use the two edges of the bill 1. The principal difference between the two groups, however, is in the nest shape - open for the Europeans and covered for the exotics. This difference in shape corresponds to differences in the begging behavior of the chicks, and in the feeding technique of the adults. The chicks of the family Fringillidae (like the European Goldfinch) and of the Serinae (such as the Canary) beg by stretching their neck high up, and the parents feed perching on the edge of the open nest. On the contrary, the chicks from the Estrildidae, for example, beg by turning their head sideways, as does the Gouldian finch. Excellent articles that cover behavior and reproduction of finches from the avicultural point of view have been published'&amp;gt;. The Gouldian Finch, like most parrot finches, grassfinches and waxbills is a cavity nester that builds unrefined nests, or chooses natural cavities in trees, sometimes not even carrying material inside them 1•The Lady Gould's Finch is one of the most beautiful birds kept in captivity, and one of the simplest to care for. I will not describe in detail its , looks since nearly everybody has seen photographs of this species in its three naturally occurring color variants. However, extensive descriptions of this bird can be found in Evans and Fidler's excellent book', in Bates and Busenbark's4, in Woolham's Handbook of Aviculture", and in the Encyclopedia of Birds by Perrins and Middleton6. Articles covering the aviculture of the Gouldian Finch have appeared in many avicultural magazines7. The most striking feature of the Gouldian Finch is the presence of sharply divided areas of intensely contrasting colors of the plumage. People interested in developing color mutations in captive birds will find in this species ample material to work with. I will not cover in detail the ever increasing color mutations of the Gouldian. This is a subject for specialists.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2750</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 1 (1992): FEB-MAR 1992; 31-35+48-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2750/2730</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
