<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/722</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">1993 Siskin Summit: A Peak Experience</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Colwell, Gail Gatewood</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Summit is ReachedIn politics, a summit is an internationalgathering of people interestedin world cooperation; in geography, asummit is the highest peak; in rhetoric,a summit is a high point inhuman achievement. In aviculture, therecent Siskin Summit was all of theseand more!On August 21, 1993, about 50 people gathered in Kansas City, Missourito participate in the first annual SiskinSummit. The AFA Red Siskin Project(RSP), which seeks to establish ahealthy, genetically-diverse captivebreeding population of this endangeredfinch, met as a group to analyzethe current status of the project and toplan for its future. The goals of theSiskin Summit were many: 1) to inspect and improve the generalorganization of the project,2) to learn about genetics and otherdynamics in establishing a captivebreeding population which will somedaybe appropriate for re-release intoprotected wild habitat,3) to discuss fiscal requirements ofan ambitious, completely privatelyfunded project such as this,4) to explore actual mechanics of rerelease,5) to meet with representatives fromthe Red Siskin's natural habitat rangein Venezuela, and many more.Cool Crest Family Fun Center inKansas City was the site for the SiskinSummit. Yvonne Patterson, promotionaldirector for the RSP, hosted theSummit and organized the meetingareas, meals, and social activities. Allagreed that the Siskin Summit atmospherewas a fabulous mixture ofhome-style comfort, professionaldiscourse, scientific interchange andfestive camaraderie.Down to BusinessIn the opening moments of theactual Siskin Summit business day,RSP Director Kevin Gorman was presentedwith a plaque of appreciationfor his leadership. In pa1t, the plaqueread, "You have helped us turn ourideals into actions." Shortly afteraccepting his award, he began theproceedings by showing a ve1y colorfuland inspiring slide show about theRed Siskin (Carduelis cucculatta). Hedescribed how pet-trade trapping hasdriven this little finch to the brink ofextinction in its native Venezuela, andhow the RSP has undertaken a mission to save this bird.Next, Antonio Rivero, just in fromVenezuela to attend the Siskin Summit,spoke on the plight of the Red Siskinin the wild. A private aviculturistand conservationist himself, ProfessorRivero told of his own country's rolein the international exploitation of theRed Siskin. He spoke with passionand energy of his desire to rectify thissituation by aiding the RSP in its mission.He also gave a slide show of theRed Siskin and its native habitat.Professor Rivero was gracious andappreciative for his invitation (the provisionsof his ticket fare were paid forby the AFA's RSP).Robert Smith, Ph.D., ecologist representingthe Venezuelan government,accompanied Professor Rivero fromVenezuela to provide a slide showabout the government's interests inthe Red Siskin. He spoke of the difficultpolitical and financial issues relatingto ensuring protected habitat inVenezuela. He also made the importantpoint that it is, indeed, trappingwhich has pushed the Red Siskin sonear extinction, since habitat is availableand suitable for the bird and itsneeds. Indeed, he said, the Red Siskin'srequirements are very compatiblewith traditional Venezuelanfarming and land management. Hepresented information on various rereleasesite possibilities. He alsooffered the support of the Venezuelangovernment (in particular, the interimpresident, who sponsored and paidfor his trip to the Siskin Summit) to theRSP, and expressed the hope of beingmore actively involved in the future.Professor Jim Hardin, wildlife biologistfrom the University of Wisconsinat Stevens Point, spoke on the philosophyand mechanics of captivebreeding population management. Heused flipsheets and lectured to presentthe many subtleties involved in captivebreeding: genetic diversity mustbe analyzed and maintained, characteristicsof wild populations must beexplored and utilized in making captivebreeding decisions, and variouscomputer-aided techniques can helpus pursue these ideas.Mary Cahow, biologist, also fromthe University of Wisconsin at StevensPoint, presented her ongoing Master'sresearch on the songs and calls of theRed Siskin, for which she has receivedgrants from the RSP. She is now carryingout a highly complex study of the Red Siskin call notes. She showed ussome of her techniques, whichincluded direct sound analysis, andmore. She hopes to discover theextent to which the Red Siskin's callnotes are learned and/ or innate, andhow this may impact captive breedingand evenn1al re-release. Her work willbe invaluable as the RSP moves closerto reintroduction. Moreover, her workwill be of great interest to the ornithologicaland general scientific communitiesas well, since it will givemore information on the nature of learned versus innate behaviors inanimals. Mary also has a special affinityfor the Red Siskin, since she is asuccessful project breeder as well as aresearcher.Steve Fowler, associate breeder andlong-term supporter of the RSP, spokeon his current breeding facilities andgave much useful information abouthygiene maintenance, infection controland general aviary management.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/722</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 16-20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/722/705</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
