<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2803</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-05T18:52:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">News Briefs and Notices</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">New Amazon Parrot Society FormedThe Amazona Society has been formed and is dedicated to the following goals:1. To building self-sustaining captive populations of all the Amazona possible,2. To disseminate avicultural and scientific information on the genus Amazona to all members and other interested parties through the newsletter,3. To take an annual census of the captive population of the genus Amazona,4. To the re-introduction of those threatened Amazona species when there is a self-sustaining captive breeding population, and when protected reserves in their native habitats have been secured,5. To assist where possible the preservation of the genus Amazona in the wild.If you are interested in the Amazon species we would like to have you join the Society. The newsletter will be published four times a year, more if enough articles warrant it. The president and treasurer for 1984-1985 is James J. Murphy, and the editor of the newsletter is Jan R. van Oosten. If you wish more information please send request to: The Amazona Society, P.O. Box 110637, Tacoma, WA 98411-0637, U.S.A.We will send you a membership application, Vol. 1, No. 1 of the newsletter, and the 1984 census by return mail. New Cockatoo Society FormedA cockatoo society has been formed and dedicated to the preservation of the cockatoos of the world through education and captive breeding. All who have or are interested in cockatoos are invited to join the society and share knowledge and experience regarding this beautiful family of birds. There is a bi-monthly newsletter edited by Joe Lannom that contains much data of interest to all aviculturists interested in cockatoos.For further information contact Cockatoo Society, 26961 N. Broadway, Escondido, CA 92026. Natural History SafariTo KenyaThe Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia is sponsoring a special 18-day natural history safari to Kenya beginning January 30, 1985. Members of the expedition will be able to explore the ecology of East Africa, including its remarkable variety and abundance of bird life. There will be many opportunities to observe and photograph other African wildlife as well.The itinerary includes Samburu, Aberdare National Park, Lake Nakuru, Lake Naivasha, Maasai Mara, Tsavo and the Indian Ocean. There will also be a train trip from Mombasa to Nairobi.Cost is $3,550 per person including round-trip air fare from Kennedy Airport in New York City, and other aspects of the journey. It also includes a $ 300 tax-deductible contribution to the Academy of Natural Sciences.For further information call David Blanton, (607) 257-3091 or write to:Voyagers International, P.O. Box 245, Aurora, New York 13026.Free Seminars From TheSan Francisco SPCA onExotic Pet Bird CareBird expert Roberta Lee will present a one-day seminar on the care of exotic pet birds. The seminar will focus on the humane care of toucans, mynahs and all species of parrots (including cockatiels and parakeets). Nutrition, housing, breeding, training, routine and emergency health care, and the status of these birds in the wild will all be covered,Live animal demonstrations and displays will be a major part of the session. Those who attend will receive free samples of avian products and a 56-page book on the care of exotic pet birds.Seminars begin September 9th, 1984.They will then continue on October 21st, 1984 and will be repeated on the second Sunday of every month. Each program will start promptly at 10:30 a.m. and will run to 4:30 p.m. with a 45-minute lunch break.The Exotic Pet Bird Care seminars will take place at The San Francisco SPCA, 2500 16th Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, (415) 621-1700. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-05</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2803</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 11 No. 6 (1984): DEC 1984- JAN 1985; 6-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2803/2787</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
