<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/571</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Experiences with ''Mac;' the Severe Macaw</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McOmie, S. Marianne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It all began one Indian summer daywhen, at a local outing of our birdclub, I met one of the most beautifulgreen birds I had ever seen.Our bird club had an annual date atthe fall fair to show our birds off tothe public and also to each other. Ihad brought a variety of small birds,parakeets, finch and cockatiels. Thepeople next to me had brought amagnificent Scarlet Macaw, a Blueand Gold Macaw and the first minimacawI had ever seen, a ravishinglybeautiul Severe Macaw (Ara severa).I overheard Sue and Bob talkingabout selling this little green bird.I couldn't believe my ears . So Iscrewed up my courage and approachedSue. Rather timedly I askedhow much this bird was worth. Myhopes were dashed when she toldme that she had just finalized a dealfor Mac. Someone was going to trade her some cockatiles and a variety of other birds for her. Well, I asked herto please think of me if the deal wentsour because I really thought thisbird was great.Later on that day, my husbandjoined me in showing off our birdsand he also met the Severe. Like me,Jeff also thought that she was a lovelybird, but he wasn't quite ready tojump through hoops to own her. Butwe did talk to Sue and she told us theprice of the bird if her other deal fellthrough. She seemed to feel that thedeal was solid.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/571</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 47-52</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/571/554</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
