<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3464</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-02T16:55:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Conservation Corner</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boyd, Janice D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AFA Avian GrantsProgram UpdateFour projects have been selected for the2006-2007 AFA Avian Grants program:• A joint avian conservation research grant in conjunction with Loro Parque Fundación• Avian intelligence studies byIrene Pepperberg and the AlexFoundation• Population Levels Assessmentand Ecology of the Blue-headedMacaw under the oversight of DonBrightsmith of the Schubot ExoticBird Health Center at Texas A&amp;amp;MUniversity• Assistance with equipping the newaviary for the Puerto Rican Parrot(PRP) Recovery ProgramIn this issue of the Conservation Corner,Jafet Velez of the PRP Recovery Projecthas helped write a summary of this project,its history, accomplishments, and future,so that readers may understand why thisis such a valuable effort for aviculturists tosupport.The Puerto Rican ParrotRecovery ProjectJafet Velez-Valentin - US Fish and WildlifeServiceJanice D. Boyd, PhD AFA Conservationand Research Committee ChairThe Puerto Rican parrot (Amazona vittata)is the last survivor of the four nativeparrot species of the United States, theothers -- now extinct -- being the Carolinaparakeet, the thick billed parrot (hangingon in Mexico), and a parakeet endemicto Puerto Rico with no common name,Aratinga maugei. This last survivor hasthe dubious honor of being one of the 10most endangered birds in the world, withfewer than 30 existing in the wild. But inthe aviaries of the Puerto Rican ParrotRecovery Program live over 200 of theseparrots, and because of this, the PuertoRican parrot has a chance of making acomeback. The US Fish and WildlifeService, the Puerto Rican Department ofNatural and Environment Resources, andthe US Department of Agriculture ForestService are cooperating on the RecoveryProgram for the species. The agencieshave successful captive breeding programsand so far about 40 individuals have beenreintroduced into the Caribbean NationalForest in eastern Puerto Rico.HistoryPuerto Rico was formerly entirely forested,and the Puerto Rican parrot once wasabundant throughout all forest types onthe main island, on the nearby offshoreislands of Culebra, Vieques, and Mona,and some claim also on St Thomas inthe US Virgin Islands. “Iguaca,” as it wascalled by the now extinct Taino Indians, isa bright green bird with a red forehead,a white ring around the eye, a whitebeak, and blue underwing feathers. Thejuveniles are very similar in appearanceto the adults, and as with most Amazons,the males and females appear alike to thelimited human eye.Human impacts upon the islands werelargely to blame for the decline of theparrot population during historic times.Deforestation and shortage of nestingsites, hunting because it was consideredan agricultural pest, and capture for thepet trade began to noticeably reduceits numbers by the latter half of the 19thcentury. Up to 99% of the original forestswere cut down for sugar cane monocultureand other agricultural uses, laterreplaced by industrial development andurbanization. The Culebra subspecies (A.v. gracilipes) was extinct by the late 1800’s- early 1900’s. Hurricanes in 1899, 1928and 1932 drastically reduced and in somecases eliminated the remaining enclaveson the islands and on the mainland. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3464</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 33 No. 2 (2006): Number 2  2006; 59-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3464/3448</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
