<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1164</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:31:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Aviculture: An Instrument of Preservation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elgas, Bob</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Had aviculture existed in the past, as it does today, the Cuban Macaw,' the Passenger Pigeon, and the Labrador Duck might not now be extinct. Sadly, with the passage of time, the increasing pressure of an expanding human population will inevitably result in the extermination of additional species. However, since preservation through captive breeding is possible, many can be saved.As compared with a few years earlier, aviculture, particularly within the private sector, is much advanced. Breeding, incubating and rearing techniques have improved dramatically. Many rare species are being successfully bred. As noted above, the future of wildlife, particularly birds, is increasingly precarious. Our capability to preserve them through captive breeding becomes enormously important.There are three major areas in which propagation can be undertaken. The first is through governmental initiative, secondly by breeding programs of zoological institutions, and third through breeding efforts within the private sector.Avicultural programs at governmental level have been infrequent, with marginal results. Breeding programs at zoos have been more successful and,some noteworthy results have been achieved. Zoos however, function primarily as display institutions and are not intended as breeding facilities. Although they have successfully bred rare species, their efforts have been directed primarily toward the propagation of high profile mammals. Most zoos do not concentrate on breeding birds-not because they lack the capability, but because they frequently do not have sufficient facilities.Circumstances within the private sector are quite different. There are numerous individuals with the capability, the desire, the dedication, and the facilities to successfully breed birds. Unfortunately, a major component that is largely restricted, is the opportunity. Unlike governmental or zoological institutions, for whom stock is available, for private aviculturists, the opposite is true. We in the private sector are forbidden the possession of most native birds, and therefore, are denied the opportunity to breed them. It seems unrealistic that zoos may possess native birds, for public display, while aviculturists are not allowed to breed them.As it refers to exotic, or non-native species, aviculturists have a wider opportunity for possession than they do with native birds. However, regulations are being continually proposed and frequently enacted to also curtail our access to these species. Rather than continuing to enact restrictive regulations, our governing agencies need to recognize the value and importance of captive propagation.As indicated, it is unlikely that significant programs can be anticipated at the governmental level, and only limited efforts by zoological institutions. Private aviculture does have the capability to successfully propagate birds, and should be given the opportunity to do so. To demonstrate the capability of Aviculture to preserve rare birds, it would be worthwhile to examine its role in saving the Hawaiian or Nene Goose (Branta sandvicensis) and the Laysan Duck (Anas laysanensis).The Hawaiian Goose, which appropriately is the State Bird of Hawaii, had become so decimated that by the mid- 1940s the total population was fewer than 40 individuals. In 1950, three of these geese were sent to the Wildfowl Trust in England, where they were bred successfully. Ultimately, hundreds were reared, and breeding stock was transferred into other facilities. Captive breeding was so successful that eventually more than fifteen hundred birds were returned to Hawaii and released into their natural environment. In addition, many hundreds were established in private programs, where they continued to breed freely.Then, as the future of the Nene seemed secure, misfortune prevailed. Without effort to affix blame, for various reasons, the wild population in Hawaii declined. It was proposed that the Hawaiian Goose be declared endangered. In-as-much as the Hawaiian Goose existed in the wild, only in that state, and since there were large captive breeding populations within the continental United States, it was suggested the endangered listing should be confined only to Hawaii.Despite an overwhelming recommendation to that effect, the Fish and Wildlife Service declared them endangered, not only in Hawaii, but in the continental United States as well. As a result, it was no longer lawful to transfer Nene Geese across state lines. Consequently, aviculturists curtailed their breeding programs and domestic populations decreased dramatically. In reflecting upon that earlier time when the Nene population had reached an all time low, aviculture came to the rescue. After an incredible recovery, an ill advised decision by a governmental agency virtually paralyzed that recovery. Because of that decision, the future of the Hawaiian Goose is far less secure than it should have been.As the name implies the Laysan Duck is native to the island of Laysan, a tiny bit of land in the northwest quadrant of the Hawaiian Islands. Laysan is only about three miles in length, with a small central lagoon. Early in the century, rabbits were introduced and ultimately denuded the island of vegetation. As a result, the Laysan Duck was almost exterminated. At one time, the entire population was fewer than 10 individuals. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1164</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 3 (1997): MAY-JUNE 1997; 48-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1164/1143</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
