<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3052</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-17T17:41:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Northern Rosella</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Northern Rosella, also known as the Brown's Rosella, is quite a rarity in American collections. It is found in the extreme northern and northwestern parts of its native Australia. The Northern Rosella is a small rosella (28 cm.), the only rosella that is smaller is the Stanley, or Western Rosella (25 cm.). There are no subspecies of the Northern Rosella.Although very beautiful, this rosella does not have the multitude of colors that can be seen in many of the other rosellas. The most striking aspect to their coloration is probably the pattern of the body colors. The feathers of the back and wings are black with broad yellow margins; and the feathers on the rump and underparts are yellow and edged narrowly with black lace-like fringes.Both sexes of the Northern Rosella are alike in coloration and only after close observation of known pairs can it be sexed. The males are overall more intense in coloration, especially the white cheek patch and the violet-blue edge below.Though the males of the rosella group are known for their wide, heavy upper mandibles, it is especially noticeable in the Northern Rosella. This species is also very agile on the wing and can maneuver very well with sharp, quick turns.The Los Angeles Zoo acquired a group of Australian psittacines in August of 1976. Among this shipment were four Northern Rosellas. These birds were eventually placed in the Zoo, but some were first year birds and many were in poor condition. A specialized avian breeding complex was then planned for this valuable group of birds. Through the direction of Warren D. Thomas, D.V.M., Director, and Richard Runde!, Curator of Birds, and the funding by the Greater Los Angeles Zoo Association, this complex became a reality. During the interim time of planning and building, these parrots were placed in the Aviary Section of the Zoo.The four Northern Rosellas were observed closely as to coloration and behavior and it appeared that they were two pairs. One of these pairs courted and went to nest in a relatively short time. It is very remarkable that after the tremendous stress and several transfers that they would ever think about nesting this season. In the middle of October they were placed alone in a large aviary that had recently housed eagles. This exhibit was hexagonal in shape with a width of 14 feet and a height of 17 feet. There were definite signs of courtship and feeding of the female in January of l 977. Three cocka ti el-type nest boxes were placed high in the aviary. The rosellas chose an east-facing nest box which was 11 inches long, 9 inches wide, and 10 inches high. The entrance hole was 2 ~ inches in diameter. It had been filled with one inch of wood shavings.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3052</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 3 (1977): JUNE-JULY 1977; 22-24</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3052/3036</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
