<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3032</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-17T09:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Leges Avis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lawrence, Edwin E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">MR. &amp;amp; MRS. A.V. CULTURE AND NEWCASTLE DISEASEDISCLAIMER:(The following hypothetical case is a fictionalized attempt to deal with a clear and present danger to avicultural interests.)Mr. &amp;amp; Mrs. A.V. Culture are familiar to regular readers of this column, but to introduce them once again, this happy, wholesome couple has as their avocation and part-time business a variety of bird raising pursuits - in short, the A.V. Cultures are established,' successful and avid bird people. A few months ago they purchased an Ashy-headed Phoenix bird from XYZ Exotics, Inc., a well-known commercial bird dealer that advertises nationally - "No bird too big/too small" - "All our birds are inspected and have feathers'"The A.V. Cultures, who ordinarily use quarantine precautions when new birds enter their premises do not do so on the date that they receive this long-awaited specimen, feeling that the bird had little chance of having problems since it had reportedly already lived nearly a decade in the U.S., and besides, they were very bushed the day that the bird arrived, so it was placed in a pen by itself and they went on about their chores - chores that have been going on for the 15-20 years that they have been raising exotic species and building up their bloodlines.Comes the dawn bright and sunny, and Mr. Culture looks in the pen and notes that the Ashy-head had bitten the dust. He knew that the old bov was something of a geriatric case among birds, but even though death is expected it often comes as a shock to use. He mutters something about you win some and lose some, and goes on about his business.The next day he finds several very expensive gamebirds and peacocks dead in nearby pens. He can think of no explanation for their deaths - the weather has been mild and they all appeared to be without problems one day and the next day they were dead in their pens. He bundles up the carcasses and sends them off to the State veterinary inspection service. Each morning Mr. &amp;amp; Mrs. A.V. Culture find more dead birds and they become both frightened and agitated because they have now lost nearly $20,000.00 worth of breeding stock. There is some delay in getting a diagnosis from the State lab, however, when it comes back it is definite and succinct: exotic Newcastle.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3032</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 2 (1977): APR-MAY 1977; 16-18</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3032/3016</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
