<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1288</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Breeding of Regent Bower Birds (Sericulus chrysocephalus)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hamilton, Neil</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionA total of 14 known bower birds species are found throughout Australia and New Guinea. Six of these are found· within Australia. The most poplar two species in captivity today are the Satin Bower Bird and the Regent Bower Bird. They are very striking in color and are presently in demand by aviculturists. There are usually also one or two other species, but they are not available in great numbers, .e.g., Great Bower Bird and Western Bower Bird.Bower birds can be considered very hardy in captivity and are usually used as display species in many bird collections. Their overall husbandry and breeding techniques have long been taken for granted with most bower birds coming into captivity directly from the wild. This trend of collecting birds directly from the wild has slowed down somewhat so the pressure is on all of us to breed, record, and maintain many softbilled species. This, in turn, will increase our understanding, knowledge, and, who knows, may even help support the wild population in some way.The Regent Bower BirdThe Regent Bower Bird Sericulus chrysocephalus is found along the east coast of Australia from New South Wales into Southern of Queensland. A second sub-species Sericulus chrysocephalus rothschildi is believed to be found further north in Queensland.DescriptionThe male Regent Bower Bird has a forehead, crown, nape to mantle rich golden yellow, suffused with orangered on forecrown and hindneck. The two outermost primaries and their coverts black, remaining flight feathers, golden yellow with black tips becom- ing broader toward outer primaries. Secondary-coverts and tertials, rich golden yellow with other parts of the body mainly black. Male bower birds usually mature at around six or seven years of age.The female Regent Bower Bird is usually larger than the male with the crown and nape sooty black. She is prominently brown with grayish to white feather markings throughout the rest of her body. Immature birds are similar to adult females.AcquisitionsOn the 22nd October 1987, the Perth Zoo acquired a pair of Regent Bower Birds of unknown age from Taronga Zoo. These birds were collected from the wild in October 1985. One of the main reasons for Perth Zoo becoming involved with bower birds was to obtain more breeding and captive information on them. The Perth Zoo uses the Regent, Satin and Great Bower Birds as analogue species to gain and gather information which may help alleviate the future threat to bower bird species either here in Australia or in New Guinea.Housing and BehaviorWithin Perth Zoo these birds are housed in adult pairs or one male to two females, using two or three aviaries side by side to allow introduction, breeding, and for other management reasons. This arrangement allows us to quickly separate the males from the females or, visa versa, remove offspring with minimal disturbance to them.When the Perth Zoo first considered breeding Regent Bower Birds, we prepared two to five aviaries for breeding and maintaining ·them long term. In 1985 when we obtained our first pair of immature Regent Bower Birds from Taronga Zoo, we set aside two of our display aviaries. This was partly to enable us to show the public these beautiful birds but, most importantly, to monitor their behavior, knowing from previous experiences what they could do to each other.These two aviaries are 2.70m (9.5 ft) in length, 4.5m (16 ft) in width and 2.70m (9.5 ft) in height. Both are made of 50 ml (2 inch) pipe and l.6mm (one inch. by half inch) heavy wire. They also have a sheltered 1.8m (8 ft) area in each aviary. The aviaries had been well planted before to allow safety for the birds, and to give the plants enough time to become established. As bower birds are big plant eaters and destroyers, plants such as Fish Bone Fem, tree ferns, some native plants, fig tree species, fruit trees, Hibiscus plants, etc., can all be used in the aviary. It is important to provide plenty of decayed leaf mulch and fine sticks each season. The staff replaces all dead tea trees in the shelters, trims plants and re-mulches these aviaries every Autumn.Introduction of bower birds can be very stressful to the birds which is why we used two aviaries side by side with interlocking doors. They were well planted so the birds could escape from each other. At least two feeding and drinking stations should be available so individual birds can not dominate a single station. Close staff observations are very important during feeding.metsThe main diet of bower birds at the Perth Zoo consists of minced heart, ground dog kibble, cheese, egg mix (insectivore mix), S.A. 37. (mineral and vitamins), diced fruits and vegetables such as bananas, pawpaw, rockmelon, grapes, pears, apples, oranges, tomatoes, watermelons, figs, currants, corn, carrots, lettuces/spinach etc. Finch or a parrot mix is also given, along with mealworms, fly pupae, moths and native figs which can be collected in the zoo grounds. This is fed to the birds twice a day. In addition, when there is young, the female receives live baby (pinky) mice and moths three to five times a day, as well as the normal twice a day feeds. If the female does not have young then she will leave any baby mice offered. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1288</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 2 (1998): MAR-APR 1998; 58-61</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1288/1267</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
