<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2640</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-18T20:08:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Captive Propagation of the Collared Sunbird</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dellinger, Rebecca Maria</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Eckart, Christopher J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionThe Collared Sunbird (Antbreptes collaris) is one of 117 species in the family Nectariniidae which is comprised of the Sunbirds and Spiderhunters. The Collared Sunbird is a common and widely distributed species throughout the Ethiopian region of Africa (Clements, 1981).Both sexes of this active and inquisitive species are metallic green above and bright yellow below. The male is distinguishable from the female by his green throat which is bordered below by a narrow purple band. Individuals measure about nine centimeters in length and weight approximately 7. 5 grams to nine grams.The first captive fledging of the Collared Sunbird in Great Britain occurred in 1987 when a private aviculturist succeeded in rearing one chick (Ridd, 1988). In September 1989, the Dallas Zoo fledged a Collared Sunbird chick that is believed to be the first fledged in the United States. The New York Zoological Park successfully reared two Tacazze Sunbirds (Nectarinia tacazze) in 1960 (Conway, 1961). The Denver Zoological Gardens fledged a female Buffthroated Sunbird chick (Nectarinia adelberti) in 1989 (pers. comm.). Housing and CareIn November 1988, the Dallas Zoo received seven wild-caught Collared Sunbirds from Bellbird, Inc. During the quarantine period, the birds were segregated by sex, four females and three males, into two "cubes" similar to the exhibits described later in this article. In January 1989, the birds moved to the Bird and Reptile House. A pair was placed off exhibit. A pair was placed on exhibit and the remaining three birds, two females and one male, were housed together on exhibit.The exhibits were fiberglas formed "cubes" measuring 145 centimeters high, 110 centimeters wide, and 110 centimeters deep. The front of each cube is window glass.The exhibits are perched with locally-cut, small trees and vines supplemented with plastic boxwood vines. The plastic vines are misted daily so the birds can leaf bathe, which they do readily. In each exhibit, some of the cut vines, Japanese Honeysuckel (Lonicera japonica) and Rattan Vine (Bercbemia scandens), are gathered into a wreath and suspended in a corner by wire covered with aquarium air tubing. Tubing is used to prevent the birds from injuring a wing on the wire.Above each sunbird exhibit are two fluorescent light fixtures. Four Sylvania 20-watt, two-foot-long lights are used for each exhibit. Three of the lights are cool white and the fourth is a Gro-Lux. Lights are turned on at 6:45 a.m. and off at 5:00 p.m. during winter months and at 6:00 p.m. during summer months. Skylighting allows the birds some twilight time.The Collared Sunbirds are fed at 7:30 a.m. and again at 1 :30 p.m. Their diet presently consists of Avico Sunbird Nectar, Scenic Bird Food Pellets (apple-flavored), Soft-billed BirdFare, fruits and live food. All solid food items are lightly dusted with Super Preen vitamins and oyster shell powder. The policy of dusting the food began July 2, 1989, after a nesting female Orangequit (Euneornis campestris) developed symptoms of calcium deficiency. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2640</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 2 (1991): APR-MAY 1991; 40-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2640/2610</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
