<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2095</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-07T03:36:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Vets Corner: U.S.D.A. Rules on Pet Bird Transportation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Svedeen, Kendal P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A number of changes have been instituted by the U.S. Dept. of Agriculture regarding the importation of personally owned pet birds. Commercially imported birds in large numbers come under an entirely different set of U.S.D.A. regulations. The most recent pet bird importation regulations were effective as of Jan. 15, 1980, and apply to all countries except Canada. In some ways they are more strict than previous regulations, and in other ways more lenient. The overall objectives are to eliminate the importation of birds infected with Exotic Newcastle's Disease (V.V.N.D.), and to control the spread of Psitticosis. Newcastle's Disease is becoming more of a worldwide problem. It is estimated that if this disease was to become a problem in the United States, it could cost the taxpayers in excess of $230 million a year to attempt to control it.Psitticosis, or Parrot Fever, is contagious to humans, and without proper treatment is usually fatal to both man and bird. This disease is treatable with Chlortetracycline (C.T.C.), and all birds under the minimum quarantine period of 30 days are appropriately treated with this antibiotic. However, we know that it takes at least forty five to ninety days of treatment with C.T.C. to be assured that birds are "clean." Therefore, it is advisable to isolate and treat newly acquired birds with C.T.C. for two to four weeks. Requirements:A pet bird brought into the U.S. must be quarantined for at least 30 days in a U.S.D.A. operated facility. A maximum of two psitticine birds per family per year are allowed. There is no limit on other species (within reason). During the quarantine period, the birds are isolated and treated in individually controlled and ventilated cages to prevent any cross contamination. The Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (A.P.H.I.S.) conducts appropriate tests on the birds to insure that they are free from any disease communicable to our poultry population. If any birds are found to be infected, they will be refused entry, and must be either returned to the country cc origin at the owner's expense, or humanely euthanized. All imported birds will have numerically registered leg bands attached.Procedure:If one is planning a trip to a foreign country, and anticipates the purchase of birds, quarantine space at one of the listed U. S.D .A. facilities must be reserved and paid for in advance. A deposit of $40 per cage is required, and a cage will accommodate two parrot type birds, or a variable number of soft-bills, as long as they are compatible. Total cost estimates at present are about $80 per cage for one bird, and $100 per cage for two psitticines (or a larger number of small soft-bills) which must be paid upon release from quarantine. Obviously, it is more practical and economical to bring in two birds as long as they get along well together.Additional charges can be incurred for transporting birds from the Port of Entry to the quarantine station.When a bird is purchased in a foreign land, it is necessary to obtain a health certificate signed by a veterinarian accredited by the government of that country, certifying that the bird is free from any communicable disease. It must also indicate that the bird is being exported in accordance with the laws of that country, and must be written in, or translated into the English language. When applying for the cage reservation, requestthatU.S.D.A. form 17-23 be sent to you. It is an acceptable health certificate in English. Transportation from the Port of Entry to the bird's quarantine station must be pre-arranged as well. When the bird is released from quarantine, have it examined by your personal veterinarian, and treat it with C. T. C. for thirty days.Ports of Entry:In order to obtain the cage reservation, first write to the Import-Export Staff, Veterinary Services, A.P.H.I.S., U.S.D.A., Hyatsville, M.D. 20782. Request a copy of the pet bird import regulations and Form 17-23. Send the form and a certified check for $40 to the Port Veterinarian, A.P.H.l.S., U.S.D.A., (City, State, and zip code below):Nogales, AZ 85621 Lawndale, CA (L.A.) 90261 San Ysidro, CA 92703 Miami, FL 33152 Honolulu, HI 96850New York, NY 11430 Brownsville, TX 78520El Paso, TX 79902Laredo, TX 78040 Canadian Birds:The same basic rules apply, but the birds need not be quarantined as long as you certify that they have been in your possession for at least 90 days, were kept isolated from other birds during that period, and are in good health.Taking your bird out of the U.S.?Identification of the bird is the key factor. Either a numbered leg band or a tatoo is essential. Leg bands can be removed or exchanged, so a tattoo is a much more reliable means of identification. If a bird is going out of the country for less than 60 days, a health certificate signed by a U.S.D.A. accredited veterinarian, identifying the bird by tattoo or numbered leg band is all that is required. Special provisions must be made in advance with the U.S.D.A. if the bird is going to be outside the U.S. for more than 60 days. The bird must also be isolated from other birds during its absence. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2095</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 9 No. 3 (1982): JUNE-JULY 1982; 6-8</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2095/2066</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
