<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/730</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T03:26:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Emergency Evacuation of Birds in Harm's Way</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worth, Gail J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It usually happens when you leastexpect it, that telephone call in themiddle of the night, that weather forecast,that sudden realization that I'vegot to evacuate my birds right now!Since we usually have about as muchtime to prepare for that vague "it'llnever happen to me" emergency asyou just had while reading this paragraph,the time to prepare is now!Be it a hurricane, earthquake, flooding,tornado, or firestorm, few aviculturistsare immune from the possibility(dare I say eventuality) that evacuationof the breeding stock and/ or petsmay be necessary to save their lives.Of course, in the case of earthquakes,tornados, and firestorms, such as therecent ones in southern California,little or no warning is usually the case.But even if there is no warning beforea disaster occurs, preparation forevacuation might still be beneficial formoving the survivors out of a disasterarea.There is one cardinal rule to planninga safe evacuation of birds. This is:compile all necessary equipment inan easily accessible location and donot use it for any other purpose. This,of course, is easier said than done.How many of us have, in our possession,right now enough crates to safelymove all the birds in our collections?Even if you purchase enough cratesfor this purpose initially, it is so easyto use a crate here and there until thattime that the emergency actuallyoccurs and then there aren't enoughcrates. Therefore, it is important toestablish this crate cache and not touse them for any other purpose. Thesame is true of nets. Enough nets ofsufficient size and variety should beon hand. These are the two basic elementsof bird evacuation. Havingenough vehicles to move the birds ifnecessary is also important but, sincewe never know when this might benecessary, this aspect is a bit more difficultto control. If you don't haveenough capacity in the vehiclesusually on hand, it is wise to keep alist of people with telephone numbers by the telephone whom you could callon for help in the event of an emergency.There are other items that I recommendaviculturists keep on hand inthe event of an emergency. Each situationwill dictate which of these itemsmight be important in a given emergency.I would recommend keepingall of these items handy.Emergency PlanWrite an emergency plan, make severalcopies of it and make sure thateveryone who might be involved in anevacuation or emergency has a copyof this plan. Keep several copies ofthis plan in your emergency cache.Plan an order of evacuation based onefficiency of evacuating the largestnumber of birds in the shortest possibletime. You might wish to stage apractice drill without actually removingthe birds to familiarize everyonewith emergency procedures. Discussworst case scenarios with everyonepotentially involved. Make sure thateveryone is familiar with the emergencyequipment cache and knowstheir own role in the situation.WaterKeep enough bottled water for yourself,family members, employees,birds, and other animals for severaldays. Pipes break, electricity fails wellpumps, contaminated water comes infrom the purification plants - any ofthese things might happen.FoodKeep enough food on hand thatdoes not require refrigeration for anypeople or animals that might beinvolved in an emergency. It is hard toestimate how much might be necessarybut keep some reserves so thatthere is enough to last for severaldays.Flashlights and CandlesEmergencies often happen in themiddle of the night and loss of electricityis often a factor so flashlights inthe emergency cache can be invaluable.Batteries should also beincluded. Candles might also come inhandy. Don't forget matches.First Aid KitsEmergency first aid equipmentshould be kept for both people andanimals. Most of us are familiar with items we might expect to see in a firstaid kit for humans. Many items thatare necessary for avian first aid areonly available through a veterinarianand it is advisable to consult youravian veterinarian for recommendationson what your kit should contain.Your own kit should be tailored to theneeds of your collection, your level ofexpertise, and the probable nature ofyour emergency. Suggested items fora kit might include Lactated Ringer'sor Pedialite, tuberculin syringes, ophthalmicdrops/ointment, topical ointmentfor injuries or burns, gauze andbandage tape/materials, antibiotics(oral and injectible), dexamethazone,oxygen, and equipment for gavage(tube) feeding.Extension Cordsand GeneratorThese two things might not beappropriate for all situations but, ifyou have egg incubators and/or isolettesfor babies that require electricityfor heating purposes, these two thingsare essential. Don't forget three-prongplug adaptors for the three-prong plugextension cords and gas for the generator.Make sure you know how to usethe generator before you need to andkeep it in an easily accessible place.Radio andjorCellular TelehoneCommunication or contact with theoutside world might be crucial in yoursituation in the event of loss of electricityand/or telephone service.There are other things that youmight think of that would be importantto your particular potential disaster.The purpose of this short article isnot to be a complete guide to anyemergency but rather to be a reminderthat none of us is immune to this....</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/730</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/730/713</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
