<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4010</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Call for Presentations 2024 Conference</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Staff, AFA Watchbird</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 1 (January/February 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.2024 CALL FOR PRESENTATIONS The American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. 50th Annual Conference September 5th, 6th &amp;amp; 7th, 2024 Hilton Hotel Orange County/Costa Mesa 3050 Bristol St. Costa Mesa, California 92626 The American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. (AFA) is a 501(c)3 non -profit, educational organization established in 1974 whose purpose is to represent all aspects of aviculture and to educate the public about keeping and breeding birds in captivity. AFA will be celebrating its 50 th anniversary in 2024.We invite you to submit a proposal for a presentation to be made at our 50th annual conference. Proposals should be submitted in the form of an abstract of two hundred (200) words or less, accompanied by a brief biographical sketch of one hundred (100) words or less, identifying the author’s experience with the topic to be presented and to include the name of the author(s), mailing address(es), email and all phone contact information for the author(s). If there is more than one author, please indicate if one or both will present. Accepted abstracts will be published in the program with the author ’s biography and picture. No personal contact informationwill be made public. Abstracts will be accepted now through May 31, 2024. AFA will provide a complimentary conference registration package and one banquet ticket to each confirmed speaker. All other arrangements, including guests, transportation and hotel accommodations, are the responsibility of the speaker and/or the speaker’s sponsor.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4010</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 1 (2024): Watchbird January/February 2024; 17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4010/3970</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
