<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1635</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:50:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Mother Nature's Gift</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Swicegood, Carolyn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">M other Nature has provided an extraordinary substance from a surprising source to benefit her feathered creatures. An extract of a simple food item has proved to be effective in combating hundreds of pathogens that affect birds, including parasites, bacteria, virus, and fungi. This food-derived substance is used by a growing number of aviculturists, pet bird owners, and veterinarians. It is a natural, safe and non-toxic disinfectant and cleaner as well as a preventive against disease-causing pathogens. It also is used to disinfect food and water, to prevent mold growth on home-grown sprouts, to clean cages, aviaries, and homes - all without harming birds or the environment.From the SeedSurprisingly, this powerful product is made from the lowly grapefruit seed! The antimicrobial properties of the extract of grapefruit seeds and pulp was discovered in 1972 by Jacob Harish, a physicist and immunologist, as a result of his curiosity about the bitterness of grapefruit seeds.University and Laboratory TestsAt the University of Georgia, tests were conducted to evaluate Grapefruit Seed Extract (GSE) as a disinfectant in tests against E. coli, Salmonella sps., and Staph aureus. According to Roger Wyatt, Ph.D., and Microbiologist for the university, "Our studies indicate excellent potential for these products (GSE) .... The toxicological that I have reviewed indicated that this product and the active ingredient poses very low toxicity. As you know this is important because most disinfectants that are currently used in either animal or human environments have moderate to high toxicity and extreme care must be exercised when these prod- ucts are used ... In view of the reports that we have discussed, the wide spectrum of activity that GSE offers (antiviral, antibacterial; Gram positive and Gram negative, antimycotic, and antiprotozoan) will undoubtedly aid in its acceptability."Dr. Wyatt's findings have been confirmed by a variety of clinics and labs, as well as universities from around the world. GSE is non-toxic, environmentally safe, and quickly biodegradable. It causes no side effects and is 'often dramatically less expensive than existing treatments or chemicals for similar applications.Some physicians have found that GSE is as effective against candida, a yeast infection, as Nystatin or other antifungal preparations. It is also effective against protozoans such as giardia or entamoeba histolytica. Researcher Dr. Leo Galland says that it is more effective than prescription medicines such as metronidazole against these protozoa! parasites. There is considerable research to support the claims of GSE's efficacy as a natural antibiotic, anti-fungal, anti-protozoan, anti-viral and antiseptic disinfectant As a germicide, GSE has multiple uses and it is non-toxic and non-irritating when diluted as directed.Bio Research Laboratories of Redmond, Washington, USA, tested GSE, a commercial chlorine bleach, and colloidal silver against Candida albicans, Staphylococcus aureus, Salmonella typhi, Streptococcus faecium, and E. coli. GSE proved superior and the test report concluded:"All microorganisms tested were inhibited with moderate levels of GSE liquid disinfectant. High levels of chlorine bleach inhibited the test organisms, but moderate levels were not effective. Because the GSE liquid was inhibitory at much lower levels, it may be assumed that it is ten to one hundred times more effective than chlorine against the organisms used in this study. On average, GSE proved to be ten times more effective than the colloidal silver."GSE is compatible with most antibiotics. It does not produce the negative side effects associated with antibiotic use. Proponents of GSE claim that it does not attack normal gastrointestinal bacteria as antibiotics do. To ensure that this is not a problem, I would use a probiotic after treating with therapeutic dosages of GSE. Even if it is unnecessary, it will do no harm. GSE rarely causes allergic or toxic reactions. Aspirin is said to be 25 times more toxic than GSE.According to The Journal of Orthomolecular Medicine, Volume 5, No. 3, USA, 1990, an international research team examined the effect of GSE on 770 strains of bacteria and 93 strains of fungus and compared this with 30 effective antibiotics and 18 proven fungicides. GSE was found to perform as well as any and all of the tested agents. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1635</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 2 (2001): MAR-APR 2001; 27-28</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1635/1612</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
