<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/758</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:01:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Maylayan Long-tailed Parakeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tongyai, Singkata</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of the genera of psittacine birds found on the Asiatic mainland, the genus Psittacula is the most nurnerous (12 species) and contains the largest species in size. Many members of Psittacula have rather long tails which gives them a very graceful appearance. The Maylayan Long-tailed Parakeet (Psittacula longicauda) is, in my opinion, one of the most elegant and handsome species in the genus Psittacula. Unfortunately, it is also one of the most difficult to breed and raise from the time of hatching. This species is not confined to the Maylayan peninsula but is also found on many islands in the South China Sea and in the eastern Indian Ocean. Because its range is wide and many islands are isolated, there are five subspecies. Although the literature indicates that the juvenile birds look like mature females, my male juvenile had the characteristic red-colored eye-brow feathers from the time he first feathered out. The Long-tailed Parakeet prefers a lowland habitat which puts it in some jeopardy as much of the lowland area is being converted to agricultural use. The bird finds sufficient food in the palm plantations but doesn't fare as well in other agricultural zones. The population of this species is declining not only through the destruction of its habitat but also from shooting, trapping, netting and the taking of babies from their nests. During my many visits to the Far East, I've noticed fewer and fewer numbers of the various members of the Psittacula genus. This holds for wild birds as well as captive birds in the various local bird markets. In the bird markets there is no such thing as sanitation. Birds are jammed into filthy holding cages and must share water from a communal bowl which, I believe, has never been cleaned, let alone sterilized. Dead birds are removed and thrown away without a thought of determining the cause of death. Oh yes, a few "scientific minded" shop keepers throw various antibiotics into the drinking water but without knowing the disease, the dose or the duration of treatment. As a result, these birds often develop problems they wouldn't have had otherwise and many microbes become resistant to the antibiotics. These are the birds that are shipped overseas. Thanks to our quarantine system, not many sick birds get through to our market. People in the Far East seem to enjoy having birds in their possession but very few have any intention of breeding them. These birds are, therefore, essentially dead as far as conservation is concerned. Unfortunately, most of these birds will not live very long after being exposed to diseases in the holding cages. Those that do live will suffer from malnutrition as very few of the people have any knowledge of bird husbandry. In northern Thailand, I saw an amazing method of feeding baby parrots (Blossom-headed and Slatyheaded). These babies were brought down from the mountains by tribesmen after removing them from tree holes to be sold to traders. In this instance, the trader's five year old daughter had the duty of feeding the baby birds. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/758</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 2 (1994): MAR-APR 1994; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/758/741</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
