<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/801</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Richard Topper</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Edwards, Kim</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Rchard Topper was born andraised in southern Wisconsin.He lived and worked for several yearsin ew York. Over the many years heworked for American Express , helived in Hong Kong, Australia andmany locations in Europe.Richard began his interest in breedingbirds in the mid-1960s. His interestwas piqued by the birds he saw beingbred (or attempted) by many of thebusiness acquaintances he had inEurope, Australia and the Orient.Many of these people were attemptingto breed different species of parrotsand finches. Several were attemptingto breed hummingbirds. This intrigueover the difficulty and the challengesit presented caused him to try it forhimself.Richard and his wife Bonnie beganwith finches and canaries. They bredGouldians , Cut Throats and manyother species. He soon saw a challengein breeding and showing EnglishBudgies. During this period ,Richard's job required him to travelextensively . He found many otherbreeders and began to increase hisinterest in the parrot family.In 1971 , they moved to a ranch inGilroy, California and began to breedin earnest. They acquired birds fromaround the world and began theattempt to reproduce each pecies.They bred many other avian typessuch as Ground Fowl (Guinea, Peaand Specialty Chickens) and Waterfowl(Ducks, Geese and Swans). Theyalso raised Koi and Guinea Pigs.In 1975, Richard had began to rai ebirds as a full-time occupation. His kitchenalways had boxes full of babybirds that were being handfed. Inthese boxes were all types of rosellas,ringnecks, Amazons, macaws, cockatoos,eclectus, conures of all types ,African Greys, grass, racket and broadtail parakeets as well as many others.During the first years in Gilroy,Richard began working with severalnutrition companies to help himincrease the production of his collection.General knowledge of parrot andfinch nutrition was nonexistent.Richard , working with the help ofthese companies, watched the differencein the production of the flockwhen the birds were provided a balanceof nutritional supplements. Thenhe began to modify the grains andseeds to increase the nutrition providedand increase production. Thusthe Topper Bird Ranch Diets weredeveloped.In 1982, Richard and Bonnie movedtheir collection of birds, dogs and catsto Lexington, Torth Carolina. Therethey built a new home and a new feedmill to continue to produce the TopperBird Ranch Diets.Richard and Bonnie branched out intheir interests. They began to raiseLlamas, Emus and Rheas . An attemptwas made to raise Wallabies, but thewinter proved too cold. Their interestin orchids also expanded into severalgreenhouses.In 1985, Richard and Bonnie weredivorced. Shortly after the separation,Richard met a lovely lady named Gailand married her in 1986. Gail's interestswere not the parrots, but she didenjoy the rattites. Gail's main interest.is horses. Richard insisted that it hadto be a small horse, not a standard.Gail has been doing exceptionallywell in the show ring with her miniaturehorses. Their mini horse ranch isknown as GTR Mini Ranch.Around 1990, Richard decided tosemi-retire and sold all of the orchidsand almost all of his birds. Thereremained some eclectus, greys and amacaw on the ranch.About two years ago, Richard wasdiagnosed with lung cancer. Thegrowth was slowed and it appearedthat headway was being made. But onApril 30, 1994, at the age of 62,Richard lost his battle with cancer.We will miss Richard for the assistancehe has given so many breeders.The loss of knowledge from any oneindividual is hard to measure, but, ifyou measure it by the number of birdbreeders and pet owners he helpedover the years, it is a great loss.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/801</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/801/783</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
