<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/629</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Rosellas: Colorful &amp; Delightful Parrots</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hall, Gene</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The genus Platycercus, commonlyknown as Rosellas, comprise a groupof eight species and are indigenous toAustralia. They are very colorful, neithernoisy or destructive, and reproducequite readily in captivity. Theyare very active both in the air and onthe ground.All Rosellas possess cheek patchesand have the characteristic Australianbroadtail , which is used to displaytheir varied moods. The median wingcoverts generally are the color of thebreast and are edged in black. Thecolors range from red , orange andyellow, to green, blue, black and white,which doesn't miss much. Individualspecies descriptions can best befound in the many books available.Sexes are colored alike making itdifficult to pair them correctly. In the" dark ages" of aviculture, the "Rudkin"method was the rule. If a pairlaid an egg, you had a hen. If ithatched, you had a '' pair. '' In spite ofall of our advances in the field of aviculture,that method has remainedvalid . Many books describe thetheory that the wing stripe found onthe underside of the primary flightfeathers is a guide as to sex, however,I have not found that theory to bedependable. Now that surgical sexingis available, obtaining true pairs isnot difficult. There is a good supplyof well bred, strong stock availabletoday. And thus, there is absolutelyno excuse for breeding brother-sisterpairs. There is also no shortage ofgood, reliable aviculturists available,enabling trading of stock to ensurecontinued strong specimens forfuture generations.As long as I am on my soapbox, Ican find no reason or excuse for thebreeding of hybrids. For those amongus that must, try raising chickens!The Green Rosella is found on theisland of Tasmania; the Brown's orNorthern in found not surprisingly inNorthern Australia; the Stanley orWestern in Western areas; and theRed or Eastern, Mealy or Blue, Yellow,Adelaide and Crimson are allfound in the South-central and Southeasternregions. As in the case ofmany species, sub-species occur, andagain are described in the manybooks available.Rosellas are quite hardy and inmost areas of the United States canbe kept in outside flights. In the colderregions , it would be well to provideinside-outside areas for theircomfort. In their native surroundings,Rosellas fly great distances intheir quest for food and water. Thusthey have developed the ability ofstrong, rapid flight. For this reason , Ifeel that they are best kept in as longa flight as possible. It need not bewide and, as they are not prone tochewing the flights to the ground, 19gauge wire will do nicely.Only two problems are common intheir care. since they love to feed onthe ground, Rosellas are susceptibleto worms. With the help of your veterinarian,a good preventative programin this area is very necessary fortheir good health. The second problemhas to do with their rapid flight.Broken necks and head injuries arecommon, but this can be correctedby building the open end of the flightsolid. If it is wire, the birds will oftenattempt to fly straight through it,thus a broken neck is the result.Otherwise, conventional aviary constructiondesign will work nicely.Perches should be placed at theextreme ends of the flight to allowthe maximum distance for exercise.Tree limbs, securely mounted, arebest as they vary in diameter which isbeneficial for fertility.A good rule to follow is to neverplace pairs of Rosellas next to eachother. If you must, double wire isneeded as they will fight and causegreat harm to each other through thewire . They also are apt to '' fall inlove" with the girl-next-door andthus doom the breeding season.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/629</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 30-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/629/612</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
