<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1766</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-25T16:00:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Other Side of Feather Destruction There is Hooe</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Meyers, Jayne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A bird that is determined to pick, pluck, barber, or otherwise destroy its plumage can cause its owner a type of frustration unlike any other. Despite providing the healthiest possible diet, spacious accommodations, a variety of toys, daily companionship, and undying love, sometimes our feathered friends begin and continue their pursuit of nakedness for no apparent reason. Having survived two bouts of feather destruction with my eight-year old Solomon Island Eclectus named Bink E Berde, I have seen the light at the end of the tunnel (or perhaps I should say at the end of the "shaft").From the moment of our first meeting, Bink E has been an agreeable, outgoing and mellow Eclectus. I have been fortunate because my career made it relatively easy to provide him with an enhanced lifestyle, including his very own spot at the law firm where I worked. In fact, Bink E cheerfully accompanied me to work every day for nearly seven years, relishing his role as chief attention grabber and the world's first "Parrotlegal."During our off hours, Bink E Berde has accompanied me on long daily walks around San Francisco, becoming a welcome visitor at all of the businesses in my neighborhood. He delights in the sights and sounds of the city, frequently chatting, singing or whistling as we wander. He enjoys being fussed over by his many friends and acquaintances. Recently, he embarked on a career as a "feathered therapist," participating in animal assisted therapy visits to various nursing homes, senior citizen day care centers, and other facilities in San Francisco. A very vocal fellow, Bink E often requests an adventure by saying "out now" and expresses his delight with exclamations of"happy bird" and "I love you."During the autumn of 200 l when he was not quite six years old, Bink E experienced what I thought was a severe molt. I had never seen him with so many bald spots or such extensive feather loss. It never occurred to me that he might be feather picking, primarily because I had never witnessed him deliberately removing a feather. His personality was the same and there had been no changes in his diet, environment, or routine. Bink E's feather loss took place over a short period of time. After a few weeks of finding feathers in the cage, feathers on the floor and feathers in his food and water crocks, the shedding stopped. I thought his molt was over and that I soon would see new pinfeathers. I tried to keep Bink E as comfortable as possible with frequent baths and regular misting with a high quality aloe spray. Extra portions of protein and calcium rich foods were added to his diet to encourage feather growth. I truly believed I was dealing with nothing more serious than an extreme molt.When there was zero feather regeneration after three or four months (and I do mean zero - not a pin feather in sight), I became concerned. Still believing that this was a molt, albeit a bizarre molt, we headed for the vet. I hoped for reassurance that there was no active disease process preventing the growth of new feathers. Well, it took no longer than ten seconds flat for the good doctor to enlighten me, pointing out that Bink E was exhibiting a typical feather picking pattern across his breast, shoulders, legs and under his wings. Heartbroken, I protested, explaining that I had never witnessed Bink E deliberately pull out a single feather. My vet then asked, with a grin, if I ever slept. I was devastated, heartsick, and immediately wondered what I had done to harm my precious parrot companion.After a thorough exam that included blood work, Dr.Galvin proclaimed Bink E healthy. He spent a great deal of time with me, discussing possible causes and cures as well as reiterating much of what I already knew about feather destruction, that is, that it can be quite difficult to discover the cause and even tougher to stop. In Bink E's case, giardia, skin disease (including dry skin), feather malformations and a host of other possible causes were ruled out. Food allergies were possible, but not suspected, given Bink E's history. Dr. Galvin explained that any of the known treatments are "hit and miss" and suggested that we try HCG* (a type of hormone injection). While he was unable to explain definitively why this treatment modality worked, he did say that it had been helpful in a high percentage of the cases he had treated. I nervously agreed to the injection, but after all the reading I had done and all the tales of woe I had heard, I was not terribly hopeful.Over the next few weeks, I did my best to prevent Bink E from absorbing my stress by pretending that everything was perfect. There was no further feather loss, nor had I seen a single new pinfeather. We returned to the vet for a recheck after a month and Bink E got a second injection of HCG. After a second 30-day period, lo and behold, Bink E finally started looking like a pincushion. Whether the HCG had anything to do with his feathers starting to grow remains an unsolved mystery. However, I understand that the primary purpose of the HCG therapy was to curtail and/or prevent feather destruction. Since Bink E had stopped ripping out his feathers months earlier, I declined further treatment.During this very frustrating time, I became hell bent on solving the mystery of why Bink E had destroyed his beautiful plumage. I carefully (and unceasingly) examined and re-examined Bink E's diet, environment, toys, and activities. [talked to anyone who would listen, including his breeders, other breeders, friends, and acquaintances, and read whatever material I could find that addressed the causes and treatments of feather destruction. No one was able to ascertain a definite cause and no one could offer an absolute solution. It had been months of endless frustration and maddening speculation. Anyone who has been through this problem with a beloved bird knows how distressing the process can be.Finally, during the spring of 2002, Bink E was once again in full feather and looking great. During the many months that it took for his feathers to grow back, I never saw him pick, pluck, barber, or otherwise destroy a feather. I breathed a giant sigh of relief and hoped the problem was over.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1766</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 30 No. 4 (2003): Fourth Quarter 2003; 42-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1766/1741</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
