<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1353</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:24:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Why I Became a Life Member of AFA</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Winter, Don</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Awonderful opportunity is now available from AFA - the Life Membership. Through the efforts of James Hawley and Bruce Winter (no relation to me) the details of such a membership were established. I have seen Life Memberships in other organizations fail economically. This one has been very well thought out. The fact that 70% of the money goes into an endowment, never to be touched is the key. Had it gone to fund a special project, years would go by, the project long forgotten, and the membership rolls would still have free subscription obligations forever. The $700 portion will be enough to fund a membership even at a very low interest rate.A $1000 expenditure is one I look at very carefully. I am probably not a typical Life Member. However, I feel compelled, obligated, obsessed with sharing the reason I chose this option.First, I have never been famous, partly because I have never done anything really amazing. And, likewise, I've never done anything really stupid enough for the news media to talk about it incessantly. I do get criticized at a lot; but, I'll bet you didn't know that.By becoming a Life Member of AF A, I gain instant fame for a reasonable sum of money. I can now print it on my business card, I'll be on computer lists in the AF A business office; and people will talk behind my back. At a minimum, people will think I did something really great or really stupid; they just won't remember which. How else could you ever get lasting fame for less money? Maybe I'll develop a pompous attitude. I always wanted to do that. I might even get a Tee Shirt with the words, "You can't impress me. I am a Life Member of AFA" emblazoned on the front. The AF A is a fine organization. It will be around forever. As an organization, its agenda cuts through the fluff and places a focus on the important issues. Educating about legislative issues and bird welfare are at the top of the list. AFA does not appear to get bogged down with special accomplish-nothing-but-we-had-fun-doing-it type projects.So, if you are considering a Life Membership with AF A, hopefully my comments will reinforce your decision and you'll move on it now. + </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1353</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 4 (1999): JULY-AUG 1999; 57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1353/1331</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
