<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4129</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T23:43:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Update on Parrot Avian Bornaviral Infection</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hoppes, Sharman</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 48 Number 1 (October 2021).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Update on Parrot Avian Bornaviral InfectionIntroduction For people who love their birds like family and aviculturists whose passion and livelihood is their birds, a diagnosis of proventricular dilatation disease/avian ganglioneuritis can be overwhelming and raise a wide variety of questions. The etiological agent, Avian bornavirus (ABV) that causes avian ganglioneuritis or proventricular dilatation disease (PDD) was initially identified in macaws and called macaw wasting disease in the late 1970s. Over the years, it has had many names including neuropathic gastric dilatation and myenteric ganglioneuritis, but is best known by pet bird owners as PDD. ABV has been found in more than 80 species of birds worldwide, both in captivity and in the wild, including parrots and other psittacines, finches, canaries, waterfowl, toucans, raptors, and various other birds. Macaws, Amazon parrots, cockatoos and African grey parrots are the most...system (seizures, tremors, blindness, ataxia, proprioceptive deficits). The kidney and heart may also be affected. There is anecdotal evidence that acute feather picking may be a clinical sign. Birds may exhibit only GI signs, only neurologic signs, or both. Some data suggests that Old World psittacine species are more likely to exhibit neurologic signs, while New World species are more likely to present with GI signs.Diagnosis Definitive diagnosis is via histopathology on necropsy or biopsy tissues. Histopathologically, there is a lymphoplasmacytic ganglioneuritis which may be present in the brain, spinal cord, peripheral nerves, nerves of the gastrointestinal tract, heart, adrenal gland, kidney, or lung. Blood tests include serology and PCR techniques. Antibodies to PaBV antigens can be detected in most birds with clinical PDD, but not all. They may also be present in infected birds who show no clinical signs. Detecting antibodies in an apparently healthy bird indicates the bird has been exposed to PaBV, but does not stipulate that the bird will develop clinical disease. Using PCR techniques, PaBV can be detected in droppings, tissues, and anecdotally in blood. In several studies, PaBV was detected in the tissues of up to 100% of birds who died or were euthanized due to PDD. PaBV is often detected...Clinical signs PaBV/PDD is a progressive neurologic disease that may present with a variety of clinical signs based on the affected site and species of bird. Clinical signs may be classified as gastrointestinal (anorexia, weight loss, regurgitation, and passage of undigested food in the feces) or central nervousClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4129</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 48 No. 1 (2021): Watchbird October 2021; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4129/4089</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
