<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2994</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-15T08:02:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dear Sirs,I can hardly wait for the Watchbird to come every two months. I raise a lot of birds and really enjoy reading and learning more about them. The June/July issue of the Watchbird didn't come until August 8th. I was really upset and disappointed when I found the whole magazine was on '' game birds"The first story on waterbirds I didn't mind and I turned right on hoping to find something on cage birds. The next article was on Peacock Pheasants, then waterfowl, then Pigeon Pox, then Geese, Tragopans, and Doves. By this time I could hardly believe I was reading the Watchbird.I haven't joined a poultry club or a gamebird association because I am not interested. I don't mind sharing an article or two with the gamebird people but please lets have something for people who raise cagebirds. Now I have to wait another two months for the next issue and pray it has some information on cagebirds as that is why I took the magazine in the first place.Sincerely, R. L. Chico, CAYou have brought up two very pertinent points of interest. First, regarding our specialty issues we have taken your advice and shall include a broader variety of articles in the magazine. We will try to go about 50% specialty and 50% general interest articles and hope you are not disappointed in the future. On the other hand, Madam, I think anyone who is really interested in the birds of our world woulri have to enjoy the June/July Gamebird issue. The color photographs alone make the magazine worthwhile, The Tragopan pictured on page 38, the Impyan on page 35 and the Mandarin Duck on page 14 are among the most beautiful birds on earth. Their beauty is their justification. They should be appreciated as rare and lovely avian gems regardless of what you raise in your birdroom.Now, the second point you alluded to is the fact that your magazine arrived late. Our apologies for that. To prevent that from happening again we have done some reorganizing at our staff level. The most important change is that Mr. Lee Horton has been appointed Managing Editor. His responsibility is to run the business end of the magazine and expedite all phases of publication. Although Mr. Horton is a rather young man he has been retired for several years now and spends most of his time drinking mint juleps with his feet propped up under a shade tree on his estate. We are confident that he can handle the business end of the Watchbird with expertise and skill and that the activity will be a welcome change for Mr. Horton.Ed. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2994</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 5 (1978): OCT- NOV 1978; 41-44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2994/2978</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
