<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1876</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-14T21:52:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Illinois HB0707:Local Groups Work Together to Defeat Proposed Legislation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Crean, Jason J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">February 11, 2005, the AFA notified me that there was pending legislation in the Illinois House ~epresentatives that, if passed, would greatly affect the way we keep birds. If that was not bad enough, we only had three days in which to respond. As President of The Avicultural Society of Chicagoland (www.tasc-chicago.org), I am an active aviculturist and leader to individuals who attend our club events and meetings in order to learn more about our feathered friends. This includes pet bird owners, breeders and those concerned for species in the wild. However, I was surprised when it came to my attention that a bill had been proposed and was making its way up through our state's legislative branch. Thanks to the AFP\s legislation watchdog representatives, I was alerted to the potential danger to aviculture this bill presented. As I reviewed the legislation, I was confused by the generalizations listed in the bill that could make it difficult to share homes with our birds in Illinois.In 2004, the Avian Regional Cooperative (ARC) was formed to better communicate with our fellow bird groups. The ARC consists of representatives from each of the local bird organizations in our area. Last year, this group proved invaluable when sending our comments in response to the changes to the Animal Welfare Code. The ARC was also vital in responding to this local threat. This bill was discussed with the ARC representatives so the information could be passed onto their respective club members. After reading HB0707, many people became alarmed due to the generalized rules, and wondered how this could affect the common bird owner. What was frightening was the way that this bill was put into motion - it was quietly slipped in without the knowledge of the avicultural community or the general public.The ARC communicated this concern to all of their members and the response was overwhelming. We received the names, addresses and emails of the legislators who sponsored this bill and we mobilized our members to email and write letters to the associated representatives. Some legislators responded, while others did not. On February 25, we received an email from the representative who sponsored the bill. She stated "at this time, I have decided not to move the bill forward."Days later, a local Town Hall meeting was hosted by Representative Elaine Nekritz (D) from the 57th District in the State of Illinois. Although the meeting was geared for local constituents, we felt this might be a perfect opportunity to find out specific facts on the status of this bill, as well as its origin. Northern Illinois Parrot Society (www.nipsparrot.org) President Sheryl Robinson and Treasurer Judy Kramer, both members of ARC, and I attended the meeting. Due to the meeting being a general session with an open forum, we needed to wait our turn. Since Ms. Robinson is a resident of Representative Nekritz' District, it was decided she would ask the pertinent question: "What is the status of HB0707?" Representative Nekritz responded that, due to the overwhelming response from bird  owners, she decided not to call the bill as previously planned. This was what we had waited and hoped for! Finally, a factual response to the question we all wanted answered. After the session, we talked with her briefly and inquired on the origin of the bill. She explained that the legislation was proposed by "a bird rescuer in Northbrook," a northern Chicago suburb. We were surprised to learn that one individual could propose laws which could have affected so many bird owners.We continue to keep in contact with Representative Nekritz, who has been most gracious and fair in her responses. We were very happy to have the opportunity to speak with her. However, the looming shadow of the extremists is still present and we need to be vigilant in keeping our eyes and ears open to any potential problems that may arise in our avicultural community. We must also watch other states to be sure these bills are not copied and proposed, since this is a common ploy of extremist groups. Once a bill is written in one state, it becomes very easy to copy it and propose it another state. Recently this occurred when a law prohibiting exotic animals, which originated in New York, was brought to the City of Chicago. Thanks to many vocal animal owners and breeders, this bill was not passed. We must be aware and stay awake to watch for any future potential dangers.Here is a synopsis of the bill, HB0707, as it was introduced:Amends the Animal Welfare Act. Replaces the term "pet shop operator'' with "animal caretaker'' throughout the Act. Provides that licensees under the Act shall provide for their animals a sufficient quantity of good quality, wholesome food and water, adequate shelter and protection from the weather, annual and necessary veterinary care, and a stimulating and enriching environment. Provides that an individual who violates any provision of the Act or a Department rule...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1876</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 31 No. 4 (2004): Number 4 2004- Number 1 2005; 24-26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1876/1847</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
