<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1035</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T03:34:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question: What temperature and humidity levels do you recommend for incubation of parrot eggs? What incubator do you recommend? M. Reisman Florida Answer #1: It is difficult to recommend the exact temperature and humidity requirements for all parrot eggs as species differences exist. In addition, the type, location, and ambient climate of the incubator can also influence proper temperature and humidity settings. One could discuss these topics ad nausea and many literature sources exist. Approximate temperature setting for incubating eggs in a forced-air incubator is 99.1° F, and one degree higher for still-air incubators. During hatching, the temperature should be dropped to approximately 98.5° F. Incubator humidity is set at 80-84° F (wet bulb) and the hatcher is set at 92° F (wet bulb). Specific species or individual eggs may need different settings depending on past hatchability problems. There are many kinds of incubators and the exact make will depend upon the aviculturist's needs as far as cost or size. One must keep in mind the number of eggs to be incubated, whether the eggs will be hand turned (minimum of eight times per day), how the eggs will be turned automatically, how the eggs are placed into the incubator, and whether the incubator is forced-air or still air. Forced-air models offer a more steady temperature. Parrot eggs can be sensitive to turning mechanisms so rough mechanisms should be avoided. Certain incubators may have trouble maintaining proper temperature and humidity uniformly throughout the in cu bat or, especially if the incubator is underfilled with eggs or if there are wide swings in the environmental temperature and humidity. Eggs can he hatched with even the cheapest of incubators as long as the aviculturist keeps good records and ensures steady environmental conditions in the incubator room. Eggs should he hatched separately from the incubating eggs as contamination can he a risk from hatching eggs, as well as the need to maintain different temperature and humidity settings for hatching eggs. The Humidaire and the Grumbach incubators seem to be the most common in U.S. aviculrure. Kim]. Joyner, DVM, MPVM Raleigh, NC Answer# 2: The proper temperature range for incubation of psittacine eggs is 99-99. 5° F with a wet bulb temperature of 80-82° F. Hatching temperatures should be 98.5° F. Both Humidaire and Grumbach are excellent incubators with Grumbach being a ve1y high-tech unit. James M. Harris, DVM Oakland, CA parrot eggs requires the aviculturist have knowledge of the stages of incubation, the gaining of which may involve periods of trial and error as to what techniques work best depending on the particular circumstances and the species being worked with. Artificial incubation can, essentially, be considered both an art and a science. General recommendations for incubator settings for parrot eggs are temperatures of 99 or 99 .5° F with a humidity level of 82° F wet bulb. For the aviculturist just starting in incubation, these recommendations are a good place to start. If these guidelines result in high hatchability and survival· levels, then continue using these values. If the hatchability is low or the babies have difficulty in the hatching process, then these recommendations should be reviewed-along with hatching technique and sanitary considerationsand potentially revised. In my own aviary, I found that my success rate following these guidelines was less than acceptable, hence, I started experimenting with temperature and humidity levels. Thus, by trial and error, I have for many years had a very high hatchability and survivability rate using a set of values that vary from the general recommendations. With all the species I work with, I find the best success rate using an incubation temperature of 98, F with a wet bulb reading of 90, F. The species include cockatoos, macaws, Amazons, Greys, pionus and eclectus parrots. As to the best incubator for hatching parrot eggs, that is probably similar to asking a number of experienced aviculturists their preference in a handfeeding formula. There are a lot of favorites as individuals may have had positive experiences with different formulas. This is often the case with incubators. Many different brands and models are on...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1035</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 2 (1996): MARCH-APRIL 1996; 43-44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1035/1015</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
