<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1251</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:33:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">CONSERVATION COUNTERPARTS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Parr, Mike</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">C onservation Counterparts is designed to help conservationminded North Americans partner with, and raise funds for conservation groups and projects in Latin American and the Caribbean. The program is run by American Bird Conservancy (ABC), in cooperation with Partners in Flight, and aims to conserve wild birds and their habitats throughout the Americas. Migratory birds recognize no national boundaries and are the perfect means of developing international cooperation for conservation.We are all concerned about the fate of the rainforests, and of our migrant birds as they head south in the fall. Conservation Counterparts provides the opportunity for you to take positive action to make a difference right now. Each of the projects presented is being conducted by a reliable, respected group, and will help both resident and migrant birds as well as other wildlife.The projects are spread across the Americas, and include a wide range of conservation initiatives from species protection, to organizational support, habitat management, ecological investigation, and the training and development of individual conservationists.In addition ro a fundraising target for each project, this article describes volunteer opportunities (where they are available) and also provides information on visiting the projects where this is possible. If you wish to participate at this level, ABC can put you directly in touch with the group concerned (we are unable to accept liability for any issues relating to volunteer activity or travel). We hope you enjoy reading about these initiatives and look forward to hearing from you soon.The first focus is on the Great Green Macaw Project. Other projects will follow in subsequent issues.Great Green Macaw Project, Cerro Blanco, EcuadorA program ro conserve the Great Green Macaw in the CeITo Blanco protected forest, western Ecuador. The project is being carried our by Fundacion Pro-Bosque and will establish an education center and program for local schools, evaluate artificial nest box designs, conduct aerial surveys to identify areas suitable for nesting macaws, monitor and protect nests, and sample macaw DNA to clarify the population status. Funds required: $33,250.A volunteer biologist with South American experience is needed to help carry out field surveys of Yellowcheeked Amazons, and Red-masked Conures in the reserve. Four volunteerfield assistants are also needed to help with nest site monitoring and nest box placement for Great Green Macaws. Park guards can lead groups of 2-4 people to observe macaw nest sires herween july and October (depending on accessibility of nests). Funds raised for this project will he marched by the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1251</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 1 (1999): JAN-FEB 1999; 30-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1251/1230</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
