<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3553</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-23T17:03:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">2008 AFA Convention</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Wayne E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">2008 Convention SpeakersDon’t miss an exceptional group of speakers at this year’s American Federation of Aviculture 2008 Convention! Speakers and topics are subject to change. This partial list of speakers will be updated monthly on the AFA website at www.AFABirds.org.❖❖ Mattie Sue Athan:»» Retired BreederCockatoos - WhereShould They Go?❖❖ Laurie E. Baker:»» Understanding BasicBird Behavior❖❖ April Blazich:»» Wonder Weeds»» What’s Good for theGoose is Good for theWhole Flock!❖❖ Carolyn Carr:»» Belize - Life in aSubtropical Countrywith Emphasis on theDevelopment of aProgram to Protect theKeel-bill Toucan❖❖ Neville Connors:»» Australian Cockatoosin the Wild and in theAviary»» Australian Lorikeets!The AdvancementsOver the Past TwoDecades❖❖ Jason Crean»» The Beak Speaks!The Green Aracari inAviculture❖❖ Thomas M. Edling,DVM, MSpVM»» Aviculture and theRetail Pet Industry❖❖ Susan W. Farlow»» EffectiveCommunication inHuman and AvianEncounters❖❖ Madeleine Franco»» Flock ManagementTechniques forthe “ExcessivelyEnthusiastic”Avicultural Hobbyist❖❖ Walter Frey, Ph.D.»» Keynote Address»» Flocking Birds from aBreeder’s Perspective❖❖ Carol Frischmann»» Sponsored byInternational ConureAssociation»» Preparing CompanionBird Buyers for aLifetime Commitment❖❖ Bennett HennesseySponsored byBird Endowment»» Where a Park Won’tDo: ConservationActions with LocalCommunities to HelpProtect the BolivianRed-fronted Macaw(Ara rubrogenys)»» Protecting aSubspecies beforeit becomes anExtinct Species: ThePalkachupa Cotinga(Phibalura boliviana)in Bolivia»» Conservation Actionsfor the WattledCurassow (Craxglobulosa) and thePeruvian SouthernHorned-Curassow(Pauxi unicorniskoepckea)»» Saving the CriticallyEndangered, BolivianEndemic BluethroatedMacaw (Araglaucogularis)❖❖ Sharman Hoppes,DVM, DiplomateABVP-AvianTexas A&amp;amp;M University»» Update onProventricularDilatation Disease❖❖ Terri Jones»» Attracting the YoungAviculturist»» Make Bird Toys fromNothing!❖❖ Karen Justice»» Training theSpix’s Macaws - A“Spix-Rerience”❖❖ Josef Lindholm III»» Cotingas in theTwenty-First Century»» Birds in Germany: TenZoos in Thirteen Daysor, if This is Thursday, itMust Be Krefeld!❖❖ Adrianne W. Mock»» EnvironmentalEnrichment forCaptive Birds❖❖ Mark Romansky»» Anatomy of aSuccessful ParrotRehoming Program❖❖ Jean Pattison»» Dos and Do Nots ofBreeding and RaisingGreys and OtherAfrican Parrots❖❖ Linda S. Rubin»» LinebreedingPractices in PsittacineHusbandry»» Linebreeding SmallHookbills for Health,Fertility and Longevity❖❖ Wayne E. Smyth❖❖ Nancy Speed»» Inside the Nestbox ofthe Cuban Amazon❖❖ Darrel Styles, DVM,Ph.D.»» Update on AvianInfluenza❖❖ Dr. Ian Tizard,BVMS, Ph.D., ACVMTexas A&amp;amp;M University»» The Status of theSchubot Exotic BirdHealth Center and ItsRole in Aviculture❖❖ Ricardo ValentinSponsored by Amigosde Las Aves USA andSchubot Exotic HealthCenter»» History of the PuertoRican Parrot CaptivePropagation ProgramBased on Experience atRio Abaja Aviary»» Successful Breeding ofthe Puerto Rican Parrotat the Rio Abajo Aviary❖❖ Genny Wall»» Introduction to thePolitics of AnimalLegislation❖❖ David Waugh, Ph. D.»» Is Sustainable Trade ofWild Parrots Possiblefor Their Conservationin Cameroon?❖❖ Jamie Whittaker»» The Aviculture Puzzle❖❖ Bonnie Zimmermann»» Kembali Bebas AvianRehabilitation Center- Evolution of a Dream</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3553</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 35 No. 1 (2008): Number 1  2008; 9-18</dc:source>
	<dc:language/>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
