<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1706</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-25T15:57:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Texas Bird Club Donates $10,000</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kinsey, Tom</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">S an Antonio's Alamo Exhibition Bird Club announced that its donations to organizations promoting bird welfare will total ten thousand dollars for 2003. This is the most the club has ever been able to give in one year. The money is raised primarily through their bi-annual Bird Marts, a Fall Mart in September and the Fiesta Bird Mart in April.The largest single gift is to Texas A&amp;amp;M Veterinary School providing four one thousand dollar scholarships to veterinary students with a strong interest in caring for birds, and fifteen hundred dollars to A&amp;amp;M's Schubot Center For Avian Research. The San Antonio Zoo received fifteen hundred dollars, eight hundred for the education department and seven hundred for the "Adopt an Animal" program to support seven birds, ranging from the small Gouldian Finch to the largest of parrots, the Hyacinth Macaw.Also receiving money from AEBC were Responsible Pet Owners Alliance, five hundred dollars; American Federation of Aviculture, one thousand dollars; and Last Chance Forever bird of prey rescue, five hundred dollars. The remaining five hundred dollars will be given out as needs are identified.Alamo Exhibition Bird Club, led by president Thomas Neeley, is the oldest non-profit bird club in San Antonio and among the largest bird clubs in Texas. The primary mission of the club is to promote avian education. A.E.B.C. sponsors bird marts twice a year, TI1e Fiesta Bird Mart during Fiesta and the Fall Bird Mart in September, bringing people from all over the country with birds of all ages and species, birdcages, toys, playpens, books, feed, and other bird related items. The next event is the Fiesta Mart at Live Oak Civic Center on April 19,2003.According to club president Alamo Exhibition Bird Club vice president Tom Kinsey presents a$1,500.00 check to San Antonio Zoo Marketing Director Jordan Fisher: The money is to be divided between the Education Department and the "Adopt an Animal" program to support 7 birds in the zoos huge bird collection.Neeley, "Our members have a wealth of information to share with one and all. Most of our members have been keeping and breeding birds for many years and are able to help with questions and problems of all aspects of bird care. We love to see new bird lovers at our monthly meetings."    </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1706</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 30 No. 1 (2003): First Quarter 2003; 25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1706/1683</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
