<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3007</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-15T16:35:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Raffle Winners - 1978.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The 1978 National Raffle Chairman, Joe de Aguiar, has expressed his sincere thanks to all who donated prizes, purchased tickets, and lend support in any way to the success of I the 1978 AF A Raffle recently held at the Convention. WINNERS LISTWINNER     PRIZES    DONORSChris Rowley  '78 Chevrolet Chevette   A.F.A.Shirley Olfs pr. Umbrella Cockatoos    Harold YanikBob Austin       African Grey Parrot           Frank MiserDarla Walker pr. Golden Mantle Rosellas Gene HallVirginia Smith pr. Cinnamon Cockatiels Tom SquyresJ. Zey pr. Cinnamon Cockatiels Nancy ReedBarry Adler pr. Turquoisine Parrakeets Mark RunnalsJim Heinen pr. Red Rump Parrakeets Jerry JenningsHarold &amp;amp; Helen Hanson pr. Bourke Parrakeets Ralph SmithMilo Garner pr. African Ringneck Parrakeets Stan DumkeJoseph Idings pr. Pied Cockatiels Steve &amp;amp; Sharon ClauseJack Schultz Blue Fronted Amazon Charles Terris AviariesDavid Hilberg pr. Mutation Love Birds Richard MatticeR.C. Mealey pr. Blue Peach Face Love Birds Dr. Richard BaerBuz Neely pr. Blue Masked Love Birds James CampoloPam Laddy pr. Fischer's Love Birds Clifton WittCheron Wise pr. Pearl Cockatiels Mrs. Mike SimmonsDale Thompson pr. Normal Cockatiels Joe LannonCharles Noble pr. Normal Cockatiels Henry DrymanAl Valenzuela Portable Aviary Firtile FingersFrank Miser pr. Gloster Canaries Janice PritchardDavid Hilberg pr. Peach Face Love Birds Harold BrownMike Fisher pr. Mutation Love Birds Agapornis AcresPatrick Joy pr. Mandarin Ducks Mickey OllsonJane Kennedy pr. Bokhara Pigeons Michael CurtisDr. Raymond Jerome pr. Extra Fancy Tumbler Pigeons Michael CurtisWilliam Kwist Book, Finches &amp;amp; Softbills Don ThomasClyde McFall pr. Bourke Parrakeets Jim SmithRichard Barker pr. Cape Doves Moe RatliffRichard Mattice I yr. Subscription, Watchbird Joe de AguiarJody Laurence Check for $1 ,000.00 A.F.A. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3007</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 6 (1978): DEC 1978- JAN 1979; 32-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3007/2991</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
