<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2418</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T14:47:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">News and Notices</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In Memory ofan English AviculturistPeter Tabonyby Joan Davis Fremont, CaliforniaPeter Tabony passed from this world February 18, 1986 after a lengthy and valiant struggle against cancer. He owned and operated Blean Bird Garden near Canterbury Kent, England. The facilities house one of the largest private collections in England. There are macaws, cockatoos, parakeets, owls, softbills, peafowl and pheasants, with some macaws flying at liberty - something which he was very proud of. The family will continue with the management of his legacy.Mr. Tabony attended the AFA convention in Florida in 1984 and also the 1985 convention in San Francisco. He was sought by many to speak about his "cockles" and macaws. He also flew to Utah following the San Francisco convention where he was a guest speaker at a local bird club. AU who came to know him fell in love with his charm and wit. Those of us here and around the world, who knew him mourn the loss of a very dear and much-loved man. He will be remembered for his extraordinary contributions to aviculture. Experts to SpeakThe following world-class avian experts are confirmed speakers for the A.F.A.'s National Convention in New Orleans, August '86. Be sure to attend and meet them.Jo Hall (Texas), Handfeeding of Psittacines, Paul Roth (Brazil), a) Hyacinth Macaw; b) Habitat Partitioning of Sympatric Parrots in So. Amazo na, Jerry Jennings (California), Keynote Speaker; John O'Neil (Louisiana), Birds of Peru; Lisa Hartman (Wisconsin), International Crane Foundation; Clive Roots (Canada), Softb il ls , Noel Snyder (California), California Condor; Denna Ferris (California), Conures, Bill DeLaMare (Washington), New Flight Designs for Cold Weather; Lindsay Clack (Pennsylvania), Softbills, Robert Travnicek, MD, ABFP (Nebraska), Budgerigar; N. B. Cooper (England), West Australian Cockatoos; and Wolfgang Kiessling (Lora Parque, Canary Islands), The Challenges of Successfully Managing a Bird Park. Memorial toDr. Jean Delacour and Rocco SanducciThe International Foundation for the Conservation of Birds is proud to announce the International Symposium on Breeding Birds in Captivity in memory of Dr. Jean Delacour and Rocco Sanducci, February 11-14, 1987.Approximately forty speakers from around the world will address a variety of subjects including aviculture, nutrition, general husbandry, ecology, conservation, field studies, medical research, etc.We invite all of you to become a part of this experience. It will be held at the Sheraton Premier Hotel, Universal City, California. For more information please write to IFCB, 11300 Weddington Street, North Hollywood, CA 91601, USA. Attention:Clive Roots FoundThe American Federation of Aviculture is proud to announce that the famous Clive Roots has been found. He is alive and well and living in Winnipeg as director of that city's Zoologic Gardens. Moreover, he has agreed to speak at the National AFA Convention in New Orleans. Mr. Roots is best known for his world's first breedings of: Little bee-eater, Blue-crowned motmot, Brown-throated barbet, Red-billed hornbill, Green wood-hoopoo and Southern tree pie.He is author of Softbilled Birds, South American Birds and Reptiles, Tropical Birds, and Exotic Birds for Cage and Aviary.Be sure to attend the AFA National Convention in August and hear this authoritative and fascinating speaker. Avian Seminar April 26, 1986Avian seminar with Dr. Kevin Flammer; special session with Dr. Ted LaFeber. April 26, 1986, 10:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Holiday Inn - Asheville Airport, (I-26, exit 9), North Carolina.Sponsored by Smokey Mountain Cage Bird Society. For details call (704) 456-6764. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2418</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 2 (1986): APR-MAY 1986; 42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2418/2391</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
