<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2526</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-15T14:01:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Paramyxovirus 1: The Pigeon Plague</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mosca, Frank</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A pigeon sits on the ground. It tries to fly to its perch but succeeds only in crashing into a far wall. Another bird tries to peck a grain from the feed tray. It fails because, at the last second, its head jerks spasmodically and is twisted violently away and back around. It tries again, and fails again. Desperate, the bird tries to fly. Instead, it rolls into an uncontrollable series of fit-like spasms.Domestic pigeon breeders around the world have seen this happen in their lofts since the first report in Europe in 1982. Other symptoms include an early and extremely watery diarrhea. Many breeders have characterized it as a "flood" in the loft. Some birds show partial or complete paralysis. On posting, some specimens show lesions of the brain and other internal organs. Mortality rates are above 90 percent with those surviving often showing manifestations of the disease for the rest of their lives. One breeder I know lost over 300 birds in two weeks.The disease is paramyxouirus 1 (PMV-1). PMV-1 is related to the virus which causes atypical fowl pest (Newcastle disease) in chickens and related birds but PMV-1 is not a threat to anything but pigeons and doves. The virus has been shown to attack Columba and Streptopetia species. It may be capable of attacking other genera also. I have not heard of it attacking any of the native American doves but this may simply be because infected birds die without being noticed. Flocks of feral pigeons have been decimated.The virus is spread by direct contact from bird to bird or indirectly through dust infected with the virus. It may be spread from dust on a loft visitors' shoes or clothing. The incu: bation period is about three weeks. During this time, there are no symptoms but infected birds may spread the disease to others at shows, in the loft, or when sold.There is no cure! However, there is a preventative vaccine. Joe Quinn, then chairman of the American Pigeon Fanciers Council, was able to interest the Maine Biological Laboratory in producing a killed virus vaccine. He was then able to get the vaccine okayed for use in all states. This oil-based vaccine is injected under the skin of the neck. Effective protection is provided by two injections spaced a month apart with a yearly booster. The vaccine retails for about $15 per 50-dose vial and $ 20 per 100-dose vial. These doses are racing-homer-sized bird doses which is 0.5 cc/bird, much more than would be required for smaller doves.My friend, his two sons, 14 and 15, and I have. personally vaccinated over 2,000 racing pigeons and many ringneck doves (Streptopelia roseogrisea - Goodwin). We lost only three birds. These were in the first hundred we did and we were still nervous and learning the technique. All the dead birds were posted. We found two died due to our carelessness in inserting the needle. The other died of anaphylactic shock (a severe allergic reaction).Over the last five years, hundreds of thousands of show and domestic pigeons have been vaccinated across the United States and Canada. The number reported as lost due to vaccination is so low as to be practically zero. There are still some foolish breeders who believe the whole story is a scam thought up by a company to make money. None of these breeders have sat and watched his whole loft die within a week or so.I put a stray bird into my loft for less than a half hour while I readied its holding cage. I lost ten birds and a season's breeding. Thankfully, all my older stock was vaccinated. None of the vaccinated birds showed any symptoms. Remember, it's your choice. For your birds' sake, please don't make the wrong one. Emergency vaccination after infection can sometimes produce enough antibodies to protect a few of the latest infected birds. Early vaccination can eliminate the worry totally. Don't take a chance with a virus that could wipe out your years of breeding or your valuable stock. The first step is to quarantine anything you bring in for a minimum of three weeks. The second is to vaccinate.If your own suppliers don't yet have the vaccine available, it may be purchased along with needles and syringes from Foy's Pigeon Supplies, Box 27166, Golden Valley, MN 55427 or Strecker Supply Co., Box 330-P, Selbyville, DE 19975.Directions for Use forAvian Paramyxovirus Vaccine - Type 1 Killed VirusIntroductionAvian Paramyxovirus-Type 1 ( called PMV-1) was first diagnosed in the United States in early 1984. By 1985, it was widespread throughout the Northeast and had been diagnosed in many other areas. The pathogenicity of the disease varies greatly but in many cases heavy losses have been reported. Shows and races bring together large numbers of pigeons from different locations which provides an ideal opportunity for the virus to be spread from bird to bird. The infected birds are then returned to their lofts to infect their penmates. There is no cure. Prevention through vaccination is the only way to control this disease.Signs and SymptomsThe most outstanding symptoms of PMV-1 are incoordination, twisted necks and paralyzed limbs. Less specific symptoms include decreased feed intake, increased water consumption, loss of weight and watery droppings. In the most advanced stages, the birds may be found laying on their sides with complete paralysis.The VaccineAvian Paramyxovirus Vaccine-Type 1, Killed Virus is a sterile product and contains no live organisms which can infect your pigeons or cause disease. Paramyxovirus immunity develops through the slow release of dead virus from the oil emulsion vaccine.Care of VaccineThis vaccine should be stored in the refrigerator but not frozen. It should not be injected when cold. Remove the vaccine from the refrigerator and allow it to warm to room ternperature (70 °F to 80 °F) before use. This will make the vaccine easier to inject and will greatly reduce the shock of injection. Shake well before using.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2526</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 3 (1990): JUNE-JULY 1990; 16-18</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2526/2496</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
