<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2799</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-02T16:16:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cooperative Breeding Can Make a Difference</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Garsee, Sharon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"Auiculturists have come to be guardians of a biological treasure, one they hold in trust for the rest of the world ... " (Toft, C., et. al., 1995)T he Wild Bird Conservation Act of 1992 essentially removed the United States from international bird trade. We can no longer depend on wild stock for our breeding programs. In the last five years many commonly imported species have become scarce. Our breeding populations are becoming aged. The clock is ticking away for captive propagation of our beloved birds. What can we do to make a difference?We should begin thinking of the whole population instead of just what we're going as individuals. Private aviculturists have made great strides in the past twenty years. We have developed into real professionals even though the majority practice the profession on a part time basis. All of our knowledge and expertise will he in vain if we have no birds to pass to the next generation. Breeders of domesticated animals have recommended a minimum of 500 individuals would be required for the genetic diversity needed to sustain a species in captivity. Realistically, no individual would be able to accomplish this. However, if each of us directed our efforts toward a particular species, we would soon make substantial pools of that species available. Begin making plans to register the pairs with a studbook or a cooperative breeding program.StudbooksStudbooks record valuable tracking information. AZA studbooks record all living species, deceased individuals, movement of the species and genetic records. They also direct and control breeding within their system. Private avicultural organizations establishing studbooks generally record all individuals of the species, breeding results, genetics, and assist members in locating needed stock. They do not control or direct breeding. No commitment is required of members to hold back stock or track progeny.Cooperative Breeding ProgramsCooperative breeding programs generally have a founder stock belonging to the consortium, thereby establishing a stable genetic pool that can be counted on for the future of a species. Most projects are set up so that participating breeders split the progeny with the project. When the project involves extremely rare birds, the participants may be required to retain all progeny until large numbers are attained.All avian species should be considered in danger of extinction in the United States. Some have more immediate threats such as; life span, numbers available, delicacy, difficulty in reproducing, and commercial undesirability. Species that are sought after in the pet trade have the best chance of survival. In other words, those with a commercial value are the least likely to become extinct, however, genetic records will still be valuable. The best way to keep those records is AFA's central registry. When a central registry is well established, records of individual genetics will be available even if the bird is sold into a pet situation and later re-enters a breeding program CommitmentBegin your commitment in stages; permanently identify your birds, update your records, register your birds, participate in surveys, join or start a studbook, and, ultimate!y, participate in a cooperative breeding program. Be aware that a cooperative breeding program is a commitment to a long term preservation project and will require some private financing. Programs linked to a non profit organization such as your local club or national club, may entitle you to a tax deduction for any bird donated to the program.If you can demonstrate you cannot locate enough stock for a program, apply for permission to import through an approved WBCA Cooperative Breeding Program This is accomplished by appointing an avian oversight organization and completing the application for the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2799</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 1 (1998): JAN-FEB 1998; 55-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2799/2783</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
