<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2705</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-25T20:57:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">But What is a Softbill ... Really?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Geesey, Brenda</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Softbill- A relatively new term for a group of birds whose bills are not adapted to cracking seeds or tearing flesh as a general rule. Clive Roots, in his book "Softbilled Birds;' gives this definition: '' Cage and aviary birds with relatively soft bills which feed on insects and larger animal prey and soft plant material and whose young are helpless at birth'.' An addition to this is given by Richard Mark Martin in his book '' Softbilled Birds in Cage or Aviary:' He adds, "Any small to medium land bird which feeds on soft bodied food'.' This last precludes raptors, ducks, waders, finches and parrots leaving marginals such as crows. Other characteristics shared by most softbills are the absence of a crop and the style of feeding the altricial young by carrying morsels of food to them instead of by regurgitation.They occur in five major classifications, with some overlapping.1. Omnivores2. Frugivores3. Nectivores4. Insectivores5. CarnivoresMost common and familiar birds in this broad group are the native robins, jays, starlings, warblers, thrushes, etc. Closer to the equator, around the globe, more and more softbill species abound because of the greater year-round availability of fruits and insects. Our native softbills migrate to warmer climates because they need to follow a seasonal food supply. Many common zoo specimens on exhibit are softbills, for example the toucans, hornbills, tanagers, hummingbirds, babblers and honeycreepers.Because "softbill" is not a specific term, it isn't possible to describe or illustrate a standard example in the way we can describe a finch or a parrot. The softbill species come from all parts of the world and include perching birds, terrestrial birds and some who spend the greatest portion of their lives air-borne. Some weave nests, some are cavity nesters, some are mud builders and some are brood-parasites.The most varied and musical of songs and the most dazzling colors and combinations of color and iridescence come from this group. Softbill plumage is amazing in its' variety of types and textures.Because they are not destructive to woodwork, perches, nestboxes or plants (with a few exceptions), and their droppings are not caustic, they can live in a symbiotic relationship with plants in an aviary. They will enjoy the fruits and flowers and the insects they attract. For pure aesthetic pleasure, a planted flight with a mixed collection of softbills is unbeatable. Relatively light gauge wire and light weight wooden framework will be enough for them. Many of them will sing brilliantly and many will reproduce with good management.This category of birds deserves the attention of committed aviculturists and will repay your efforts handsomely. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2705</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 5 (1991): OCT- NOV 1991; 26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2705/2685</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
