<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2094</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-07T02:49:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From The Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">FROM THE EDITOR'S DESKLest the A.F.A. as an organization be put into occassional jeopardy, I wish to reiterate the fact that I, S.L. Dingle, your humble servant, am responsible for the material in this column. The views expressed herein are those of the participants and do not necessarily reflect the official position of the A.F.A. Because of tight deadline schedules and to expedite the handling of mail those of you who want to participate in this "Porum by Mail'' should send your letters directly to me at P.O. Box 340, Norco, Ca., 91760. This will save time and expense.And now, on to the bag of mail.Dear Sir,I am writing in reference to your letter in the Feb/Mar 82 issue of Watchbird. Mrs. Dunlap wrote to you telling of the death of her double yellow Amazon parrot.I find your advice to be very poor. First is your advice to "learn all you can about your bird's health and rely upon the vets as little as possible." I have been treating birds daily for 5 years and I still see cases that are puzzling. How do you expect an individual with one pet bird to diagnose and treat their own bird. I do not believe that this is possible for the majority of bird owners. There are vets in every major city in this country who routinely treat birds and are very knowledgeable about them. If your advice to ''rely upon the vets as little as possible'' is followed we will soon be back to the times 10-20 years ago when very few veterinarians (in case you don't know) knew about or treated birds. I firmly believe that there is no one better qualified to diagnose and treat birds than veterinarians.Second, I believe if Mrs. Dunlap had spent a little time looking for a veterinarian who specialized in birds, she would have had a much better chance of saving her bird. In many instances bird owners take their birds to their regular veterinarian asking or demanding that he treat the bird. The doctor is then obligated to perform this service. The veterinarian is not entirely without fault because he should recommend someone who works on birds routinely, if he himself does not.I am sure that the present state of pet bird medicine would be very primitive at best without the contribution of veterinarians around the world. If this represents the thinking of the A.F.A. and Watchbird, I will find it very hard in the future to support your organization.Sincerely, Jon F. Esposito, D.V.M.El Paso, TexasI certainly hope sir, that you understand avian medicine better than you understood my answer to Mrs. Dunlop. For your convenience I'll restate the threeparagraph answer in the most succinct terms.Paragraph one. Three different vets took your money and fatled to save your bird. Learn all you can about bird health. Paragraph two. There are some excellent bird vets in your area. Paragraph three. Learn other bird people's recommendations regarding parasite control and good veterinarians.Now that you better understand what I said, I trust we are in better accord. I'm sure that even you, doctor, would never suggest that avicultunsts should cultivate ignorance regarding their bird's health. And we both agree that there are good bird vets who should be used at need. Of course, the better health care one provides for one 'sown birds (proper diet, housing, sanitation, freedom from stress, etc.) the less often veterinarian services are needed. It is an unhealthy and unnatural generation that depends routinely upon the drugs and knives of the healing practioners - and that goes for animal care too.The A.F.A. and good bird veterinanans have always worked hand in glove. Indeed, the A.F.A. and "Watchbird" have fostered and supported the advance of pet bird medicine. And many veterinarians have been exceedingly helpful to aviculture through the medium of the A.F.A. I am sure that this happy liaison will continue and I hope you 're part of it.Dear Sheldon,As president of the American Federation of A viculture, I was distressed to read a recent comment of yours in Watchbird magazine in which you voiced your personal opinion on the integrity of the medical profession.Statistics estimate that about ten percent of all medical people are incompetent or disreputable (and I image about the same could be said of all professions and trades). This is a far cry from your statement.It is unfortunate that the bird owner who wrote you had the unhappy experience of consulting two apparently incompetent veterinarians in seeking treatment for her pet bird. It is true, too, that many vets lack knowledge and experience in the care of aviary birds. On the other hand, though, the AF A has long been a firm supporter of veterinary avian medicine. The annual vet seminars held in conjunction with the AFA conventions have always been among the most valuable programs-for laymen and veterinarians alike.Whatever your personal bias may be, I am going on record here to affirm AF A's continued and dedicated support of veterinary avian medicine and the thousands of very fine doctors who practice it.Tom Ireland, PresidentAmerican Federation of Aviculture </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2094</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 9 No. 2 (1982): APRIL-MAY 1982; 42-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2094/2065</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
