<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2028</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-19T21:26:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding of the Scarier-headed Blackbird</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shelton, Larry C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of the 94 species of icterids, many have frequently been exhibited in zoos and some, such as the common troupial, have long been popular cage birds. However, probably less than 25 species have ever bred in captivity-and certainly none with any regularity. Three reasons for this paucity of captive breeding successes would seem to be: (1) the large quantities and varieties of live food necessary for fledging the young; (2) the difficulty in providing suitable nesting sites and the specialized nesting materials required by some species; and (3) in the case of colonial nesters, sufficient specimens to trigger breeding behavior and enough space to set up territories-a difficult condition in most captive circumstances.The Philadelphia Zoo's experiences in 1978, 1979, and 1980 and early 1981 with the scarlet-headed blackbird (Amb/yramphus ho/osericeus) demonstrate that, with careful management and manipulation, these circumstances can be overcomeeven with a highly sociable acterid such as this species. The only member of its genus, the scarlet-headed blackbird is a splendidly handsome bird-both sexes are velvety black with scarlet head, breast and thighs. It is 9112 inches in length and has a stiletto-like beak. Found from southern Brazil to northern Argentina, this blackbird is an inhabitant of reed beds and marshes. It wades along the water edges, opening its needle-like beak to explore waterlogged debris in its search for insects and other food. W.H. Hudson in Birds of La Plata (1920) has this description:" ... The birds are lively, active and sociable, going in flocks from halfa-dozen to thirty birds; they remain all year and inhabit the marshes, from which they seldom wander very far but seek their insect food in the soft decaying rushes. They are common on the swampy shores of the Plata, and when seen from a distance, perched in their usual manner on the summit of the tall rushes, their flame-colored heads shine with a strong glory above the sere, sombre vegetation ..... </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2028</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 4 (1981): AUG-SEPT 1981; 22-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2028/1999</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
