<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2049</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T01:41:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Avy Award Winners</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A new committee for determiningAvy awards recipients was formed at the 1981 AFA convention in San Diego. The seven members that were nominated for this committee are Robert Berry, Francis Billie, Gene Hall, H. Richard Mattice, Nancy Reed, Larry Shelton, and Dale Thompson. This committee voted for new rules to be used. The basic guidelines were followed, but the rules were simplified. One important rule will be that each award nomination will be checked out carefully through one or more of the committee members. All rules will be published in the Watchbird at a future date.All rules that were voted on will be first used with 1982 award nominations. There will be a certificate award for a First Breeding in the U.S. Avy awards will fall into two categories. The Gold award will be an honor award for those persons who have contributed significantly to the aviculture world. The Silver award will be an achievement award and there are several categories.The Avy awards is one of the few ways to give honor to our fellow aviculturists.Probably the largest group of aviculturists ever assembled in the U.S. was present at the San Diego banquet when the Avy awards were given. There were several unusual first breedings given in 1981 and the award recipients were widely spread throughout the U.S.(Additional photos of Avy Award winners to be shown In future Watchbird issues.)The following are the recipients of the 1981 Avy awards:CATEGORY I, SILVER AWARDIst U.S. captive breeding award James Duroy , undulated tinarnou (Crypyurellus undulatus)Smith &amp;amp; Wells/Blue Sky Aviaries, tinamou (Cryturellus paruirostris) Ramon Noegel &amp;amp; Greg Moss, CaymonBrae Amazon (A. ieucocepbala besterna)Tony Silva, slender bill conureGerald L. Schulman &amp;amp;John Vanderhoof, New Guinea bloodfinchCATEGORY IIIprogress in establishing a new mutation in U.S.Dr. Rainer Erhart, rose mutation of the Bourke parakeetCATEGORY IVconsistant breeding of a difficult speciesPenny Luczak, blue naped parrotCATEGORY Voutstanding show achievement m English budgiesWilfred E. LumbCATEGORY VImost progress with an individual speciesJohn Biggs, Sr. lovebirdsRamon Noegel &amp;amp; Greg Moss, hawkheaded parrotRose Herman, lories Roland Dubuc, lovebirds Louise Dietz, conuresZOO CATEGORYU.S. first breedingPhiladelphia Zoo, Larry Shelton, Emerald starlingSan Diego Zoo, Kerry Muller/ Art Risser, Blue faced honeyeaterGOLD AWARDfor outstanding contribution to a vi cultureRamon Noegel, outstanding work with Caribbean Island Amazons and other psittacinesTom and DeeDee Squyres, for their work in originating and developing the American Cockatiel SocietyJames Gunderson, for furthering the field of aviculture through breeding many species, and his assistance to othersRosemary Low, many years of outstanding contributions to aviculture as breeder and writer.BRONZEA.F.A. service awardsClifton Witt, continuous legislative work Helen Hanson, executive secretary Sharon Claues, 1st commercial, publicoriented "Pet Fair"Jim Reid, 1980 convention chairman, Las VegasMarguerite &amp;amp; John Agrella, CITESendangered species alertRobert ]. Berry, curator of birds, Houston Zoo, best Watchbird article, ''Breeding Cockatoos and Macaws in Captivity," Feb/March 1981 issue.... </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2049</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 5 (1981): OCT-NOV 1981; 44-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2049/2020</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
