<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2352</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T14:45:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Melba Finch</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Black, Robert G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Melba finches are a species that is seen occasionally in aviculture, but they are not plentiful and only very rarely breed successfully. Virtually all of the melba finches available to American aviculture are imported from their native areas of Africa.The melba finch is native over a wide area of central and southern Africa, but not in the areas of rain forests. It is a bird of the scrublands and savannas. The acacia thornlands are a favorite habitat, and they will be found in semidesert areas and desert edges, as long as some thorn cover is available. Though usually found near a water source, the melba finches are also found in the dry Kalahari desert. This indicates that they are well adapted to live for long periods without water.Fortunately, the melba finch has gone through fewer name changes than many of our other common avicultural species. The name "melba finch" is used most widely and commonly, but this bird may also be called the melba waxbill and occasionally the green-winged pytilia.Linnaeus coined the original scientific name for this species in 1758, Fringilla melba. Later research and study resulted in a change of the scientific name to its current form, Pytilia melba. In some older works, you may see the genus name Pytilia spelled Pytelia. Since· melbas are native over such a wide range in Africa, ornithologists have described a number of subspecies that differ slightly in coloring. The songs and calls of the varying subspecies may also differ noticeably.Melba finches are easy to sex once they have reached their adult plumage. As shown in the photographs, the most noticeable difference is the bright red face and yellowish breast of the male, which are totally lacking in the hen. The young cannot be sexed reliably until they begin their molt to adult plumage. The first red feather that appears in the face of a molting youngster will be a sure indication that the bird is a male.Melba finches are waxbills, and like all other waxbills, they eat large amounts of insect food in the wild. This source of protein and other vital nutrients is removed as the bird is trapped and subjected to captivity, shipping, and a lengthy quarantine. Severe stress results, with a high mortality rate once the birds reach their destination. For this reason, melba finches have gained an undeserved reputation for being extremely touchy birds. In their desperate search for the complete protein that their bodies need, newly-imported melbas will often engage in severe featherplucking. Feathers contain the complete protein that they need, and they seem to know this instinctively.For ten years I have harped on protein deficiency in finches, and still over 90% of the finches that I see are suffering from severe protein deficiency. These birds must have a rich source of complete protein to remain in good health, and particularly before any breeding attempts will occur. Melba finches are no exception to this rule. The best natural sources for this complete protein are insects and mashed, hard-boiled eggs. Commercially made foods such as monkey pellets, game bird starter, turkey starter, and dry dog food are also good, if you can get the finches to eat these products. This may take some time, since birds do not recognize these crumbled and pelleted products as food. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2352</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 4 (1985): AUG-SEPT 1985; 50-56</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2352/2325</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
