<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/447</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Red-bellied Maea-ws Reared at Loro Parque</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Low, Rosemary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The red-bellied (Ara manilata) is adistinctive small macaw about 20in(SOcm) in length . Most macaws havepart of the !ores feathered but thetotally bare !ores and yellow facial skindistinguishes manilata from all others.This species is mainly green, with blueon head and wings and a maroon patchon the lower abdomen. Undersides oftail and flight feathers are olive yellow.The bill is black and the iris is darkbrown.It occurs throughout most of theAmazon basin, its distribution coincidingwith that of Mauritia palms onwhich it feeds. Common in the wild, itis rare in captivity, although quite a fewhave been exported from Guyana inrecent years.I believe that the most suitableenvironment for captive birds is an outdooraviary in a warm climate and aspacious indoor aviary in a coolerclimate. A small cage should not beconsidered.At Loro Parque the red-bellied macawwas represented by a pair in the offexhibitbreeding centre and by twomales on exhibit, when I became curatorin February 1987. The pair had beenin residence at least four years withoutattempting to breed. This is not an easysubject in captivity, being extremely susceptibleto stress, also to obesity. Few ofthe wild caught birds which aviculturistsobtain survive more than two years,unlike other Ara species which adaptvery well to captivity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/447</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 1 (1989): FEB-MARCH 1989; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/447/432</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
