<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2053</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T01:42:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Blue Mutation of the Fischer's Lovebird</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The blue Fisher's lovebird that is pictured above is believed to be the true blue mutation of this species. This mutation was bred by Carl Grun of Norco, California. This mutation has been authenticated by several good lovebird aviculrurists. Though observations have been made that a blue Fischer's could be obtained from an out-crossing with the blue-masked lovebird, the above is not the case. This is a mutation that occured while in-breeding the pure Fischer's lovebird. It shows no signs of the Bluemasked x Fischers hybrid. This mutation is recessive and is now in the aviaries of two good aviculturists, Ralph Smith of Calimesa, California, and Rainer Erhart of Kalamazoo, Michigan. It will be exciting to hear of the developments and the new colors that will be obtained from this beautiful mutation .•Endangered Species PortfolioNow A. vailableThe A.F.A. has compiled a series of beautiful prims of many endangered species of birds. The prims are on fine quality paper suitable for framing. The colors are as fantastic as the birds themselves.In addition to the twenty-two fullcolor prims of the birds, the Portfolio contains an introduction by Frank S. Todd, one of the best aviculturists and ornithologists currently at work with birds. Mr. Todd has studied birds in the wild in all parts of the world and has authored numerous scientific papers and the modern classic Waterfowl: Ducks, Geese, and Swans of the World.The captions to the prints (primed separately) were written by Dr. Jean Delacour, the greatest living aviculrurist and bird authority in the world. In his ninety-second year, Dr. Delacour drew upon his vast experience and his fine library at Cle res, France, to set down the pertinent data regarding the various endangered birds presented in the Portfolio. All of Dr. Delacour's work is high on the list of collectables.This outstanding Endangered Species Portfolio was printed in a limited edition of 1000 copies. To get yours while they are still available send $15.00 to the A.F.A. Home Office, P.O. Box 1568, Redondo Beach, CA...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2053</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 6 (1981): DEC-JAN 1981; 13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2053/2024</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
