<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/672</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">President's MessageConservation small grants suspended; a sign of hardeconomic times or a question of priorities?The American Federation of Aviculture has a long standinghistory of providing "se~d money" for avian research andconservation projects. In 1982, the research fund awarded itsfirst five grants. Five years later, in 1987, the conservation fundwas established to aid in important avian field conservationstudies. Over the years, the conservation fund has providedfunds for the study of nearly every kind of bird imaginablefrom trogons to tanagers, hombills to hawk-eagles. For years,the only criterion was that the species needed some conservationaction. Recently, however, as AFA's own "in house"conservation projects expanded, it became apparent that theresimply wasn't enough funds for everything. The criterion forawarding small grants was refined to require the species beingdealt with to, at least, be represented in captivity and anavicultural component be incorporated in the project. With thecoming of age of "avicultural conservation" more proposalscontinued to be submitted.At the winter meeting of the Board of Directors, held in LasVegas, Nevada, the opportunity to support the field release ofBali Mynahs provided the ultimate challenge. The project wastailor made in promoting "aviculture as a field conservationtool" yet no funds were available for the project. AFA's ownRed Siskin project was limping along on a less than $10,000 ayear total budget. The board quickly approved the funding ofthe project but then wrestled, for nearly an hour, trying tolocate a source for the money just pledged. During the recentspring Board of Director's meeting it was decided totemporarily suspend the awarding of all conservation grants.The entire concept of grants for field conservation studieshas always been of debatable value by much of the membership.The theory was that aviculture can learn from fieldstudies and some field conservation strategies can be aided byincluding a bit of aviculture.The financial realities of AFA are a reflection of theorganization's constant desire to provide something tangible toits members in exchange for their dues. A glossy, polishedmagazine, monthly FASTADS, numerous costly mailouts, allhave created a situation whereby the dues had to be increasedsimply to meet the cost of services provided. This situationdoes not provide organizational support of non-service relatedactivities. Special projects and efforts must be funded throughspecial donations and volunteer labor. Long term projects, likethe Red Siskin project, are founded on the belief that funds willcontinue to be donated.Aviculturists invest a great deal in their birds. In many cases,they are holding species endangered in the wild. Possibly thelast of the species. Unfortunately, some species have actuallybeen rendered endangered due to trade itself. We have aresponsibility to the birds themselves to think of them as something other than a possible source of revenue. Carelessconsumptive use of other nations' wildlife will encourage strictgovernmental regulations. A friend who is a native of a ThirdWorld Nation recently asked •' Why should Americans be ableto buy and sell our countries' endangered species in an effort tomake a fast buck?"Having exotic birds is a privilege. Recall that we are not ableto legally possess our own bird life. If the privilege is abusedon the local level, you may have to get rid of your birds. If it isabused on a national level, we all face the possibility of havingto deal with endless permits and inspections. The success wehave in breeding birds frequently will not make a major impacton our own lifestyles but it may determine the very existenceof our birds on planet earth. Consider the fate of the SoccorroIsland Dove had no one bred it. Remember the CarolinaParakeet and those that said, "who would want to breed such acommon bird?"We are doing aviculture and avian conservation a disserviceif we mentally separate the birds from their natural environment.While AFA is no longer providing the conservationgrants, it remains committed to promoting the "big picture" ofexotic birds as residents of planet earth. Thinking of them asonly a means of making a few extra dollars is a short-termconsumptive strategy that does not enhance aviculture or avianconservation.Note: A list of avian field conservation projects is availableat the AFA Business Office (P. 0. Box 56218, Phoenix, AZ85079-6218, Tel. (602) 484-0931) should clubs or individualsdesire to contribute to field conservation projects.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/672</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 50-55</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/672/655</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
