<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/441</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-13T15:46:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Tampa '88</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, Phyllis K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Parrots and Pirates have come and gone from Tampa but not without a lot of good memories, lasting friendships formed and bonded , and a proud smile on the faces of the 14th annual committee personnel of a job well done. AFA started the convention activities with a smashing get-together of board of director members, foreign visitors , speakers , and committee personnel. The attendance was so great we had to order additional Swedish meatballs (at a private party'). The party got underway and was in full swing while President Tom Marshall conducted an executive board meeting next door. After the meeting , the executive board members moved into the party room and started mingling with the group. While I was busy meeting Joe Cuddy and Tony Pittman of the United Kingdom and introducing them to others in the room including Eric Peake, and Dwight and BethGreenberg, two committee personnel who just returned from England, Davis, Vicki, Chuck, Dallas and the others were meeting with other visitors. Moving from group to group,  learned that Juan Santiago was visiting from Puerto Rico and Fraser MacDonald from Nova Scotia and welcomed them to the convention. I soon realized that we had a great group of people already at the hotel preparing for the...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/441</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 6 (1988): DEC-JAN 1989; 38-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/441/426</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
