<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3889</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-17T03:14:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bird Band Passivation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Honig, Matt</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In this new era of laser-engraving technology being used across the globe for bird leg bands, it is important to understand the potential benefits, risks, and pitfalls associated with laser engraving on stainless steel. This article outlines our journey as a company as we work to produce the highest-quality stainless steel bird leg bands possible. It is our hope that this provides breeders, conservationists, zookeepers, pet store owners, and aviculturists with a better understanding of the complexities involved in stainless steel leg band manufacturing.
My name is Matt Honig, and I am the owner of American Bird Bands. For the past four years, we have partnered with the AFA to produce their leg bands in both aluminum and stainless steel. We began with a single laser engraver and quickly determined the settings needed to engrave deeply into both materials. While deep laser engraving works very well for aluminum, it presents a unique challenge when applied to stainless steel—specifically, the engraved areas can become susceptible to rust.
To understand why this occurs, it helps to briefly review why stainless steel is typically resistant to rust. Stainless steel differs from other types of steel because it contains a high percentage of chromium. The two most common grades are 304 and 316 stainless steel. Grade 304 contains approximately 18.5% chromium, while grade 316 contains about 17.5% chromium along with 2.2% molybdenum. The addition of molybdenum makes 316 even more resistant to corrosion than 304.
In both cases, the chromium reacts with oxygen in the air to form a thin protective layer of chromium oxide on the surface of the metal. This layer prevents corrosion. If the surface is scratched, cut, or sanded, the chromium oxide layer is temporarily removed but will usually reform on its own—unless something interferes with that process.
 
[For the full article and image, please continue to the PDF]</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3889</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 52 No. 2 (2025): AFA Watchbird Fall/Winter 2025; 38-41</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
