<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/573</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Holiday with a Difference and a Purpose (a report on an experience in Mexico)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pittman, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It was quiet as we carefully madeour way up the slippery trail, clamberingover the occasional fallen tree,avoiding the hanging Hanas and thevicious thorns on the stems of thechocho palms while picking out thejagged volcanic rock boulders litteringthe path with our flashlights. Aswe neared the top of the ridge, thesky lightened with the rays of the risingsun. The air was cool and damp.At the top, the four of us sat under agigantic strangler fig tree and waitedin silence.The dawn was swift as usual in thetropics. Down below us in the mistcovered valley, the lead male in atroop of howling monkeys began togive voice, the sound echoing againstthe hillsides. Over our heads weheard the unmistakable creaking cryof a Keel-billed Toucan. It wasanswered softly by another and thenwe watched seven dark shapes divedown into the greyness of the valleylike cormorants diving into the sea,bill extended and wings held back. Asthey reached the tree tops lowerdown, they began to fly and disappeared.We listened to one of the manysongs of the White-breasted WoodWren and the forest stirred with daylightlife. The leaf-cutting ants beganto run along their trails with theirload of freshly cut leaves, enteringtheir nest through holes in the top oflittle perfectly formed invertedflowerpot mounds under a nearbytree. Then we heard the lowing ofcattle in the distance and the murmurof people rising and starting the day'swork. The idyll was interrupted andwe were reminded of our purposethere.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/573</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 58-60</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/573/556</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
