<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/896</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:18:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Modern Miracle, Aviculturists United at April 6 USFWS Meeting</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Desborough, Laurella</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Aviculture United!For the first time in the history of aviculture in the United States, a coalition of avicultural groups stood before the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) on April 6 and presented their position on government mandated marking and certification. This meeting was to address only Section 114 of the WBCA: programs in the private sector for marking, certification of facilities, and conservation projects. The presentations were specific in detail and clear in intent: there is no need for governmenc required marking and certification. Many organizations and bird clubs sent letters to the USFWS and many sent representatives who spoke before an audience of 114 people, and presented their comments to the four representatives of USFWS in attendance: Dr. Susan Lieberman, Rosemarie Gnam, MarkPhillips and Roddy Gabel. Themeeting had to be moved fromthe original location due to thelarge number of people in attendanceand therefore , started at10:00 am and continued until 1:00pm. Representatives from the followingorganizations spoke·:African Lovebird Society, American Federation of Aviculture ,American Lory Society, Bird Clubsof America, Canadian Parrot Association,Florida Federation ofAvicultural Societies, InternationalAvicultural Society, InternationalLory Society, International ParrotletSociety, Model AvicultureProgram, National Cockatiel Society,National Finch and SoftbillSociety, and Society of ParrotBreeders and Exhibitors.Representa tive s fr o m lo c a lclubs and clubs across the U.S .made presentations: Arizona AviculturalSociety, Arizona AvianBreeders, Arizona Seedcrackers Society, Avicultural Society ofTucson (AZ), Capitol City Bird Society(CA), Central PennsylvaniaCage Bird Club, Exotic Bird BreedersAssociation (CA), Federation ofPennsylvania Aviculturists, KansasAvicultural Society, KentuckianaBird Society, Orange County BirdBreeders (CA), Parrot Breeders Associationof Virginia, PhiladelphiaAvicultural Society, Raleigh-DurhamCage Bird Club (VA) and SanDiego bird Breeders. Twentystates and 40 organizations wererepresented at this meeting. In addition, bird clubs from across theU. S. sent letters to the USFWS insupport of the AFA position.Representatives from other concernedorganizations and the petindustry made presentations: Associationof Avian Veterinarianswas represe nted by Susan Clubb,DVM; Association for Parrot Conservationwas represented byScott Derickson; Association ofZoos and Aquariums was representedby Don Bruning; PetIndustry Joint Advisory Councilwas represented by MarshallMeyer; Mark Hagen representedthe Canadian Parrot Association;Sun Seed Company was representedby Jeff Clark; and WorldWildlife Fund was represented byGinette Remley.Suzie Sanders of the HumaneSociety of the United States andAnn Michaels of the EnvironmentalInvestigation Agency madepresentations . Teresa Telecky ofHSUS also attended. Laura Simonsof the New Jersey Wild Bird RegulatoryDivision spoke forrequired marking of birds to controlsmuggling. This was the mostcontroversial presentation as Ms.Simons indicated the New Jerseybird law was very successful. Thisis the most restrictive exotic birdlaw in the U.S.AF A Information PacketThe American Federation of A vicultureprepared and presented toUSFWS a packet which includedthe AFA position paper on markingand certification which statedthat no new regulations wereneeded because the private sectoris quite effective in these twoareas. The packet also containedinformation on p ast conservationprojects funded by AFA, as wellas the two major on-going projects:the AFA Red-fronted MacawProject and the AFA Red SiskinProject. Most of the members ofthe AF A Board of Dire c to rs werepresent, including Gary Lilienthal,AFA Legal Counsel and Bob Berry,AFA Executive Director. Mr. Berrypresented the AFA position toUSFWS.In addition to the above, manypeople interested in the WBCAand its effects attended both theaviculture unity meeting onWednesday evening and the meetingheld by USFWS on Thursdaymo rning. The meeting was viodeotapedand audio-taped by theAFA for future reference.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/896</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 3 (1995): MAY-JUNE 1995; 18-19</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/896/878</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
