<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/674</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Visits ...  Emerald Forest Bird Gardens, Inc.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The whole thing really began inIndia in 1969 while Jennings wastraveling. He bought a pair of TricoloredNuns from a roadside vendor.Although his travels lasted a full year,Jennings kept this pair of birds withhim in his car - a mobile aviary, as itwere. He was hooked.Eventually Jennings returned toSouthern California and settled downto work. He also began a bird hobbyto satisfy his fascination with finches-a hold over from his travels with theNuns. I've had the enjoyment ofwatching Jennings, the bird hobbiestdevelop into Jennings, the seriousconservationist, avict:lturist andowner of one of the nicest bird farmsI've seen - Emerald Forest BirdGardens, Inc., in Fallbrook, California.I'm not sure if Emerald Forest islabor efficient or cost effective but Idon't really care. It's the pristinebeauty and tranquility of the locationthat I enjoy and the way in whichJennings has blended the captive collectionof birds in with the local environment,and the environment israther wild and natural. Native wildlifeincludes coyotes, bobcats, the occasionalcougar, racoons, opossums,and skunks. Most of these critters posea predatory threat to the captive birds(fat meals) so Jennings has had to takespecial precautionary measures tokeep the varmints out and the birds in.The area is also home to 12 kinds ofsnakes including four species of rattlers.The property has a natural pondabout an acre in size that attractsnumerous species of wild birds. Someyou won't find in the average backyard are Great Ibis, Cormorants, threespecies of heron, Mallard Ducks,Green-winged Teal and American Wigeon. Dusk brings on the chirpingand booming of two species of treefrogs and at least one huge bullfrog.The Jennings home and office overlooksa large valley. It's the valley thatcontains the pond and aviaries. Theaviaries are scattered about seeminglyat random but the effect is excellent.There are enough hills, gullies andglades that many of the aviaries arerather isolated. The birds have a greatdeal of privacy and, in some cases,probably feel they are still in their ownjungle habitat.There are 250 flights that include afew large pasture-like enclosures. Thepond is fenced also. Some aviaries areconstructed in the old· steel-frame-onthe-ground, traditional manner(except they are on cement pads)while others are of wooden constructionand are actually on the dirt. Thereare numerous banks of the "CaliforniaBreeder" aviaries which are suspendedfrom frameworks so the birdsnever get on the ground. Jennings washappy to point out that all the aviariesare designed to be serviced from theoutside. This gives the birds a greatsense of security and, of course, is easier for the attendant.In addition to the aviaries there areseveral important outbuildings on thefarm. The 1,000 sq. foot nursery islocated somewhat in the center of theproperty. During the heavy breedingseason the nursery is fully utilized.During the off season, the odd handfulof babies are cared for and handfed in the main house. There is a largehospital room that is self containedeven to having a full shower installed;and a new kitchen that will contain allthe modern equipment necessary toprovide fresh, clean food for the largenumbers of birds is currently underconstruction.Emerald Forest Bird Gardens reallydoes house a lot of birds. There are110 species on board. They aredivided about one third parrots, onethird soft-bills and one third waterfowl.I remember when Jennings hada very excellent collection specializingin various finches. Over the years hisinterests have expanded and the currentcollection reflects this.In the soft-billed category Jenningsspecializes in the Ramphastidae -toucans, toucanettes and aracaris.Indeed, the world's largest and most diverse collection of toucans is right here at Emerald Forest Bird Gardens.Jennings has 20 species of this colorfuland somewhat absurd family of birds.Their vivid splashes of color areappropriate to their clown-like antics.Entertaining birds, these.For Jennings, however, there is aserious side to keeping the world'slargest toucan collection. He breedsthem. The tropical and nee-tropicalhabitats of many toucans are disappearingquickly. Many toucan speciesare not established in aviculture at alland other species are represented byonly a few pairs in America. Jenningshas established a non-profit ToucanPreservation Center that has fundedtoucan research in the jungles of Peru.They have a 60' boat to explore thewaterways and glean information onthe resident toucan populations. TheToucan Preservation Center has publishedtwo scientific papers on theirwork.In connection with the toucanresearch, Jennings owns a ranch in theCosta Rican rainforest where he hopesto preserve a suitable habitat to keepand raise toucans. His goal there andin Fallbrook is to establish large captivebreeding populations of the taucan family. With trade in wild-caughtbirds essentially over, this captivebredpopulation will serve as a sourcefor zoos and other serious aviculturists.Jennings feels that not many ofthe soft-billed species will make it inaviculture in the long run. When theycan't be replenished from the wild,they will eventually die out in aviculture.He loves the challenge of breedingsoft-bills --especially the toucans.I've already said that I've knownJennings for 20 years. He is an authenticcharacter who has travelled theworld and has many wild adventuresto tell about - mostly involving birdsand learning more about them. All thiswhile I've enjoyed knowing Jenningsand listening to him. No matter whereyou stand regarding Jerry, bosombuddy or disinterested bystander, youhave to give him credit where it's due.I consider him to be the world's foremostexpert regarding the toucanfamily in aviculture. He has raised 17of the 20 species he keeps and, of the17, at least seven were world firstbreedings.Although the toucans, toucanettesand aracaris dominate the EmeraldForest Bird Garden collection inimportance and achievement, thereare numerous other soft-bills that Iwas very glad to see. The Fairy Bluebirdshave a beautiful, large aviary thatshows them off to great advantage.The tanagers, troupials, mot-mots,touracos and hornbills are birds youdon't see in many collections.In the parrot department, Jenningshas seven species of macaws, ninespecies of cockatoos, Hawk-headedParrots, several eclectus species, a fewAustralian parakeets, and some littlehanging parrotlets. Most of these birdsreproduce.The waterfowl are not as easy toobserve as many of them inhabit theswampy pond and have plenty ofccver. I enjoyed immensely just sittingand watching the action on the pond.It is a real nature treat. The PurpleGallinules are my favorites but theBlack-necked Swans run a closesecond. Actually, at the time of myvisit in early February '93, the waterfowlcollection was in some disarray.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/674</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 60-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/674/657</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
