<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4093</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:20:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cruising to Patagonia, the Falklands and Antarctica</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cunningham, Kirsten</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cunningham, Jason</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 2 (April 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Cruising to See the Penguins of Patagonia,by Kirsten Cunningham with Jason Cunningham Owners of the Everything Bird Store Tampa, FLThe desire to visit such seemingly unreachable destinations and see the various penguins of Antarctica, Argentina, and the Falkland Islands only grew more fervent for me as COVID crushed our chances of boarding that ship not once, but twice—causing us to wait over 3 years for this highly anticipated trip. The cruise season for Antarctica is…well, January, so if a cruise has to be pushed, it is pushed a full year! However, I am pleased to announce that I just returned one month ago from this long-awaited peregrination. Three whole weeks in South America, the Falkland Islands, and Antarctica with my husband, Jason. And now, I’d like to share with you some of what I learned about the birds at the bottom of the world, and some of my travel tips to let you know how I did it—how I always do it—taking a “trip of a lifetime” once or twice a year. Experiences like seeing the Magellanic penguins...Space did not permit printing Kirsten’s full article but if you’d like to know more about her tips for taking trips of a lifetime,check out the digital issue of Watchbird. https://online.flippingbook.com/view/209718674/Birds have always been one of my greatest loves, ever since I was young. I intrinsically began collecting bird toys as a small child, including my painted “parrot on a stick” that I asked for even before I was in kindergarten. Watching wild birds was a frequent pastime, and I begged my parents for a pet parrot. I would also draw birds often as a child, including many penguins with my best friend Sarah, all through middle school and high school.One might think that to see a plethora of birds on a cruise that you’d need to pick one with ports in a tropical locale, such as the Caribbean, Brazil, or Costa Rica. Jason and I have taken those tropical cruises, and we did not see nearly as many birds on those expeditions as we saw in Argentina, Chile, Antarctica, and the Falkland Islands. Merlin Bird ID was an app recommended by one of our fellow cruise patrons that did a great job helping us identify the birds we were seeing, including many types of skuas, petrels, albatross, and of course, penguins!One extra special touch that Norwegian Cruise Line planned for us on this voyage was the addition of three scientists, experts all, on subject matter related to the Antarctic leg of our explorations. They taught us more about the areas we were visiting and really made sure we got the most out of our visit, educationally. Before this cruise, I pictured Antarctica as this icy, rocky, desolate, unforgivingly windy, snowy, and barren wasteland hostile to all life forms. What I learned is that Antarctica has an impressively rich ecosystem if you look closely enough. The sky is full of seabirds. There was a morning off the coast of Deception Island where we could see whale spouts all around the ship. More than a few times we were surrounded by chinstrap penguins porpoising in the water as they dove for small fish and krill, the keystone species of the Antarctic continent. We saw orcas and fin...Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-04-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4093</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 2 (2023): Watchbird April 2023; 22-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4093/4053</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
