<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/525</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Artificial Incubation and Hand,yearing of Red Wattled Lapwings</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, Ron</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In 1987 , the staff at Miami Metrozooartificially incubated six RedwattledLapwing (Vanellus indicus)eggs representing two clutches fromthe same pair. Five of the six eggswere hatched and successfully reared,which was a captive first breeding forthis species in the United States. Sincethen, a total of 23 lapwings have beenraised.Red-wattled Lapwing eggs average42.7 x 30.85 mm in size (26 eggs) andare light brown colored, splotchedwith a darker brown. The eggs aretypically oval shaped, round on oneend and pointed on the other. We donot have any fresh weights on theseeggs as the adults were a llowed tocomplete a clutch before the eggswere pulled for incubation. Theclutch varied between three and foureggs.All eggs were incubated in aHumidaire model #20 self-turning table top incubator. The eggs wereincubated at 99.5 °F and started in amedium humidity at 82 °F wet bulb.Experience has shown that a higherhumidity is required, therefore eggsare incubated in a wetter incubator(90 °F wet bulb). All eggs are weighedthree times per week and graphed tolose 15% of initial weight. It shouldbe noted that because of the shape ofthe lapwing eggs, the fresh weightformula (W = Kw x LB) w ith thestandard weight coefficient does notwork. * Fresh weights of the lapwingeggs will be needed in order to calculatethe proper kw factor. Twentythreeof 26 lapwing eggs havehatched and two eggs were inadve rtently broken d uring incubation. Theincubation p eriod is 29 days and theaverage hatching weight is 14.7grams.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/525</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/525/509</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
