<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3880</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-17T03:14:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">President's message</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Waskey, Lewis</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Greetings,
The American Federation of Aviculture’s 2025 Annual Educational Conference in Raleigh, North Carolina, was a great success and enjoyed by all who attended. Our keynote speaker, Kashmir Csaky, delivered an inspiring presentation to kick off the event.
On Thursday evening, the Legislative Workshop offered both fun and valuable insights. Jodie Olmos and Robin Sullivan presented an engaging role play featuring an animal control officer attempting to enter a parrot owner’s home based on an unjustified complaint from a neighbor. Another scenario depicted a city council proposing restrictions on residents’ ability to own animals. Jodie Olmos, our Legislative Vice President, also presented awards for outstanding legislative efforts and provided an update on the many bills and ordinances that continue to challenge animal ownership.
Friday evening brought the Blues Bash, generously sponsored by Dorothy Paterson, Executive Director of the Bird Endowment. Bennett Hennessy and Dorothy Paterson reported on the remarkable progress made in increasing the Blue-throated Macaw population in Bolivia. Conservation Awards were presented in recognition of outstanding contributions to Blue-throated Macaw conservation—both in-situ and ex-situ.
Saturday morning featured the Youth Program, presented by Adrianne Mock and Julie Corwin, which was well attended and received enthusiastic participation. The conference concluded Saturday evening with the Banquet, where President’s Awards and other honors were presented. The Fabulous Five Raffle drawing, silent auction, and live auction added excitement to a memorable night.
Our 2025 Educational Conference was both fun and enriching for everyone involved. Thank you to all who contributed to its success. We look forward to seeing you next August in St. Louis, Missouri, for our 2026 Educational Conference.
Warm regards,Lewis “Buddy” WaskeyPresident, American Federation of Aviculture, Inc.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3880</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 52 No. 2 (2025): AFA Watchbird Fall/Winter 2025; 3</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
