<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4087</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:20:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Identifying and Overcoming Husbandry Challenges of Great Blue Turacos</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ness, Kristine</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 2 (April 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Identifying and Overcoming Husbandry Challenges of Great Blue TuracosGreat blue turacos (Corythaeola cristata) are a large, showy species that make a great addition to aviaries and quickly capture the fascination of anyone who encounters them. However, great blue turacos have historically been challenging to manage and are notoriously one of the most difficult turacos to care for in captivity. Being able to identify these challenges and finding appropriate ways toknown for fright molting (simultaneously dropping several feathers from the rump, back , and especially the tail) in an attempt to escape a predator when caught. Great blues are susceptible to capture myopathy (exertional rhabdomyolysis), which is a non-infectious disease where excessive exertion or extreme stress leads to serious muscle damage and even death. However by providing the proper housing and environment, turacos can be quite productive in captivity. By learning proper handling techniques and providing adequate medical care these birds can live long healthy lives.The typical nutritional breakdown of the wild great blue turaco’s diet has not been researched adequately, making it challenging to provide a comparable diet in captivity. Studies of great blue turacos in the wild have shown that their diet is composed mainly of about 75% fruit and 25% leaves. In captivity turacos often have loose feces, so providing foliage with fresh young leaves and tender greens is essential.Wild great blue turacos can be rather gregarious and often forage in large flocks and gather in groups of up to twenty birds. In captivity, however, they are often housed in single breeding pairs or small family groups due to limited exhibit spaces and small overall collection size. Depending on the size of the enclosure and density of plant material, some turaco species may be successfully housed together. Great blue turacos usually do best with birds smaller than themselves but will still likely show aggression during the breeding season. Great blue turacos are very prolific and haveClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-04-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4087</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 2 (2023): Watchbird April 2023; 12-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4087/4047</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
