<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1971</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-22T04:12:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Canary Culture: Dominant White Canary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bucci, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Reading the latest issue of Uce//i, a bird publication from Italy, I came across a very important bit of information. I feel obligated to share this information with you. Let me translate and quote from Ucelli:"Recently we came to a clear and precise conclusion. The conclusion was reached during a recent reunion of expert breeders from different parts of Europe . . . When one of the parents possesses double factor "Dominant White" - practical experience has shown that this is possible - none of the offsprings will be yellow. A white dominant canary with double factor, mated to a buff yellow, results in all dominant offspring."I feel obligated to disqualify the statement that double white factor is lethal. For some time, the suspicion has existed that there is nothing lethal about the dominant white canary. Presently, we are in a position to confirm the fact with certainty." The fact that the opposite was accepted does not prove its soundness. With all probability, nobody has ever taken the pain to examine and prove it in reality."Mating dominant white to dominant white is the only way to obtain dominant white canaries of good quality."The above quote is by J. de Ridder for A.O.B. (Belgian Committee for Color Bred Canaries).Back in the February I March 1977 issue of the Watchbird, I wrote an article on white canaries. At that time the lethal theory was accepted, and the article reflected that theory.Mating dominant white to dominant white should give us 25% double white factor offspring (the old theory tells us they would die). These double white factor canaries should be easily recognized.They shouldn't have any of the yellow or orange suffusion on their wing butts and tail-feathers like their brothers and sisters who are carriers of yellow.The double factor is homozygote and the single factor white is heterozygote. Let me show you the difference with the Punett Square: Figure "A" represents the mating of two white canaries. Both parents are heterozygotes (carriers of yellow), and are represented by two chromosomes on the outside of the large square. Within the large square there are four small squares, each represents one offspring. The small square containing the "WW" is the double factor white. The two small squares each containing "Wy" represent two single factor white canaries. The fourth small square containing ''yy" represents a yellow canary.The conclusion can be made that the mating in figure "A" will give us 250Jo double factor white, 500Jo single factor white, and 250Jo yellow. Note that with the previous theory, double white is a lethal factor, and it would be impossible to ever have a living canary of this kind.If we mate a double factor white to a yellow canary (figure "B"), the results are lOOOJo single factor white canaries. A double factor mated to another double factor results in lOOOJo double factor, (figure "C''). And a single factor white mated to a yellow will result in 500Jo white single factor and 500Jo yellow (figure "D'').Next breeding season, those breeders who have white canaries ought to perform a few experiments. The experiment should involve white to white matings, and look for that all white canary (double factor). The subsequent year, mate it to a yellow or another all white (double factor white). The result should be I OOOJo white canaries. The last ought to be repeated several times to remove any doubt.Let all of us pursue in this direction and within two year, come up with a fact, and remove all the doubts for good. I am willing to collect the data from each of you, compile the information, and publish it in the Watchbird. Perhaps some of you have already done some experiments on the subject. Let me hear from you.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1971</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 5 (1980): OCT-NOV 1980; 40-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1971/1942</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
