<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3332</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-08T20:36:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Identify This Chick</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Several members guessed thatthe chick featured in Watchbird,Vol. XXXIX Nos. 2&amp;amp;3 was a toucan, when it was an image of a Green Aracari chick (Pteroglossus viridis), presented by Jason Crean.The species is named for the green feathers covering its back. Males' crowns are black, while females' are reddish-brown.Its diet consists mostly of fruit, including the fruits of Cecropia trees and the palm Oenocarpus bacaba. The serrated edges of the Green Aracari's large bill help the bird to grip and gather fruit. Insects are also an occasional part of the diet, giving the birds protein. Breeding occurs from February to June. It nests in tree cavities, producing two-four white eggs. The parents cooperate in rearing their young.In captivity it is the most frequently bred member of the toucan family and is the most popular as a tame hand-fed pet. It requires a large cage and enrichment to prevent boredom due to its active nature, and a high-fruit diet. When all these requirements are met it is an affectionate companion for many years.John Bornemann correctly identified the baby chick in the photo. Congratulations!Look for additional baby bird pictures received by our membership for you to identify in the future. To submit a photo, please contact the AFA Watchbird editor at afawatchbird@afabirds.org </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3332</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 39 No. 4 (2012): Number 4 2012; 49-50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3332/3316</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
