<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1660</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:51:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">International Conure Association</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">On August 8, 1997, cofounders Brent Andrus and Sandi Brennan, as well as others attending the AFA convention in San Antonio, Texas, formed the International Conure Association (ICA). At that meeting the by-laws were ratified and the first officers were elected.Current Officers President: Sandi Brennan Edgewood, NM Vice President: Fran Smith Ramona, CARecording Secretary: Lisa McManus Aurora, COCorresponding Secretary: Nora Schmidt Corpus Christi, TXTreasurer: Brent Andrus, CPALas Vegas, NThe objectives of the Society are the study of conures in captivity and in the wild, the dissemination of information for the care, breeding, and feeding of conures in the home and aviary, the perpetuation of all conure species, in particular, those threatened with extinction, and the publication of matters pertaining to conures and aviculture.The goals of the International Conure Association are:1. To provide information, in the form of a quarterly journal, on the needs of conures both in the home and aviary.2. To assist persons in locating that perfect pet or breeder, by way of advertisements and hy maintaining a database of members and what they are breeding, selling, or looking to buy.3. To promote the breeding of less common conures hy helping breeders determine what bloodlines they have and where they may find persons who have unrelated ones.4. To keep stud hooks on less common conures.For its members, ICA will send information quarterly, set up so it can easily he kept in a standard three ring notebook. If you wish to sell something you can advertise for a small fee. If you are looking to buy, it is free.ICA maintains a web site at: http:/ /www3.upatsix.com/ica/Check the email list at: lntlConureAssociation@ yahoogroups.com!CA will keep a database of those persons willing to have their names, and phone numbers given out to those seeking information. regarding conures.JCA recognizes that some species of conures are threatened or endangered. Birds can no longer he taken from the wild and imported into the U.S. It is also difficult to transport them from one country to another even if they are captive bred. For that reason, ICA recognizes the need to manage the breeder birds very carefully so that future generations can enjoy them.The !CA plans to start studbooks on those conures whose numbers are so small that they are in danger of being inbred. By tracing bloodlines and keeping records, !CA can help people find unrelated birds when they want to set up pairs for breeding.ICA also accepts articles for its publication. Anything from a diet tip, a funny story, or a picture to a detailed article. Your experience is valuable, share it if you can. Send all articles to PO Box 70123, Las Vegas, NV 89170 ~  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1660</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 3 (2001): Third Quarter 2001; 22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1660/1637</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
