<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3156</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-03T21:02:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Avy Award Categories &amp; Rules</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The deadline is approaching to apply for the most celebrated and esteemed awards presented in American aviculture for those who qualify, the prestigious AFA AVY Awards. The AVY's are considered the highest awards bestowed in U.S. aviculture.Categories are open to AFA members and in some instancesother aviculturists or institutions-who have uniquely distinguished themselves in challenging and difficult areas of aviculture.Although it is not mandatory to award all categories every year, nominations in all areas are encouraged.Nominations for each award category must be submitted by Dec. 31, 2010, to AVY Awards Committee Chairwoman Linda S. Rubin at LSR@CockatielsPlusParrots.com.Nominees will be published in a future issue of the AFA Watchbird and AFA in Brief Awards merited for previous years will be considered for presentation at the 2011 AFA convention when confirmed by the committee.U.S. FIRST BREEDING AVY AWARDS1. Nominations for a First Time Breeding must be within the past five years (exceptions are permitted by committee ruling).2. Nominees must have bred the species for a First Breeding within the United States.3. The nominee does not have to be a member of AFA.4. Each nominee must submit an article, inclusive of dates, on the avicultural details of the First Breeding, which will be submitted to the AF A Watch bird. The editor of the AF A Watch bird will form an article for publication if all relevant facts are included.5. Nominations may be submitted by the breeders of the First Breeding or by any other individual or Affiliated Club.6. Nominees for a First Breeding must establish that the young of the U.S. First Breeding are completely weaned and selfsufficient before submitting the nomination. Birds that are not weaned before nomination deadline ( due to late hatching dates in that calendar year), should be nominated the following year after self-sufficiency has been proven.7. Confirmation of First Breeding nominations will be verified through the AFA Awards Committee.8. Nominations for First Breeding Awards will be published in the AFA Watchbird to aid in their confirmation.9. Scientific names will be used from Maron, Boch &amp;amp; Farrand Jr. 10. Only identifiable subspecies will be given recognition. Subspecies of an avian species that has already been bred in the U.S. will not be awarded unless there is sufficient documentation on both the species previously bred, and the subspecies nominated, provided that there is little difference. The AVY Awards Committee will make the final decision.11. Nominations must be submitted by Dec. 31 of the nominating year. The award will be presented at the AFA convention the following year, which will allow the Awards Committee time to confirm the First Time Breeding.Nomination Requirements for First Breeding Awards Nominees must submit a completed copy of the Breeding History questionnaire.Nominees must submit photographs of both weaned young and of the parent birds for the purpose of documentation and species identification.Nominees must submit a name, address, and phone number, of a witness other than the breeder. Confirmed nominee must submit a completed article for publication in AFA Watchbird.ZOO CATEGORY AVY AWARDSCATEGORY I. Most Progress for the Establishment of an Individual Species or Group of Related Birds.Category 1 recognizes aviculturists who have made the effort to successfully breed a species or related group of birds on a consistent basis.Success must be achieved with a minimum of two pair, or through the second generation if it pertains to a single species.The Awards Committee will judge whether establishment is achieved. Birds with a shorter reproductive life span (such as finches), will need greater numbers produced than birds that have longer reproductive life spans (such as parrots).The difficulty of each species to reproduce offspring will be taken into consideration by the committee.Category II. Breeding a Difficult SpeciesBreeding a significant or highly difficult species reflects the obvious use of sound Management techniques. This category eliminates chance breedings and must be well documented.,1Nomination Requirement for Zoo CategoriesNominations for the Zoo Category awards may be made by zoo personnel from the nominating institution.Achievements must have occurred within the United States. Confirmation of a Zoo Category award nomination will be verified through the Awards Committee.Nominations must include detailed written qualifications for the institution nominated for the Zoo Category award.Nominations for a Zoo Category award must be submitted by Dec. 31 of the nominating year.The award will be presented the following year at the AFA Convention, which allows the committee time to confirm the nomination.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3156</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 37 No. 1 (2010): Number 1  2010; 38-42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3156/3140</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
