<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2312</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-07T16:46:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Convention '85 Preview</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The AFA is proud and honored to announce that the famous Pilkingtons, Clare and Terry, will be the featured budgerigar speakers at the San Francisco Convention August 8, 9, 10 and 11, 1985.They are currently the champion breeders in the United Kingdom. As witnessed by their virtual sweep of the 1982 and 1983 World Shows. They are acknowledged as having the current best stud in England. Beyond that they have written extensively concerning the production of exhibition budgerigars. They are well-versed on all aspects of budgie breeding. The couple has proved to be valuable lecturers in the UK by even the oldest of the old timers.Since they are working with what is acknowledged as being the best budgies in the world, their knowledge of the production of these birds will be instrumental to all of us in the USA who wish to produce this kind of bird.Their appearance at the AFA convention is due solely to the West Coast affiliates of the American Budgerigar Society donating their expenses and thus allowing AFA to be the venue for their lectures. All of the lectures will be preserved on video tape for replay around the US.AFA applaudes the new and close relationship with ABS and we all sincerely hope this is just the beginning of a firm and mutually beneficial relationship.As the Pilkingtons are the current world experts we feel this is an outstanding way to start a new and beneficial cooperative between two of the strongest avicultural organizations in the world. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2312</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 2 (1985): APR-MAY 1985; 43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2312/2286</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
