<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2019</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-26T04:45:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA offers GROUP BIRD INSURANCE to members</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The following incidents are not imaginary. They are true and can be verified for you doubting Thomases.Item. A well-known California aviculturist had his aviaries broken into three times within two weeks and most of his birds were stolen. Some teenage boys were caught but only three birds were recovered. The stress was so great that the aviclturist, already in poor health, had a stroke and died.Item. A Los Angeles county dealer had his shop broken into on a regular basis and thousands of dollars worth of birds were taken. A stake-out operation eventually caught some boys cutting through a roof vent. The boys confessed but almost none of the birds were recovered.Item. A world renowned bird man had his aviaries broken into in broad daylight three times in a week. All of the breeding parrots were taken just prior to the spring 81 breeding season.Item. A local Norco bird dealer suffered an armed robbery and lost a hyacinth macaw.Item. I myself came home one day to find an aviary door swinging open. A pair of blue ringnecks was missing and, of course, never recovered. The emotional shock is great-akin to seeing a loved one have a serious auto accident. The frustrations are even greater. At least in an auto accident one knows the proper steps to take toward recovery.The list of cases that I am personally aware of would fill three pages. And the dollar amount of losses is staggering- way up in the hundreds of thousands of dollars. Often a lifetime of collecting and breeding is destroyed in an instant. Many of us are too old and too poor to rebuild our bird collection once it is destroyed.There is help, however. The A.F.A. offers a totally unique program to insure your birds. With insurance, at least you will collect the money you deemed your birds worth. The above mentioned aviculturists wound up with nothing. Nothing but a terrible depression, frustration and sense of emptiness.The A.F.A. Group Policy offers insurance coverage in the event of death or destruction of an insured member's birds resulting from or made necessary by any of the following perils:1) Fire, including consequential damage resulting therefrom as hereinafter provided, or lightning which strikes premises;2) Riot and civil commotion;3) Explosion, Smoke damage, Sonic boom;4) Aircraft, meaning thereby direct loss or damage caused by objects falling therefrom;5) Earthquake; Flood (meaning rising waters including breakage of boundaries) of rivers, lakes, dams, and similar bodies of water;6) Collapse of buildings, bridges, or culverts;7) Collision, derailment, or overturning of conveyance while in transit by railroad and I or motor vehicles;8) Windstorm, cyclone, or tornado, and wind driven rain or hail;9) Being accidentally struck or run over by any vehicle other than one owned or operated by or for the assured;10) Domestic or predatory animals;11) Vandalism or malicious mischief;12) Theft or Burglary;13) Accidental shooting except by the insured or employees of the insured. For as little as l 1/2 % annual premium based upon the declared value of the insured birds, you can insure your birds through A. F .A. Insured members will receive their own policy statement outlining the above described coverages and procedures for making claims in the event of loss. Each claim will include a deductible as low as $100.00 per claim.Due to the numbers of birds and the high population density, California aviculrurists are especially vulnerable to thievery. The A.F.A. does not want to see a single member lose their hobby or business to burglars. Please, for your protection, send your name and complete address to the home office for a group bird insurance application."American Federation of Aviculrure (Group Bird Insurance)P.O. Box 1568Redondo Beach, Ca. 90278 (213) 3 72-2988 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2019</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 3 (1981): JUNE-JULY 1981; 28</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2019/1990</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
