<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/460</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the editor's desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Watchbird magazine is undernew editorship as of November 18,1988 . jack Clinton-Eitniear, SanAntonio, Texas ; Dale R. Thompson,Canyon Country, California; JerryJennings, Woodland Hills, California,will be serving as the editorial staff.Eitniear has been a contributingauthor to Watchbird for many years.He is president of the InternationalSoftbill Society and editor of its quarterlybulletin, "The Honeycreeper; 'editor of "The Eyas;' a publication ofthe Institute of Wildlife Managementof the National Wildlife Federation'sRaptor Information Center, LatinAmerican Region. He also servesas co-editor for Vulture News, a journalof the Vulture Study Group of theEndangered Wildlife Trust, SouthAfrica. Eitniear has published overfifty articles, both popular and scientific,in various magazines, journalsand bulletins and has made literarycontributions to several books andfilms .Thompson is one of AFA's originalmembers and a long-standing contributorof fine photos and articles tothe Watchbird and has served manyyears as staff photographer. Thompsonwas assistant curator of birds atthe Los Angeles Zoo during the '60sand through the mid '70s. He thenmoved on to become director ofBehavioral Study of Birds , Ltd. ,Newhall, California. In addition to hisregular contributions of talent to theWatchbird, he has served AFA as AvyAwards chairman and conventionspeaker committee chairman. Someof his current projects are involvingproduction of wildlife programs forPBS television.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/460</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 1 (1989): FEB-MARCH 1989; 43-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/460/445</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
