<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1154</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:31:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">INDOOR AVIARY DESIGN AND MANAGEMENT ... Passing the Test: Becoming a Breeder Bird in the Future Breeder Program</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hartman, Steven P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">At Hartman Aviary we have approximately 100 pairs of vared species of psitticines set up for breeding at any one time. Of these, approximately 20% are domestically raised birds. Often we have as many as 50 additional individuals in our future breeders program. This group consists of many species of all ages that are in the process of getting their education, maturing and developing a bond with their future breeding partner.My primary objective with aviculture is to selectively breed a better pet bird (keeping in mind that I also would like to make some money at the same time). To this end we tend to be choosy about the individuals that make it into our breeder program. We avoid prospects that have developed neurotic tendencies like plucking, screaming and biting, and we steer toward birds who have had pet experience through adolescence and still remain an acceptable pet.When a pet owner calls and tells me they have a wonderful bird who they can't stand anymore because of the screaming, biting and his indecent exposure I counsel them on rehabilitation or steer them to another breeder. The exception to this agenda is when the subject is a rare bird who needs to be bred to maintain the gene pool.Feeding, Weaning and SocializationAll of our birds produced for future breeding stock are parent reared, when possible, until about three weeks of age and then removed for weaning by humans. I am not opposed to parent weaned birds for breeding stock but feel there is little to be gained by this practice and much to lose through decreased production by the parents. Leaving young birds with their parents also necessitates a larger cage space to wean and allow socialization of the offspring for up to one year. This practice would also deprive young birds from interacting with other adults and chicks of their own age. While we often romanticize the positive benefits of the parent-chick relationship, I feel that most of the benefits have a genetic predisposition at their roots. For instance, I believe the weaning and early nurturing behaviors often cited as benefits can be encouraged almost as well by humans because of the genetic imperative of these traits.Introduction to SocietyAll parrots at Hartman Aviary are integrated into a flock after they have passed through the quarantine process. This flocking occurs in our future breeding zone. The purpose of this program is three fold:Our first goal is to physically condition the birds until we know they are in excellent condition. Many of the birds used for production in the United States have had a previous life as a pet. We find many instances where these birds were not properly cared for, mentally and physically, by very well intentioned owners. This condition also occurs in commercial aviaries through out the world.The second reason for flocking is for the birds to learn to communicate with each other. Birds raised as pets, housed in breeding facilities, or raised only by their parents have had limited exposure to other parrots. Parrots communicate primarily through body language and humans typically override their natural instinct to read body language with second guessing thoughts. This causes a great deal of confusion in a baby parrot. Parrots are just like humans in that we need more than just our families to learn to communicate in the real world. Since our birds are forced to choose a mate in somewhat abnormal circumstance, even in the best of domestic scenarios, I take this challenge very seriously. Our parrots are housed in groups of 20 or more parrots of several different species, large and small. Depending upon the past history of an individual it may stay in the flock for a minimum of six months up to years. During this time individuals learn how to behave and hopefully develop the desire to become over achievers.The third reason for flocking is for each individual and each pair to comprehend flock etiquette. From a bird's standpoint, not only is this important to survive being locked in a cage with another bird all your life, but you need to know what is on the minds of the couples housed around you. When you have a very dominate male across the aisle constantly staring you down, does it mean that he hates you or just doesn't want you coming into his territory .? Should you be feeling intimidated or be sticking your tongue out at him? In a flock situation an individual and or a pair can find out what it is all about to come too close to another's mate or to wander into an area claimed as home territory by another pair. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1154</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 3 (1997): MAY-JUNE 1997; 27-28</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1154/1133</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
