<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1324</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:34:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Convention Corner '99 Denver, August 11-- 15</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Davis, Kelly</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AF A's 25th Anniversary Convention is taking place at the Adam's Mark Hotel in exciting downtown Denver, Colorado. This year AFA's speaker line-up includes numerous interesting and beneficial presentations and topics for everyone. Whether you are a bird breeder, or you just purchased your first pet bird, AF A Convention '99 has a session for you. Don't miss this once-ayear opportunity to hear great speakers on bird breeding, nutrition, mutations, buying your first bird, and much more! Listed below are some of the great speakers lined-up for the AFA's Silver Anniversary Convention. • John V. Azua, Curator of Birds, Denver Zoo, will be discussing the captive propagation of the Palm Cockatoo at the Denver Zoo. • Nancy Chambers, from New Yark City and owner of Urban Bird, will give her talk on breeding in the city. • June DiCiocco, owner of Hideaway Farms, is speaking on the rare Finsch's Conure and other red headed Aratingas. • Amy Kendall Flanagan and Eileen Maher, San Diego Zoo, are speaking on breeding the Northern Blue Dacnis at the San Diego Zoo. • Daniel Garza, Catalina Porras, Juan Vargas, and Edward Inigo from the ARA Foundation in Isla Socorro, Mexico will be talking about the capture and breeding of the Socorro (green) Parakeet. • Ken Graham, from Arizona, has been successfully maintaining and breeding the Lilac-breasted Roller. He will discuss the specifics of how and why he succeeded. • Malcolm Green will be joining the AF A from the UK to discuss the pros and cons of pellets vs. supplements. • Alan Lieberman, from the Peregrine Fund, is speaking on the translocation and establishment of a new population of Ultramarine Lories in the French Polynesian Marquesas Islands. • Dawn-Michelle Atallian and Andy Maycen, also from the San Diego Zoo, are discussing breeding the Wrinkled Hombill. • Teri McAuliffe, of Jungle Paradise, shares her experiences traveling with eggs and hatchlings. • Steve Martin, of Natural Encounters, will present how to get a better understanding of your birds. • Jeff and Edna McConnell will tell us how to get a breeding loan, and if it will work. • Alicia McWatters, Ph.D., of Holistic Avian Healthcare, will be talking on strengthening bird's immune system through natural methods. • Andrea Medrano, from the Chaffee Zoo in Fresno, California, will he speaking on approaches to keeping free flight Australian birds at Chaffee Zoo. • Julie Weiss Murad, from the Gabriel Foundation, is speaking on rescue, rehabilitation, adoption, and sanctuary: a practical approach and also on the Pet Trac, unwanted birds: what you can do to help. • Bob Nelson, a private avicul- turist, is discussing the Quaker Parakeet and its mutations. • Bill Nichelmann is the presi- dent of Capitol City Bird Society in Northern California and is discussing how their Crisis Management Team has been successful. • Shelly Nice, from the Dallas World Aquarium, will be talking about the 16 species free-flight toucan exhibit at the aquarium. • Mike Perrin, from South Africa, is presenting on the conserva- tion biology of the Cape Parrot, Poicepbalus robustus. • Lyrae Perry, breeder of Asiatic parakeets, will be talking on the identification, care, and breeding of all species of Psittacula. • Gamini Ratnavira, of Hidden Forest Art Gallery, is speaking about a visit to the Emerald Isle - Sri Lankan Wildlife. • Tani Robar, from Seattle, Washington will be on hand to demonstrate how to trick train your bird. • Janice Rothe, owner of Presents for Polly, will be talking about safe bird toys and give a workshop where you can make your own bird toy. • Carmen Rowe, also from Seattle, Washington, will be discussing the importance of international trade in wild-caught parrots. • Linda Rubin, president-elect of the National Cockatiel Society, will be talking on Cockatiel mutations in the new millennium. • Daniel Shearing, from the UK, will talking about the concept of quality as applied to aviculture. • Tani Smida, owner of Birdlady's Babes, will be discussing nutrition and its importance in an aviary management plan. • Paula Strasser, of Pippin's Roost Exotics, will be talking about setting up a bird nursery. • Barry Wold, of Shingle Springs, California, will be presenting on the legislative and citation process. As you can see, Convention '99 has a topic for everyone. AFA will be hosting speakers from far parts of the world and on a wide variety of topics. Besides an array of educational speakers, AF A's exhibit hall will allow you to see the latest and greatest in avian equipment and supplies. Help AFA celebrate its 25th Silver Anniversary in Denver Colorado at Convention '99. Make plans now to attend! </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1324</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 3 (1999): MAY-JUNE 1999; 31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1324/1302</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
