<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4028</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From Blue and Gold to Global Goldens</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Redden, Lynn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 2 (April/May 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.In the heart of avian passion, a journey began 25 years ago with a single pair of Blue and Gold macaws. Unbeknownst to their caretakers, this endeavor would evolve into a global phenomenon, centered around the vibrant and captivating “Golden Macaws.” The journey took an unexpected turn when three lutino chicks hatched from a single clutch of the original pair, sparking curiosity and a quest for understanding. Armed with photographs, the enthusiasts ventured to the American Federation of Aviculture (AFA) convention, seeking guidance. The response wasoverwhelming, and with the support garnered, a breeding program was set into motion. Patiently awaiting the maturation of their avian companions, the breeders refrained from selling any golden macaws until they had amassed a flock of 20, proving that the elusive trait was a genetic recessive lutino and not sex -linked. With each generation, the program thrived, establishing the groundwork for a unique legacy.The impact of this breeding initiative has transcended borders, with these majestic birds finding homes worldwide. The success has not only brought joy to enthusiasts but has also inspired others to embark on their own golden macaw breeding endeavors.From the intimate enclosure of the original pair&amp;#x27;s aviary to the far reaches of the avicultural communities, the golden macaws have become ambassadors of passion and perseverance. As the legacy continues to spread its wings, the original caretakers were awarded the coveted American Federation of Aviculture’s Silver Avy Award for establishing a new mutation within a species and they can take pride in knowing that their dedication has fostered not only a vibrant avian community, but also a global appreciation for the resplendent beauty of the golden macaw.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4028</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 2 (2024): Watchbird April/May 2024; 22-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4028/3988</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
