<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2328</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-08T18:07:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">First Captive Breeding of the Spot-billed Toucanet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The spot billed toucanet (Selenidera maculirostris) is one of six similar appearing members of the lowland toucanet genus Selenidera, which replace each other geographically in Central and South American forests from northern Honduras to southern Brasil and northern Argentina. All six species exhibit heavy sexual dimorphism and, in contrast to the mountain toucanets, e.g., emeralds, crimson rumps, etc., are extremely colorful in appearance.The sexes are similarly patterned, but differently colored. The male's head, neck, and breast are black, whereas the female's are brown. The back, wings, abdomen, rump and chestnut-tipped tail are olive green. A yellow collar separates the head from the back. The flanks and thighs are chestnut, the vent crimson. The bill, for which this toucanet is named, is greenish gray except for a series of vertically elongated spots on the sides of the upper mandible. Each bird's beak is so uniquely patterned as to make it individually identifiable.The facial skin surrounding the eye of the spot bill is unusually extensive for a Ramphastid (a feature totally lacking in the mountain toucanets) and is a brilliant turquoise blue. To the rear of the facial skin begin brilliant yellow ear coverts that extend outward into tufts in the male. The eye itself is unique as the iris, yellow in color, is horizontally banded giving the appearance of an amphibian.The spot bill is a lowland forest dweller ranging from southeastern Brazil to the northern part of Argentina. Little information is available on habitat and behavior, let alone the spot bill's status in the wild, an unfortunate though common story among toucans.The history of spot bills in captivity is sketchy as well. Few specimens have been imported into the U.S. and most aviculturists have never seen this delightful creature. If the spot bill is rare, the other members of the genus are virtually nonexistent in zoological collections.In early 1983 a small number of birds were imported from Argentina into California, Florida, and perhaps New York. Prior to that time an occasional bird appeared, usually a male, but no pairs were established, as far as it is known. With the exception of a hatching and early death of one chick at the London Zoo in 1917, no other known captive breeding attempts have occured in the Western world.In February 1983, I acquired two pairs of spot bills from a Florida importer. After a routine veterinary health examination and thirty day isolation, the birds were placed together in an unplanted 8' x 12' x 6' aviary, where they remained several months for evaluation. After the birds had settled down and adjusted to their new environment, one male and one female were observed constantly sitting together, while the other two remained aloof and apart. The interested parties were subsequently removed to a planted flight of identical dimensions, where they were housed alone.The flight design consists of a shelter covered on the top, sides and back, occupying one third of the enclosure, the remainder of which is screened in halfinch hardware cloth and open to the elements year round. The plantings consist of honeysuckle vine, potato vine, and Brazilian pepper tree, all of which were overgrown through the top of the flight providing constant shade.A nest log taken from a palm tree, measuring approximately three feet in length and nine inches in diameter, was hollowed out with a chain saw to an internal depth of approximately eighteen inches and a diameter of six inches. A two and a half inch entry hold was made in the side of the log approximately three inches below the top. The top of the log was covered with a one inch, cut to fit, pine lid. This nest was placed on a platform in one comer of the shelter as close to the ceiling as possible.It was over a year after the spot bills were set up, before they paid any attention to their nest log. In May 1984 they were observed entering and leaving the nest over a period of several days and could frequently be heard digging inside. By the 14th of May it was apparent they had begun to incubate, both parents sharing the duties. Throughout the incubation period, and after the chicks hatched, the male continued to excavate and otherwise remodel the interior. On May 28th the first faint sounds of nestlings could be heard from within the log, which was not visually inspected, however, untilJune 18th out of fear that any disturbance would result in abandonment. All observations were made with the aid of a small mirror, inserted throught the entrance hole, and a flashlight. The chicks were checked in this fashion every other day.At approximately twenty-five days of age, head and throat feathers are sufficiently developed to make sexual determination possible. Since both chicks were males, they were removed for handfeeding in the expectation the parents would recycle and produce females, which they subsequently did. Since this nest was never disturbed from the onset of laying until the chicks were approximately three weeks of age, it is not known how many eggs were laid or how many chicks hatched.Throughout the nesting cycle the parents were fed an ambitious diet of Purina Hi-Pro Dog Kibble (served dry), grapes, diced apple, banana, papaya; peas, com, carrots, mealworms and a mouse daily. Fresh water was available at all times and the fruit was sprinkled with Vionate vitamins. It should be noted that the yound receive their moisture entirely from the fruit and not from the drinking water available to the parents.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2328</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 3 (1985): JUNE-JULY 1985; 36-38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2328/2301</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
