<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/723</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cute Songstrous Glosters</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vigran, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Attractive, diminutive, easy to breedand easy to care for, Gloster canariesare one of the most in-demand type ofcanaries today.Lacking the in-depth history ofmany canary varieties, the Glostercanary is a fairly new phenomenon,first a pp~aring on the British showbench in the 1920's. In a crossing ofrollers, cresteds and borders, Mrs.Rogerson is credited for starting theGloster fancy further popularized byactive show enthusiasts of the time.Mrs. Rogerson hailed from GloucestershireCounty, hence the nameGloster for the type.Glosters come in two compatibletypes; the corona or crested bird andthe consort without a crest. Eithermale or female can have the crest -but a crest must be bred to a non-crest- a corona to a consort.Breeding crest to crest can cause notonly undesirable visual damage butmay cause damage to the cranial bonestructure and produce a lethal genecombination where chicks will die inthe shell or shortly after hatching.The ideal Gloster should have ashort, cobby body approximately fourto four and a half inches in length. Thetail should not be exceedingly longand if crested, the crest should radiatein a uniform fashion from a goodcenter and the feathers should comedown to, but not block, the eyes, leavingthem discernible. A show birdshould sit balanced on the perch withno swaying or hunching of the back.Unlike some of the larger canarybreeds, Glosters are fairly easy tobreed. As previously mentioned, onebird will have a crest, the other shouldnot and it doesn't matter who has thecrest.Care should be given in matchingpairs. If a hard-feathered bird (onewith tight feathering) is used, a softfeathered(more loose feathering)mate should be chosen.Glosters lay three to five eggs and itis best to remove eggs so they won'tstart developing until the last egg islaid (often a different shade of blue). Ifall the eggs start incubation togetherthere is less of a risk of losing a babythat is younger and smaller and cannotstretch as far as its older siblingsfor food from the parents.An open nest of wicker or an openbox can be used. Grasses, cottonstring and washed burlap make goodnesting material. When the hen isready, and only when she is ready,she will spend a day, maybe two,building and preparing her nest, testingit often by sitting in it and makingproper adjustments.Eggs hatch in 13 to 15 days and mosthens will remain quite tight to the nestfor the first week. Baby Glostersshould be banded at six or seven toeight days when pin feathers are evidenton the wings - any earlier andthe bands may fall off or the hen mayremove them; any later and thebabies' feet will have grown too largeto get the bands on.It's fun to watch the babies develop,which can be done easily in the opennestenvironment. The male will helpwith the feeding and sometimes sit onthe nest when the hen leaves for abreak.Gloster babies fledge at approximately21 days. A second nesting sitewith fresh material should be offeredor the hen may decide her offsprings'feathers may line her new nest verywell.Once fledged, the young with theirfather can be separated from the hen.The male can be removed once a dayfor a short period of time and placedback with the hen to fertilize her newclutch of eggs, but should be backwith the chicks to spend approximatelythe next two weeks weaningthem.Hard boiled eggs or commercial eggfood and spray millet work well asweaning tools. The babies will flydown and beg from their father at thefood dish and soon learn where thefood actually comes from.A seed diet needs to be supplementedwith green, leafy vegetablesand whole grain bread as well as otherfruit and vegetable treats the canarieswill take. Egg food can be offered asan enticement to begin nesting, butshould be limited while the hen isincubating her eggs. Once babieshatch, fresh egg food a couple times aday will encourage feeding.Grit should be offered to canaries aswell as ground, dried egg shells, cuttleboneand/ or commercial calciumpowder. Canary hens, especially,require a lot of calcium for egg production.A lack of calcium can resultin soft shelled eggs or the inability tolay eggs altogether. This can be fatalto the hen.Many young male Glosters will try towarble a little song at eight or 10weeks of age. However, they won'tdevelop their full song until after theirfirst molt at four to six months of age.Most bird fanciers and breeders aresold on the pleasure brought by a canary'ssong. Glosters, with their cuteBeatle-like haircut appearances, havelooks to match their songs. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/723</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/723/706</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
