<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3205</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-30T12:46:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Specialties Meet at Magical Event</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">II f nother spellbinding array of ~ meetings was held during the AFA Magic of Birds 36th annual convention in St. Petersburg, Fla. Continuing this historic tradition-where national specialty members gathered for information and cameraderie-AFA is watching its affiliates begin to grow and change with the times over the years.Thursday night began the traditional meetings with the August convention drawing an increase in numbers from recent years.Participants this year included the Caique Enthusiasts, Cockatiel Foundation, Florida Federation of Aviculture, International Conure Association, Lineolated Parakeet Society, Lory League, and Pionus Breeders Association. Firsttime meetings at the convention were held for both the Cockatiel Foundation, Inc. and the recently formed Lory League. (Any of the AFA Specialties can be located under Specialty Groups on the AFA website, www.AFAbirds. org).Meetings began by 6 p.m. and ended by 9 p.m. and were held in multiple rooms, running between one to two hours, depending upon interest. Some assemblies included introductions, member discussion of topical events, subjects of mutual interests, questions and answers, or additional speaker talks and presentations.The Florida Federation of Aviculture held a special and memorable memorial for Bill Richardson, a well-known AFA member and highly regarded aviculturist who passed away just before the convention. The memorial was well attended by aviculturists and attendees wishing to pay their respects.All in all, the meetings ran smoothly and provided a venue for membersto get reacquainted, learn new or important topic and event information, or just relax and socialize.The 2011 convention is already organizing to include the AFA Specialty Affiliates on Thursday evening, with the possibility of spilling into Friday night, depending upon the demand. Specialties that sign up early get first choice selection of meeting times and it is recommended to respond early.Notifications to specialty delegates have already been sent out in the AFA Specialties and Affiliates Quarterly newsletter, volume 2.1, which is also being loaded on the AFA website.For more information on the 2011 specialty meetings, please contact Specialty Organization Vice President Linda S. Rubin at LSR@CockatielsPlus Parrots.com.The newly formed AFA Specialty: Lory League The newly formed Lory League had a good turnout and drew a lot of interest in St. Petersburg.According to Andrew Cook, Founder of the Lory League, "Since its founding, the Lory League has quickly become very active in responsibly promoting lories, educating on their proper care, and bringing together breeders and owners. We've been able to sponsor lories for teachers where the lory can become an integral part of the lesson plan with regards to art, reading, health, science, and even helping with social and behavior skills. And we're really hoping to help fund zoo exhibits and conservation programs."Andrew continues, "The Lory League is also actively bringing in youth through Junior Lory Leaguers and Camp Lory, to train young people on lory biology and behaviors, and on proper care oflories. We hope to have young aviculturists trained to participate in conservation field work and captive breeding programs."Our group is focusing on thesocial aspect by hosting regular meetings, becoming involved with sponsoring bird shows, and proudly affiliating with national aviculture groups like the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc."We recently hosted a workshop and participated in the vendors hall at the AFA Convention in Florida. It was a successful and fun event that brought all kinds of lory people of different backgrounds together."The pinnacle of the Lory Leagueis the annual Lory Show where we bring in speakers from the U.S. and around the world to educate the public on lories. We include youth programs, interactive lory exhibits, a lory walkthrough, lories for sale, the pet shop lory lab, and so much more."The next Lory Show event is April 7-10, 2011 at Yard Birds Mall and Events Center in Chehalis, Wash., and is a part of CreatureFest. Admission is free to the public. We want everyone to come to learn about and enjoy lories."The Lory League is a pro-aviculture club and welcomes all members who own, breed, or have an interest in lories from anywhere in the United States. The Lory League is even free to join. There's many ways anyone can become involved and really have fun with lory enthusiasts, and of course, with the lories themselves."For further information on the Lory League, visit http://pets.groups.yahoo. com/group/nwloryleague.To learn more about any of the AFA Specialty Organizations, or to visit their websites or contact delegates, visit www.afabirds.org/specialty.shtml. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3205</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 37 No. 4 (2010): Number 4  2010; 25-26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3205/3189</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
