<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2632</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-13T16:14:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Parrot Pediatrics: Recognizing and Preventing Common Diseases</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Murphy, Joel D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Pediatric problems face both the experienced aviculturist and the novice. As we advance in our knowledge of avian science and husbandry, new diseases have been found as well as solutions to old problems. Raising baby parrots will always be as much art as science. This discussion, however, will primarily deal with the science and medicine of baby parrots.Reasons for Handfeeding1. Tame babies - Imprinting to people is probably the best reason.2. Abandonment - Lovebirds, cockatiels, prolific parents often abandon babies, making it necessary to raise by hand.3. Poor maternal instincts - Broken eggs, injured babies.4. Increase number of clutches - Many pairs will go back to nest after babies have been removed if environmental and nutritional factors are right.5. Weather conditions6. Disturbances - Visitors, animals.Handfeeding Recommendations1. Remove babies from the nest at two to three weeks of age to allow normal bacterial flora establishment and vigor. Expert aviculturis t can remove babies earlier without problems.2. Keep each clutch in separate brooders to reduce spread of viral and bacterial disease. Do not allow any utensil or syringe to be shared between each brooder.3. Keep babies warm.day 1 - 99.5 ° Fahrenheit day 2 through 10 - 95 to 97 ° day 10 to 4 weeks - 85 ° feathered chicks - 7 5 to 80 °Make sure that in keeping the babies warm the heat is from an indirect source. Heat lamps and heating pads often cause overheating and burns. Be extremely careful if using a direct heat source.When checking the temperature of the brooder, if using direct heat, make sure that you are measuring the temperature where the babies are sitting as temperature can vary greatly.The best brooders are pediatric incubators which can often be purchased used from a hospital. If these are not available, numerous manufacturers make bird brooders and advertise in bird publications. These brooders are usually very expensive compared with used medical incubators, however.4. Keep clean - Shredded paper is one of the best substrates for the floor as it is easy to change and non toxic.Disposable diapers are also an excellent substrate. Crushed walnut shells sold as Critter Litter make a good substrate.Avoid material with fiber. Baby birds have an uncanny ability to wrap any fiber around their extremities usually resulting in leg injuries.Avoid corn cob and wood shavings as the babies often consume these products and sometimes require surgical removal. Also, corn cob often causes a thick, oily dust that causes sinusitis.5. Incubator/brooders should have square walls. Curved walls predispose leg deformities.6. Feeding utensils should be used for only one incubator and sterilized after each feeding. Wash hands with disinfectant to reduce spread of virus and bacterial disease.7. Mix food fresh or use Micro Block by Phoenix to prevent bacterial growth in food.8. If using Monkey Chow, make sure to boil it as it can sometimes contain gram negative bacteria.9. Make sure feeding formula is warm but not hot as it can burn the crop. Be especially careful with microwaved food as it can have hot spots. Heat to between 98 ° and 100 °. Keep food cooler than 105 °.Handfeeding Formulas There are probably as many handfeeding formulas as there are aviculturists. Some are excellent and some leave much to be desired. If a handfeeding formula is time proven and results in healthy babies, it is probably fine. Most of the handfeeding formulas that I computer analyze are incomplete but, with the addition of a few nutrients, do well. There are numerous commercially prepared handfeeding formulas that may or may not result in as good a diet for your baby as a homemade diet.In general, I recommend sticking with a formula if it works for your babies. Diets that work well for another aviculturist may not always work well for your birds. Have your veterinarian computer analyze the diet to make sure the protein, vitamin, and calcium levels are adequate. If the babies have poor weight gain, poor feathering, stress lines on the feathers, spraddle leg, frequent fractures, beak deformities, or die of vitamin overdose, switch to one of the commercial prepared handfeeding formulas.One of the advantages of the commercially prepared formulas such as Lake's Parrot Buffet, Roudybush, or Lafeber is that all you have to add is water. This can be a real time saver compared to some of the handmade diets we analyze.The handfeeding formula should be made fresh at each feeding to prevent bacterial overgrowth. Bacterial overgrowth can occur as soon as 30 minutes after mixing...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2632</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 2 (1991): APR-MAY 1991; 21-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2632/2602</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
