<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4165</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T23:56:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">First - Do No Harm!</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Darden, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 3 (July 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Another bustling baby season has arrived. Up with the summer sun, birds are belting out territorial warnings and beautiful sunrise serenades, as youngsters beg for breakfast. Even with mom and dad on 24/7 duty, the infant mortality rate is high for all feathered creatures. Birds are fantastic parents but they must take their own survival into account as well, and it can be hard for humans to accept that if the risk is too high, they may abandon their nests and chicks. Those nestlings need help but many babies that come into rehabilitation centers are healthy fledglings with attentive parents, that have been kidnapped by well-meaning humans. Deciding to intervene in the name of helping or taking a hands-off approach and trusting nature requires a little homework, patience and observation.allows rain to drain through. Hang it on a branch as high up as you can or nail it to the tree. Just make sure it’s secure so it won’t be knocked or blown off and the baby will not tumble out. Watch from a distance, ideally inside your house, for one to two hours to see if mom and dad hear the baby and return. Birds are wonderful parents and will always care for their babies if they’re able to. Put gloves on to handle wild birds because they have parasites, lice, mites, ticks, bacteria and diseases or wash your hands thoroughly afterwards. If you don’t see any activity, line a small box with a soft cloth or paper towels, poke breathing holes in it and place the baby inside. This will keep it calm while you call a local rehabber for assistance. Keep the box away from loud noises, pets and children. Fill a sock with birdseed or uncooked rice and warm in the microwave for 20 to 30 seconds....It’s important to first identify what you have found; a hatchling, nestling or fledgling.  Hatchling – a newborn recently hatchedfrom an egg, bald, eyes closed.  Nestling – less than two weeks old with aThank you to Patricia Slakey, a songbird rehabber, who graciously provided information for this article despite being in the middle of baby season.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-07-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4165</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 3 (2023): Watchbird July 2023; 10-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4165/4125</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
