<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/887</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:17:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">What Does it Take to Become an American Budgerigar Society Judge?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Denny, Don</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To become a champion exhibitor or an American Budgerigar SocietyCABS) judge in this hobby is equal inmy mind to a person wanting tobecome a superstar in any sport! Howmany people become a Barry Bondsin baseball, a Joe Montana in footballor a Michael Jordan in basketball?We have our superstars in birds, justas they do in the cat, dog, rabbit andhorse hobbies. Everyone cannot be asuperstar, just as everyone does notaspire to become a judge. However,the following thoughts reflect what Ibelieve it takes to become a successfulA. B.S. panel judge.First, advance from novice to showmanchampion. Second, become asuccessful winning champion exhibitorwith wins in three different shows,under three different judges (placingeither first, second or third). Becomean active, participating member of alocal A.B.S. affiliate club. Meet all thequalifications and rules to qualify, andlast, pass all testing procedures inforce at the time of your application.The above is the "formal" process.Let's talk for a minute about the "informal"process. One of the most importantunwritten rules is to be able totake criticism after you have tried yourvery best to place birds as you seethem. We are all human and we all seethe birds somewhat differently. We allinterpret and judge for the standard aswe envision it to be.Remember everyone is not truly"qualified" to be a judge, even if theymeet all the qualifications. In spite ofall the pressure, you need to berelaxed and yet intense when placingbirds, have total confidence in everymove you make and especially whenyou talk and explain your rationale inplacing one bird over another.Does this sound like a tall order? Ibelieve it is. I also believe that mostjudges in the 40-plus years of a breedingprogram tend to be on a downhillslide, losing activity in competing andraising budgies and this will hurt hiseye after becoming a judge. Somemaintain and hold on a little longerthan others, but it is not easy.I personally feel to remain a successfulchampion exhibitor and a suebycessful A.B.S. judge you must exhibitat least 10 shows per year and judge atleast three or four more. You shouldattend meetings and be totally activein our hobby. And, if that does notkeep a member busy, utilize at least100 bands a year.As I said in the beginning, becominga "superstar" in our sport requires the same dedication as in any other. Ittakes all levels of people to make itsuccessful, just like it takes all levels inall sports for one to achieve success.We have to support all levels of ourhobby. We need to always look up atour goals, never down at anyone,treating everyone equally and enjoyour wonderful hobby.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/887</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 2 (1995): MAR-APR 1995; 53</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/887/869</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
