<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/209</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:16:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">the Vets Corner: RESEARCH IN EXOTIC BIRD DISEASES</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cooper, Ralph</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Those of us who work with exotic birddiseases are repeatedly faced with thelack of really definitive information onthe subject. Pathologists like myself, whocome from a background in poultrydisease, are especially aware of the deficiencyas compared with the enormousamount of information and continuingresearch which is characteristic of thepoultry field. This situation is easilyunderstood when a few basic facts of lifeare recognized. Most information ondisease , its true nature and treatment,comes about in response to a need. Thepoultry industry has traditionally knownhow to attract the attention of research erswho are interested in seeking solutionsto their problems. They have also knownhow to finance such formal research,because research is usually cos tly in bothmoney and men. Consequently, researchin the field of poultry diseases is about asadvanced as the state of the art permits.This is in glaring contrast to the situationin pet and exotic birds . With a few notableexceptions, most research has beenconducted by a few interested professionalsor laymen who are motivated bynecessity or curiosity. Traditionally , eventhe valid information which comes fromthis sort of individual effort has not beenmade known to the other workers in thefield in any sort of organized basis.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/209</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 3 No. 5 (1976): OCT-NOV 1976; 18-19 &amp; 46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/209/200</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
