<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/458</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pigeon Artand the Man Who Collects It</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Parrott-Holden, Jan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">What could be harder to definethan art? Art has been called "naturemade by man:' It 's been termed"truth;' "beauty;' "the shadow ofdivine perfection:' Pretty heady ideas- all. And yet, if you live with art, ifit is the passion of your existence, artcan easily be defined as "life:'Lots of people collect art. They liketo keep beautiful things close at hand.They may specialize in still lifes, inportraits, land or seascapes. But fewcollect " pigeon art:' Lynn Watsondoes.As far back as 1959, when Watsonwas just a school kid , he lovedpigeons. Fact is, he was raising themat the age of five. But prior to thattime he had never known there werebooks or paintings depicting theinfinite variety of these birds. Then afriend showed him a marked cataloguefrom the Los Angeles PigeonClub's famous "Pageant of Pigeons"and a passion for pigeon art wasborn.At the age of fifteen , Lynn became amember of the Los Angeles PigeonClub and received the club's bulletins,then being both expensively andexpansively produced by DonAndrews, a man with considerablereputation as a pigeon lover, and acollector of outstanding pigeon art.It was meeting Mr. Andrews andanother pigeoneer of longstanding,Mr. George Neuerburg (one-time presidentof the LAPC) which openedyoung Watson's eyes to the fascinatingpleasure of collecting beautifulpigeon paintings.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/458</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 1 (1989): FEB-MARCH 1989; 32-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/458/443</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
