<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4044</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:16:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Rehabilitating a Red-tailed Hawk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Darden, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 3 (April 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.by Jennifer Darden, Pet Bird Association of VirginiaWhen your dinner moves at speeds of 8 to 25 miles per hour, there is no time for hesitation, second guessing or checking both ways for cars. A red-tailed hawk begins his hunt from the high vantage point of a telephone pole, light post or tree top. You may see him soaring in the sky, as he scans the ground for movement. By using binocular vision that is eight times greater than humans’ visual capabilities, he can spot a mouse from 100 feet in the air. With a tasty target in sight, he dives at speeds that can reach 120 miles per hour, quickly focusing as he descends. Implementing the element of surprise, he attacks from behind, his single-minded mission, to snag his next meal. Unfortunately for these clever hunters, this laser focused approach does not calculate the oncoming car that will simultaneously reach the rodent.Vehicular strikes are one of the greatest threats to the red tailed hawks and one of the most common problems that send birds of prey into the care of local rehabbing organizations such as, TREE (Tidewater Rehabilitation and Environmental Education). Injuries usually include, fractured wings, leg or eye injuries.Other dangers for hawks include shootings, activities that threaten their nests, rodenticide poisoning, electrocution, emaciation, methane burns and netting used on driving ranges at golf courses. Life in the wild is tough, even when you are a powerful bird of prey. Territorial battles between hawks, turf wars and attacks from predators such as great horned owls or a larger hawk also cause injuries.Weighing two to four pounds with a three-to-four-foot wingspan, broad tail marked by a beautiful rusty patch, bodies draped in copper, brown and white splotched plumage, red-tailed hawks are a majestic symbol of flight and freedom. The laws of nature dictate that we deliver them back to the wild. The laws of man demand it through The Migratory Bird Treaty Act of 1918. One of the country’s oldest environmental laws makes it illegal to capture or kill any native migratory bird or to possess or destroy its feathers, nest or eggs. Selling, trading or transporting is also prohibited. This important legislation protects over 1000 species of birds, including hawks.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4044</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 3 (2022): Watchbird April 2022; 20-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4044/4004</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
