<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3992</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T20:18:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">When Every Day is Turkey Day</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">PhD, Constance Woodman,</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (October/November 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Cold turkey Loretta came into my life a couple of days before Winter Storm Uri in 2021. She had been wandering in the road near Hill Country Aviaries, when Mark Moore, one of the partners at Hill Country, caught her up for me. We called around, no one would claim her. I said I ’d keep her in my garage for a couple days while figuring re -homing.Then the cold hit. The inside of my house was 55º F with my fireplace constantly in use. The storm knocked out power, closed roads, and froze waterlines across Texas for over a week, with weeks of work following to repair roadway damage and waterline systems.And I had a fifteen pound turkey during a major emergency. I could not put her in the garage or outside, as she was not temperature acclimated, and I could not take her anywhere. The wild outdoor birds were literally freezing to death. I had to either figure out how to live with a turkey in the house for the foreseeable future or have a roast.I decided I’d have a house turkey. No jive turkeys Keeping a turkey like a parrot is not a standard operation. I got lucky that Loretta is a hen. As a domestic turkey she will want to nest for most of the year if given something to sit on (she has a favored golf ball.) And when nesting, she has an instinct to hide her body waste to avoid showing predators there’s a nest site nearby. Right away I saw that she scratched at her water bowl and spilled it when she got off the nest (which is a sofa cushion.) So I filled a litter pan with an inchof water and sure enough, she would hop off the nest and go scratch in the litter pan. It took about fifty training sessions to get her to reliably stand in the middle of the pan, and also to scurry over to the pan when I said “go potty.” During warm months the pan can be outside and she ’ll go to the door an “luululululuuu” until I let her out to use her box. In the cold months the litterbox is indoors.The catch with the potty training is the molt, where she loses the nesting behavior as she replaces feathers. Then I have to use clicker training/operant conditioning to keep the litterbox behavior going until she nests again. If I get lazy, I will have to contend with turkey turds. An easier compromise is to put her outside all day during the molt, let her sleep in her favorite spot inside at night, then kick her back outside when I wake up. Luckily, she is lazy and tends to wake up after I do, avoiding the dreaded “good morningClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3992</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 4 (2023): Watchbird October/November 2023; 12-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3992/3952</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
