<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/652</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Update: Arizona Seed Crackers Society Halfmoon Conure Breeding Consortium</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clifton, Gary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AFA has awarded a grant of$2000.00 to the ASCS HalfmoonBreeding Consortium to obtain additional,unrelated breeding stock andto help cover costs for using theSPARKS computer program. Thus far,one bird has been purchased at a costof $65.00 and the SPARKS user fee of$200.00 per year will be paid to ISIS(International Species IdentificationSystem) in May when it becomes due.Prior to obtaining the AFA grant, theConsortium has raised funds andspent approximately $3000.00 onbirds and the initial ISIS fee of $250.00.Presently the Consortium owns fivepairs of A.c. clarae and has foursingles paired with privately-ownedmates. Additionally, there are threepairs privately held but registered inthe studbook. These birds are allpaired to achieve maximum geneticdiversity, but one privately held pair isalmost over-represented in the populationand some of the rest of the populationconsists of siblings. The AFAgrant will allow purchase of additional,unrelated stock. In addition tothe A.c. clarae population, the consortiumalso owns two surplus malesof the A.c. eburnirostrum sub-species. Identification of Sub-species1. Aratinga caniculan·s canicularis-The nominate species has a large ishorange area on the forehead andstrongly resembles a Peach-frontedConure except for beak coloration.A.c. canicularis has horn coloredmandibles, both upper and lower.2. Aratinga canicularis eburnirostrum-Similar in appearance to A.c.canicularis overall, the most obviousdifference is beak coloration. Thelower mandible has a large dark spoton each side, at first glance thissubspecies appears to have a horncolored upper and blackish lowermandible. Closer examination revealsvariable horn colored areas on thelower mandible, typically a thin"stripe" right down the center. Theorange on the forehead extends toand comes in contact with the bareeye ring.3. Aratinga canicularis claraeSimilarto A.c. eburnirostrum but witha more restricted orange area on theforehead. Beak coloration is a horncolored upper mandible while thelower mandible is horn colored with alarge black spot on each side as in A.c.eburnirostrum. Forshaw describes themarkings on the lower mandible asbeing more blackish in A.c. claraeand more brownish-black in A.c.eburnirostrum, but specimens seenby ASCS haven't shown any discernibledifference between the subspeciesin terms of beak coloration.The orange on the forehead is variablebut definitely more restricted than inA.c. canicularis or A.c. eburnirostrum.At one extreme the orange onthe forehead may be restricted to twoor three feathers, at the other extremethe orange will extend almost, but notquite, into contact with the eye ring. Ingeneral terms, the orange area on theforeheads of A.c. canicularis and A.c.eburnirostrum are much like the foreheadmarkings of the Peach-frontedConure, whereas the orange markingof A. c. clarae does not come into contactwith the eye ring and usually isnoticeably smaller overall.Appearance is quite similar in allthree sub-species, a close look for distinguishingfeatures is required to distinguishamong them. Even with the close similarity in appearance, theASCS Halfmoon Consortium will notknowingly hybridize between thesubspecies since we haven't donefield studies and do not know if thereare behavioral differences in wildpopulations. A.c. clarae in the wild isconfined to western Mexico, in anarea Forshaw describes as "from Sinaloasouth to Colima and inland towestern Durango and central Michoacan."Since Mexico halted explorationin 1980, this species hasn't been legalin international trade for over adecade. Overwhelmingly common inthe United States in the late 1970s,today they could be described asuncommon, but available. Generallyspeaking, breeders have devoted theirefforts and resources to breedingmore financially lucrative species. Asa result, the population in captivity inthe United States has declined sharply.Anecdotal sampling of breeders inArizona and Florida suggest thespecies is less prolific than some otherconures, with one or two clutches peryear typical. Clutch size frequently isthree or four, at times only one or two.Breeding appears to be definitelyseasonal, from early March untilmid-May.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/652</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/652/635</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
