<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2963</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-14T08:52:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bird Shows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">August 26, 1978 Wisconsin Cage Bird Club 1st Annual ShowQA Inn, Hwy. 41 Appleton, WI.Contact:Show Sec., Dennis Gelhar, 1045 Alva St.Menasha, WI 54952November 16,17,18,19, 1978 American Cockatiel Society wil I present theirFirst National Cockatiel Speciality Show Atlanta, GeorgiaShipped in birds accepted" For information:Jo Hal I, Route 1, Box 33 Thorndale, Texas 76577November 24, 1978 National Cage Bird Show at theAtlanta Airport Hilton Georgia Poultry Laboratories has issued the following information for those wishing to ship birds into the state of Georgia for entrance in the show.**You will no longer be required to obtain an approved permit for pet and/or caged birds prior to their ship-ment into Georgia. 'In lieu of the permit, you will be required to furnish to the Georgia Poultry Laboratory, P.O. Box 148, Oakwood, Georgia, 30566, either an invoice, bill of lading, or letter on each shipment which gives the following information:1. Name and address of shipper.2. Name and address of consignee.3. Approximate date of shipment.4. Method of shipment.5. Number and types of birds in each shipment. The New Hampshire Cage Bird Associationwill hold itsFourth Annual Showat the Holiday Innin Nashua, N.H.Anyone needing more information may contact:A. Wayne Grant5 Westray Drive Nashua,N.H.03060 Membership Secretary, NHCBAOctober 20-21, 197837th Annual Show Central Ohio Bird Fanciers, Inc. at theNational Guard Armory State St.Wisterville, Ohio Judges, Type - Ed Rogacki Color - Scott RitchieBudgerigars - Dick Ryan Exotic - John Knipp Show Sec. Peg Larson 9767 Blacksnake Rd.Utica, Ohio 43080October 28, 1978 Ohio National Color Breeders Club 31st Annual CageBird ExhititionBlessed Sacrament Church Auditorium. 3381 Fulton Road, Cleveland, Ohio.Judges:Nu-Color and Red Factor, Lillian Knaggs Type, Ed Rogacki Foreign, Bill Saraniti Show Sec.Carol Hensley 21017 Clare Ave.Maple Heights, Ohio 44137 December 1, 2, 3, 1978 Orange County Bird Breeders 2nd Annual Open Bird Show Orange County Fair Grounds Building No. 1688 Fair DriveCosta Mesa, CA 92626 Contact:Mrs. D.M. van Dijk8071 Mermaid Circle Huntington Beach, CA 92646November 17,18,19, 1978 The Central California Cage Bird Club announces theTwenty-fifth Annual Show Modesto Racquet Club 200 Norwegian Avenue Modesto, Calif. 95350Judges:Red Factor, Frank Crane Type, Chuck Hudson Foreign, Paul Schneider Show Theme:SILVER ANNIVEFi.::,t-1RY Show Mgr, Ray Ricketts 620 Amber, Modesto, CA 95350 Show Secy/Treas, Dan Minuzzo 3420 Colonial Dr.Modesto, CA 95350October 6,7 ,8, 1978 The Mid-America Cage Bird Society's34d Annual All Bird Show Ramada Inn WestDes Moines, Iowa Judges:Budgies, Gil BarbozaType Birds, John Knipp Hookbills &amp;amp; Exotics, Ray Johnson Red Factors, Ray Johnson/ Mark WhiteakerFor information contact:Doug Hatcher Advertising Chairman Route 1, Box 136 New Virginia, Iowa 50210 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2963</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 3 (1978): JUNE-JULY 1978; 43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2963/2947</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
