<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/623</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-10-02T17:44:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action... NEWSandVIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Saffell, Chuck</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hurricane Andrew Relief Update A Big THANK YOU! by Chuck Saffell, First Vice-President Palmetto, Florida As part of the Hurricane Andrew avian relief effort, between September 3rd and October 17th, the following supplies were collected at the Palmetto, Florida warehouse and trucked to the AFA-SOFAR warehouse which is located three blocks from the Miami International Airport: 32,000 lbs. seed and pellets, 250 lbs. millet, 300 lbs. Avi-cake, 200 lbs. hand feeding formula, 40 lbs. vitamins and minerals, 170 lbs. veterinarian supplies, 10 lbs. Lactobacillus, 50 lbs. peanuts, 50 lbs. Honeytreat, 100 lbs. Crazycorn, 700 lbs. Zoopreem, 80 lbs. "J" clips, 30 lbs. wire cutters, pliers, J clip and other tools, 50 each syringes, 600 feet shade cloth, 2,000 feet cage wire, 80 each premanufactured cages, 40 each stainless steel food bowls, 3 boxes bird toys and dishes, 200 each cage door latches, 1 each very large bird net with extension handle, 12,000 each flashlight batteries, 6 cases juice drinks for the workers. Between September 2nd and October 31st, 700 manhours were donated at the Miami warehouse by AFA-SOFAR club members. Sixty-eight trips were made out of the warehouse by truck or van and on these trips 220 deliveries were made. An additional 30 trips were made from the warehouse to West Palm Beach, Lantana and Ft. Lauderdale to pick up donated supplies from other depots. On the first day that the SOFAR warehouse was opened, the following load went out to drop-off points where people could pick up supplies: 2,000 lbs. parrot mix, 1,000 lbs. canary, 1,000 lbs. finch, 2 boxes of com and 500 lbs. hookbill mix. On the Hurricane Andrew Relief Update A Big THANK YOU! by Chuck Saffell, First Vice-President Palmetto, Florida As part of the Hurricane Andrew avian relief effort, between September 3rd and October 17th, the following supplies were collected at the Palmetto, Florida warehouse and trucked to the AFA-SOFAR warehouse which is located three blocks from the Miami International Airport: 32,000 lbs. seed and pellets, 250 lbs. millet, 300 lbs. Avi-cake, 200 lbs. hand feeding formula, 40 lbs. vitamins and minerals, 170 lbs. veterinarian supplies, 10 lbs. Lactobacillus, 50 lbs. peanuts, 50 lbs. Honeytreat, 100 lbs. Crazycorn, 700 lbs. Zoopreem, 80 lbs. "J" clips, 30 lbs. wire cutters, pliers, J clip and other tools, 50 each syringes, 600 feet shade cloth, 2,000 feet cage wire, 80 each premanufactured cages, 40 each stainless steel food bowls, 3 boxes bird toys and dishes, 200 each cage door latches, 1 each very large bird net with extension handle, 12,000 each flashlight batteries, 6 cases juice drinks for the workers. Between September 2nd and October 31st, 700 manhours were donated at the Miami warehouse by AFA-SOFAR club members. Sixty-eight trips were made out of the warehouse by truck or van and on these trips 220 deliveries were made. An additional 30 trips were made from the warehouse to West Palm Beach, Lantana and Ft. Lauderdale to pick up donated supplies from other depots. On the first day that the SOFAR warehouse was opened, the following load went out to drop-off points where people could pick up supplies: 2,000 lbs. parrot mix, 1,000 lbs. canary, 1,000 lbs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/623</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 6 (1992): DEC-JAN 1993; 51-54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/623/606</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
