<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/659</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EX LIBRIS: lhe Estrildian</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Estrildian is a magazine of theEstrildid Society. It was established inthe United Kingdom in 1991 for thewelfare, study and breeding of estrildidsin captivity. The original conceptof the founders of The EstrildidSociety was to cover only those waxbillsbelonging to the genus Estrilda,but this was expanded to cover allestrildids . There has been some discussionregarding whether or not thismagazine should cover finches outsidethis group, such as the Cubanfinches (Grassquits). No matter whichway this goes, this excellent newsociety provides much needed informationon the many estrildid finchesnow found in captivity. Al though thissociety is based in England, the maga- very possible that those finches nowfound in our aviaries may be thefounding stock for upcoming generations.The Estrildian not only gives excellentinformation on individual finchspecies , it also provides details onmany related subjects. These subjectsrange from how to cultivate live food(insects, larvae, etc.) for our finches towhich species are compatible witheach other.This is an excellent magazine for thebeginner or for those experiencedfinch breeders wishing to branch outinto new species . A beautiful colorillustration of an Orange-cheekedWaxbill graces the cover. This illustrationwas done by Howard Robinsonwho also includes excellent black andwhite finch illustrations throughoutthe magazine. Of interest to me wasthe "Member's Sales and Wants" sectionin the back of the magazine. Thewants far outweighed the sales whichillustrates the great need to learn howto successfully reproduce these birdsfor many generations. This magazineis a great stai1 to filling this need.Subscriptions for The E.&amp;gt;trildian are$45.00 (U.S. currency - personalchecks accepted) for U.S . aviculntrists.The checks should be made out toThe Estrildid Society and sent toMalcolm Story, 29 Sherburn ParkDrive , Rowland Gill, Tyne &amp;amp; Wear,United Kingdom, NE39 IQU. •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/659</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 16-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/659/642</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
