<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/737</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Recent Research on the Anodorhynchus Macaws Feeding Habits</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pittman, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Until very recently, little was knovrnabout the feeding habits of the Anodorhynchusmacaws . The earliestdetailed references I have found ontheir feeding habits both occurin H.W. Bates' The Naturalist on theAmazons, first published in 1863about his 11 year sojourn in Brazil.In the chapter entitled "The Tocantinsand Camera", his entry for 7thSeptember, 1848 includes the following:"We saw here, for the first time,the splendid Hyacinthine Macaw(Macrocercus hyacinthinus, Lath., theAraruna of the natives), one of thefinest and rarest of the parrot family.... It flies in pairs, and feeds on thehard nuts of several palms, but especiallyof the Mucuja (Acrocomia lasiopatha).These nuts, which are so hardas to be difficult to break with a heavyhammer, are crushed to a pulp by thepowerful beak of this macaw."Four years later in describing the"Voyage up the Tapajos", he wrote,"The Macaws were found feeding insmall flocks on the fruit of the Tucumapalm (Astryocaryum tucuma), theexcessively hard nut of which iscrushed into pulp by the powerfulbeak of the bird. I found the craws ofall the specimens filled with the sourpaste to which the stone-l ike fruit hadbeen reduced."For the next 125 or mo re years theredoes not appear to have been muchadded to these two pieces of information.Goeldi , in his As Aves do Brasil of1894, appears to have transferred thefeeding habits of the HyacinthineMacaws described by Bates to theGlaucous Macaw (Anodorhynchusglaucus) and this was then repeatedby Helmut Sick in his great workOrnitologia Brasileira of 1984.In the last few years, research carriedout by Munn, Yamashita, Brandtand Machado has confirmed Anodorhynchusmacaws to be special istpalm-nut feeders. In our own visits to the Pantanal in Brazil, we have observedthe Hyacinthine Macaws feedingoff " acuri" palms (Scheelea orAttalea phalerata) and "bocaiuva"palms (Acrocomia aculeata).In my report in the ovember 1992issue of the Parrot Society Magazine("The Glaucous Macaw. Does it StillExist?") on our visit to Argentina, Paraguayand Brazil to investigate theextant habitat of the Glaucous Macaw,I related how Joe Cuddy and I speculatedfrom numerous historical referencesto the flora of the region that theGlaucous Macaw fed exclusively offthe palm nuts of the yatay palm (Butiayatay) and had become extinct because of clearance of the yataypalm groves throughout its distributionarea.This has now been confirmed in anarticle by Carlos Yamashita and Maurode Paula Valle published in the April1993 issue of the BOC Bulletin. In thisarticle, the authors compared the billcu tting action and efficiency of theAnodorhynchus macaws, whichspecialize in palm nuts , and o thermembers of the parrot family, whichare not such specialists.The Anodorhynchus macaws areknown to have the strongest chiselaction with the lower mandible of allthe parrot family. Both the Hyacin-thine and the Lear's Macaw use thecutting edge of the "chisel" to splitpalm nuts in two. It would appearlogical to assume that the GlaucousMacaw, as a member of the Anodorhynchusgenus, shared this characteristic.For their study, Yamashita and dePaula Valle measured the chisel widthof all three Anodorhynchus species aswell as that of 13 other parrot speciesin museum skin collections. They alsocollected palm nuts opened by differentspecies of macaws to compare thecutting pattern.The mean chisel width size for nonpalm-nut specialists ranged between7.4 mm for the Red-shouldered orHahn's Macaw (Ara nobilis) to 15.4mm for the Green-winged Macaw(Ara chloroptera). The Anodorhvnchusmacaws had a much larger chiselwidth with a mean of 22.4 mm for theLear's Macaw (A. leari) 24.2 mm forthe Glaucous Macaw (A . glaucus) and30.6 mm for the Hyacinthine Macaw(A. hyacinthinus). The authors alsodiscovered that body size does notcorrelate to chisel width . The RedfrontedMacaw (Ara rubrogenys), forexample, is smaller than the Blue andYellow Macaw (Ara ararauna), buthas a wider chisel width. The Lear'sMacaw, Blue and Yellow Macaw andScarlet Macaw (Ara macao) are similarin size and weight, but have verydifferent chisel widths with a mean of22.4 mm, 11.3 mm and 12.2 mmrespectively. Some conures have ve1ywide chisel widths in relation to theirsize.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/737</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 48-50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/737/720</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
