<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3261</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-02T17:36:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">SPBE Bird Show</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">For the first time in exactly a quarter of a century, a flash of brilliant feathers caught the eye of spectators during the recent AFA convention where attendees were invited to watch live parrots, "in the feather," judged at a Society of Parrot Breeders &amp;amp; Exhibitors show. The Lor-yLeague.org hosted the event Saturday morning, August 6th, along with co-host, the Lineolated Parakeet Society. All three organizations, LoryLeague.org, Lineolated Parakeet Society, and the Society of Parrot Breeders &amp;amp; Exhibitors, are nationally affiliated with theAFA.The SPBE show was an overwhelming West Coast success with 51 parrots represented by a dozen exhibitors-benching more than 50 parrots qualifies the event as a "major show." The turnout enabled all top ten parrots-known as the "top bench"-to earn points towards champion and grand champion status. Earning points to finish a champion can mean more to some exhibitors than the lavish show ribbons and awards distributed to winners. According to show organizer and AFA Northwestern Regional Director Julie Corwin, "The idea was to bring birds back to AF A. Our questionnaire revealed AFA members wanted to see birds while at the convention, so I thought, what about having birds for display? I chose to affiliate with SPBE because of the friendly support they offered. The Lory League could host the event with the Lineolated Parakeet Society as co-host. It was a huge success."A first in SPBE history-or perhaps any USA parrot show of the past-was the entry of a Black Palm Cockatoo that came in 6th Best Novice Parrot and won Audience Favorite. The Palm's owner, longtime AFA board member and AFA Cooperative Breeding Program Chair Mary Ellen LePage, brought the rare Palm for others to see. Gollie, a member of the largest subspecies of the Palm, Probosciger atterimus goliath (Proboscis is Greek for nose, gero is Greek for carry, and atterimus is Latin for black), drew a lot of attention. LePage works with a number of cockatoo species and exhibiting Gollie provided a rare opportunity for attendees to directly view a Black Palm Cockatoo, perhaps for the first time.Other unexpected rarities that were benched included a number of seldom seen species at USA shows, including a Black Lory, Stella's Lory and a Cloncury Parakeet, among others.As the officiating SPBE panel judge, I had the honor of judging the event and was delighted to see both an impressive diversity of species, as well as parrots of very high quality. Considering how far some birds had to travel (including those that came by plane with their owners), the turnout was most impressive.The SPBE Standard for Exhibited Parrots describes five categories that include conformation (40 percent), condition (30 percent), deportment (15 percent), color (10 percent) and presentation (5 percent). Although each of these categories is assigned a weighted percentage, the birds are actually judged by a oneon-one direct comparison method, rather than assigning actual points, with the weighted categories instead serving as a guide. By SPBE rules, rarity is never an issue in judging, which allows the best bird in the competition to emerge over all.As required by SPBE shows, the birds are entered in show classifications that are divided into the major geographical regions with subdivisions in the South Pacific, Afro-Asian, and New World distributions, with two additional subdivisions for Open Entries and Novice. Open entries may include birds that are unhanded, or that wear an open (split) leg band. Novice exhibitors may show birds with clipped wings however, these entries are marginally penalized. Without all flight feathers in evidence, it is challenging for a judge to accurately evaluate the back-line, proportions and length when judging the conformation of a bird. However, many novice birds can and do make top bench, as they did at the August 6th show.Bird shows are actually beauty contests at a "moment in time."This is because birds can change from show to show, from week to week, and even moment to moment. Overall quality as judged by genetic conformation-and superb condition and deportment as reflected by the exhibitor's work invested in show cage training, frequent bathing and top nutritional programs throughout the year-usually provide a bird with a high chance of scoring a win at shows. However, conformation is heavily considered as reflected in the show standard, and judges keep the genetic traits of birds in mind because the winners will often be bred and pass desirable traits onto their offspring. It is the savvy exhibitor who remembers that a bird show is merely a "snapshot in time." And, that Polaroid, (or video), can change from show to show.Judges are often asked, "How do you decide between totally different species, with birds representing all colors and sizes?" SPBE panel judges are supposed to be able to identify and be familiar with the major characteristics of most parrots, plus we have been rigorously tested and qualified through our own show wins in order to become a certified judge. However, the actual answer is akin to judging apples against oranges. In the end, while considering the SPBE Standard, a judge must ask himself, "Is this the best bird I've seen of this species that is in front of me, compared to the best bird I've seen of that species?" The answers are usually quite clear.As in most shows, a few of the birds might have placed differently given additional mistings of warm water to tighten feather condition, or extra show cage training to become more at ease and confident on the perch, which can help any bird improve for the next show. As SPBE judges, we try to encourage the strong points in birds and place comments on the show cage tags to help exhibitors chances in the next show.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3261</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 38 No. 3 (2011): Number 3 2011; 37-42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3261/3245</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
