<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/725</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Roller Coaster Novices, Hang In There! Part One</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Denny, Don</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Day, Larry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sitting around over lunch, trying todecide what novices would like toread, made us think about what novicesneed to hear.Exhibition budgies - staying at thetop is one of the hardest animal breedinghobbies around. The up and downroller coaster of good babies and badproblems is as challenging as in anyanimal species you choose to breed.Sometimes a lot of money helps, buta lot of people haven't gotten very faror stayed at the top very long evenwith a lot of money. Fortunately,many good breeders are just plainworking folk with only so muchmoney to spend on a hobby. Timeand patience equals money.Disappointments come often, evenfor the best breeders. Large babies diefor various reasons; their tails fall out,never to return; they get too flecked;or they will not breed.To stay in the hobby, you need tolove budgies. You can get irritated atlosing; mad at bad judging; go berserkover politics; and start twitching overbreeding problems. But, if you lovethe birds, you will stay.We started thinking of a whole list ofthings that can go wrong and why wethink they do go wrong.More than a few hens are incrediblychoosey about their mates. You try to"force" mate them by picking out theircock because, darn it, this pair is perfect.But there is no fertility the firstround. Being a believer in your highquality mating, you try a second time- no fertility. We have even knownpeople to try three times. But, we seldomtry a second round with the samepair if the first round is infertile.Throw the pair in the flight together.If they act like perfect strangers afterhaving been together for a round ortwo - they are. It's better to let thesehens pick a mate to get them goingwith fertility.Some hens sight mate to cocks, butnot to the ones you'd choose. They like the one in the next cage or acrossthe way. They will lay eggs, but arereally mated to another cock, so theeggs are infertile. Just being in separatesections for 10 to 14 days doesnot always cure them.Larry had one hen that he sent to afriend's house for two months andthen brought her home, but to a differentpen from her "true love." Afterfour months of trying to remate, hegave up and put them together. Sixyoung were produced in the firstround; one as good a stock hen asmost people ever own and the resttotal duds.Best-to-best or buff-to-buff matingsoften, even if fertile, will not produceyoungsters. Dr. John Baker, a researchveterinarian at the University of Liverpool,believes many of these embryosare weak and die within a few hoursof development. If they go full term,they may die while hatching or neverstart pipping.Jo Mannes of Germany (consideredto be one of the finest budgie breedersin the world) says mate unlike birds- bigger to smaller, soft feather tohard feather. We say it, too.Some hens are so big, buff and goodlooking they don't even bother to lay.Most of the time, the best breeders willbe the slightly lesser quality, occasionallya lot lesser quality sisters ofexceptional hens. We usually try theseslightly lesser sisters to the best lookingcocks. We do not waste the bestcocks on low-percentage hens duringthe first part of the breeding season.There is always time for long shotslater.We don't know how many timespeople have looked at birds and said,"These $150, $200 or $250 birds arenot any better than the $50 or $75birds I just bought from Joe Blow."This is very true. As Larry once told anovice couple who asked for hisadvice, "This bird may not look anybetter than your birds at home, but Iabsolutely guarantee that its brothers,sisters and parents are far better." Severalyears later they thanked Larry forhis advice.Of course, they have also boughtseveral birds that did not produce verygood-looking birds. But it is the goodbreeding bird whose young make uslook like we know what we're talkingabout. And, all things being relative,they did not pay that much for thewhole bunch put together.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/725</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/725/708</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
