<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/866</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:17:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Handfeeding Eclectus Parrots</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Desborough, Laurella</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Four subspecies of eclectus parrotsare commonly available in the U.S.:Grand or Eclectus roratus roratus originatingfrom Ceram and Buru, Redsidedor Eclectus roratus po(ychloros originatingfrom New Guinea, vosmaeri orEclectus roratus vosmaeri originatingfrom the larger northern and centralMoluccan Islands, and Solomon Islandor Eclectus roratus solomonen..-;is originatingfrom the Solomon Islands. Eachof these subspecies originates from a distinctisland or group of islands or NewGuinea, separated by many miles ofocean. Although all eclectus parrots displaymany common characteristics, eachsubspecies also displays distinct developmentaland behavioral characteristics,indicating aspects unique totheir subspecies. Eclectus males are basicallygreen and females are basically red.The three common methods of raisingparrots are the following: 1) parent rearingfrom day one to weaning; 2) han drearingfrom day one(or close to day one);and 3) handrearing from two to threeweeks of age. Over the past 10 years wehave employed all three methods of rdisingeclectus parrots.Parent Rearing Edectus ParrotsThis method produces a youngsterthat is completely familiar with beingfed and reared by a parent and thus hasthe knowledge and first hand experienceto be a highly qualified candidatefor successful pairing with a mate, makinga nest, producing fertile eggs andsuccessfully rearing youngsters.Handfeeding From Day OneMany parrots are handfed from dayone in order to produce a young parrot that desires human companionship.Handfeeding from day one may be a necessityif the nesting hen refuses to feedthe chick or if the hen's mate refuses tofeed her. This may be no fault of the henor her mate but may be the fault of thebird breeder who has not provided thepair with the correct cage set up or thecorrect diet for rearing youngsters. Occasionallya hen who normally feedsfrom day one has a health problemwhich requires the eggs or chicks to beremoved from the nest, necessitatinghandfeeding from day one, or close today one.Eclectus Chicks Are DifferentEclectus parrot chicks are very unlikeAmazons, greys, macaws and cockatoos:they do not have any down andseldom have more than one clutchmate. Therefore, a brooder temperaturethat works well for Amazons and greysmay stress and chill an eclectus chick Acold chick cannot properly digest formulaand grow, but generally dieswithin five to seven days with food inthe crop.Many breeders who have extensiveexperience and success in raising otherspecies follow the same procedures thatproduces fine Amazon and grey chicksbut which do not work for eclectus. Thethree critical areas foreclectus chicks areas follows: 1) brooder temperature andset up, 2) correct formula and formulatemperature, 3) proper handfeedingprocedures.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/866</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 1 (1995): JAN-FEB 1995; 47-51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/866/848</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
