<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1587</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:54:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Red Siskin Recovery Project Past Perspectives and Future Directions</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Styles, Darrel K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he American Federation of Aviculture created the Red Siskin Recovery Project (RSRP) in response to the conservation needs of the highly endangered Red Siskin (Carduelis cucullata). This species has experienced extreme pressure on wild populations due to its popularity as a caged bird. The RSRP is striving to assist in the conservation efforts of this species by supporting scientific studies and domestic avicultural production. This discussion will detail some of the history of the Project and outline the challenges presently facing the program.The Red Siskin is the national bird of Venezuela where it is colloquially known as "el cardenalito'' or "little cardinal." Prior to heavy exploitation due to the caged bird trade, the Red Siskin enjoyed a wide range that extended from northeastern Colombia, across northern Venezuela, and on to Trinidad. Some current field studies reveal only two areas of habitat left in Venezuela, a small colony in Colombia, and a scattered feral population in Puerto Rico. The birds are seminomadic throughout the year, and will range up and down mountain slopes in their search for food. Red siskins have even been observed at high altitudes in evergreen forests, where cool zones of fog and rain persist all year. However, much of the activity of this species occurs in the deciduous forests of the lowlands.The Red Siskin became increasingly threatened in Venezuela and so in 1944, it became the first bird in the world to be protected by law. The Red Siskin has been kept as an avicultural specimen for some time, but its prima-ty use is in the production of red factor canaries. Originally, canary-siskin hybrids were produced in the mid- 1920' s. Canary-siskin hybrid males were produced in the first generation, some of which were fertile. These hybrid males where then paired back with canaty hens until in the fourth generation, fertile hens that carried the red factor trait were produced. Selective breeding intensified the color, however breeding Red Siskin males to female red factor canaries results in the most intense coloration. The use of Red Siskins to produce these color-type canaries along with extirpation in their home range for caged birds has severely reduced the populations in the wild. Although no legal export from Venezuela has occurred, internal pressure from poaching for the local trade, smuggling, and habitat destruction still take their toll. This bird is protected by the U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service's Endangered Species Act; so inter-state commerce is regulated by a permit process.In 1985, the Venezuelan Audubon Society's Conservation Committee approached the American Federation of Aviculture about assisting in conservation efforts of the Red Siskin. In 1989, the AF A began compiling studbook data and laying the groundwork for a captive breeding program. The American Federation of Aviculture's Red Siskin Recovery Project was then formed. The Project has three main goals:• To create a sustaining and stable captive breeding population of Red Siskins to meet the needs of commercial aviculture and thus relieve pressure on populations in the wild.• To promote and assist in the con- servation of this species by public education and support of ornithological scientific endeavors.• To work with ornithologists and field biologists to provide research subjects and supply captive bred specimens for potential re-introduction programs.The RSRP is a consortium consisting of volunteers including individual aviculturists and zoological institutions operating under the aegis of the American Federation of Aviculture. These participants contribute a portion of their offspring to the program for propagation purposes. The breeding stock is composed of privately held birds and those on loan for the AF ARSRP. Project participants must meet an established set of requirements before being permitted to join the program. These requirements include: being a member in good standing with the AF A, possessing breeding experience with passerines, knowledge and experience of proper aviary and flock management, a working relationship with a qualified avian veterinarian, and the sincere desire to assist in the recovery of the species. The flock record and studbook are maintained using a computerized database by Dr. Orland Baker, who has been the studbook keeper since the Project's inception.One of the biggest challenges facing the RSRP and preventing further expansion of the program is control of specific diseases. The greatest danger is from avian tuberculosis, which is an insidious and difficult to diagnose disease caused by a group of slow growing bacteria called Mycobacterium auium and Mycobacterium genovense. The magnitude of infection by this pathogen is unknown but it has caused death and loss of production throughout the Project. This disease is not specific to the Red Siskin, but is a threat to birds in aviculture worldwide and is a major problem in zoos and aviaries. The signs of infection are typically "going light" despite a ravenous appetite, poor quality plumage. malaise, imbalance and/or difficulty in moving, and chick death. Avian tuberculosis can be occult for years before beginning to cause clinical disease; typically after a stressful event such as breeding or movement to another aviary. Often, the offspring die followed by clinical disease in one or both of the parents.Diagnosis in the live bird is very difficult due to the low numbers of bacteria being shed, and intermittent shedding habits making culture or special stains not very useful. Most veterinarians make the definitive diagnosis on histopathology in the dead bird. Although the disease can be treated, it is an intensive and time-consuming process and, furthermore, it is unknown whether the infection has been cleared or simply suppressed. What is needed are accurate and reliable tests to screen potentially infected birds and prevent the disease from entering the aviary. Now, here's the good news.In July of this year, the American Federation of A vi culture in conjunction with Texas A&amp;amp;M University College of Veterinary Medicine and the Schubot Center for Exotic Bird Research; the University of California at Davis College of Veterinary Medicine; and the Lincoln Park Zoo received seed grant money from the Pet Care Trust, Inc. to research and develop tests for avian tuberculosis in the live bird. The Red Siskin will be the flagship species for this research effort. Each of the research institutions will provide some degree of matching funding thus augmenting the research efforts. The Texas A&amp;amp;M/Schubot Center group will be developing serological antibody tests; the UC-Davis group is developing gene probes (PCR); and the Lincoln Park Zoo is working on serological antigen (bacterial protein) tests. The AFA is supplying the funding for necropsies and helping to monetarily support the research efforts.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1587</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 5 (2000): Sept-Oct 2000; 58-59</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1587/1564</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
