<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1098</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:21:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DIETS of Softbilled Birds in Captivity</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vince, Martin</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">First, let's be clear what a softbill is: it's not a bird with a soft beak, hut merely a bird that eats soft food, such as fruits, insects, meat or nectar. And, although a softbill will often eat several different foods, it will tend to fall into one of the following distinct, dietary categories: Omnivore, Frugivore, Nectivore, Carnivore or Insectivore. It is these dietary categories and some of the softbills associated with them that are the subject of this paper.OmnivoresLet's begin by looking at probably the largest group of softbills in aviculture-the omnivores. To accurately describe their dietary requirements it is necessary to divide this category into two parts: omnivores that need more fruit in their diet compared with those that require more meat or insects.The fruit-biased omnivores include Lesser Green Broadbills, leafbirds, Fairy Bluebirds, most of the tanagers, euphonias, bulbuls, South American barbers, manakins, toucans and many more. For them about 65% of the diet should be chopped fruits including also greenfood such as lettuce or spinach-indeed, some tanagers appear to have a distinct need for greenfood, and if it's not provided are much more inclined to damage plant life. The remainder of the diet can he a number of ingredients- mynah bird pellets or any of the proprietary softbill foods can be used to provide the real nutrition necessary for long-term health. The diet can be enhanced with chopped hard-boiled egg and a selection of insects such as mealworms and waxwonns. But the livefood is poten- tially fattening and should only he used in moderation; and, in fact, generally it is not vital in a maintenance diet for birds in this grouping. It is, however, necessary for the rearing of young or as a valuable conditioner to encourage breeding. Nectar is important for certain species in this section. Leafbirds especially need it for good health and, to a much lesser extent, Fairy Blue-· birds, manakins and tanagers.The second group of omnivores represents species that are closer to the insectivores and carnivores in their dietary needs, and includes such birds as mynahs, starlings, jays, drongoes, orioles, marshbirds, mockingbirds, mesias, Pekin Robins and, Asiatic cuckoos and coucals. For these species a diet of 40% fruit is suitable. with the remainder heing a proprietary softhill food or even dog chow. Chopped hardhoiled egg can also he added, and because insects are more important for this group, about 5% of the diet should he livefood.When selecting fruits for your birds, almost everything can he used from spinach and tomatoes, to bananas and pears, including also mixed vegetables. Bananas are sometimes descrihed as toxic. Large quantities of unripe bananas can he he dangerous, hut used as only a part of a balanced diet, are as safe and valuable as most other fruits. Oranges are sometimes overlooked because of the scouring effect they may have on the digestive systems of some hirds. But again, if used as only a part of a balanced diet, they are perfectly safe; and for softhills. such as Red-vented Bulhuls, that cannot synthesize vitamin C, a daily intake of citrus fruits can he ve1y heneficial. Avocados, on the other hand, are well known for heing toxic to psittacines hut can also he dangerous Lo softbills, since they contain particularly high levels of vitamin E. This is a fat soluble vitamin: it's stored in the bodies of most animals and can accumulate to the point of being toxic. Therefore, to he on the safe side, avocado should comprise no more than about 5% of a softbill diet, and perhaps its long-term use avoided altogether.Dried fruits such as sultanas, figs, prunes and apricots can he included in a softhill diet. They should he soaked for a couple of hours in water, and then rinsed ve1y thoroughly before feeding. Many softbills especially enjoy soaked sultanas, hut all of the dried fruits are very fattening and must not he over-fed. As ingredients in a maintenance diet, dried fruits are not usually vital. Instead, they are most useful when over-wintering softhills outdoors in unheated accommodation. Dried fruits along with grated cheese and cooked potatoes fuel the body through freezing temperatures and, providing the softhill is particularly hardy, properly acclimated and supplied with an excellent shelter, no harm will come to it. At the end of winter these high energy foods are then removed from the diet to prevent obesity. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1098</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 6 (1996): NOV-DEC 1996; 42-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1098/1077</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
