<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4136</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T23:43:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Powerful Beaks</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fundación, Loro Parque</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 48 Number 1 (October 2021).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.AVICULTURE AT LORO PARQUE FUNDACION AVIARY “LA VERA”Director Científico Loro Parque FundaciónThe independence phase in parrots is always one of the most delicate stages in their development. At Loro Parque Fundación we pay a lot of attention to this process as it is the moment when they begin to carry out their daily activities in a self-sufficient way. It will mark their good health and also the way they relate to their environment. In this important period, one of the parts that should have the best growth is the beak. This is soft when they are hatched, hardens as they grow, and can suffer deformations or fractures for a variety of reasons. It is a horny part of the bird, and it renews itself over time. These layers are sometimes visible as broad scales. Its good condition determines the health of a parrot as it is a priority part of its digestive system, as well as being one of the main tools through which they relate to their environment. In fact, the part that best...Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4136</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 48 No. 1 (2021): Watchbird October 2021; 24-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4136/4096</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
