<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2464</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-13T17:20:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Buffon's Macaw</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abramson, Joanne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article has been written in an attempt to clarify the differences between the Buffon's macaw and the military macaw. Both species are very distinct in their habits, social behavior and in their physical appearance. In my opinion, the Buffon's should be classified as a separate species from the military. The Buffon's and the military are as distinct as the greenwing and the scarlet macaw. Both may be basically green, but the similarity stops there.The first of the problems encountered with the Buffon's macaw (Ara ambigua) is the varied names it has been given. They have been called great green macaws, grand green macaws, grand military (Buffon's) macaws [Low) and Ecuadorian (Chapman's Green) Ara militaris quayaguilensis macaws [Low]. I would like to call for a moratorium on new names for Ara anbigua, after all, how many names can one bird tolerate. Throughout this article the before mentioned bird will be called Buffon's macaw.Description: The Buffon's length is 85 cm (34 in.). The military length is 70 cm (28 in.).Weight: The Buffon's weights range from 1,264 grams (2 lbs. 13 oz.) to 1,587 grams (3 lbs. 8 oz.). The military weights range from 650 grams [McDonald pers. comm.] to 1,051 grams [Galvin pers. comm.].The Buffon's weigh up to 454 grams (1 lb.) heavier in size" As with all of the large macaws, it can take up to two years for Buffon's to reach their full size and weight.Head: The Buffon's head is much larger than the military with a darker near-red facial patch that easily darkens when excited. The beak is also much larger than the military, giving an appearance similar to a greenwing macaw.Body Coloration: The Buffon's has a lighter, lime green overall color. The military has a darker green, frequently with a bluish-tinged head.Tail: Here is where the most outstanding color difference occurs. The Buffon's central and lateral tail feathers show a brilliant rainbow of color. The feather portion close to the quill tip is bathed in red-orange, then orange, than a greenish-yellow, ending in a turquoise tip. The lateral feathers, in addition, have a bright gold area on the median portion. The size of the Buffon's feathers in both length and width are larger, in proportion to the bird's size. The military's feathers are a deep reddishbrown, tipped in deep turquoise.If you compare one tail feather with the photos, you should be able to verify if you own a Buff on' s or a military. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2464</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 5 (1986): OCT- NOV 1986; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2464/2437</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
