<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3349</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-09T10:56:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ban Birds in Connecticut? I don’t think so!</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferragamo, Concetta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Ban birds in Connecticut? A sleep-deprived local lawyer (Mr. Bennett) from the small town of Chester, Connecticut decided to do just that because he was furious with a neighbor's "crowing" rooster. His rage led him to file a proposal that would not only ban roosters but went as far as to include parrots and prohibit any animals "including fowl, which howls, barks, brays, bellows, calls, screeches, squawks, or makes other sound during the day or night at frequent and/ or extended periods of time." (See official proposal). Keep in mind that ordinances like this are frequently copied verbatim and introduced into other municipalities across the United States. This petition set off a bomb mobilizing a chain of command in bird clubs and the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. (AFA). It sounded something like this.Cheryl Fullerton, a member of the Connecticut Parrot Society (CPS), an AFA affiliated bird club, saw a legal notice for a nearby town in her local newspaper. An ordinance was being proposed that would ban poultry, parrots and some other animals in the town of Chester, Connecticut. Cheryl then alerted the CPS President, Bob Cosgrove, of the pending situation. Barbara Cosgrove, his wife, is a board member of CPS and is also the AFA State Coordinator for Connecticut. So Barbara then notified Concetta Ferragamo, the AFA Northeastern Regional Director who got several of the AFA Board members involved in reviewing the proposal. AF A Legislative Vice President, Genevieve Wall, Esquire responded and her AFA legislative committee team went into action.From there the AFA chain reaction was effective and played out perfectly. Kathy Heaton sent out notices far and wide spanning the entire United States and even internationally. From anywhere outside looking in, the teamwork was most impressive. National and local Bird club Presidents alerted their clubs, members posted on several social media networks and the notice of the proposed ban on birds went viral. There was an impressive alliance from breeders, pet owners, sanctuaries, rescues, shelters, trainers, authors, consultants, veterinarians and people who did not even own birds. Bird lovers pulled together and completely overwhelmed the town of Chester with piles ofletters and emails objecting to the ban.The hearing was scheduled for January and plans were underway to have several key people from bird clubs, the AFA, and many others present. A strong contingency of AFA members showed up and/or were in route for the January hearing when word came down that the fire marshal was forced to cancel and postpone the meeting. Apparently the gathering crowd exceeded occupancy limits for the venue with well over 500 attendees already present. Dr. Amy Hopkins (CAFA), Margaret Warren (CPS), Michele Parrott (CPS) accompanied Concetta, the AFA Regional Board member, and her husband Enzo Ferragamo to the hearing. Other AFA members were in route and were told to turn around due to the last minute cancellation and postponement. The meeting was tentatively rescheduled for February in a larger arena.Additionally, the community of Chester had an outpouring of their own. The crowd was massive and even contained some entertaining characters. There was a large group of people wearing chicken hats that broke out in a chant to end the proposal right then and there. Their request was denied due to regulations and the proper way to proceed under law. The Bennett's were present as well and apparently humbled by the crowds. They escaped as quickly as possible. It was clear that there were more Chester residents that were opposed to the proposed ban than in favor of it.Concetta spoke with Zoning and Planning Commissioner Jon Lavy about the proposals and national responses that poured in from AFA and others. Lavy recognized the name of the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. as a professional national education organization that often gets involved in these types of cases. Lavy stated that the stacks ofletters were overwhelming and they had not had the chance to look at all of them yet. Lavy was reassured that there would be more letters to come. Commissioner Lavy was pleasant despite the tough predicament. Concetta and Lavy spoke about different alternatives such as helping the Bennett's with sound proofing techniques and Lavy and other members of the zoning and planning board seemed interested and asked questions. Concetta assured the commissioner and officers that the present group would be returning for the next hearing and that there would be more AF A friends joining along. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3349</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 40 No. 1 (2013): Number 1  2013; 41-42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3349/3333</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
