<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/610</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">General Management at the Parrot Breeding Centre</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lavril, Carine</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Diet is a very important part of themanagement of any aviaries. Whatwe put in the food we feed our birdsis what we get out of them: goodhealth, happiness and good breeding.We prefer to spend more on goodquality foods than risk sicknesses andhaving to spend so much more intreatments and eventually losing avaluable bird.But before I go any further, onething must be clear: whatever is writtenin this article is what we do at theParrot Breeding Centre. It works wellfor our parrots, but it does not meanit is the only way of feeding thesebirds. I just want to share with youour experience.Sprouting the SeedsThe reason why we sprout ourseeds is that we firmly believe thecloser we get to a natural diet thebetter. Sprouted seeds are of greatnutritious value because the oil contentof the seed is lowered considerably.As the sprout grows, it uses thisreserve of oil as does an embryoabsorbing the egg yolk to develop.Second, in the process of germination,the vitamins are brought toactivity for the growth of the sprout.Live vitamins are irreplaceable, andthis is where the breeders giving onlycooked beans are facing big trouble.Adding artificial vitamins is good aslong as the general diet provides liveones.But sprouting seeds takes timeunless one can train the staff to do itthe right way. It is crucial to do itproperly otherwise fungi or germscan develop. Also, this food must bediscarded when the evening feed isbrought or, at the latest, the nextmorning. Our staff cleans all thedishes early in the morning and thisavoids the seeds going sour.This is how we do it: the seeds aresoaked in a large bucket of water towhich has been added calcium propionate.This is absolutely necessary toavoid the development of germs orfungi during the germination pro-cess. We do not always know wherethe seed bags have been stored nor inwhat conditions, before theyreach us. If one does not have thetime or the means to do it the properway, the best is to stick to dry seeds.Sunflower seeds are soaked for 24hours with calcium propionate andrinsed very carefully the next day,then left in the same bucket but withoutwater. In winter, it may takeanother day for the sprouts to beapparent. Oats will have to soak for48 hours in water with Safe Sproutbut this mixture will have to bechanged after the first 24 hours.Then it will take another two to threedays. Wheat is soaked for 24 hours,then rinsed and left without water forthree days.All seeds will have to be rinsedevery day whether they are left tosoak or without water. Sometimeswe sprout Mung beans. Wheat isreduced after the breeding seasonand increased again just before. Itcontains vitamin E which induces thebirds into breeding condition, providedthey are ready. Oat is quitehigh in protein and sunflower is agood, nutritious base. It containsmany vitamins and minerals.Every morning, six large bucketsare prepared carefully with two partssunflower, one part oat, half partwheat. This represents three-fifths ofthe total amount of food given in themorning. To this is added two tothree tablespoons of a calcium supplementin the form of powder.One tablespoon of Biorhem is alsoadded, it contains dried lactobacilliwhich are friendly bacteria that helpreduce the pathogenic bacteria. Severalveterinarians, especially Dr. KimJoyner, are still studying the realeffects on psittacines. One tablespoonof kelp is alternately added,this seaweed powder is very high incalcium and all vitamins and minerals,with Beefee Powder.The seeds are then well mixedtogether with those powders. In themean time, fruits such as apples,oranges and pawpaws are cut intosmall pieces. These are fed daily. Yellowfruits are very high in vitamin Aand consequently are excellent forAfrican Gray Parrots and especiallyEclectus Parrots.Other fruits given in season: figs,grapes, plums.Grated vegetables offered dailyinclude carrots, beet roots with theirtops, sweet potatoes, turnips, andfresh lucern. Fruits and vegetables represent two-fifths of the totalamount of food given.Dried corn cooked for three hours(or 1-1/2 hours in a pressure cooker)is added daily and soya beans, cookedin the same way, are added once aweek.All this is mixed together with thesprouted seeds in the buckets, andfed to the birds immediately.We feed them ourselves becausethe amount varies from species tospecies and even from pair to pair.For example, Spectacled Amazonsout of breeding season require morefruits and vegetables than seeds,otherwise they grow too fat. It alsoallows us to check on every one ofthe birds. A sick bird requires quickaction. Slices of corn on the cob aregiven daily to the Palm Cockatoosand to the Eclectus Parrots.In the evenings, two to three timesa week, we give them Avi-Sup mixedwith warm water. We have foundthat they will eat more readily if it isoffered warm and especially whenthe weather is cold.A vi-Sup is a South African productwhich consists of pre-cooked, easilydigestable, human-grade qualityingredients that have been blendedtogether in the correct balance ofproteins, fats, carbohydrates, fibres,vitamins and minerals.At the start of the breeding season,Avi-Sup is fed every evening to thebreeding birds. When the chickshave hatched, we add scrambledeggs, but they have to be wellcooked to avoid any eventual germs.Available at all times in a seconddish are dry seeds containing a mixtureof canary, millet, sorghum,linseed (in small quantities: it is quiteoily but helpful in preventing eggbindingconditions). Every singlepair, from the smallest conure to thelargest macaw, gets it and they allenjoy it. In winter and at the start ofthe breeding season, the larger parrotsget pecan nuts regularly.This diet works very well at ourCentre. It is essential to provide thebirds with top quality foods as well asa diet correctly balanced in order toprevent diseases, poor breeding,poor hatchability, egg binding and allproblems related to any deficiencies.What would be saved on food wouldbe spent ten times more in medicineand veterinarian costs. It is essentialto work with an avian veterinarian ordietician to make sure the diet is theright one for the type of birds onekeeps.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/610</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 24</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/610/593</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
