<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3279</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-03T12:31:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">COVER STORY: Golden Conures</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Speed, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Golden Conure (Guaruba guarouba) is known throughout the world for its unique beauty and delightful personality. It is known by many names in different localities-the Yellow Macaw, the Yellow Conure, the Ararajuba, the Golden Parakeet and the ~een of Bavaria Conure.Although the Golden Conure was previously included in the genus Aratinga, many who have kept and studied the habits of this lovely parrot over a number of years suspected the classification was incorrect. Genetic analysis in the early 2000s proved that the Golden Conure is more closely related to the Red-shouldered Macaw (Diopsittaca nobilis), therefore, it was reclassified to the monotypic genus Guaruba which is considered the sister genus to Diopsittaca.DescriptionThe Golden Conure is indeed distinctive in appearance, behavior and vocalization. It averages about 14 inches in length and has an average weight of about 300 grams. The body plumage of the adult is a breathtaking yellow that rivals the most perfectly colored lemon. The primary, secondary and major coverts are dark green. Feather quills are white and a bare white ring surrounds its very kind and observant eye. The macaw-sized beak is horn colored with some bluish mottling occurring throughout, especially toward the tips. The tip of the upper beak is dagger sharp. Legs and feet are pinkish with black mottling. The iris is brownish with an orange tint.Juveniles are clearly identifiable by the appearance of numerous olive green feathers interspersed throughout the body. Juvenile feather quills are dark green. The amount of green markings a juvenile may possess is random-no two are colored alike. Adult plumage is almost always completely attained by the age of two. The juvenile has a beguiling and innocent expression and is also easily identified by its seemingly immature behavior in a flock containing mature birds.Range, Habits and StatusThe Golden Conure is native to a very remote area in northeastern Brazil. The World Parrot Trust, through its Golden Conure Survival Fund, has funded several studies of the Golden Conure, the most recent being done in 2006 and 2007 by Thiago Orsi Laranjeiras. His lengthy observations indicate the bird is known in approximately 70 localities in five Brazilian states, most of which are in the State of Para. It is also distributed across eastcentral Amazonia, from northern Rondonia to western Maranhao, always south of the Amazon River and east of the Madeira.Laranjeiras noted that Golden Conures flock, feed and nest communally. Groups forage in the canopy of the primary and secondary forest and spend much of the day at feeding sites. He observed them eating from 11 different types of trees and, depending upon the tree, the birds consumed fruit pulp, skin and seeds. The murud trees (Byrsonima ssp) appear to be a favored and important food resource. The birds also use this opportunity to socialize, allopreen and play before returning to their roosting site as a group. Preferred nesting sites seem to be in open, degraded areas near patches of intact forest.The main threat in the wild continues to be the deforestation of the Amazon. The construction of the Tucurui Dam, which flooded approximately 888 square miles of rainforest, had a significant negative impact upon the Golden Conure and as many as 294 species of other indigenous birds.These extensive studies may well have a tremendous impact on the future survival of the Golden Conure in the wild. Thankfully, there are protected areas that shelter populations, including the Amazonia and Jamanxim National Parks, Tapajos, Iraituba, Trairao and Caixuana National Forests and the Gurupi Biological Reserve. These protected areas represent the best hope for survival of the Golden Conure. It is obvious more field studies are needed to plan for the future. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3279</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 38 No. 4 (2011): Number 4 2011; 33-44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3279/3263</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
