<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/448</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding Cycle of the Gouldian Finch</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mobbs, Anthony J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of all the Australian finches, theGouldian appears to have the mostpronounced breeding pattern and, ifthe species is not allowed to carry outthe full cycle, it is more than likely abreeding attempt will fail.To someone who is not conversantwith the breeding behavior of thespecies, certain aspects can provesomewhat worrying. It is, therefore,beneficial for a breeder to fullyunderstand the cycle as not only 'Yillthis eliminate need for concern, itshould also enable a breeder to producemore chicks each year.HousingIn the United Kingdom the majorityof Gouldian finch enthusiastshouse their breeding pairs in individualcages. This is due partly to thesomewhat inclement weather weexperience. In certain areas of theStates, many breeders no doubt housetheir Gouldians in communal aviariesor outside flights. However, as mostGouldian finch breeders are interestedin mutations, it is preferable tocage breed, even where weather conditionsare ideal for outdoor breeding.More control can be maintainedover caged birds, which is essential ifa breeder wishes to line breed.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/448</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 1 (1989): FEB-MARCH 1989; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/448/433</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
