<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1637</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:50:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EX LIBRIS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AuSrRALIAN BROAD-TAILED PAJmm-s BY STAN SINDEL AND jAMF.&amp;lt;; GILL. HARDBACKED, 336 PAGF.S, 82 COLOH PHOTOS, EIGHT rx_'l.'.w LINE DHAWINGS, SINGIL PRF,,S, 1999, P.O. Box 9, ALISTRAL, NSW, 2171, /\t;~THALIA. Approx. $50.T he broad-tailed parrots are among the most popular in aviculture and I believe this to he the best hook written on the subject. The authors recognize eight species of rosellas (while acknowledging some of the species are closely allied) and they also treat the prominent subspecies and certain racial variants. They maintain the Barnardius genus for the Mallee, Cloncurry, and Port Lincoln ParrotsHaving kept and bred all hut one of the species mentioned in this most excellent new hook, I easily recognize the virtue of the information presented and would dearly loved to have had it in my early birdkeeping efforts. The authors are absolutely the most knowledgeable that I have ever read on the subject.And their hook is very well organized, too. After the Introduction (he sure to read this as it is a key of sorts to the rest of the book), the chapters are:• Housing • Diet• Management • DiseasesThe next section looks at the birds themselves with an entire chapter devoted to each of the 11 species Under "Housing," the reader is given the four common types of aviaries used for this group of birds with the virtues and hazards of each. This is a very good chapter and will save the reader much grief if the construction principles are followed -- and there are many options, one of which should fit your needs whatever your situation. Many of you unfamiliar with the metric system of measurements will shower blessings upon the authors for including in parentheses the American conversions of their measurements, e.g., 4 m 03 ft). You are on your own regarding temperature measurements, though. There are three excellent figures depicting elements of aviary construction that can he ve1y helpful in building new aviaries or remodeling the old ones.In the "Diet" chapter, you'll get all you need to know about feeding this family of birds including a basic seed mix, greenfood, vegetables, fruit, sprouted seeds, rearing food, and handfeeding diets. There are references to the broad-tailed birds' propensity to become obese and how to avoid it. "Management" says it all. This chapter contains data from cleanliness in the aviary to feed and water facilities, health issues, nesting, pairing, colony breeding, transporting, and everything in between. It is a remarkable instruction manual for all aviculturists experienced or not.But I believe the reader will most enjoy the 11 chapters chock-full of exciting information on the individual species and subspecies. You'll get the standard history, range, and field notes but you'll also get what you've never gotten before - lots of exquisite photos of the species, subspecies, and (can you believe it?) the plethora of color mutations. I had no idea there were so many beautiful mutations among this group of birds. You will he delightedAustralian Broad-tailed· Parrots by Stan Sindel and James Gill is absolutely the last and best word on these wonderful aviary birds. By all means a1Tange to acquire the hook.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1637</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 2 (2001): MAR-APR 2001; 31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1637/1614</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
