<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2325</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-08T18:07:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Visits ... Susan Lane's Suburban Flights</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Millstone, Michelle Brucker</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To many aviculturists, the heart of the Arizona desert might not seem the most likely setting for a suburban psitticine aviary. But Susan Lane has found this to be a very suitable environment. She has created an avian oasis within the confines of her Tucson home.Floor-to-ceiling glass enclosures, called atriums, are very popular in many homes in the Southwest. They are commonly planted with a variety of foliage, bringing inside a feeling of the outdoors. Susan Lane's general love for animals, along with a desire to add life and beauty to her atriums, sparked the initial interest in our feathered friends.This new fascination with birds began five years ago with the purchase ofasad-lookingmealy Amazon. Gomer, a surgically-sexed female, had been improperly care for, housed in an undersized cage at the pet store. As a result, she had many problems including minor kidney damage, dirty vent, watery stools and a missing toe. Having had only a budgie as a child, Susan Lane's knowledge about birds was limited. So, with the help of our local zoo veterinarian, Dr. Thomas 0. Miller, and considerable reading, a suitable program for housing care was established. Gomer was no longer considered "mean and untrainable" as once thought. She has proven to be a gentle companion, as well as a prolific breeder.Amidst the comforts of the living room, we find Gamer's four foot wide and seven foot long natural home. This atrium is completely enclosed by glass with a skylight serving as the sixteen foot high ceiling. Access to the atrium is from the hallway, through an open sliding glass door. Only the sliding screen door is secured to prevent Gomer from wandering. Due to its location within the home, this aviary is temperature-controlled with the rest of the house.The enclosure is planted with nonpoisonous foliage located just out of Gamer's reach, along with realistic silk plants, which she does not care to chew. The palo verde and mesquite are Arizona's most commonly found desert trees. The palo verde tree is poisonous, however mesquite is quite good for birds. So, cuttings of mesquite branches were placed throughout the aviary.Recently Bruce, a male mealy Amazon, was introduced to Gomer. A brown heavy vinyl garbage can decorated to resemble a whiskey barrel was hung at the eight foot level of the atrium to serve as a breeding center. This avian pairing resulted in the first clutch of two. The birds permitted Susan to fondle and tame the babies, all in the familiar surroundings of her own living room.Two larger atriums adorned with plants can also be viewed from the living room. It, therefore, seemed logical to create another suburban aviary with the addition of beautiful exotic birds. The second, very spacious glass enclosure measures sixteen feet wide, twenty feet long and ten feet high. Unlike the first atrium, this one is enclosed on three sides by glass and one side by a stucco wall. It is also open to the sky, thus necessitating a secure, yet ventilated covering. This was accomplished by nailing one half inch by two inch wood strips to the studs around the upper periphery of the enclosure. Netting was then attached to the wood strips using u-nails. It was further necessary to cut and resew one corner of the netting to accommodate a 30-foot palm tree. As added protection from the elements, a plastic mesh screen {like those commonly used to protect fruit trees) was placed over one half of the net covering. (Both the netting and screen were purchased inexpensively at a plant nursery.) This covering has lasted five years and has eliminated the need for a supporting center post, which would detract from the overall "natural" appearance. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2325</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 3 (1985): JUNE-JULY 1985; 27-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2325/2298</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
