<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/957</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:18:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Parrots for Dollars :   Rare Is Desirable</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">ask any American parrot keeper whether they would rather be given a Rose-breasted Cockatoo or a Nanday Conure and most likely their reply would be, "The Rose-breasted, of course."But what if imported Rose-breasted Cockatoos were available at $99 each;and the Nanday Conure was the last known female in the USA?It's a funny business, this aviculture for dollars.For some reason within the depths of human psychology, the rarer an object - or creature - the more desirahleit often hecomes. Even prior toEgyptian times, the nohle, the wealthy,the fortunate collected and displayedunusual objects or animal species toobtain oohs and aahs of esteem fromtheir fellow humans. I do it. You do it.We all do it. Rare is desirable.But why? And to what end?"It is the old five-year cycle in the hirdtrade," explains Rick Gerdl, a devotedand decidedly uncommercial breeder ofAustralian parakeet species in SouthernCalifornia. "A friend calls you up and says'I can't find any such and such species.''Well, I have one pair.''Do you want to sell them?'The word gets around and sooneveryone is looking for that species. Theprice goes up. More people huy themand set them up. Within four or five yearsthese pairs hegin to produce babies.Then someone comes up with 20, 40,100 babies they cannot afford to feedand house. They dump them on the market.The price goes down and we beginagain."Whew!Economically this is a working freeenterprise system. But is it aviculturallysound? Danger exists at the low endof a cycle when a species supposedlyhecomes undesirable.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/957</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 4 (1995): JULY AUG 1995; 13-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/957/938</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
