<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/689</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Understanding the Principles of Stress Reduction in the Aviary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bratt, James</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Every morning I wake up between6:30 and 6:45 a.m., stumble into thekitchen and start a pot of coffee. Whilethe coffee is brewing, I let the dogsout, walk to the end of the drivewayand get the paper. Then I return to thekitchen where I pour two cups of coffee,take out a prepared container ofsoft food and bag of frozen vegetablesand head out to the barn where myaviary is located. Once there, I feedthe horse and chickens, and then sitdown to watch the birds and drink myfirst cup of coffee. At 7:30, I put downseed, change drinkers, ptit soft food inthe breeding cages and flights, alongwith some frozen vegetables, andthen sit again to watch the birds anddrink my second cup of coffee. Myroutine is consistent, day in and dayout, broken only by the occasionalrushed morning due to other commitments.Each of our animals has adjusted tomy routine. Ami whinnies and startswalking to her stall as the back dooropens -not the first time when I letthe dogs out -but when she sees mecoming with coffee cups in my hands.As I approach the barn, the budgiesare already starting to chatter, even inthe winter when the sun is not yet up.As I get about 20 yards from the barn,one of the roosters crows and I canhear the turkey and hens starting torustle around. When I sit with my firstcup of coffee, none of the budgies godown for food. It is only after I put thesoft food and vegetables out that thefirst will fly down to see what thegoodies are for the day.As I became increasingly aware ofthese routines (habits), both mine andthe animal's, I was struck by thethought of a number of a1ticles I haveread over the years regarding need forconsistency and routine in aviarymanagement.Routines (habits) conserve mentalenergy by eliminating the need tothink things out in advance and tomake moment to moment decisions.Physically, they eliminate randompurposeless motions. When alteredover a period of time, they cause littlestress because of our ability to adjustour behaviors and create new behaviorsbased on our experiences with the new situation. Although budgies donot possess varying degrees of intelligencelike we do, they do possess theability to learn specific things. Biologically,this makes a lot of sense. Thereis a real reproductive advantage forany species which happens to havethe capacity to modify its behavior inspecific ways when confronted withvariability in its environment. So, notunlike us, changes in routine overtime are met adaptively with littleneed for our concern. However, Ihave also recognized how natural myown routine feels and how out of sortsI feel on those occasional days whereit is interrupted because of o"thercommitments.This feeling, "out of sorts", is mybody's physiological response to thestress caused by sudden change.Without routine, in a constantlychanging, unpredictable environmentthis physiological response is intensified.In humans we refer to it as anxiety.In a biological sense it means thatwe are expending an inordinateamount of energy adapting to environmentalchanges.In the animal world, the ultimateconsequence of all behaviors is theability or inability of the individual totransmit its genes to the gene pool ofthe next generation. All behaviorscenter on finding food, avoiding predators,locating a mate, inducing a mateto breed and caring for the offspringof that breeding. When budgies arerequired to expend a lot of energyadapting to changes in their environment,it interferes directly with theirability to conserve and focus theirenergies on these objectives. In thisrespect, while routine is certainlyimpmtant to the conservation of energies,it is not the only adaptation to anenvironmental factor that represents athreat to our budgerigars' ability toultimately pass on their genes.While most fanciers wouldacknowledge that sudden and dramaticalterations to routine or managementpractices, such as changingfeeds or feeding schedules should beavoided when possible, few have consideredthe stress exerted on theirbirds by the addition or removal of anumber of birds to or from theirflights. That budgerigars have some sort ofestablished social order and displaysocial behavior in the wild is arguable.The establishment of flocks seems tobe regulated by the density of availableseed rather than by the need forsocial interaction. As local crops areabundant, flock size is large. As thefood sources are more geographicallydispersed, the flock sizes are smaller.In observations of nesting hens sl1aringthe same nesting sites and sometimesthe same nest holes, the comparabilityseemed more a response tonecessity (the absence of other nestingsites in that locale than to thedesire to "be together:' Even the degreeof strict pair bonding that weobserve within our aviaries may notbe observed in the wild, as single henshave been seen to copulate with onecock and then immediately accept asecond and third cock without leavingher position on the perch. What socialinteractions do occur within the feralpopulations seems mostly to center onactivities associated with reproduction.In this feral setting, the impact ofenvironmental stress caused by thechanging densities of the flock arecounteracted by the fact that looselybonded groups tend to break off together.The impact of sudden individualdeaths due to predators, while itmay require adaptational changes forthose other individuals looselybonded to it, has essentially no affecton the flock as a whole due to thesheer numbers of individuals involved.In comparison, it has been fairlywell established that within an aviaryand especially within a flight somesort of established social order doesexist. One, seen infrequently in thewild, is a hierarchy of dominance, orpecking order as one would find in aflock of chickens. This has been evidencednot only in feeding trials andsituations of overcrowding, but is dramaticallydemonstrated by the territorialbehaviors of the hen in defense ofthe nest box and immediate vicinity ofthe nest box in colony breeding situations.While cocks, other than the pairbonded mate, are allowed to sit on thebox perch without reaction, otherhens are attacked savagely and onlythe pair bonded cock is allowed toenter the box.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/689</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 48-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/689/672</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
