<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2514</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-14T12:27:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ravens: Lore and More</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Believe me gentle readers, when speaking of zoos there is much to be said for small and intimate. Here at the Southern Nevada Zoological Park in Las Vegas, binoculars are not necessary. The pathways and benches are within a few feet of the exhibits. This happy condition allows the visitors to observe the animals close-up, indeed, nose to nose or nose to beak in some cases. This excellent condition also has a seldom recognized bonus - that of observing the observer. I have observed many a curious quirk in various and sundry visitors while they were looking for the same in a particular animal subject.One of the most consistent and predictable patterns of human behavior shows up as follows: Across one wall here at the zoo there are two aviary exhibits, one containing three large and beautiful macaws and one containing two glossy black ravens. One can stand and look into both aviaries at once. No big deal so far. Then one hears an absolutely avian voice saying: "Hello! I love you." Every eye, every time, turns to the macaw aviary to see which bird spoke.Then again one hears, "Hello' I love you, love you, love you!" and every eye switches in amazement to the raven sitting wisely on its perch in the adjoining display. Yes, indeed, folks, the raven out talks the parrot. The visitors, however, have been programmed to expect the parrot to talk and to expect nothing spectacular about so ordinary a bird as a raven.But is the raven an ordinary bird? I think not, my friend. A little observation and research shows it to be quite an extraordinary species of bird.My first experience with ravens was in the boreal forests of Alaska where I often saw the large, silent, solitary raven perched atop a dead tree watching me as intently as I watched it. A raven has a way of cocking its head to one side and observing one with great curiosity. A youth at the time, I couldn't help feeling that the raven was much more intelligent than I. Time has proven that early surmise correct. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2514</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 2 (1990): APR-MAY 1990; 48-50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2514/2485</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
