<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/974</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:18:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">APA   21st Annual Convention   New Orleans, Louisiana Radisson Hotel, 1500 Canal Street   August 9-12, 1995</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Radisson Hotel, formerly the Clarion Hotel is located just 5 minutes by taxi and a 15 minute walk (6 blocks) from the world famous, French Quarter. Other services include: Airport Shuttle to and from New Orleans International Airport, 24 hours a day, 7 days a week. Cost is $10.00 each way. Taxis are also available, for $24.00 each way. Free hotel shuttle from 10:00 a.m. - 12:00 midnight, leaving the hotel on the hour. Stops include: French Quarter, Jax Brewery, Aquarium of the Americas, Riverwalk &amp;amp; casinos. There is also a rooftop patio, hot tub and exercise room along with 2 restaurants and bars available. Check-in time is 3:00 p.m. and check-out time is 12:00, don't forget to mention that you're with the AFA to receive the special convention rates of $87 /night plus taxes. For reservations or hotel info call: (800) 824-3359. Reservations need to be made before July 15, 1995 to get this special rate. Our Host Club, the Gulf South Bird Club has arranged two ve1y exciting outings, a river cruise up the Mississippi river to the New Orleans Zoo, (one of the top zoos in the country) for a special behind the scenes tour on Wednesday, August 9, 1995. There will also be a Louisiana in the Afternoon swamp cruise through the timeless beauty of the Cajun country and tour of Destrehan Plantation, the oldest documented plantation house left in the lower Mississippi River Valley. Fine Food and Fun: there is never a lack of things to do in New Orleans. The flea market is open 7 days a week from dusk to dawn with everything for sale from souvenirs to jewelry and native crafts. Sample all kinds of live music in the French Quarter, world famous for its Jazz, there's also Blues, Cajun "Zydeco" and Rock 'n Roll for your listening pleasure. Follow the action on Boubon Street where you will find a carnival of cafes, cabarets, shops and numerous fine restaurants. Take a streetcar ride on the oldest continuously operating street railway system in the country. The ride tours St Charles Avenue and winds its way past the beautiful antebellum homes New Orleans is known for. There is also the Aquarium of the Americas that feature aquatic treasures from North and South American waters and the new "jewel of the Amazon" exhibit with wildlife native to the Amazon rainforest. The Aquarium is open from 9:30 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. For art lovers don't miss the New Orleans Museum of Art, open Tuesdays thru Sundays from 10:00 a.m. - 5:00 p.m. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/974</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 4 (1995): JULY AUG 1995; insert</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/974/954</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
