<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1977</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-06-28T02:49:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Feeding Program For Cranes</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">LaRue, Chris</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There arc probably a-, many di ffcrcru diet'&amp;gt; fed Lo crane' a' there arc collection' \\ ith cranes. Some reeding programs arc quite different from other' but many have been succcss ful in maintaining and breeding \Ol11e '&amp;gt;PCCiC'&amp;gt; of crane'&amp;gt;. ;\losl diets consi-: or a mixed grain ration or a commercial grain-based pelleted ration. These diets usually vary in protein from 20% - 40° o for the breeder diet. Some or these reeding program'&amp;gt; may also be '&amp;gt;UPplerncrued '' ilh Iivh or meat.The International Crane loundaiion in Baraboo, Wixconxin maintain'&amp;gt; a captive propagat ion program w i: h 14 0 f l he world's 15 vpccics otcranc-. BeG\U'&amp;gt;C oi L he large number or crane' in the collection and the cmphasi-, on reproduction, a feeding program ''as established that i-, economical, ca'&amp;gt;~ to handle. and prov idc-, for the nutritional needs or the bird-. This feeding program is based on four diets, each developed specifically for a certain time in the bird's fife and Ior the changing season. of a temperate climate.The Breeder diet is a 20.5°'0 protein rat ion wii h 2.450/o calcium and .890"0 phosphorous. This diet is cu st o m manufactured in a 3/16" pellet and is fed to all adult bird 3 year'&amp;gt; old and older during the breeding season. The Breeder diet i-, start ed the first of September. No fish or meat i'&amp;gt; added Lo the diet although the ration doc'&amp;gt; contain fish and meat meal. The only supplement given during the breeding season is ground oystershell. The oystershell i&amp;lt;i mailable at all times in a separate container. Studies at !CF have sho« n that some birds eat very little oysiershcll while those that do, generally eat more towards the end of the laying season. In some individuals the daily oystershell consumption peaks approximately .+8 hours prior to egg laying.When the breeding season encl'&amp;gt; the birds arc placed on the i\ laintenance diet for the fall and winter. This diet is a 19 . .+% protein ration with I OJo calcium and .86% phosphorous. Like the Breeder diet it is custom made in a 3116" pellet. During the cold weather of a Wisconsin winter the birds are given a small amount or whole corn dailv for additional carbohydrates. The vlainrcnancc diet i-, led yctu round 10 unmaturc bird-, lor ihcit t"ir..,1 three vcar-.Nc11 ly hatched chick' arc -rartcd on a 2311 u protein ration in a I x" pellet. The pellet ..,i;c i-, not di Ificult Ior 1 he bird-, Lo Gil and &amp;lt;ccm-, 1 o aid i 111 each i ng 1 hem 1 o accept food from a &amp;lt;poon during their f"ir'&amp;gt;l k\1 dav-, Thc chick'v growth rutc mu-t bc watchcd closely Lo a\ oid O\ c111 eight bird, and subsequent leg problcm-, '&amp;gt;UCh a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;lipped 1c1Klo11., on the hod joint. Gcncrallv , a crane chick 11 ill lo-.c weigh: for the Iirvt day' before beginning Lo gain weigh]. AL about I() dayv to 2 II l'Ck' or age [he chick ', daily \I eight gain \1 ill approach 20° o. ·\! thi-, lime the chick'&amp;gt; arc '-II itched form the Si an er diet 10 1 he Grow er diet 11 hich i-, the va me basic Iorrnu la a' 1 he\ lai 111 cnancc ra- 1 ion. The only difference in ration' i'&amp;gt; ihat the Grower i-, made in the I 8" relict. The 19..f0"o protein otrhc Grn11c1 ration -,Jm11, dow 11 weight gain allow ing 1 he chick\ kg'&amp;gt; 10 -,1 rcngthcn to accommodate the increase in weight a., it grow-. When abou1611cck-, old l he chick can cal l he larger .\ 16" pellet From da'.&amp;gt; I 10 J momh-, the chick&amp;gt; arc exercised daily 10 help comrol wciglu gain and strengthen their legs. During 1 hcsc exercise periods 1 he chick' freq ucnt ly cal numerous grasshoppers. crickciv. and other in-cci-; The chick-, arc alvo given accc'' to and use of a &amp;lt;mall pool to '&amp;gt;II im in.For large nurnbcr-, or crane, a pelleted rat ion ha-, many adv am agc-, ii i., ca-,\ to store, con. cniem 10 feed, and prov idc-, the birds a well balanced nutruional diet. The U\C of four separate dict-, al101\&amp;gt;, for the changing nutritional need&amp;gt; or the bird- at different age'&amp;gt; and during different time or the year. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1977</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 6 (1980): DEC-JAN 1980; 15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1977/1948</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
