<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1742</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-25T15:59:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Red Siskin Project Updates:   Breeding Season   How Did We Do This Year?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hansen, Paula</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Red Siskin Project (RSP) is having a fair season. Due to the record breaking rainy weather on the east coast this spring, project Siskins were off to a late start. This also slowed down everyone else in prospective pairings of unrelated stock. The west coast did better.It has been sometime since RSP has had any exposure or sponsorship to keep exchanges happening and with the outbreak of Avian TB which is now under control we're off and running.Many of you have been wondering what has been going on. Last quarter AFA Watchbird shed some light and RSP will be sharing with AFA Members in the Watchbird Journal on a regular basis. And soon there will be a link from the AFA new website to the RSP site. Updating will be easier as we upload information and pictures directly.Many of you are searching for that Yahoo Red Siskin Group. Sorry, but it's available for our breeders only. It is most necessary for us to network through this free media to manage ourselves and birds. Please feel free to email your questions to phhansen@earthlink.net or the AFA office.Due to the limited dollars available, the printing of 200 newsletters is not supporting our birds but taking needed dollars away. But interested parties will be able to view information by downloading from the RSP website or reading AFA Watchbird for updates. RSP website is under construction - please be patient. Remember the need to exchange and share in order to support the breeding and husbandry is critical to this consortium. Yahoo has limited our ability to expand, due to the free memory limits set recently. Our website will have a link to contact our breeders for any questions you may have also.Dedication and determination have reached fruition just prior to the APA Convention this August. RSP Subcommittee Board member Ron Castenor polished off a wonderful product that is now available to all - a CD Slide Show. This CD is played on your PC. It contains pictures of RSP Siskins, adults, nests, hatchlings, juveniles, and contains sound bites of their song. This is exciting for those who have never experienced this song. RSP encourages Regional Directors and State Coordinators obtain a copy and play the presentation to their local groups, and clubs. With each CD will be a pamphlet provided to read aloud during the presentation. Clubs are welcomed to request a copy of this CD directly from RSP. The cost includes shipping and handling. All proceeds will go directly to RSP to keep it moving forward.Another development came to light after months of locating a company to digitize our Red Siskin logo. Marketing Marlene Minor, and a project member will have available Red Siskin Project Polo-shirts. Both items were presented during the APA Convention. Keep your eyes open in the AFA Watchbird and APA's new website for both of these fundraisers. Income will help pay for lab testing, shipping expenses, and educational tools.Education and Sharing Information.Another way to gain knowledge and experience (and I believe there is no other way) is at your local club meeting. Invite your local state APA Representative or Regional Representative to come to the club and speak about what is new at AFA and ask them to bring information on the Red Siskins! Don't wait to be contacted by them. They are all listed in this magazine.Recent DonationsWhat did the project receive this year?In February, 2002 MichelleRichardson contacted RSP regarding the donation of Red Siskins Mr. Bud Ricks bequeathed to the family. The Siskin Project Director coordinated the arrangements for the donation. According to information given by the family, these Siskins are descendants of importations during the 1940s and 1950s. Thanks to this donation RSP will hopefully be able to continue this line for the next 50-60 years. Unfortunately, no breeding records were recovered. The birds are estimated to be approximately eight years old. Even if RSP can obtain one offspring from this genie source this would be exciting. Following USFWL rules, a Letter of Transfer was created to document this donation.During March, 2003 Cathy Estes, of Eugene, Oregon, donated a female Red Siskin. No parentage records could be located. RSP was informed that the New Jersey breeder was not registered with any consortium or listed in RSP studbook. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1742</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 30 No. 3 (2003): Third Quarter 2003; 30-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1742/1717</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
