<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2274</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-02-27T07:11:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bird Show Notices</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The 1984 National Cage Bird Exposition will take place at the Ramada Hotel O'Hare, Manheim &amp;amp; Higgins Rds., Des Plaines, IL 60018, on November 15, 16, &amp;amp; 17, 1984. The National Exposition is the "Academy Awards" of the bird world; exhibitors come from across the United States to compete for the coveted Kellogg Awards and the ultimate trophy, the Scannell, which is awarded to the Best Bird in Show. With these stakes, it is no wonder that the National Exposition is "Your Show of Shows," the largest show in the nation, and is growing each year.To continue the tradition of the National, the judge's panel is carefully selected with emphasis on maintaining the high standards of the National, and we are proud to announce the 1984 Panel:BordersRobert Ross, Canada TypesMargie McGee, California GlostersPaul Williams, Nebraska American SingersDaniel Feduk, New York and Ethel Keizer, Illinois LipocbromeBill Henderson, Indiana MelaninCase Quick, Canada Foreign/HookbillDick Clarkson, Florida BudgiesErmafern Collins, Iowa CockatielsRalph Bowman, Iowa LovebirdsDr. Al Decoteau, Massachusetts With these talented judges, the '84 how looks like another winner, and many of the top birds in the U.S. will pass their close scrutiny; over 3,000 birds should be entered.In keeping with tradition, the A.FA. will hold its next regional meeting in conjunction with the National Cage Bird Exposition. The Board of Director's meeting will begin at 8:00 a.m. 17 November. There will also be public seminars on a variety of avian subjects.The A.FA. is most fortunate to have Mr. Geoff Attwood of Devon, England as the feature speaker. Attwood is one of the premier lecturers in the world today on the subject of the production of exhibition budgerigars. He acquired his first budgies 30 years ago and ten years later became the aviary assistant to the fabled Mrs. A.M. Moss of Torquay whom many people believe had the greatest stud of exhibition budgerigars in the world. In his own right Attwood has bred some of the finest budgerigars ever produced including the bird that was second only to Alf Omerod's famous dark green cock that won the club show. Attwood is a Budgerigar Society judge on the main panel. Many top breeders have purchased birds from Attwood to upgrade their own stock, and in every other matter Attwood is considered one of the best budgerigar breeders in the world.Other top notch speakers include Lee Horton on lovebirds, Scott McDonald on avian medicine, Rainer Erhart on cockatiels, Bill Reichert and Don Perez on canaries, and David Guin speaking on the classification of Amazon parrots.For more information telephone Ray Rudisill (314) 645-6757.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2274</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 11 No. 5 (1984): OCT-NOV 1984; 38-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2274/2248</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
