<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3987</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T20:18:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">2023 Conference Recap</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferragamo, Concetta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (October/November 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.The action packed weekend was the first time the three organizations American Federation of Aviculture (AFA), Avicultural Society of America (ASA) and Organization of Professional Aviculturists (OPA) joined for an “Aviculture United” trifecta - educational conference. Talk about the “go-to” for everything aviculture, this was the event to attend. Here are some of the highlights of the conference starting with the two keynote speakers, Jamie Whittaker for AFA and Mindy Patterson for ASA and then there were non-stop presentations of 32 different talks starting from early morning straight into the evening Thursday, Friday and Saturday concluding at the Saturday night banquet.Speakers There were some top avian doctors who gave wonderful presentations, Susan Clubb, DVM (The role of Avian Veterinarians in Implementation of the Animal Welfare Act), Carol -Lynn Meissner, DVM (Viruses and Zoonotic Diseases with avian influenza as a model), and Sharman Hoppes, DVM (Update on Avian Bornavirus). If you didn ’t make it to the conference, Dr. Hoppes has also provided an article in this issue of Watchbird with her update.International vet tech and HARI spokeswoman, Josee Bermingham presented a talk about holistic first aid. Attorney, David Garcia spoke about the new USDA regulations resulting from the Animal Welfare Act..Miel Niemann is no stranger to AFA, having made the trip from Germany with her parents on numerous occasions, but 2023 marked her first appearance as a presenter. Tony Silva was scheduled to make a presentation via Zoom, but managed to arrive in person all the way from India!There was also a special surprise speaker in the person of Dr. Cody Yager, a veterinarian with the U.S. Department of Aviculture. Dr. Yager has been a key player in the development of the avian regulations for the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS). With assistance from Steve Duncan and David Garcia, attendees got an in depth understanding of what will be required under the new regulations and had an opportunity to have a multitude of questions answered.AFA Legislative VP, Adrianne Mock and Lobbyist, Mark Finkelstien conducted part two of Legislation 101, a legislative workshop which was open to the public both for in -person as well as zoom attendees. Part one of the presentation was held on September 7, 2023, via zoom. Handouts from the presentations are available for download at https://online.flippingbook/view/192028009.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3987</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 4 (2023): Watchbird October/November 2023; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3987/3947</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
