<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3526</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-22T21:48:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">28th Annual AAV Conference</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cosgrove, Barbara</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The AAV Conference was held at the Westin Hotel in Providence, RI. August 4~9, 2007. There were hundreds of veterinarians, not only form the USA and Canada, but also from around the globe. Also, in attendance were veterinary students, presenters, avicultural organizations, avian club members and vendors.I was honored to have been asked by Dr. Laurie Hess DVM, Diplomate ABVP (Avian Practice), a member of the AAV Board of Directors, to speak on August 4'h. My topic, "Let's Talk: Parrot Breeding"was well received and included a CD presentation of my parrot babies, nursery, and some of the aviaries.As the Connecticut State Coordinator to AFA, Linda Rubin, Northeast Regional Director asked if I would have a booth for AFA at the AAV Conference. The rest is history-va huge success and the building of a great rapport with AAV! On August 7 and 8, 2007, the AFA display was magnificent and drew people like a magnet, bringing hundreds of people for AFA information. My husband, Bob, Michele Parrett, Connecticut Parrot Society Club Delegate to AFA and myself handed out close to 300 hundred veterinarian brochures, AFA applications, Fundamentals of Aviculture course inforrnation and more, to veterinarians, students and all other attendees. Twenty-nine CITES pins were soldl Ten veterinarians joined and many more were planning to go to the AFA web site to join.We spoke each day with many people about AFA and all its benefits, including its involvement in legislative issues effecting avian species. Also discussed was the new AFA course, "Fundamentals of Aviculture" by Rick Jordan and Barbara Heidenreich. We highly recommended it to the doctors for their veterinarian technicians and clients, and all others involved in any aspect of aviculture. We saw a great deal of enthusiasm about the course.As one of the founders and current president of the Connecticut Parrot Society, Inc., an AFA affiliate club, I felt fortunate to represent AFA and CPS. I also had the pleasure of talking with people I hadn't gotten to see in awhile, among them Dr. Irene Pepperberg and Liz Wilson. I also had the pleasure of meeting Barbara Heidenreich, as well as other presenters and vendors.What a positive move AFA made in enjoying a good rapport with such a prestigious association as AAV. Both groups certainly share so many common interests. AAV has asked that AFA be a presence at all their annual conferences in the future! </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3526</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 34 No. 3 (2007): Number 3  2007; 51-52</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3526/3510</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
