<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4098</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:20:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Message from the President</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">LePage, Mary Ellen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (January 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Looking back on 2022, it was a busy year. The American Federation of Aviculture (AFA) resumed publishing Watchbird on a quarterly schedule, and presented a great educational conference in Virginia. AFA Disaster Relief was busy helping our bird community in Florida after Hurricane Ian. AFA also contributed to two conservation projects, Natura Mexicana Scarlet Macaw Conservation and Costa Rican Yellow–naped Amazon Conservation Initiative and sponsored a nestbox for the Blue-throated Macaws through the Bird Endowment. Please donate to AFA so we can increase our activities.In 2023, our 49th annual Conference will be held in Dallas at the Hilton Richardson Dallas Hotel from September 28-30. This year the American Federation of Aviculture joins with the Avicultural Society of America (ASA) in presenting a joint conference. We believe this joint conference will be more and better than individual conferences.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4098</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 1 (2023): Watchbird January 2023; 3</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4098/4058</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
