<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1329</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-10T22:47:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Adelaide Rosella</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hutchins, Barry R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Introduction For many years there has been conjecture whether the Adelaide . Rosella is a true species or a subspecies of the Crimson Rosella Platycercus elegans elegans. The latter follows the usual taxonomic nomenclature and for the purpose of this article I, too, will treat the Adelaide Rosella as a subspecies with different forms (i.e. races). While saying this, there are minor character differences between the Crimson Rosella and the Adelaide Rosella. Crimson Rosellas are more tolerant to humans in the wild, they readily accept feeding stations in parks and gardens and will put their trust in "the hand that feeds them." Adelaide Rosellas are more distant to humans. They tend to be forever alert and could not be classed as tolerant of humans. Crimson Rosellas tend to spend more time on the ground during the winter months foraging for food, compared with Adelaide Rosellas which spend more daylight hours in the canopy of shrubs and trees. This could purely be a feeding pattern as the vegetation is so variable over the distribution of both groups of birds. For readers who are interested in the different subspecies, I have given a descriptive word picture of their plumage, coloration, distribution and habitat. This is followed by the housing and captive breeding sections. Subspecies Platycercus elegans fleurieuensis Ashby 1917 Generally referred to as Adelaide Rosella or rosies. Description: Adult Male. The adult male is approximately 13.5 inches in length. The feathers of the mantle and back are black, edged with orange-red, being more orange-red than black. The underparts are bright red with the upperparts paler than the Crimson Rosella P. elegans elegans. Adult Female. The adult female is similar to the male hut the head is smaller and the upper mandible is nar- Distribution of Adelaide Rosella, fleurieuensis, adelaidae, subadelaidae rower and smaller. Immatures. Immatures are similar to P. elegans adelaidae and are described under "immatures" of that species. Distribution P. e. fieurieuensis occupies an area embracing Cape Jervis to Victor Harbor and Goolwa to Happy Valley Reservoir south of Adelaide. Opinions differ on this northerly boundary hut as there is a great variation in color with this and its allied subspecies, a distinct limit of the distribution is difficult to define. I have, therefore, included the area where numbers of these brightly colored birds are found, even if others of less brilliance do inhabit the same area. Habitat The area inhabited by .fieurieuensis is referred to as the Lower Mount Lofty Range and includes some beautiful country of rolling hills and valleys with permanent creeks and small rivers, with an annual rainfall of approximately 24 inches. Much of this area which has a wide range of trees and shrubs is used for dairy farming and mixed farming but, probably because of its somewhat hilly terrain, many trees have been left providing an ideal habitat for the subspecies which, if not increasing numerically, are at least holding their own. Many towns exist within their range and suburban Adelaide is fast spreading into the southern areas but, because people like to grow fruit and almonds, it is unlikely that their presence will have any great effect on the avian population. In latter years people have begun to study the bird's environment and are inclined, where possible, to leave as many large trees as is practicable, Platycercus elegans adelaidae Gould 1840 Also known as Adelaide Rosella. Description Adult Male. The adult male of this subspecies is approximately 14 inches in length, The forehead and crown is red, nape and side of the neck orangeyellow marked with red, cheek patches violet-blue; hindneck, mantle, scapulars and back black, with each feather margined with varying shades of color from olive-yellow, red, dull brick-red to yellowish green. Underparts vary from scarlet to orange-yellow, rump and upper tail-coverts olive-yellow marked with red; primaries black with dark blue on the outer webs; median upperwingcoverts black, bend of wing and secondaries pale blue. The central tail feathers are dark olive, washed with green with the remainder being pale blue tipped with white; bill is a greyish-horn color, iris dark brown and legs grayish. Adult Female. The adult female is similar to the male with the body color being just as variable. The head is smaller and upper mandible narrower. Immatures. The nape, mantle and hack are greenish-olive and the rump is olive-green; cheek patches violetblue, red frontal band extending onto crown, breast and abdomen greenish- is referred to as the Lower Mount Lofty Range and includes some beautiful country of rolling hills and valleys with permanent creeks and small rivers, with an annual rainfall of approximately 24 inches. Much of this area which has a wide range of trees and shrubs is used for dairy farming and mixed farming but, probably because of its somewhat hilly terrain, many trees have been left providing an ideal habitat for the subspecies which, if not increasing numerically, are at least holding their own. Many towns exist within their range and suburban Adelaide is fast spreading into the southern areas but, because people like to grow fruit and almonds, it is unlikely that their presence will have any great effect on the avian population. In latter years people have begun to study the bird's environment and are inclined, where possible, to leave as many large trees as is practicable, Platycercus elegans adelaidae Gould 1840 Also known as Adelaide Rosella. Description Adult Male. The adult male of this subspecies is approximately 14 inches in length, The forehead and crown is red, nape and side of the neck orangeyellow marked with red, cheek patches violet-blue; hindneck, mantle, scapulars and back black, with each feather margined with varying shades of color from olive-yellow, red, dull brick-red to yellowish green. Underparts vary from scarlet to orange-yellow, rump and upper tail-coverts olive-yellow marked with red; primaries black with dark blue on the outer webs; median upperwingcoverts...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1329</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 3 (1999): MAY-JUNE 1999; 42-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1329/1307</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
