<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3311</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-07T10:19:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">25 Things to Do in San Antonio</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">1. The Alamo is the number one attraction in San Antonio.If you don't knowTexas history, surely you will remember the John Wayne movie! "Remember the Alamo"!2. The Buckhorn Saloon and Museum, a San Antonio tradition since 1881. Wildlife and the Wild West combined for a great place to visit.3. Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center, art exhibits and crafts of the Native Americans and Latinos.4. IMAX Theatre in Rivercenter Mall, downtown. Relive history's thirteen days of glory as 189 Texian and Tejano defenders fight for Texas in the Alamo.5. Japanese Tea Gardens, walk the winding pebble walkways and the stone bridges. Relax by the waterfall and tranquil pools.6. King William Historic Area, this 25 block area on the south bank of the San Antonio River dates back to the late 1800's. It was originally settled by prominent German merchants and is now, as then, an elegant residential area.7. La Villita, inside these shops you will find artists and craftsmen making unique items.8. Market Square - El Mercado, patterned after an authentic Mexican market, the square is alive with activity from early morning until late at night.9. Natural Bridge Caverns is the largest cavern in Texas and attracts 250,000 visitors a year.10. San Antonio Botanical Garden with global flora, native Texas plants and a greensward for South Central Texas.11. San Antonio Missions National Historical Park is a cultural oasis in the heart of San Antonio. The 819 acre park offers visitors a journey back in time in Texas history. 12. San Antonio Zoo, recognized as one of the top zoos in the country, has one of the largest bird collections in the U.S.! Don't miss the behind the scenes tour available to interested attendees on Wednesday afternoon.13. Serengeti Resort, enjoy a wine tasting from the "Wines of the World Tour''. Enjoy your wine on the veranda and watch as the giraffes and zebras pass you by.14. Tejas Rodeo, a live pro rodeo facility. You can have your picture taken on the photo bull or try your hand at riding the mechanical bull.15. Tower of the Americas, built for the 1968 World's Fair.Standing 750 feet tall and offering a breathtaking view of the city.16. The River Walk winds and loops under bridges as two parallel sidewalks, lined with restaurants, shops, hotels and more. Take a river cruiser or a sunset taxi ride from downtown on the river.17. Pearl Brewery-site of the historic brewery founded in 1881.18. Fiesta Texas! Is a 200 acre theme park featuring rides and great shows.19. SeaWorld-full of endless adventures for everyone. A Sunday afternoon visit is planned for interested attendees. See Sea World with friends!20. Haunted Tours of Downtown San Antonio, let the Sisters Grimm lead you on a candlelight tour of the supernatural side of the city.21. Golf! Historic Brackenridge Park golf course, designed in 1915 is the oldest public track in the state. It is also the home of the Texas Golf Hall of Fame.22. Ripley's Believe It Or Not Museum with a 4D theatre and over 500 displays of the odd and unusual - Believe it or Not!23. Louis Tussaud's Plaza Wax Museum representing Hollywood scenes and the new Freedom's Journey for history buffs.24. Spanish Governor's Palace, this National Historic Landmark was constructed in the early 18th century and restored in the 1930's.25. Aztec Theatre, a beautifully restored 1926 theatre on the banks of the River Walk. Built in the Mesoamerican style, the theatre is home to the San Antonio Rose Live show .. . . and much, much more! </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3311</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 39 No. 2-3 (2012): Number 2&amp;3  2012; 25-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3311/3295</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
