<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4019</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Why Exotic Animals Should be Legal to Own in The United States</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rio, Catalina Del</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 2 (April/May 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Do you remember the 2011 cartoon movie Rio? Did you know that it ’s based on a true story? The Blue Spix ’s Macaw of Brazil was declared extinct in the wild in 2000, but they still existed in captivity in extremely low numbers in private collections and a couple of zoos. A global effort was put in place to create a conservation breeding plan to bring this species back from the brink of total extinction. Spix’s macaws still exist. The real-life story is even more incredible than the movie! Habitat loss is the number one cause of animal species becoming endangered and/or going extinct. Thousands of species around the worldare near threatened or highly endangered. Many other species have already gone extinct. Why couldn ’t they have been saved? Did no one care about them? Was there enough knowledge to keep them alive in captivity while a wild reintroduction plan could have been implemented? Should we even care if a species goes extinct?Now, imagine this: If people didn ’t know about the problems facing wild animals, why would they care about saving them? If the countries where these animals are native do not value their existence and value their habitat, how will they avoid extinction? Who will fight for their existence? Wild animal conservation organizations, zoological organizations, and animal enthusiasts are primarily responsible for exposing exotic animals to the public, educating the public about them, perfecting how to maintain them in captivity and reproduce them successfully, and preserving theirwild habitats. Even if a species has an excellent wild population and is not currently threatened, conditions on the ground are dynamic and can literally flip overnight due to geopolitical conflicts, catastrophic weather, disease, and all -out war. If something terrible happens to a species that would cause them to become threatened or even go extinct, captive breeders can bring them back.I grew up with my family, keeping and breeding exotic animals such as birds and reptiles. My father has been involved in the exotic animal world for almost 40 years. He is currently the Chairman of the American Federation of Aviculture Committee for CITES (Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora), a global organization that manages all animal and plant species. He works with zoos and private breeders to preserve exotic species in captivity. He is colleagues with many of the people who are partof these conservation breeding and reintroduction programs. Our family currently is working with 11 different bird species that are threatened or endangered. Over the years, we have kept and bred many dozens of species that are threatened or endangered. We need to prevent restrictive laws that are constantly pushed by animal rights zealots whose sole purpose is to eventually eliminate all zoos, exotic animal keeping, and pets and to break the human-animal bond completely.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4019</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 2 (2024): Watchbird April/May 2024; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4019/3979</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
