<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/790</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-13T16:18:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The International Parrotlet Society</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The International Parrotlet Society is a non-profit bird club which is dedicated to the breeding, maintenance, education, showing, conservation and keeping of parrotlets. Although current members focus on birds from the genus Forpus, the International Parrotlet Society also encourages the breeding of the genera Nannopsittaca and Touit. The club was founded by Sandee and Robert Molenda, and Gloria Balaban, aviculturists who had bred these tiny parrots exclusively for years with great success. Being frustrated with the lack of accurate information available and the anonymity of parrotlets in general, they decided to form a parrotlet-only bird club. This would allow pet owners and breeders to compare notes, exchange ideas and swap stories as well as promote the keeping of parrotlets within the avicultural community. So, with very little money, even less experience and a lot of hard work, the International Parrotlet Society was begun. In August 1992, the first meeting was held at the American Federation of Aviculture convention in Miami and it has been growing steady and strong ever since. Currently, the club has over 250 members in three different countries. Although most of the members are breeders, about 20 percent of the members keep parrotlets as pets only. Each member receives a bi-monthly newsletter with articles written by breeders and pet owners on subjects such as nutrition, identification of species and subspecies, breeding methods, training techniques, handfeeding, banding, parrotlet psychology, color mutations and behavioral problems. Members are also encouraged to submit individual questions and concerns in the Shorties column. While other members most often respond, several veterinarians are available for medical and scientific advice. Since February 1993, each issue also contains a beautiful color photograph identifying a different species or subspecies of parrotlet. In January of each year, a confidential survey is taken of the entire membership, both breeders and pet owners. All members answer questions regarding nutrition, hygiene, cage requirements, species and number of birds owned and any deaths. Pet owners are asked about socialization, favorite toys and talking ability. Breeders answer questions concerning incubation, handfeeding, banding, egg viability and baby production. This information is then tabulated and published in the newsletter. steady and strong ever since. Currently, the club has over 250 members in three different countries. Although most of the members are breeders, about 20 percent of the members keep parrotlets as pets only. Each member receives a bi-monthly newsletter with articles written by breeders and pet owners on subjects such as nutrition, identification of species and subspecies, breeding methods, training techniques, handfeeding, banding, parrotlet psychology, color mutations and behavioral problems. Members are also encouraged to submit individual questions and concerns in the Shorties column. While other members most often respond, several veterinarians are available for medical and scientific advice. Since February 1993, each issue also contains a beautiful color photograph identifying a different species or subspecies of parrotlet. In January of each year, a confidential survey is taken of the entire membership, both breeders and pet owners. All members answer questions regarding nutrition, hygiene, cage requirements, species and number of birds owned and any deaths. Pet owners are asked about socialization, favorite toys and talking ability. Breeders answer questions concerning incubation, handfeeding, banding, egg viability...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/790</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 3 (1994): MAY-JUN 1994; 50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/790/773</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
