<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/648</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Artificial Incubation of Exotic or "Non-domestic " Bird Eggs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kuehler, Cyndi</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Artificial incubation of bird eggs isnot a new avicultural practice,although the actual origins have beenlost in the passage of time. One of thefirst records of human beings artificiallyincubating and hatching eggswas written in the fourth centuryB.C. by Aristotle. In his writings aboutanimals, he described some of the earliestknown techniques: "in somecases, as in Egypt, they are hatchedspontaneously in the ground,by beingburied in dung heaps. Instances haveoccurred of eggs being deposited inwarm vessels and getting hatched spontaneously" (Aristotle, 1910). DeReaumur (1750) also wrote about thesuccess of the sun-dried mud brick(adobe) incubating ovens of ancientEgypt, and is quoted as saying "Egyptought to be prouder of them than herpyramids." Techniques involvingchicken and duck eggs also originatedduring the same time period in ancientChina and spread to what are now thePhilippine Islands, Vietnam, Laos,Cambodia and Taiwan.During the 20th century, the poultryindustry elevated the art of artificiallyproducing chickens into the realm ofmodern science, and today it is aninternational food industry. Techniquesfor producing, storing, incubatingand hatching eggs arewell researched and continuallyimproving. Unfortunately, the correcthusbandry techniques for artificiallyhatching most exotic or "nondomestic"bird eggs are still in theexperimental phase. However, thebasic principles which govern thedevelopment of the chicken in an artificialenvironment also applies toother bird species. Poultry literature isan excellent source for learning techniquesand determining causes ofmortality in exotic birds.Today the role of the aviculturist isexpanding, and effective captivepropagation programs incorporateknowledge from disciplines such asavian science, field biology, genetics,nutrition, veterinary science andbehavior. The exotic bird industrywhich involves zoos, conservationistsand private aviculturists is evolvingvery rapidly. Age-old avicultural wisdomcombined with poultry techniques,such as artificial incubation andinformation about birds in the wild,improves husbandry and maximizesreproduction in a captive environment.The benefits of artificially incubatingbird eggs are well known. Captivebirds do not always incubate or hatchtheir eggs successfully and inadequateparental care often results in eggabandonment, breakage and chickmortality. Manipulating egg productionby removing eggs from the nestfor artificial incubation and hatchingalso induces hens to "double clutch"and lay additional eggs during thebreeding season. This is a managementtool which has been used successfullywhen the production of additionalchicks is critical, as in the caseof endangered species such as theWhooping Crane (Crus americana),San Clemente Loggerhead Shrike(Lanius ludovicianus mearnsi)(Kuehler et al., 1992) and the CaliforniaCondor (Gymnogyps californianus)(Erickson and Derrickson,1981; Kuehler and Witman, 1988).The successful hatching of eggs inan incubator requires two things: a"potentially hatchable" egg and anadequate incubation environment.First, in order for an egg to be potentiallyhatchable it should be clean andfree of viral, bacterial and fungal infection,and it must have been producedby genetically and nutritionally soundparental stock. Contamination,inbreeding and inadequate maternaldiet can result in eggs which are nothatchable under conditions of eithernatural or artificial incubation. Thesecond requirement is the correctincubation environment. This meansthat the dry bulb temperature, humiditylevel and turning process is appropriatefor optimal embryonic development.Egg StorageTo improve the chances for a successfulhatch, eggs should be set assoon as possible. Egg storage is a husbandrytechnique which enablesbreeders to hatch clutches togetherand simplify the chick rearing processby producing birds which can bebrooded in like-age groups. However,proper techniques for egg storage areoften overlooked which results in anincrease in early embryonic mortality,poor hatchability, prolonged incubationperiods and weaker chicks (Proudfoot,1968; Chahil and Johnson,1974).Loss of hatching viability appears tobe species dependent and very little isknown about the storage tolerance ofnon-domestic bird eggs. For example,Chukar (Alectorus graeca chukar)eggs can be stored for as long as 28days without any effect on hatchability,while Cockatiel (Nymphicus hollandicus)clutches stored for only sixor seven days show a reduced hatchrate; eggs stored for longer than eightdays do not hatch at all (Woodard andMorzenti, 1975; Roudybush, 1984).If storage is necessary, nondomesticeggs should be maintainedat 12.8 to 18.3°C (55 to 65°F), at a relativehumidity of 80 to 90 percent,for no more than seven days(Schwartz, 1977; Roudybush, 1984;Kuehler, pers. obs.). Holding temperaturesabove 26. 7°C (80°F) will allowcell division to continue at an abnormalrate resulting in decreased hatchabilityand abnormalities in the brainand eye regions of developingembryos. There is also some evidencesuggesting that placing eggs in fineporedplastic bags that allows someair circulation, increases the hatchabilityof stored eggs. The incubation periodis still longer than normal becausesome embryos, from stored eggs,require a longer developmental period(Bowman, 1966; Schwartz, 1977).Sanitation/Egg ContaminationParent birds and the hatchery itselfare both recognized as potentialsources of infection in newly-hatchedchicks and incubating eggs. Becausethe hen uses a common passage forboth eggs and fecal matter, and theincubator environment is warm andmoist, embryonic diseases are causedboth by the intestinal contents of parentbirds and contamination fromincubators and hatchers. Microbialcontamination resulting in infection isof two types: exterior eggshell-bornediseases and interior egg-borne diseases.Contaminants are more easilyeradicated from the surface of theshell than from within the egg.Hatchery sanitation should includemaintenance of disease-free birds anda well ventilated, easily cleaned incubationand hatching area. Protocolswhich emphasize egg handling withclean, dry hands and a flow patternwhich minimizes traffic from areasthat are possible sources of contamination(such as adult breeding stock)are optimum.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/648</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 37-46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/648/631</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
