<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/640</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Echo Parakeet ... the world's rarest parakeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Venning, Judith</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Recent successes in field managementof the Echo Parakeet are givinghope for the future of this highlyendangered bird. The world's rarestparrot struggles to survive in theseverely degraded forests on Mauritius,a tropical island in the IndianOcean. The Echo Parakeet is confinedto a small patch of endemic forestencroached upon by introducedplants which are unsuitable for feedingor nesting. Less than a dozen birdsstill exist in the wild. The World ParrotTrust, an environmental conservationcharity based in Cornwall, U.K., is participatingin a dual scheme to provideconservation management to the wildbirds, while attempting to breed additionalEchos in captivity for eventualreintroduction to the forest. In additionto funds, the Trust has supplied afour-wheeled-drive jeep to facilitatetransport of equipment to remoteareas of the forest. Much of the fieldwork and management is coordinatedby Welshman Carl Jones, who hasbeen responsible for the project sincehe launched the rescue package in1973.Mauritius is 1,865 sq. km. and has apopulation of over a million people.When it was first discovered in the late16th century, ebony forests and palmsavannahs covered the island. Therewere giant tortoises, fruit bats andmany reptiles. There were between 30to 40 unique species of bird includingsix species of parrot. The most famousbird of all was the dodo.By 1972, large areas had beencleared for tea plantations and othersfor pine and softwood. A survey in1976 found only 11 species of birdand only one parrot species, the EchoParakeet. The island is now welldeveloped and little remains of thenative forest. The only sizable remnantleft is to be found in and aroundthe Black River Gorges, where theparakeets live. The parakeets have arange of about 60 sq. km. but most oftheir time is spent in an area lessthan half this size centered on theMacchabe Forest.In the early 1970s, there were about50 Echo Parakeets, but following forestdestruction in the mid '70s, theirnumbers fell alarmingly, until by 1981only ten birds were sighted.Carl Jones and his fellow field workersbegan to see results from theirresearch and breeding attemptstowards 1987. By 1990, they hadreared seven birds in captivity fromharvested eggs and chicks, andobserved nine new birds amongst thewild population of some 20 birds.Unfortunately, over two thirds of thebirds are male and the cause of thisimbalance is still unknown. Sparemales frequently fly in associationwith established pairs of Echo Parakeets.Eggs are usually laid between Octoberand December; two or three to aclutch. Carl Jones and his team do notwant to upset the natural breeding ofthe wild birds, so eggs or young areonly harvested from nests where thebirds have laid early in the season andare likely to raise a second brood laterin the year.Field studies show that plants onwhich Echos feed are so scarce thatthese green parakeets are exhaustingthemselves foraging, leaving littleenergy for breeding. Months of supplementalfeeding trials in the wildhave finally met with success. TheEchos can now feast on a selection ofreadily available fruits and chiles suspendedin wire feeding baskets whichare especially designed to suit hungryparakeets but dissuade rats, monkeysand other bird species.The Echos have great difficulty competingwith other species in their huntfor suitable nesting holes, and theireggs are often stolen by rats. Aftermuch experimentation, Carl and histeam have recently perfected artificialnest log cavities which are acceptableto the Echos when positioned, withsome difficulty and precision, on clifffaces and in tall trees. Parts of theforest are also being cleared of intrusiveexotic weeds and parakeets areshowing a marked preference forcolonizing these areas.After consultation with the JerseyWildlife Preservation Trust, the Mauritiangovernment plans to designatethe forest in which the Echos dwell asthe island's first national park. Its primarypurpose will be conservation.However, the World Parrot Tmst anticipatesthat support for "hands on"conservation of the Echo Parakeet willbe required for many years.At present there are four healthyEchos in the aviaries, aged six to ninemonths and developing well but asyet unsexed. Future plans include theresearch and creation of a new diet forthe Echos, which could produce a reallong-term benefit to the project andmay also help other species of parrot.The New York Zoological Society andthe World Parrot Tmst are starting thenecessary analysis and developmentof the new food.Anyone who wants to support thisEcho Parakeet rescue plan is asked tosend a donation or £15.00 for a membershippack to the World Parrot Tust,6G, Glanmor House, Hayle, Cornwall,U.K.Further information and photographsavailable from: Judith Venning,David Woolcock or Mary TalbotRosevear, The World Parrot Trust,Glanmor House, Hayle, CornwallTR27 4HY, U.K. Phone: 0736 753365,Fax: 0736 756438. •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/640</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/640/623</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
