<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1555</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:53:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The American Federation of Aviculture and the Ara Brasil Institute; a Partnership for the Conservation of the Spix's Macaw and Brazilian Psittacines</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schischakin, Natasha</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gallaway, Benny J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Berry, Robert J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he American Federation of A vi culture (AF A) and the Ara Brasil Institute, a newly organized Brazilian Non-Governmental Organization (NGO), have recently partnered to help in the Brazilian conservation efforts for the Spix's Macaw (Cyanopsitta spixii), one of the world's most critically endangered psittacines. (See AfA Special Spix's Macaw Report by Natasha Schischakin in Nov/Dec '99 issue AFA Watchbird).The mission of the Ara Brasil Institute is to work on the conservation of psittacines in Brazil, with particular emphasis on the "blue" macaws (Spix's, Lear.s and Hyacinth). The Institute is founded on the philosophy that sue- cessful conservation programs need to incorporate a multi-faceted approach, including field research, habitat conservation, community-based conservation, and, when necessary, captive breeding and reintroduction. It is a goal of the Ara Brasil Institute to provide linkage opportunities for the avicultural and zoological communities to partner directly on "in-country" parrot conservation programs in Brazil.Following publication of the ahove report in the AFA Watchbird, a donor came forward with a pledge of $30,000 to AFA in support of Spix's conservation. These funds were received in May 2000 and were earmarked by the donor for the implementation of the Ara Brasil Institute and their conservation activities relating to the restoration of Spix's Macaws into their native habitat. This major donation also provided the impetus for the development of various AF A projects that will lend additional financial support to this compelling and critically urgent conservation effort.In this direction, the Ara Brasil Institute will continue the successful techniques of developing in-country, community-based conservation programs for other Brazilian psittacines, enhancing protection for habitat and ecosystems. By developing a campaign in support of the Spix's Macaw Conservation program, the AFA is providing its members with an opportunity to contribute to the recovery of a species that was considered practically extinct, but which is recovering because of captive breeding and management. It is also a chance to support a multi-faceted conservation approach that has united aviculturists, field researchers, government officials, zoo professionals and the local rural villagers with a single goal-the recoveiy of the Spix's Macaw, one of the world's most endangered species.Why the Spix's Program is Important to AvicultureThe Spix's Macaw conservation program is a program that is closely associated with and dependent upon aviculture to save the species from extinction. The Spix's Macaw is endemic to an arid region of savanna scrubland in Northeastern Brazil known as the "caatinga." The loss of habitat from five centuries of human colonization of the region likely contributed to its decline. However, this very rare species was also valued in both the national and international avicultural markets. Because of indiscriminate collection, this already vulnerable species was believed extinct in the wild by 1989. At that time, there were only 11 confirmed birds in captivity worldwide, although many more were rumored to exist. Some ornithologists considered the last few captive birds to be mere relics and that, for all practical purposes, the species could be considered to be extinct. The Brazilian government rejected that view and made it possible for aviculturists to help save the species.After 10 years of intensive conservation efforts administered by the Brazilian government and the Permanent Committee for the Recovery of the Spix's Macaw, the captive population presently consists of 60 individuals and continues to grow. A reintroduction effort is now in the planning stages. This could not have occurred if the wildlife authorities of the Brazilian Institute for the Environment and Natural Renewable Resources - IBAMA (the equivalent of the US Fish and Wildlife Service) had not initiated a unique approach in their last minute initiative to save this species.The Brazilians chose to develop a program whose primary focus would he the recovery of this species, and instituted a Permanent Committee for the Recovery of the Spix's Macaw. This Committee is comprised of a diverse group which includes government officials, ornithologists, zoo specialists, as well as national and international aviculturists holding Spix's Macaws in captivity. The inclusion of aviculturists on the Committee was a bold step for the wildlife authorities, as there had been many calls by ornithologists and conservationists to simply confiscate the birds held by private aviculturists.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 4 (2000): July-August 2000; 32-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1555/1532</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
