<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1143</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:30:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Psittacine Bathing a fundamental aspect of care</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hefton, Donna M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Mnkind has kept parrots incaptivity for centuries, witheasons stemming from theceremonial needs of primitive culturesto the ornamentation of palaces andliving rooms. Today, when comparedwith other pets, parrots that are kept ascompanions are finding that their placeis held in high regard.Life shared with a parrot oftenchanges one's view of the world. Inrecent years, a shift in attitude of howwe have been keeping these birds incaptivity has become apparent throughthe extensive publishing of materialregarding cage dimensions, nutritionalrequirements, the safety of toys andmaterials employed around parrots,and the attention to the behavior andpsychology of the animal itself. Whatthese captive birds require is that wegive them what they are missing fromtheir natural environment.For the past several years I havebeen studying psittacine bathingbehavior and researching the rainfalldata in areas to which variouspsittacines are indigenous. Since themajority of these data is more thanobscure, the task of compiling thisinformation has become greater than Ihad first imagined. To put it simply, ifmankind does not inhabit a particulararea there seems to be little need toknow anything specific about it.One of the more interesting points Ihave discovered about the range anddistribution of the psittacines is thatthey tend to be situated in a sort of"geographic band" around the planet.Located in regions between the Tropicof Cancer and the Tropic of Capricorn,which are allocated zoo North and zooSouth of the equator respectively, thepsittacine has evolved in some of themost lush and humid places on earth.The exception to this are the species ofNew Zealand which seem to illustrateDarwin's concepts of adaptation andnatural selection. The parrots of thisarea have adapted and are noticeablydifferent than those residing in the zoonorth/south band. There are a fewother species outside of the "tropicalzone" also but this paper focuses onthe vast majority of psittacines whichdo live within the tropics.Rainfall amounts in the regions ofthe psittacines' natural evolutionaryprocess can technically be measured infeet, rather than inches. An abundanceof water is the general rule in this environment.Averages range from 90 to350 or more inches, with more commonaverages of Z50 to 350+ inchesper annum. For many years we havebeen instructed to "occasionally mistour birds with a spray bottle" and withthis type of information I feel that wehave done a great disservice to thisanimal.Allowing the parrot a good soakingwith plain water is essential to thehealth of the plumage, which is theprimary means of survival for birdsthrough flight, warmth, and camouflage.The avian feather is brilliantlyconstructed to interact with water. Theaccumulation of dirt, dust, and thedebris of our environment is eliminatedby the simple wetting of the featherswith nothing more than cleanwater. Removal of debris in the featherallows for a better preening result anda more accurate "zipping" of the barbuies.Parrots bathe to survive, and wethought that it just made them lookgood!The Crop BibI am presently examining a theoryas to the reason some parrots plucktheir feathers. When presented withthe question, "Why does my parrotattempt to jump into its water cupimmediately after I shower him/her?" Ihave come to believe that this is due towhat I refer to as an inadequatelysoaked crop bib. I am conductingstudies of bacterial colony countsbefore and after a good soaking of thefeathering that covers the crop. I callthis area the crop bib. My thought isthat since this area of the bird is thewarmest, or a "hot spot," it may standto reason that bacteria will grow rapidlyhere.To take it a step further, considerthe powdered species such as thecockatoos and African Greys whichare notoriously known for plucking.Imagine bacteria on the skin coveringthe crop area. Now, place the bird'snatural powder over the bacteria inthis warmest of areas and you havecreated an incubator-like environment,allowing the bacteria to proliferate andgrow on the skin. Trapped betweenthe warmth of the skin and the powderproduced by the bird, the microorganismis technically in the most conduciveenvironment for growth.Without an adequate flushing or soakingof the skin in this area, the bacteriacauses itching of the skin. This situationmay lead to feather plucking asthe bacteria grows down the skintoward the chest area where the birdcan reach the feathers. A thoroughflushing of this area is not unlike howwe remove bacteria from our handswhen we wash them. I intend to publishthe results of this study when sufficientdata is compiled.Water TemperatureWater temperature used for bathingthe parrot should also be considered.Human caretakers, with exposed skinand lower body temperatures, tend toprefer warmer water temperatures fortheir showers. Also, the surveys takenreveal that the primary caretakers ofbirds are women and most women traditionallytake hotter showers than domen. A woman may set the water temperatureand think, "Ah, that feelsgood," and proceed to put this wateron an animal that is already "cooking"at approximately 104°F.Cool down the water for your bird'sbath. Rain is cooler than the ambienttemperature in the environment. That'swhat makes it so refreshing. Parrotstend to respond more enthusiasticallyto water of cooler temperatures. Somespecies that prefer to pool bathe actuallyprefer ice water in their bath!Observe the bird to see which watertemperature elicits the greatestresponse. The majority of parrotspecies really do exhibit a preference.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1143</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 2 (1997): MAR-APR 1997; 51-52</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1143/1122</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
