<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/880</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:17:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE: "Some Thoughts on Food"</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Throughout the birdkeepingworld, there seems to be almostas many concepts about feeding asthere are aviculturists. Strong opinionsabound wherever nutritionists gather.What seems certain is that we havecome a long way: little more than onehundred years ago, psittacine collectorsin Europe were debating whethercockatoos really needed water! Andthese days many totally different feedingprograms produce monumentalsuccess.We of The Natural Choice accent severalfactors in our regular feeding schedule.The first of these is raw unprocessedfood. Each and every wild caught aviancreature imported into the US was bornand raised on natural, uncooked foodsources. That is the way the ancestors ofour captive birds survived for tens ofthousands of years. Our belief is thatbirds being fed a great part of their dietwith "unlive" or processed foods are atgreater risk to develop deficiencieswhich manifest as organ failure, reducedimmune systems, tumors, badtempers or other behavior problems. Atleast 50% of all the food we offer ourflock is in the natural form as it occurswhen harvested. Furthermore, whenpossible, we like to spend 30 minutes orso prior to morning feeding gathering"wildcrafted" food ingredients- thosetaken from nature following the patternof what other wild birds are eating in ourarea. If such sources are not readilyavailable, we turn to our garden, whichis grown without chemicals or commercialfertilizer.A typical morning feeding for our aviarieswill include seeding grasses,flower and weed buds, undried sunflowerheads, orchard papaya, guava,passionfruit, and macadamia nuts alongwith garden vegetables and greens likecarrots, peas, asparagus, beets, kale,vine spinach, chard, comfrey, celery, lettuce,nasturtium and more.Six years ago, in conjunction withaviculturist Dale Thompson in Californiaand Bob Miller of 'Til Friends" BirdDiets in New Mexico, Feathered Friendsof Santa Fe designed and began mixing a "Morning Soak Mix" based upon Thompson's work with "Soak and Cook" products being used on the west coast, but without the need for cooking. Acceptance by finicky wild-caught pets and the nutritional results compared to our old feeding program have been nothing short of phenomenal. Three months on the new diet and our pets were trimmer, more active, brighter colored at their next molt and eating a greater part of all the foods provided them (much to the benefit of our pocketbooks!).This basic mix is comprised of pearl barley, lentils, green split peas, brown rice, yellow split peas, white proso millet, raisins, whole oats, canary seed mix containing flax, rape, niger, and hemp and rolled corn. It is soaked in boiled or hot water for at least 20 minutes in the morning while we are having our coffee, drained well and mixed with our chopped fruits and vegetables and a powdered vitamin/calcium supplement.Having noticed at the shop that a vast majority of pet and hobby bird owners are unwilling to cook regularly for their birds, we chose to offer this quicker solution to the need for fresh and soft foods. The decision to include canary and other quite nutritious tiny seeds in the soak mix was to procure certain results: 1) It provides parakeets, Cockatiels, lovebirds, Australian and grass parakeets and the like with a daily dietary ingredient closely resembling seeding grasses in the wild (canary seed is akin to spinifex grass species); 2) It creates an enjoyable crunchy ingredient, in the otherwise soft food, which sticks to the pieces of carrot, squash, cucumber, lettuce and such after the entire batch is mixed up. We quickly noticed that larger picky parrots who would pick up carrot for example and drop it out of their food dish were holding onto the chunk and nibbling off the canary seeds. Four weeks later the same parrots would take a prolonged chew from such carrot chunks they were holding before letting them drop from their mouth. Presto! A whole new arena of food offerings opened up for our Goffin's Cockatoos, African Greys or Green-winged Macaws who would heretofore not touch vegetables!I, for one, no longer agree with birdkeepers who tell me that such and such a bird will not eat vegetables. One hardheaded Rose-breasted Cockatoo took four whole months before she began sampling the morning soak mix. Normally it is the aviculturist who gives up first; but we persisted in filling a cup for her every morning along with her seed mix (a holdover from the previous owners).Of course there are certain guidelines to feeding soft foods. We find cockatoos and Cockatiels are more likely to accept a variety of vegetables than loads of fruit, for example. Many pet owners cut up large hunks of fruit or veggies and when the bird throws them out, they conclude he or she will not eat that. But it takes a tremendous amount of time and effort for a bird to throw out grated soft foods. Smaller pieces has solved many a finicky-eater syndrome.Serving up live foods also entails avoiding the temptation to pour out a quantity of frozen peas and carrots every day and call that vegetables for your bird. Taste them sometime! This is not how thousands of generations of wild birds fed and evolved. We recommend pet owners look seriously at such item offered to their birds. Was it freeze dried, molded, extruded, vitarninized, boiled, toasted, pressed or powdered? None of this equates to wildcrafted bird foods with vitamins, amino acids, minerals, and complex enzymes existing in the balances put there by nature.The second factor emphasized in our aviary feeding program is variety of content. If I offer an interesting food dish to my birds, invariably they rush down to the bowl to take a look and begin eating. This means varying the fruits and veggies in weekly cycles or greater monthly cycles. Not only is strict routine of food source boring to intelligent birds, but it has the added danger of establishing dangerous metabolic routines in our flock. With all our wonderful knowledge of avian nutrition, we have not yet learned it all. To offer the same foods day in day out year after year is to risk subtle nutritional setbacks which may manifest as untimely death, mate aggression, or more commonly, breeder shutdown.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/880</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 2 (1995): MAR-APR 1995; 34-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/880/862</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
