<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1166</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:31:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Book Review: Softbills: Care, Breeding and Conservation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vince, Martin</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">W;en the great majority ofecently published avianooks on the marketinvolve parrot-type birds, it was wonderfulto see a great instructive aviculturalbook on the large group of birdsknown as softbills.Of all the types of bird held in captivityin American aviculture, the mostfragile and most likely to disappear inour aviaries are members of the softbillgroup of birds.Martin Vince has written an excellentbook on all aspects of the careand breeding of softbills in captivity.Having been involved personally insoftbills for many years (SedgewickCounty Zoo, Wichita, Kansas and mostrecently at Riverbanks Zoo andGarden, Columbia, South Carolina),Martin Vince's expertise in the care ofsoftbills really shows in this book.Other aviculturists can now benefitfrom his knowledge. I personallyappreciate receiving details on aviculturaltechniques from someone whohas first hand experience in the successesand failures that have occurredin collections of softbills.The book begins with an introductionthat defines the term "softbill."Softbilled birds do not have soft bills.Softbilled birds eat soft food. In themain, it is their food which is soft,r;Jther th;Jn their hills.Having gotten that out of the way,Vince's first chapter is called "Acclimatingand Establishing. " and tellshow to begin with new softbills inyour aviaries. This is crucial as manysoftbills are rather delicate-especiallythose imported from their native habitatwhich may be much different thanthe environment in your aviaries. Thefirst step, says Vince, is to provide thenewly arrived birds with as enticing adiet as possible. Their high metabolismdemands that they consume food frequently-usually fruits, and livefood.Only gradually can one introduce artificialfood.The same chapter also talks abouttransferring the birds outdoors. I tellswhich groups of birds are winter-delicateand which are winter-hardy. Andit gives some guidelines on feeding thebirds in the cooler locations. The chapterends by saying it takes a full year toget the softbills as acclimated as theywill ever be.Chapter Two is ''Purchasing aSo.ftbill. " It outlines a number of questionsto ask and things to look forbefore your purchase. I tells how toinspect a bird and what to look for.''Housing" is the title of chapterthree. Here you'll learn how to build aflight cage, how to plan for an outdooraviary and flight, plan for an indooraviary and flight, the use of greenhousesand ma~y other helpful hintson how to make homes for your softbills.One of the nicest things about a collectionof softbills is that plants, inmany sizes and varieties, will usuallybeautify the aviary and enhance thehappiness of the birds. From an aestheticstandpoint, a well planted softbillaviary is a joy to behold. You allknow how long a beautiful plant willlast in a parrots aviary. Most softbills donot share the parrot's destructivenature. Chapter four is entitled''Plants. "It contains excellent and specificadvice on how best to use plantsin connection with softhills and providesa long list of plants consideredsafe and another list of potentiallytoxic plants.There is a "Catching and Handling"chapter and then two long chapters on"Diets and feeding Techniques" and"Nutrition." these chapters are quitedetailed and can be referred to timeand again as you work with your softbills.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1166</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 3 (1997): MAY-JUNE 1997; 51-52</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1166/1145</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
