<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/593</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-04T01:39:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Kingfishers and their relatives in Australia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Forshaw, Joseph M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">We are going to look at the Australian members of the Order Caraciiformes, a group of birds that probably is not as familiar as many other groups of birds. I am referring mainly to the parrots, finches, pheasants, waterfowl - the groups traditionally associated with aviculture. In the United States, the Belted Kingfisher (Ceryle alcyon) is widespread and generally common, so is familiar to most of us. In southern Texas, near the Mexian border, you will find two additional species at the northern limits of their ranges; these are the large, spectacular Ringed Kingfisher (Ceryle torquata) and the smaller, brilliant Green Kingfisher (Chloroceryle americana). In general appearance and habitat preferences, all three species are similar - they frequent waterways and feed mainly on fish. In other words they conform to impressions of a typical kingfisher. Also it is noteworthy that although the Belted Kingfisher is common and widespread, kingfishers could not be considered a prominent component of the North American avifauna. In other parts of the world, notably Africa and southeast Asia, the situation is very different. In these countries, kingfishers that frequent waterways and hunt fish are a minority, and the variety of species constitute a conspicuous element in local avifaunas. Kingfishers are well represented in Australia, where the eleven species include spectacularlycolored inhabitants of tropical rainforest and the well-known species commonly seen perched on powerlines or fenceposts. Undoubtedly the best-known Australian species, and probably one of the most celebrated of all our birds is the Laughing Kookaburra (Dacelo novaeguineae), which is the world's largest kingfisher. Although most capable of quickly changing a garden fishpond into just a garden pond, the Laughing Kookaburra is not really a ''fishing" kingfisher, but is a member of the woodland or dry-country group, the group to which most species belong. Though they are often found near watercourses, these woodland kingfishers are not dependent on water, and indeed some species have adapted to semi-desert habitats. They use the same ''wait and see" hunting techniques of their fishing counterparts, though the dive is to the ground or a tree branch to capture their prey. Man-made structures are often utilized as vantage perches. Laughing Kookaburras are native to the woodlands and forests of eastern Australia, but have been introduced to Tasmania and southwestern Australia. They have successfully colonized man-made habitats, and now are familiar in city parks, urban gardens and sportsfields, and around farmhouses. They become quite tame, so have acquired a reputation as "friendly birds" and, if offered food regularly, they soon adopt a fearless disposition, even coming at the same time each day to be fed. There are many reports of birds knocking their bills against the door, or even coming into the home, if feeding is delayed. Of course, it is the strange laughing call that is the renowned attribute of these birds. The famous laughing song usually is given by two or more birds, most frequently in the twilight of early morning and evening. Dawn and dusk choruses of Laughing Kookaburras is the sound that so effectively epitomises the Australian countryside, and certainly it is out of place in early Tarzan films! Kookaburras killing snakes is a feature of Australian folklore, and there are even ballads describing such situations as a bird swooping down to kill a snake that was about to attack a playing child! The birds obviously are efficient predators of small to medium-sized snakes, but in lore their prowess is larger than life. The diet also includes insects and their larvae, earthworms, snails, freshwater crayfish, frogs, other reptiles, small birds, fishes, and of course, prime hamburger steak! Laughing Kookaburras are extremely sedentary, and they reside in clearly delineated territories, which may contain a mated adult pair or a family group comprising the adult pair with one or more auxiliaries. These auxiliaries are young from previous years; as non-breeding adults, they remain with their parents to assist with territory defense, incubation of eggs, and care of chicks. Some individuals are known to have remained auxiliaries for up to four years before replacing breeding adults. Across northern Australia, the Laughing Kookaburra is replaced by the smaller, more colorful Bluewinged Kookaburra (Dacelo leachii) with its distinctive white eye and sexually different tail coloration. The Blue-winged Kookaburra occurs also in New Guinea, where there is found the remaining two species of kookaburras. Indeed, it is ironic that the only species which does not reach New Guinea is the Laughing Kookaburra, and its species name is novaeguineae! The majority of woodland or ''nonfishing'' kingfishers belong to Halcyon...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/593</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 5 (1992): OCT-NOV 1992; 42-46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/593/576</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
