<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/433</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-03T21:40:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Avian Medical Management for the Remote Aviculturist</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clipsham, Robert C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Video Cameras as Tools for Avicultural Management. The concept of employing video cameras is certainly not a new one as far as its use as a business aide. Dating services learned a long time ago that a substantial number of potential customers could be convened together at a future date with littleinconvenience to anyone, at a fraction of the cost of actually handling large numbers of real live people simultaneously. As we look for means of improvingour ability to assist aviculturists in their efforts to increase productivity, several tools have taken on significance far beyond their original priority level when compared to our traditional tools, such as microscopes and surgical instruments. Our greatest tools are, without a doubt, our means of communication and hence the telephone and typewriter have become a mainstay in our arsenal to defeatdisease, poor productivity and cash flow losses for our clients. We have both spent a considerable amount of effort in aiding bird owners and aviculturists alike, educating them in their concern with basic sanitation, compound construction,disease control, diagnostics and preventive medical planning. As more aviculturists become aware of our availability, we find ourselves returning phone calls to more and more distant locations. At first, this struck us as being a bit curious, as we assumed that other resources closer to home would be more efficient to start with, rather than skip multiple time zones and fill Ma Bell's limitless pockets. On inquiry, we discovered we received much the same answer. Many aviculturists from ideal bird raising areas were either too far from any qualified avian medical assistanceor their veterinarian was already frustrated in the task of taking on a problem of great complexity involving multiple intertwined facets of management and disease. And, the longer we examined the problems of avicultural medical management, it became painfully clear that disease control and aviary management are one and the same. No degree of medication...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/433</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 6 (1988): DEC-JAN 1989; 14-21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/433/418</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
