<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2230</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T02:16:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Questions and Answers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tkachuck, Richard D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Greetings to those of you who share the avicultural fever. Since last I wrote a number of letters have come and as a result, I shall attempt to give some suitable answers. Which comes to a point that needs to be made. You, the reader, should take the printed material below as advice; hopefully it is informed advice, and not as ultimate truth. Aviculture is not yet an exact science and is still largely anecdotal. It is the aim of the Watchbird staff to attempt to make bird breeding almost kid-proof but as yet there is more art than science in this most wonderful of activities. So, on to the questions. -Editor.Question: Will you please ask your readers if they have a recipe for mineral block? I have my own formula for feeding newborns and would be glad to exchange in return. Your help would be appreciated.GS, PennsylvaniaAnswer: I personally have no such recipe, but would welcome such from readers. If such are sent in, please tell why you roll your own when commercially available ones are available. Also, include how long you have used such and why you think it successful. And, GS, how about telling us YOUR secret?Question: I am trying to find out if anyone outside of japan has, raises or breeds Japanese Tumblers (Parus varius) or varigated tit. How are they bred in captivity or are we locked out by the restrictions of export?Answer: An interesting question! One of my sources said that he has not seen these birds in the past 15 years. They once came from Japan and had a curious flight which resembled that of pigeons. ~ do not believe that they are banned by importation officials. If any of the readers know of the existence of such a colony in the U.S., send us a note. Perhaps if there is enough interest someone could import a few.Question: I have two cockatiels, which have recently had young. One of the chicks is 5 months old and does not have any tail feathers. He get one and it falls out in about 4 days. Other than this he is a very healthy bird.Also, I would like to know what books are available on the subject of veterinary medicine for birds.Answer: Any chance somebody is picking on the tailless critter? If not, you might have either a genetic problem for which you can do nothing or you might have a nutritional problem which could respond to treatment. With regards to the second case, have you tried supplementing the food with a vitamin and mineral mix sprinkled on the soft (fresh) food you give?Time for the soap box again. A number of the cage birds that are kept are highly inbred. As a result, an increasing number of genetic problems seem to be popping up. I know what I am going to say is hard to take, but at least think about it. Would it not be best to eliminate these birds from the breeding population? That could mean either killing them (an unpleasant option to you as well as to me) or perhaps giving them to someone as a pet who will keep them as such and not attempt to breed them. (Certainly, not selling to some unsuspecting person.) I am concerned that if we continually permit the genetically infirm to be maintained, we will eventually reap a poor harvest. Personally, I believe it is poor management to allow birds into the public arena that one knows are inferior.Some good books? Sheldon Dingle recommends these:Diseases of Cage and Aviary Birds.Margaret L. Petrak, D.V.M., Editor. Lea and Febiger, Philadelphia, 1982. 2nd Ed. (Probably the best book.)Bird Diseases. L. Arnall and I.F.Keymer. T.H.F. Publications, Inc., Neptune City, NJ, 1975.Caring for Your Pet Bird. R. Dean Axelson, D.V.M. Canaviax Publications Ltd., 41 The Links Road, Toronto, Ontario, MZPIT7 Canada, 1981.OLD BUSINESS ...A while ago someone questioned whether or not lovebirds could be kept out in the cold. I was a bit disappointed that no one from the midwest has written. Perhaps the record cold killed off everything and there was nothing to write about. We did receive mail from other regions, though, and answers from Oregon and Sweden follow.-EditorQuestion: Can lovebirds be kept out in the cold?Answer: Here in Oregon we had a cold speU where the temperature was about 5 째 F during the day and below O 째 F at night. I have an 11' x 11' x 8' high room of 3/4" plywood with two windows, cement floor and fiberglass roof with no heat or insulation. I keep black-masked lovebirds, cockatiels, Senegal parrots, and Indian ringnecks. In the daytime the 8" diameter 1-1/2" deep water dishes were changed three times a day. They were frozen solid. The birds all seemed to fare well with no indication of being sick or cold. This bird room adjoins our house with the living room window being one of the walls. The birds are under observation all day and did not appear to be affected by our recent cold spell.S.L., OregonAnswer: Regarding lovebirds and cold, I can tell about a friend here in Sweden who successfully bred Fischers lovebirds in an outdoor flight during Answer: In your column in the Dec. the winter with tern per a tu res '83 -Jan. '84 issue of the Watchbirdyou sometimes dropping to 20 째 C below asked that people respond regarding the zero ( - 4 째 F). The breeding was carried size of the flight that they breed roseUas through without any real problems ex- in. I have bred Gold Mantle Rosellas in a cept that one youngster froze to death. flightthat was 48"1x30"h x 25 "w. The It had gotten out of the nest box early 48" side was the front and was the only and could not find its way back before side to have wire. I used a nest box that nightfall. After this incident, my friend was 12" x 12" x 24"h that was fastened always helped the youngsters back into on the front of the cage. The birds were their nest box before dark each evening. fed a seed diet made by Abba Products A small indoor flight, where their food of New Jersey that was supplemented was served, was available for the birds with mixed vegetables, soaked corn, all of the time but they didn't use it ex- fresh greens, and vitamins. In one year cept for feeding. The birds had a big nest they had 3 clutches of 4 babies each. I box made of thick, solid boards and a lot took the babies when the youngest was of twigs were available. The thick 2 weeks old and hand raised them. The wooden walls...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2230</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 11 No. 2 (1984): APR-MAY 1984; 10-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2230/2204</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
