<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3135</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-02T21:31:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Conservation Corner</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boyd, Janice D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Red-browed Amazon (Amazona rhodocorytha) is endemic to the Atlantic forest of eastern Brazil and is one of the most endangered mainland Amazons. It is threatened by habitat destruction and fragmentation, as well as by the removal of young from the nests for illegal trade as pets. Less than 10 percent of the original habitat remains, and the wild population could be as low as 845 birds and continues to decline.The Institute for Research and Nature Conservation (Instituto de Pesquisa e Conservacao da N atureza-Ideia Ambiental) of Curitiba, Brazil, is conducting a project for the conservation of the species in the wild and, as an insurance policy, in 2006 also began a parallel project to establish a captive breeding program in Brazil.In 2005, Lora Parque Fundaci6n with help from one of AFA's Avian Research Grants provided a grant to the Brazilian Institute of Research and Nature Conservation (Ideia Ambiental) for the project "Establishment of a Breeding and Research Center for the Red-browed Amazon (Amazona rhodocorytha) at the Curitiba Zoo in Parana state, Brazil."In 2006 the breeding center was constructed on land owned by the Curitiba City Zoo. The scientific breeding center allows a genetically viable population of the species to be maintained in captivity, allows for exchange of information with other breeders, and can be used for possible re-introduction of birds back to the wild. Louri Klemann Jr. of Ideia Arnbiental leads the project, which also benefits from the advice of Pedro Scherer-Neto of the Curitiba Natural History Museum (Museu de Hist6ria Natural Capao da Imbuia).Klemann established the initial captive population with 21 birds that had been confiscated by the Brazilian authorities and were transferred from their facility at CEREIAS to the new center by IBAMA (Brazilian Institute of Environment and Natural Resources). Following quarantine and gender determination, these birds were placed in a large flocking aviary to choose their own mates, creating at least seven pairs for breeding. The pairs were then transferred to the breeding aviaries.The Red-browed Amazon is not easily induced to breed in captivity, and to date few breeders can report breeding successes. Therefore, two breeding seasons have been required for the birds in the Curitiba center to reach maturity and to feel comfortable with their surroundings.In 2009 the first pair to breed is currently rearing three healthy chicks, which it fiercely defends. A close observation is being maintained of the other pairs for signs that they might also soon breed successfully. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3135</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 36 No. 4 (2009): Number 4  2009; 14-20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3135/3119</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
