<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1680</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:15:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Blue-crowned Hanging-parrot ( Loriculus galgulus)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kasper, Ron</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T his family consists of 13 species of hanging-parrots including the Vernal, Ceylon, Philippine, Blue-crowned (also called Blue-topped), Maroon-rumped, Sula, Moluccan, Sangihe, Orange-fronted, Green-fronted, Green, Yellow-throated, and the Flores Hanging-parrot. But this article will feature only the Bluecrowned Hanging-parrot.DistributionMembers of this genus are found in southern and south-eastern India, Sri Lanka, Thailand, Malaysia, Singapore, Borneo, the Philippines, and some Indonesian islands. Fewer are seen in Singapore and Malaysia today but these are popular cage birds that are sometimes taken from nests in their indigenous countries.The Blue-crowned Hanging-parrot is found in southern Thailand, western Malaysia, Singapore, Sumatra, and associated islands, and Borneo and associated islands.HabitatBlue-crowned Hanging-parrots frequent the forests, forest edges, secondary growth, swamp and riverine forest, bamboo patches, mangroves, wooded gardens, coconut groves, and plantations. They are probably more abundant in carefully logged forests than in the primary forests.FoodThere are very few records but these birds are typically frugivorous, feeding on wild figs of many species, nectar, buds, oil-palm fruits, and perhaps on small insects.BreedingThe Blue-crowned is the most common species available in the U.S. although still scarce. Typicallythree eggs sized 0.74 to 0.65 inches are laid. The hen incubates while the male is responsible for feeding her.In Aviculture CagingIn captivity, a minimum of 70° F. is desired. A preferred cage size is about 6 x 3 x 6 feet although we use much smaller cages.metA typical captive diet consists of grapes, bananas, apples, pears, beets, cantaloupe, watermelon, canned sweet potatoes, a dry or liquid mixture of Jory nectar at all times. I use a blend of canary and finch seed, as Cockatiel seed seems too large for their beaks. Hangers have voracious appetites and can consume an apple in a day if split in two. Vegetables include cut up pieces of corn on the cob, which they have a real fondness for. We have noted an interesting trait with the birds - they will favor one type of fresh fruit or vegetable for a while then reject it for a few days and eat an alternate food.Hanging-parrots are basically fruit eaters in the wild and also appreciate fresh flowers like hibiscus for the pollen and twigs to use sap to clean their feathers. Because of their diet they are somewhat like softbills in cage care. They do squirt fecal matter and I use acrylic sides on the cages. Strict hygienic care is necessary as they are prone to fungal ailments due to diet and the matter that is discarded.I have been told they like baths but I do not provide them with that during the winter but they do like to keep themselves clean and will be seen preening themselves frequently. Interestingly, because of their diet of fruit, I suppose, they have a sweet fruity scent that is rather pleasant. Captive BreedingPrior to breeding, the pairs are given a wide assortment of fruits, vegetables, mealworms, lory dry or liquid mixtures, insectivore mixtures, and canary/finch seed mixture, and egg food. Artificial light is not needed for reproduction.We use parakeet nesting boxes attached to the outside so we can monitor progress and note any problems. Several inches of pine shavings are placed in the box. The females have a unique characteristic of carrying nesting material under their wings. Partially covering cages with towels to maximize privacy is helpful.The hen will begin to sit when the last egg is laid.At about two weeks of age, the babies are usually standing in much fecal material regardless of how strict the hygiene is (again, hygiene is a must with this species). At this point they are taken and handfed to weaning. Often, the female will set up another nest.As with any exotic species of bird, patience is important. Some have many clutches while a pair I have set up now has an interested female but uninterested male.At about 1-1 1/z years of age the young males begin to color up. However, in the Conservatory, weaned birds are DNA sexed and banded, which allows us to know the gender at a very young age. This helps us to plan where specific birds are most needed among Conservatory members. This also helps in preventing the very significant problem of inbreeding.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1680</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 1 (2002): Fourth Quarter 2001; 24-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1680/1657</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
