<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3282</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-03T12:31:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Post-Convention Coverage of ‘Jewels in Aviculture’</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">S an Francisco, California, could not have been a more ideal venue for the American Federation of Avicultures 37th national convention Aug. 3-6, 2011. The city of the Golden Gate Bridge, cable cars and perfect weather was the welcoming backdrop to more than 30 convention speakers packed in doubletrack talks during the four-day event.Convention attendees flocked to the San Mateo Marriott Hotel for the latest in avicultural information, an exhibit hall brimming with the newest bird-related products, silent auctions, Super 8 raffle prizes and fantastic networking opportunities. Special events included a Legislative Panel Discussion, AFA4Kidz Program, National Specialty Organization Meetings-and the first SPBE Parrot Show held at AFA in more than 25 years!The AFA annual board of directors meeting-open to all AFA members-kicked off pre-convention activities. Next day highlights included the House of Delegates meeting for AFA delegates of affiliated clubs and organizations, with presentations by committee chairs on AFA programs and activities. An off-site zoo trip for convention delegates followed at the Oakland Zoo, with an evening welcome reception in the exhibit hall sponsored by Bird Talk magazine that was open to all convention attendees. The hall showcased an array of vendors' booths and the AFA Sales Store including convention theme art work, and an abundance of unique avian, decorative and educational items.A three-day lineup of renown national and international presenters included Keynote speaker Susan L. Clubb, DVM, Dipl. ABVP (Avian) on "The Past, Present and Future of the Pet Bird Industry" and "Parrot Relinquishment Survey of 2010." Additional veterinary presenters included: Scott Echols, DVM, Dipl. ABVP (Avian) "Using Nutritional Supplements to Manage Diseases" and "What are We Really Feeding Our Birds?"; Dr. Sharman Hoppes, DVM, Dipl. ABVP (Avian) "When a Dilated Proventriculus is Not PDD"; Ian Tizard, BVMS, Ph.D., ACVM, "Avian Bornavirus Update"; Leslie Woods, DVM, Ph.D., Dipl. ABVP (Avian), and Asli Mete, DVM, Ph.D. ''A Survey of Avian Diseases at the California Animal Health and Food Safety Laboratory System-Parts 1 and 2."Other scientists and expert talks included: James Gilardi, Ph.D., "World Parrot Trust's "Fly Free" Program"; Walt Frey, Ph.D, "Breeding and Keeping the Red-vented Cockatoo-A Model for Successful and Fun Aviculture," and "Mate Aggression in Birds- Example Cockatoos"; Matthias Reinschmidt, Ph.D. "Breeding Rare Macaws at Loro Parque", Rainer Niemann, Ph.D. "From the Wild into Our Homes"; and Johanna "jeleen" Briscoe, DVM, Dipl. ABVP (Avian) "The Animal Welfare Act and How Regulations Could Affect You."Behavioral presentations included: Robin Shewokis, ''Addressing Behavioral Issues" and "Enriched and OrganizedWhat a Concept"; Kashmir Csaky, "Understanding Reinforcement and Punishment"; Linda S. Rubin, "The Ethology of Australian Parrot Flocks and Captive Behaviors"; Chris Shank, "Living With Free-Flying Cockatoos"; Alycia Antheunisse, "The Perfect Match-Ensuring the Right Parrot for the Right Person"; and Nyla Copp, "The Urban Aviary-An Insider's Thoughts on Getting Your Bird Outside."General avicultural topics included: Steve Duncan, "Psittacine Nursery Management," and "Wild Parrots of Southern California"; Jason Crean, "Using DNA to Identify a Species" and "Mutations-How They Get From One Generation to Another"; Nancy Speed, "Caiques", Fran Andersen, "Lineolated Parakeets, A Breeder's Perspective on Maximizing Pet Potential"; Dann Dunst, "Galliforrnes", Rebecca O'Connor, "Falconry, Conservation and the Future"; Margrethe Warden, "Lories in U.S. Aviculture", Daniel Sigmon, "Ecological Philosophy and its Application to the Keeping of Exotics"; Hildegard Niemann, MSc Biology, "Beauty Lies in the Eyes of the Beholder"; Lyrae Perry, "The Business of Birds"; Eric Antheunisse, "Parrot Breeding for American Pet Trade"; Madeleine Franco, "Knock, Knock, Who's There? It's Animal Control!"; and Susan van den Broek, "Specialty Avian Store's Role in Aviculture,"Innovative avicultural games were held Thursday evening, including Birdy Bingo, Flock Feud, andJeo-BIRDy (based on the popular television game show,Jeopardy), where teams answered questions on a variety of avicultural topics. Jeo-BIRDy is an impressively successful teaching tool developed by AFA Mid-eastern Director and Science Education Zoo Consultant Jason Crean. Mr. Crean is a 2009 recipient of a Presidential Award for science teachers from President Barack Obama. According to Mr. Crean, "Jeo-BIRDy categories can include proper diets, geographical distribution of birds, avian anatomy and more. Most everyone comments they learn a great deal from the game and have a blast!"AFA Specialty Organization meetings held Thursday evening included: the LoryLeague.org, Lineolated Parakeet Society, Caique Enthusiasts of America, Cockatiel Foundation, the Soci-ety of Parrot Breeders &amp;amp; Exhibitors and a special Hookbill Show Meeting in preparation of the scheduled parrot show. The AFA affiliated organizations, found on the AFAbirds.orgwebsite, are informal settings providing networking opportunities and the exchange of news and information, and are open to established members and first-time visitors.A strategically informative Legislative Workshop led by AFA Legislative VP and Attorney-at-Law, Genevieve Wall, JD, was held Friday evening. "Back to Our Roots-Grass-Roots Legislation"including panelists Steve Duncan, Brent Gattis, and Sandee Molenda-covered an overview oflegislation affecting animal owners, explaining how bills become law and how the regulatory system works. Tips were included on how to communicate with Members of Congress, Regulatory Agencies and using the media to educate legislators and the public. Panelists presented individually and a stimulating question and answer session followed.A colorful and entertaining parrot show held Saturday morning, drew many exhibitors and spectators from around the country. The show was hosted by the LoryLeague.org, co-hosted by the Lineolated Parakeet Society-and affiliated with the Society of Parrot Breeders &amp;amp; Exhibitors (SPBE)-all of which are affiliated organizations of the AFA. SPBE Certified Panel]udge Linda S. Rubin presided as judge of the event commenting on each entry in an effort to help educate those seated in the gallery watching the show.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3282</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 38 No. 4 (2011): Number 4 2011; 47-50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3282/3266</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
