<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1713</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-25T15:57:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Indian Ringneck Breeders Handbook</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Robson, Phil</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">PUBLISllED 200 IPAPERBACK - 116 PAGES - OVER 30 COLOUR PAGESINCLUDING 19 COLOUR PLATES OF INDIAN RINGNECK MUTATIONS. CllAPTERS ON STARTING OUT. ACCESSORIES, BRFEDING, DIET, l-IEALTllPROBLEMS, AND GENETICS (INCLUDING BREEDING TABLLS COVERING 19 MUTMIONS). PRICE: $24.95 + $2.05 SlllPPINGAs an old hand at breeding Indian Ring-necked Parakeets for many years, I can really appreciate the good advice found in this excellent and colorful book. It is the perfect book for the novice interested in Ringnecked Parakeets as it starts from the very beginning with the first chap-ter titled "Starting Out." Here you'll learn everything from housing toacquiring your first Ring-neckeds. The book goes on through the chapters listed above with every facet of breeding these popular aviary birds being well explained.Even the old hands like me can learn a lot in Robson's book and we can get a glimpse at how theAustralians feed, breed, incubate, handfeed, parent-raise, handle genetics, and otherwise function as the superb aviculrurists they are. I highly recommend this book if you have any interest at all in Indian Ring-neckeds or related species. It can be gotten directly from the publisher through its office here in the U.S.A. and priced in US dollars - a great convenience. Contact: Pet &amp;amp; Aviary BIRDS Magazine Pet &amp;amp; Aviary Birds Inc.Subscription &amp;amp; Advertising Office: PO Box 30806 Knoxville TN 37930-0806 USAPhone toll-free: 800-487-3333Fax: 865-690-4941 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1713</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 30 No. 1 (2003): First Quarter 2003; 43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1713/1690</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
