<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3929</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-09T03:48:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">HARI Philosophy on Nutrition Part 2</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Allen, Melanie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 3 (July 2024). The text below contains excerpts from the original article. For photographs, figures, advertisements, and the complete formatted version as originally published, please use the PDF link associated with this article. In our HARI Nutrition Philosophy part 1, focus was placed on weight management and Vitamin A assimilation. These two aspects of observation for nutritional evaluation are relatively easy for anyone who shares a life with a psittacine, be it a pet owner or a professional aviculturist to review and assess. Continuing on with the observations of diet benefit that can be easily monitored, let's take a look at more challenging elements of psittacine nutrition: Protein and Vitamin E. In essence, our parrots require a certain amount of protein - or rather a unique structural combination of essential amino acids such as lysine, methionine, arginine and a few more in their diet. The combination of essential amino acids is involved in many different biological functions such as growth, muscle, feather growth, and they help form enzymes, aid in immune system, plus impact the hormones. Some species might require unique protein levels than others, so please review with an avian veterinarian or a seasoned species specialist before making drastic changes in protein intake for your bird. What are the signs of good protein with just a mere observation approach? The best way for anyone, regardless of scientific accreditation, is look at the feathers - really look at them. The feather condition is a true mirror to the protein assimilation in a parrot as well as other critical nutrients. Look for quality condition from the rachis to the end of the barbules. Any pits? Any stress bars - horizontal or vertical? Color should be vibrant, free of breaks in the feather structure, especially on the edges of the barbules and along the shaft. Vitamin E is a fat-soluble vitamin that is found in many food sources, and the inclusion of Vitamin E is important for our parrots on many levels. Vitamin E helps to maintain tissue growth and development as well as aid in embryo development in fertile eggs. Without the proper levels of Vitamin E, a bird is challenged with muscle development, brain cell structure, and we know that deficiencies of Vitamin E interfere with reproductive success. How to make a visual assessment of adequate Vitamin E assimilation - look at the cloaca. The cloaca should be smooth and free of dried skin tissues, almost like "kissable lips," not that you should kiss your bird there. When setting up pairs for breeding, seasoned aviculturists know to assess the cloaca as a dry cloaca and signs of viral infection will negatively impact the birds' ability to reproduce. Click the PDF link associated with this article to view the complete article as originally published in AFA Watchbird.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3929</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 3 (2024): AFA Watchbird July 2024</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3929/3894</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
