<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1095</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:21:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Flame-fronted Barbet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Parr, Kym</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionTie Flame-fronted Barber Megalaima armillaris (Silhey &amp;amp; Monroe, 1993), also known as the Blue-crowned or Orange-fronted Barber. inhabits the forests and IO\Yland hills of Java and Bali (Silbey &amp;amp; Monroe. 1990). It is a common resident of primary forest and the forest edge. This species occurs from sea level up to 2500 m (8200 ft.), hut is more common above 900 m (2952 ft.) It is probably java's most common barber (Mackinnon &amp;amp; Phillips. J 993).Delacour (19&amp;gt;f7) described this species as a medium-sized (20 cm - 7.8 in.) barber with a comparatively short black hill and a soft green color. It has an orange-yellow forehead and collar, black lores and a blue hindcrown. Another identifying characteristic of this species is the bird's blue-gray colored legs and feet. As is the case with most barber species, not much is known about this bird's habits in the wild.In captivity, the Flame-fronted Barber is uncommon. ISIS (International Species Information System) historical information lists only three importa- Lions of Megalaima armillaris from l95J-1995. A reported total of JO individuals have been brought into captivity during that time. The San Diego Zoo received two of these birds in 196 J. Both died within one year. In 1966 three birds were captured from the wild and transferred to Kebun Binatong Surabaya (Wonokromo, Surabaya - Indonesia). The following year. these birds were also sent to San Diego. One of the three died in 1968, and the remaining two in 1971. None of these birds were known to reproduce. In 1992. five birds were imported for a private collection. These birds were purchased hy the Cleveland Metroparks Zoo in September of 1993. In the spring of 1995, what is believed to he the first captive breeding of the Flame-fronted Barber took place at the Cleveland Metroparks Zoo.HousingIn September 1993 The Cleveland Merroparks Zoo received 2.3 (2 male, 3 female) Flame-fronted Barbers. The birds arrived as two pairs and a single female. The latter died during the quarantine period. The two remaining pairs were each placed into individual exhibits with harp wire fronts. The exhibits measured approximately 8 ft. square. In late 1993 the first pair was released into a large (13 x I l.6 x 9.5 rn - 42.6 x 38 x 31 ft.) well-planted, walk through aviary with a waterfall flowing into a system of three pools and "open air" skylights. They shared the aviary with approximately 50 other birds of 21 species, including laughing thrushes, turacos, a Channel-hilled Toucan and a variety of pigeons, starlings and other small softbills.DietAll birds living in the aviary, are offered a variety of foods each day. The inhouse insectivorous mixture contains hoilecl ground horserneat, gamehird crumbles. shredded raw carrot, ground hard-boiled eggs in the shell, cooked brown rice and ZooVite. Also offered are chopped greens, hoiled ground horserneat, small chunks of raxv horsemeat, chopped apple, orange, banana and grapes. Other fruits and vegetables are occasionally added as they hecome available. Finch mix, clove mix and waterfowl and herhivore pellets are also available for other species in the aviary and the barbers have heen seen to rake these on occasion. Mealworrns ( Tenebrioi are given a few times each week. When barber chicks are suspected in the nest, neonate mice (Mus), waxworms (Galleria), crickets (Acbeta) and soaked mynah pellets are added to the diet. Insects and mice are alternated and the mynah pellets are available every day. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1095</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 6 (1996): NOV-DEC 1996; 30-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1095/1074</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
