<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1662</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:51:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Moody Gardens a Texas Treasure</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Just as Texas, the "lone star state" stands alone among the 50, so Moody Gardens stands alone in Texas. It is a veritable oneof-a-kind jewel that you'll never forget once you visit.Galveston Island, home of Moody Gardens, is just a pleasant 45 minute drive from Houston. As you approach the island you'll see across the bay great pyramids amidst the lush greenery. And just beyond the three pyramids lies a tall stately hotel surrounded by the palms and plants that put the "garden" in Moody Gardens.Moody Gardens can be an outstanding day-trip that will fascinate the kids as well as the adults. But, in truth, one day won't really do it. To see all there is and to absorb the wonders within the pyramids, do yourself a favor - stay several days.Moody Gardens is not just a garden in the traditional sense - it is an exciting adventure in the world's seas, jungles, and even outer space. And it has an exquisitely comfortable hotel that can serve as your headquarters while exploring. I speak from experience. I had the pleasure of visiting Moody Gardens earlier this year.The HotelYour first stop will he the newly built, nine-storey, 303-room hotel with all the amenities. I've stayed in hotels throughout the world and have never been more delighted and happy than at the Moody Gardens Hotel. Comfortable is the word.Even the lobby will grab you.In addition to cascading waterfalls, a lagoon, and tropical plants abounding, it has a floor-to-ceiling aviary filled with plants and birds including the technicolor Gouldians and some Diamond doves whose coos resound from the bar to the check-in counter. I gazed long at the cheerful birds zipping around their space, as did many other guests. The lobby sets the mood for the rest of the stay.The first floor lobby bar (just a little beyond the aviary) was the perfect setting for a relaxed evening of good conversation and camaraderie while the Terrace Restaurant was just the place for an excellent breakfast the next morning. And for the more formal festivities, the ninth floor Shearri's Restaurant provides dining elegance and Shearn's Lounge is the place for after dinner drinks and social affairs.Your large room will surpass your expectations in comfort and convenience. Mine had a wonderful view of the pyramids, the grounds, and the hay. Or you can duck out and enjoy the full service spa and salon, workout center, or even the ballroom. You won't lack for things to do or places to go. This is a hotel to rank with the finest. The Discovery PyramidWith your headquarters secured, it's just a short walk to the pyramids. Come and explore the extraordinary world of science at the Discovery Pyramid. Spectacular traveling exhibits from around the country await your arrival. Satisfy your insatiahle hunger for knowledge with live interactive demonstrations of remarkable science experiments. The world of science sur- rounds you.On May 29-August 12, Moody Gardens presents Mad Science at the Discovery Pyramid.' Mad scientists - Professor Pruvitt and Crash, take science out of the classroom and into the real world to better understand physics and chemistry. Using wacky experiments, special effects, and zany antics, these science gurus demonstrate how science relates to everyday life. Audience members are invited to join Professor Pruvitt and Crash on stage as they explore the concepts of molecular movement and exothermic reactions.If you miss the program ending August 12, you'll just have to see what's in store for you when you get there. The museum changes its exhibits regularly. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1662</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 3 (2001): Third Quarter 2001; 33-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1662/1639</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
