<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/817</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-04T03:49:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding   Spreos</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gibson, Les</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Superb Starling Spreo superbuso are one of several well known and colorful East African starlings. They are easy to feed and fairly easy to raise. This family is more often kept and bred in institutions where the common factor is a spacious aviary. In spite of the above, detailed accounts of breeding and other behavior are pretty thin on the ground. The following are notes on a single pair of Spreos. A claimed surgically-sexed pair, in apparent good health, was obtained in September and put outside in a sheltered, south-facing aviary built against a sunporch. Health. Six weeks after the pair was obtained, when cold evenings were beginning to set in, the cock began to sneeze with increasing frequency. Both birds were brought inside where the hen began to sneeze as well. They were treated (with dichlorvos and Ivermectin) for what proved to be highly resistant respiratory mites. In March they were put outside again. Although earlier examination of the droppings proved negative, in the following October when the birds were with their third family, the hen developed intermittent, yellow-brown diarrhea interspersed with normal droppings. A microscopic check showed large numbers of Capillaria eggs. This was treated by giving an unmeasured amount of a 100 mg mebendazole tablet (a piece about half the size of a small millet seed), inserted in a mealworm or a mea!worm pupa, the latter being easier. The greasy, biliouslooking excreta ceased by the next morning. Three single doses were given on consecutive days, with no more Capillaria eggs being seen thereafter. How Capillaria suddenly showed up in the hen is a mystery, for the Spreos were always in a roofed and mostly enclosed aviary. Possibly she had immature worms when acquired. A Aviary.The aviary measured 28' x 10' x 7.5' high, and was divided into a 20 and an 8 foot section. The Spreos were housed in the larger end next to a pair of European Blackbirds Turdus merula. In the nesting season, a pair of European Goldfinches somewhat reluctantly shared the Spreos' section. The aviary was heavily planted and overgrown. For the last brood of the season, most of the plants, mainly rhododendrons and two large bamboos, were removed. It was then more like the Spreo's natural, open habitat and was more to their liking, for they are not made for dashing into a nearby bush. Spreos have comparatively slow wing beats and like a clear take off and landing space. The birds became much more active in the new space, where previously they just sat about in the thick vegetation. Space, and in particular height, is more conducive to the Spreo's wellbeing and is no doubt a major factor in successful institutional breedings as compared to small, backyard aviaries. General Information When acquired, the hen was the tamer of the two, but after the cock was brought into the kitchen for a few days, he became and remained the more settled. Tameness in East African Starlings is only relative though, and in spite of this they remained secretive about their comings and goings. They are sensitive to cold (i.e., temperatures in the 40°F range) and the 20 foot enclosure proved insufficient to keep the Spreos active enough to keep warm when raw winter weather set in. A six week old chick that was being put out daily with its parents was really miserable. Eventually the adults, although very fit, began to look miserable too and were brought inside. This was in contrast to little birds such...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/817</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 4 (1994): JUL-AUG 1994; 10-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/817/799</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
