<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/527</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Mice in the Aviary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abramson, Joanne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Pests such as mice and rats canpresent significant problems for theaviculturist. Not only do they consumeconsiderable quantities of food ,but their habit of urinating and defecatingin the aviary has contributed tothe spread of disease organisms suchas Salmonella, E. coli and otherbacteria . Controlling mice in youraviary should be part of your regularmaintenance routine. Mice eat almostanything. Seed, pellets and fruit andvegetable mixes fed to birds are anatural magnet to attract all kinds ofrodents . Cement floors and smallwire is helpful, but not always practicalor effective in controlling mice.For those of you who have problemswith killing any animal, let meshare a few facts. The two mostcommon rodents are house mice andbrown rat s. There a re about 300species of mice worldwide. The wordmouse comes from a Sanskrit wordmeaning thief The common housemouse that we know today came toAmerica in ships from Europe as earlyas the 1500s. At maturity, it weighs1/2 to 1 ounce (14 to 28 grams), aboutthe weight of a Greenwing Macaw athatching. They have good hearing butpoor eye sight. Like all rodents, theyhave strong , sharp, front chisel-liketeeth which they use to tear openseed bags, gnaw holes in wood andcollect far more food than they willever eat. Mice are constantly harvestingand storing food. They live anywherethey can find food and shelter.They prefer dark , warm and quiethomes ; unused nest boxes are justperfect. They build their nests out ofa variety of materials including grass leaves and feathers.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/527</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 13-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/527/511</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
