<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2550</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-16T11:27:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ruffed Pheasants - Part 2</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Billie, Francis</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Golden Pheasant (Chrysolopbus pictus)There are two species in this genus.The Golden Pheasant (Chrysolopbus pictus) and the Lady Amherst's Pheasant (Cbrysolopbus amberstiae). These two pheasant species are among the most beautiful and certainly are the most popular of all game birds.The Golden Pheasant and the Amherst's Pheasant interbreed freely in captivity. The resulting crosses are completely fertile. This type of breeding should not be done, as it is doubtful many pure specimens of either species remain here in the United States. This was true until a few years ago, when the San Diego Zoo was able to import some new, pure bloodlines from China.Few FemalesWild-caught male Golden Pheasants from central China still reach the bird market in Hong Kong from time to time. Female Golden Pheasants are seldom ever seen, possibly because of their drab coloration.Male Golden Pheasants: brilliantly colored. Crest: large. Consists of bright golden feathers. Ruff: large. Feathers of bright orange, bordered by two sky blue bars. DisplayThe ruff can be spread like a fan across either side of the bird's head and neck. In a "full" display, the crest is raised and the ruff widely spread, so it hides the sides of the neck and head nearest the hen bird. The male's bright eye peers intently at the hen, over the upper edge of his ruff. He tilts his body toward the hen with the nearest wing slightly lowered and the other side raised. His tail tilts and spreads vertically. The scarlet tail feathers are very conspicuous in this position. If the hen stands still, the cock holds his position until she moves. When the hen moves, the cock jumps around to present the opposite side. This display is a remarkable performance.Description MaleCrown and crest: gold. Ruff: orange edged with blue-black cross bands. Upper back: Dark green, back feathers have a black border, the rest are golden yellow. The fringe passing to scarlet on the sides. Center tail feathers: black spotted and tipped with cinnamon. Scapulars: dark red. Wing coverts: deep blue. Breast and under parts: scarlet, passing to chestnut. Abdomen, thighs and undertail coverts: scarlet. Iris and orbital: skin yellow. Bill and legs: yellow.FemaleCrown and neck: blackish brown, spotted with cinnamon, buff. Rump, upper tail coverts: black. Tail coverts: barred. Legs and bill: honey yellow.Three MutationsThere are three known mutations and there is a possibility that a fourth exists.The Dark-throated Golden PheasantThese birds are similar to the Red Golden Pheasant but are deeper in color. Face, throat and upper breast, smokey black. No trace of metallic green, which indicates Amherst blood. Central retrices: barred, not spotted. Soft parts: darker yellow and sometimes blackish. Female: much the same as the Golden Pheasant, except the bird is much darker in color. · </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2550</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 4 (1990): AUG-SEPT 1990; 30-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2550/2520</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
