<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2065</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-07T01:52:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Vets Corner</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Svedeen, Kendal P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Q. My veterinarian tells me to offer most anything edible to my birds, and if they like it, fine. I know that there are certain foods that could create problems with a bird's digestive tract, but what are they?A. I am a staunch advocate of feeding a bird a varied diet of table food, snacks, vegetables, meat, and even desserts. Among the healthiest birds I have encountered, are those who have had free access to table food. Lean meat, vegetables of all types, cooked eggs, bread, tortillas, cakes, cheese and anything else the bird will accept. The only foods that may create problems are iceberg lettuce, which has zero nutritive value plus a reversed calcium to phosphorus ratio, or foods that contain highly spiced or salted ingredients. A small amount of potato chips or Fritos could be a treat and a good training aid. Grapes, apples, citrus fruits, and papaya tend to cause what I call a "functional" diarrhea. If the bird likes these fruits, offer them to him or her once or twice a week. Generally speaking, about 15 to 20 percent of a bird's ration should consist of a variety of vegetables, fruits, and snacks. Q. I have had some problems with mites and lice in my outside aviaries. I have tried a wide variety of insecticides which have been either marginally effective, or have proven to be toxic to my birds. What insecticide should I use that is both safe and effective?A. For many years pyrethrin and piperonyl butoxide formulas have been the safest insecticide preparations to use on and around birds. They are non toxic, but the problem is that they only have a "knock down" effect on the pests without actually killing them. In addition, the residual potency of them is very short-lived, like a matter of hours. In recent research, a new product has been developed which is a synthetic pyrethroid. In my experience, it has proven to be an effective killing agent, is safe, and has some residual effectiveness. The spray is manufactured by Hart-Delta Laboratories of Baton Rouge, LA, and is basically used for flea control in dogs and cats. This particular product contains some oil for coat-conditioning purposes in mammals, which should not be used on birds. However, they also produce a spray which does not contain the oil, and it is called "Veterinary Hospital and Kennel Spray." It can be obtained through your local veterinarian, and should be used judiciously. Spray the bottom of the aviary or cage once weekly, being cautious not to contaminate food or water supplies. If birds can be treated individually, spray a small amount under each wing and on their feet and legs every two weeks. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2065</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 9 No. 1 (1982): FEB-MAR 1982; 6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2065/2036</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
