<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1937</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-10-31T06:26:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">1980 National Cage Bird Show Report</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The NCBS Board of Director's meeting was held March 1, in Kansas City, MO. Preparations are well underway for the 32nd National Cage Bird Show to be held in Jacksonville, FL., Nov. 13-15. The Greater Jacksonville Avicultural Society will be the host club, with Manuel Iglesias as Show Manager.The following judges were approved by the NCBS Board:Border Canaries - Jim O'Connor, CA.Type and· Hartz Canaries - George McGinnis, Canada Gloster Canaries -John Knipp, OH.American Singers - Madeline Mysliwiec, NY.Lipochrome Canaries - Carl Welsch, OH Melanin Canaries - Case Quik, Canada Foreign and Hookbills - Richard Ryan, OH.Budgerigars - Irmafern Collins, IO.Cockatiels - Nancy Reed, CT. Love Birds -Dr. Al Decoteau, MA.The Board elected the following officers for 1980:President - Marek Whiteaker, MO. 1st Vice-President -La Verne Krauss, IL.2nd Vice-President -Harold Bowles, GA.Secretary - Harold Sodamann, KS. Treasurer - Bill Hancock, TX.Clarence King, TX.; Paul Ballew, CA.; and Paul Dee, IL. were re-elected to the NCBS Board. Bonnie Williams of Columbus, OH. was elected to join the ranks as a new director.The 1980 National Cage Bird Show will be held at the Hertz Skycenter Inn, at Jacksonville International Airport with special rates of $28 single and $34 double. It is advised that reservations be made well in advance, as only a specified number of rooms can be held for the event. Alternate hotels will be the nearby Holiday and Ramada Inn with shuttle service to the Skycenter.This year's National Cage Bird Show promised to be the biggest in decades with an expectancy of over 2,000 entries. The American Federation of Aviculture has chosen to hold their regional convention in conjunction with our activities. This will add a whole new educational dimension. A.F.A. will feature seminars and workshops headed by nationally recognized authorities on various avicultural subjects and species.The U.S. Chapter of the International Gloster Breeder's Association wiU continue its support and sponsorship, as will the Old Varieties Canary Club. These organizations encourage their membership to show with the National group.The American Cockatiel Society will hold their 3rd National A.C.S. Show in conjunction with NCBS, as will the African Love Bird Society be holding their 2nd National. (Love Birds, for the first time, will be given Division status and a Kellogg trophy.) The American Budgerigar Society's District No. 5 has also chosen to hold its regional show at the NCBS. These same organizations will be holding annual or regional meetings.We again urge that fanciers plan ahead and make reservations early. This 1980 National offers more than ever before! For further NCBS information and eligibility to win the Kellogg trophy (Division winners), one may join the National Cage Bird Show Club by sending dues ($5.00) to:Margie McGee25 West Janss Rd Thousand Oaks, CA 91360For future reference, the NCBS Board voted to hold the 1981 National Show in Kansas City, MO. Projected plans are for Pittsburg, PA. in 1982, and Denver, CO. in 1983. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-10-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1937</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 3 (1980): JUNE-JULY 1980; 12-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1937/1908</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
