<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3110</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-06-28T21:00:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">News Highlights</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Loro Parque FundacionRare parakeets in southern EcuadorGreat news has just arrived from Ecuadorean researcher Mery Juiiia about aspects of the breeding of two threatened species of parakeets in the Tapichalaca Reserve in southern Ecuador. With support from the Loro Parque Fundaci6n and Fundaci6n jocotoco, Mery has captured unique images of Whitenecked Parakeets (Pyrrhura albipectus) and Golden-plumed Parakeets (Leptosittaca branickii) and, working tirelessly in steep and forested terrain, she has advanced our knowledge of their reproduction.For two years Mery has installed nest-boxes in the 3,500 ha reserve, located on the south-eastern slopes of the Andes. Two of the nest-boxes this year have successful breeding of White-necked Parakeets. At an elevation of 1,800 m, this is in the lower part of the reserve, but is the highest breeding elevation recorded for this species. In the first box a group of six individuals had a total of 13 eggs, of which eight hatched and are developing well. In the second box, four eggs have more recently been laid by a group of five individuals. This phenomenon of breeding in groups, or cooperatively, has also been recorded in other species of parakeets, especially of the genus Pyrrhura.The breeding success of the Golden-plumed Parakeets is even more remarkable. In 2008, 17 nest-boxes were installed at an elevation of 2,600 m, and eleven of them are occupied, mainly by pairs. However, two boxes are frequented by a group of 14 adults, although until now it has not been determined how many of them are actually using the boxes for breeding. Primary forests are vital for the conservation of these species, which are threatened by deforestation and illegal trade within Ecuador. Mery's work is an important contribution to help improve their conservation. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-06-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3110</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 36 No. 1-2 (2009): Number 1&amp;2  2009; 50-61</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3110/3094</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
