<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/991</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding and Raising the Red--flanked Lorikeet Charmoysa placentis placentis, C . p. ornata and C . p. subplacens</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thober, Sharon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">E ditor's Note: Sharon Tbober and her son Brook received an AFA First Breeding Aiy Award for the nominate race of the Red-flanked Lorikeet Charmoysa p. placentis which hatched onjune 29, 1987. Since then they have specialized with this beautiful lorikeet becoming the foremost avicultural authorities on this species. We wish to congratulate them on their work as this is not an easy species to reproduce consistently. home 11 Red-flanked Lorikeets which had just been released from a quarantine station. I was surprised and delighted to see how tiny and colorful these little lorikeets were. They measure 6 to 7-1/2 inches in length one-third of which is tail length. Males and females are dimorphic in coloration. They look like two completely different species of lorikeets. The body color of both sexes is mostly green; the back and wings are a darker shade.Males have bright royal blue ear coverts which are streaked with a vio- let blue. There is variation in the subspecies. The male's cheeks, lores and chin are crimson red. Occasionally there is an iridescent aurora of aqua around the ear coverts on mature birds that can be quite outstanding, especially in the ornata subspecies.The amount of red varies in individual birds, but ornata has considerable more red than placentis. These red feathers are sometimes scattered on the chest and lower body or extend down the throat. They sometimes appear in the cere.The flanks on the side of the breast and partially under the wings of the male are always crimson red. It is the brilliantly colored red flanks of the male from which this species of lorikeet gets its name.The placentis placentis and the placentis ornata have a royal blue rump patch. In the ornata it is very large and is still visible even when the wings are folded, especially at maturity. This blue patch in the ornata almost looks violet and is quite outstanding. This, combined with their more excessive red markings and slightly darker color of green on the nape, makes them notice- ably different than the nominate placentisplacentis.The males have a yellow-green foreheadand forecrown, almost chartreuseand the ornata males and immatures canhave a spattering of red feathers inforehead and forecrown . When excit- ed, all Red-flankeds can slightly raise theforehead feathers giving a look of a verysmall crest.The placentis subplacens males andfemales have very much the coloring ofplacentis placentis males and femalesexcept they have no blue on the rump.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/991</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 1 (1996): JAN-FEB 1996; 39-44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/991/971</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
