<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1043</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:20:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Tropical Paradise for Birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bringas, Roger</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hidden deep within the urban jungle of metropolitan Manila, surrounded by millions of people, automobiles, buses, jeepnies and terrific traffic jams, lies a 15 acre oasis which gives sanctuary and provides an ideal setting for one of the largest bird breeding facilities in the world. Birds International, Inc. (BII) is the brain child and great love of Mr. Antonio deDios, a resident of Makati, Republic of the Philippines. Since childhood, deDios has had a close association with and fondness for animals. As a youth he had a variety of pers, though he never quire focused on a particular animal or species. As a young man he married then joined his brothers working for his father's transportation company. A short rime later deDios realized that the rapid development raking place inside the Philippines offered great opporrunity, and with the support and help of his wife, Ruth, he esrablished his own business dealing in automotive supplies, later moving on to heavy equipment. Wirh the business doing well, deDios and his family purchased a new home in an exclusive area of Manila. This is where he finally decided on the kind of animals he cherished the most-birds. He acquired his first macaw, then an African Grey then another bird and yet another. Most of you know the feeling. At length, the house was full of birds, then the yard. With so many pets at hand, deDios realized what curious and wonderful creatures birds are and decided to direct his efforts from pet keeping to breeding various parrot species. Neighbors' complaints about noise prompted deDios to take action. He purchased land in Quezon City, an area near Manila that was once filled with rice paddies but during the last 20 years has developed rapidly. The farm was meant to be "a place in the countryside" far from the hustle and bustle of Metro Manila. A place where he and his family could enjoy themselves in a peaceful setting and where the collection of birds could be housed without disturbing any neighbors. As time passed, the collection of birds grew and grew, finally representing species of birds from all over the world. An organized plan was settled on and eventually a full time staff of craftsmen was employed to design and build aviaries, cages, dormitories, kitchens, nurseries, an incubation room, offices, and an animal hospital. An elaborate filtration system was installed to assure the quality of the drinking water and two large diesel powered generators now guarantee a continuous source of electricity during the "brown outs" that rake place on occasion. A five hundred ton refrigerated warehouse maintains imported pelletized foods, vitamins and other perishables at an ideal temperature while fresh fruits and vegetables are delivered daily. Over time, an on-going effort to become more knowledgeable and efficient as a large scale breeding farm has brought about many renovations and changes in aviary design and husbandry procedures. Today, the majority of the parrots housed at the farm are kept in aviaries suspended above the ground. Remodeling continues daily as older style cages are replaced with the new, improved design. Stainless steel food and water cups are inserted at the front of each aviary, while in the rear section hangs the nest box which can be serviced from the outside. Bii now employs some 150 full time employees, and changes in various protocols are made when a better system is determined. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1043</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 2 (1996): MARCH-APRIL 1996; 59-61</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1043/1023</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
