<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2010</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-24T06:13:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bird Photography</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, Dan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">My philosophy of bird pictures is to produce a color print or slide which has accurate (as possible) colors, a typical pose, and in a size sufficient to study the bird in detail. In order to achieve this, I feel that one must process his own film and prints. This is especially true in the color print, because a photo-lab does not know what color the subject was. For slides, a photolab can do your job. This discussion will be limited to captive birds and primarily color photography. The same basic technique can be applied to black &amp;amp; white photography, but, when the results are so superior in color, why limit yourself to B&amp;amp;W? If B&amp;amp;W prints are required for publication, the conversion can be made by the publication facility.EQUIPMENT REQUIREDCamera &amp;amp; Lenses - Taking into account image detail, flexibility, available films, portability, and cost; my nomination is a 35mm single lens reflex with interchangeable lenses and focusing at full aperture up to the moment of exposure. Fully automatic cameras are not required as most all pictures will be made using elec- tronic flash. Depending upon the size of the birds you wish to photograph, your basic lens can be anything from 85mm to 135mm. There are many cameras and lenses on the market which can be used with very good results. Cameras larger than 35mm can be used, but, with increased film cost, increased camera cost, and loss of depth of focus. Closer than normal focusing is also requried and can be pro- vided by a macro lens, extension tubes, or auxiliary lenses. My personal equipment is two NIKON FMs (one for negative and one for slides) with a basic 105mm f2.5 lens and an I Imm extension tube. Other lenses I use are 85mm f2.0, 50mm f2.0, 200mm f4.0 and a 43-86mm f3.5 zoom.Tripod - A sturdy, repeat sturdy, tripod is required. I recommend a pan head with a tilt top. The pan head is required and the tilt is very nice when changing from horizontal to vertical format. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2010</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 2 (1981): APRIL-MAY 1981; 34-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2010/1981</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
