<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2672</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-08T05:14:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Collared Finch-billed Bulbul at Tracy Aviary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roles, D. Grenville</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Inhabiting suitable hill-scrub country in east, central and south China and Taiwan (S. s. cineriecapilus), Collared Finch-billed Bulbuls are one member of a family of about 120 species ranging throughout Africa and tropical Asia.Approximately 8 inches long with greyish-green upperparts, (greener wings and tail) and yellowish underparts with black head and terminal tail band; the face is lightly streaked with white on the cheeks and spotted with white on the nostrils and base of the lower mandible. A broad white collar separates the black head from the olive breast. Eyes and feet are dark while the thick, finch-like bill is ivory.Reputed to feed in the wild on seeds, beans and fruit (de Schauensee, The Birds of China), our birds are offered Vitabird Finch mix in addition to chopped fruits, hard-boiled egg, bird of prey diet, mealworms and crickets.We obtained four birds from Chris Johnson in Atlanta inJuly of 1987. All of the birds appeared fit and healthy, although one bird had a droopy wing, and after a three-week period in quarantine we released them into their new home in the Pheasantry.Our Pheasantry is a range of 13 large aviaries arranged in two blocks. Each block is built on a large mound or burm and is heavily landscaped and planted with trees and shrubs of Himalayan origin. Each individual aviary has its own partially openfronted shelter, fitted with a water and heat source (infra-red lamp).The Bulbuls' aviary is 15 feet square and 19 feet high at its peak; planted with Birches, Viburnum, Cornus, Dwarf Pines and Star Magnolias. Most of the ground is covered by grass, with large rocks and tree branches providing a variety of perching.The Bulbuls share their aviary with Pekin Robins Leiotbrix iutea, Laceneck Doves Streptopelia cbinensis and Chinese Bamboo Partridge Bambusicola tboracica. No bickering has ever been observed between species but the Bulbuls have been seen to chase each other on occasion.The heat lamps were left on for the first winter the birds experienced here, but they were never seen to seek out the warmth on even the coldest day, so subsequently the lamps have not been switched on. Winters in Salt Lake City can become extremely cold with temperatures regularly dipping (and often staying) below freezing. We actually have bird-bath heaters immersed in all of the Pheasantry water bowls to prevent them from freezing solid (they still freeze around the edges, however).On 4/19/88 we discovered two birds missing from the aviary. A quick check revealed a small hole at the junction of the wire mesh frame and the redwood baseboard. Formerly below ground level, it had been exposed by the activities of the Bamboo Partridge scratching and digging in the ground at that spot. I was not terribly worried since both birds could be seen exploring the giant Cottonwoods in the vicinity of their aviary, and we have almost always retrieved escapees. I remembered being told, too, of a Collared Finchbilled Bulbul which lived at liberty for years at San Diego Zoo.Unfortunately though, we were  able to recapture only one of the birds, the other I suspect was taken by one of the Cooper's Hawks which nest annually in Liberty Park. Almost exactly one year later, the birds attempted to breed for us for the first time. In mid-April, birds had been seen carrying very fine birch twigs rather aimlessly around the flight, but did not appear to be attempting any construction. However, a check of the half-open-fronted wooden nest box (5" square, 7" high and packed with hay) revealed a clutch of three eggs; markedly pyriform, basically pink and heavily marked with maroon spots and dots and dull mauve splotches.These were discovered on 4/13/89.The birds must have been extremely wary and alert to the approach of keepers, for they were never seen on or around the nest box at any time.On checking the nest box the next day, two eggs were found to have hatched, the new chicks having dark, bruised looking upperparts and pale pink underparts. Live food supplies of crickets and mealworms were immediately increased together with the number of spot checks on the adults' behaviour.It was seen that the (presumably) unmated bird was being chased around a bit (though not seriously harrassed) and the bird with the drooped wing appeared to be the male - perching prominently and vocalizing. One bird was also seen to hawk for insects. On the 15th, one of the birds had the temerity to buzz the curator, its beak snapping loudly as it zipped by my ear lobe!It was with some surprise, not to mention disappointment, that all of the chicks were discovered dead and thrown out of the nest on the 23rd of April, 9 days after hatching.Thus began a series of four failures in 1989 to rear the Bulbuls. Fertility was...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2672</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 3 (1991): JUNE-JULY 1991; 32-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2672/2653</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
