<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4055</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:18:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Captive Husbandry of Lories and Lorikeets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schmit, Matt</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 2 (July 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Captive Husbandry of Lories and Lorikeetstodus) are seeing a severe decline in numbers. The reason for this decline is multifaceted and quite unique to lories as it involves: their unique diet requirements; a disease outbreak in the late 1990’s that affected lories almost exclusively; and unbalanced consumer to producer ratio. There are a few dedicated aviculturists who have specialized in lories over the years and have been working hard to keep the species we have here in the United States thriving.Lories and lorikeets are a group of highly colorful parrots native to the islands of the South Pacific, including Indonesia, New Guinea and Australia. Depending on which taxonomy you believe, there are anywhere from 53 to 61 species of lories belonging to 10 to 19 genera.As a group, lories are considered to be threatened of becoming endangered due to their declining numbers in the wild. All the species of lories are listed on either Appendix I or Appendix II by the Convention of International Trade in Endangered Species (CITES), an international agreement between governments whose goal is to ensure that trade of wild animals and plants does not threaten their survival. Species listed in Appendix I are considered endangered and international trade of these species is permitted only under exceptional circumstances. Species listed in Appendix II are not necessarily considered endangered, but international trade of these species must be controlled in order to prevent further decline.The proper care of captive lories is essential to their well being. In my opinion, there are three areas of care that are crucial to the proper care of lories in captivity. These are diet, housing and enrichment.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4055</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 2 (2022): Watchbird July 2022; 12-16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4055/4015</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
