<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/633</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">First breeding of the Guyana Toucanet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The seven species of lowland toucanetsof the genus Selenideraoccupy the mid and upper level canopiesof the lowland tropical rainforestsof Central and South America.These birds range from central Hondurassouth to northern Argentina.None are found west of the Andes orabove an elevation of 3,000 feet. Fiveof the seven species are found inareas adjacent to the Amazon River.For example, the river itself separatesthree species to the north, and twoto the south. The remaining two speciesare found in Central America(Yellow-eared Toucanet) and southeasternBrazil (Spot-billed Toucanet).Lowland toucanets are very similarto each other. The males of all speciesare black below and green ontop. They differ from each other primarilyin beak and eye color. All haveyellow ear coverts and a yellow collar,with the exception of the isolatedYellow-eared Toucanet, which lacksthe collar. All species are dimorphic.The females differ from males in thatfive of the seven species have brownon the head and abdomen. Theremaining two, the Yellow-earedToucanet and Guyana Toucanet, areunique.The Yellow-eared Toucanet (Selenideraspectabilis) exhibits the leastdimorphism in that the female is allblack in color like the male, with theexception of a chestnut nuchal collar.In the Guyana Toucanet (Selenideraculik), the female has a blackcap, chestnut nuchal collar and a silvergray breast. This makes it themost attractive of the lowland toucanets,not only among females, butwith males as well. In fact, it evokesthe colors reminiscent of the MountainToucans (Andigena).The Guyana Toucanet is differentthan other members of the Selenideragenus in that it has a much longerbeak (three inches) and shorterwings and tail. The beak is basallybrick red and tipped in black. Thelarge, bare orbital area is a light blueand the eye is red. The male has aglossy black head and breast, withdark green back, wings and tail-thetail is tipped with chestnut. The malesports bright yellow ear coverts thatstick out slightly from each side ofthe head. It has a quarter inch wideorange-yellow collar on the nape ofthe neck. The undertail coverts andvent are bright red, and the legs arebluish grey. The female differs in thatshe has a silver-grey breast, tingedwith yellowish green on the lowerabdomen. She has a black cap andchestnut nuchal collar. She lacks theyellow collar, but does have yellowear coverts.The pair of Guyana Toucanets wereacquired in 1987 from an importer inLos Angeles, and were housed togetherin an 8' x 12' x 6' high aviaryfor two years. This flight was heavilyplanted and the birds were not disturbed.In 1988, and again in 1989,the hen laid several eggs. These,however, always disappeared. In thesummer of 1990, the birds weremoved to their new location in Fallbrook,California where they wereplaced in a similar sized aviary. Theheight, however, was increased toeight feet. Shortly thereafter the maledied and was replaced with a newbird.Since toucans prefer to nest in hollowlogs rather than boxes, a log nestmade from a section of palm treetrunk was placed in the corner of theshelter on a platform high enoughthat the top of the log was only a fewinches below the aviary ceiling. Thelog chamber was made by using achainsaw to hollow out the centerfrom one end to a depth of 18 inches.The end was then capped with apiece of plywood, and a small (2-1 /2"dia.) entrance was made in the side.This entrance hole was made byusing a door knob saw attached to ahand drill. Thus, the log nest mimicsthe natural nest these birds woulduse in the wild.The pair went in and out of theirnest log on ·many occasions in 1991.Then, in early 1992, they began tospend long· periods of time in thenest. In late April, it was apparentthey were sitting on eggs. The nestwas then investigated using a smallladies compact mirror and flashlight.The method was to insert the mirrorinto the nest entrance and then shinethe light on the mirror, which, inturn, illumiated the nest chamber.There were three eggs, white andoval in shape. These eggs hatchedbeginning on May 10, 1992 . Atapproximately four weeks of age, thebabies were removed, after a nestinspection revealed that the nest wasextremely dirty. It contained cakedfruit -and feces on the bottom. Toucansare usually good housekeepers,but this nest was the dirtiest I've everencountered and to leave them in thenest would have risked their healthand the nest's success.Upon removal, the babies werealready showing enough feathers todetermine that they were both males.This was a turn of good fortune ,since we had two extra femalesawaiting mates. The babies werehandfed for approximately four moreweeks on a " toucan milkshake" consistingof 50% Wayne's Dog Kibbleand 50% fruit mix. The fruit mix consistedof papaya, cantaloupe, redgrapes, cooked beets and cooked carrots.The dog kibble was soaked andblended into a puree, then an equalamount of fruit mix, by volume, wasadded. All of this was blended intothe milkshake, which was thenstored in the refrigerator. The mixwas made up fresh once each day.For each feeding , a glass was filledwith the amount of food needed tofeed all the toucans being handfed. Itwas then placed in the microwavefor twenty seconds, or enough timeto bring it up to room temperature.The birds were then fed every twohours from seven in the morninguntil nine-thirty at night.The two males were kept in separatecages after they were weaned.The first male was introduced to anoutside flight on August 10, 1992 andhis prospective mate placed withhim a week later. At first theyavoided each other, sitting at oppositeends of the flight. Whenever themale approached the female, shewould fly away. After a week, thefemale became less reticent and theyare now enjoying each other's company.At night, the male sleeps in thepalm log while the female remainsoutside. The second male was introducedto his new flight on August24th and will meet his mate shortly.The breeding pair has not recycledsince the young males were pulled.They have been observed inspectingthe nest, which was cleaned, remodeledand placed back in the flight.There are only a few pairs of GuyanaToucanets in the United States atthe present time. They were neverimported before 1987 and then onlya few pairs have come in at one time.There are less than 20 known pairs inavicultural hands. The Guyana Toucanet'sonly relative in captivity, theSpot-billed Toucanet (Selenideramaculirostris), has proven itself tobe the most prolific Ramphastid incaptivity. This lends hope that otherbreeders will start reproducing theGuyana Toucanet in numbers. •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/633</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 40-42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/633/616</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
