<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/675</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Peale's Parrot Finch</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Calvin, Carol Anne</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buckley, Stash</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Recently we decided to import somePeale's Parrot Finches (Erythrurapealii), a bird of undeniable beautyand allure. We felt that with the uncertaintyof the quarantine Jaws and thetightening of restrictions on the airlines,it was now or never.We made an arrangement with agood friend, Sigie Meyer, of SE Birdand Supply, to bring in some of thesebirds, domestically bred in Europe.You can imagine our joy and exhilarationwhen the day came when thebirds finally arrived in the UnitedStates and quarantine had begun.The days passed without incidentand we got a call from Sigie saying thebirds were ready to be shipped. Wefully expected that there would be aminimum of hens, and some of thebirds would be quite old. You canimagine our surprise when it turnedout that we had an equal number ofcocks and hens, all appearing to beunder two years of age.These birds were set up in two hold-ing cages for several weeks to allowthe birds to acclimate. They settleddown quickly, and we decided to pairthem up and place them in breedingcages approximately 3 feet long by 2feet high by 2 feet wide in our basement"tropical" birdroom, with a minimumtemperature of 78°F and 70 to 80percent humidity. They started nestingalmost immediately, using hay andburlap strands as nesting materials,stuffing them i~to large, closed wickerbaskets.We have noted an interesting habitwith the Peale's Parrot Finch. This isthe only parrot finch species in whichthe birds feed each other. This seemsto work both ways - the cock feedingthe hen and the hen feeding thecock. Also, the cock Peale's ParrotFinch mating dance is almost identicalto that of the cock Red-headed ParrotFinch- little more than a bobbing up and down motion. Also worthy ofnote is the variability of the extent ofthe beautiful turquoise blue on thethroat and chest of the cock.Although the Peale's Parrot Finchesloved eggfood and mealworms (aswell as everything else they wereoffered), they seemed reluctant toincubate correctly, so many eggs werefostered to Society Finches. Averageclutch size was four, with a 50 percentfertility rate.The first egg to hatch was one successfullyincubated by the parents,hatching on November 15, 1991, afterapproximately 14 days of incubation.Only the one egg hatched in thisclutch of four. After approximatelytwo weeks, during which time the pairwas supplied with eggfood and mealworms,the cock appeared bored withhis chick and feeding chores, and wasobviously ready to recycle.Fearing abandonment, we pulledthe chick and put him under a pair ofSocieties who were raising a SpectabiledMannikin of about the same age.Unfortunately, they did not accepthim. So, reluctantly, we pulled thebaby Peale's Parrot Finch, clipped ayoung Society's wings for company,and placed both in our Animal IntensiveCare Unit for hand-feeding.The baby Peale's was fed approximatelyevery hour and a half from 6:30a.m. until 11:30 p.m. with RoudybushHandfeeding Formula No. 3.The Peale's was self-feeding by midDecember,being weaned by the useof spray millet and canary/finch mixscattered on the incubator floor. Theyoung Society was instrumental inteaching the Peale's to eat seed.Subsequent clutches were fosteredto Societies with few problems, but,surprisingly enough, although babyPeale's have blue faces, this first chickwas the only one we've encounteredso far with red feathers above thebeak. Apparently there is great variationin plumage coloration in juvenilePeale's.Although these birds have come inbefore (we had four birds brought inpreviously by Sigie Meyer- only oneof which we believed to have been ahen), successful breeding seems tohave eluded this country. We wouldhope to hear of other serious breedersbringing in these birds to ensure alarge enough gene pool to establish aviable population of this beautiful andpersonable finch.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/675</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/675/658</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
