<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2610</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-04T03:31:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Establishing Optimal Conditions for Artificial Incubation of Cockatiel Eggs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cutler, Brent A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abbott, U. K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Efforts co increase the efficiency of' reproduction in companion birds most frequently involves artificial incubation. We decided co determine the incubation conditions suitable for one of the most common companion birds, the cockatiel (Nymphicus bollandicus).There is extensive literature on the factors important in successful incubation of domestic poultry and game birds. We decided co test several of these in cockatiels, including length of time that eggs can be held prior co incubation, temperature and humidity during holding and incubation and hatching temperatures. Here we report on a study of incubation temperature, which establishes that cockati els develop and hatch normally under temperature and humidity conditions found optimal for domestic poultry and game birds.A breeding colony of 65 pairs of cockatiels provided the eggs for the study. Each pair of cockatiels occupied a single cage. They were fed ad. libiturn with a breeder crumble diet (Roudybush et al., 1984).Eggs were collected daily and marked by hen I.D. number and the date laid. They were fumigated and scored for not more than three days in a cold room maintained at 12.8°C and 60% relative humidity (Cutler et al., 1985).In this study we compared three temperature regimes. The standard temperature for chickens and most other domestic or game species was used in one group, considered the control. Temperatures 1.4 °C above and below this level were compared with this standard.Prior co setting, eggs from each pair were distributed equally into the three temperature groups. Egg weights were obtained shortly after lay, at the time of setting, and at the time of transfer to the hatcher. Hatched chicks were also weighed. Eggs were incubated in Jamesway 252 incubators. They were set aircell end up, in trays fitted with special inserts to accommodate the small cockatiel eggs. The trays automatically turned every two hours.Incubation temperatures for the control and the two treatment groups were 37.5°C (control), 38.9°C and 36.1 °C. Humidity was adjusted to provide a relative humidity of 56 percent in all groups.At seven days of incubation, the eggs were candled and all infertile and early dead embryos were removed and examined for abnormalities. At 15 days, the eggs were candled and any additional dead embryos were removed and examined.In each case, eggs appearing infertile or dead by candling test were removed and broken out. Dead embryos were staged and all abnormalities recorded. Living normal embryos were transferred to hatching incubators, in this case a Lyon's Glass Top set at 36.9°C, 38.3°C and 35.6 0C. Relative humidity during hatching was increased to 67 percent. Eggs were not turned after transfer to the hatching machine.The time of onset of pipping and hatching was recorded. Unhatched eggs were kept in the hatcher for several extra days to permit chicks in the slow developing ...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2610</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 1 (1991): FEB-MAR 1991; 12-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2610/2580</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
