<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1009</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T02:36:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Three Bolborynchus</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vriends, Matthew M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">These small, charming paraleets with their wedged, long or short pointed tails and thick stubby beaks (from which their scientific name arises) are extremely popular in their native land and in aviculture. They are friendly and peaceful aviary inmates that are not adverse to a "snow bath" which is not surprising in view of their natural habitat at 8,200 ft. (2,500 m) in the Andes. The birds nest in earth tunnels about 6 'h ft. deep with a chamber or two at the end, about 10 in. (25 cm) in diameter. The eggs are laid and incubated in one of these chambers. Unfortunately, we know little more about the lifestyle of these little hookbills. The Lineolated Parakeet, however, is an exception in that it does not burrow but raises its family in a hollow tree limb. All the species mentioned in this article, though, will use a nest box in a roomy aviary. Selection of Breeding Pairs It is important that you acquire a true pair. Although the sexes are very similar, surgical sex determination is not recommended. Research has shown that these birds are very sensitive to this procedure, especially B.orbygrzesi'Us and B. aymara. Some species show a slight dimorphism, the Lineolated Parakeet and the Barred Parakeet, for example. The wing and body feathers of the hen have narrower edges and the back has less black. This is also true of the tail feathers. Sometimes there is no black at all in the tail. The best way to acquire true pairs is to place a group of birds together in an aviary and allow them to pair off. Members of this genus usually get along well with their own and related species so that this can be done without too much risk. Over the years I have had the pleasure of many species in my aviaries. Yet, in the breeding season (and this can sometimes be wholly different) I am always somewhat afraid of egg binding-in spite of the fact that all hens are carefully monitored (unknown to the birds) twice per day by my bird attendant who works about eight hours per day. Hens suffering with egg binding can, in my experience, rarely be saved. Thus, birds which are too young should never be mated up. I give birds under 14 months no possibility of going to nest by giving them only large sleeping boxes. During the cold, short days, breeding is generally far from their thoughts. Housing and Nest Boxes Good breeding results are achieved in nest boxes with a height of 12 in. (30 cm) and a floor area of 8 X 9 in. (20 X 20 cm). These boxes are divided into two parts with a false floor about 6 in. (15 cm) high. The lower chamber can be reached by the birds through an opening 2 % in. wide in one of the back corners of the false floor. This chamber can, thus, be used by the birds as a nursery. A perch 2 in. (5 cm) in diameter and 10-18 in. (25-45 cm) wide is affixed just below the entrance hole to the upper chamber. 'Depending upon.its width, the perch may be partly or wholly pushed through to the back wall of the upper chamber and affixed there so it cannot move. Place a strip of mesh or affix a few thin nails on the back wall above and below the opening in the false floor to help the birds enter and leave. I recommend that you install a little inspection door in one of the side panels of the lower chamber. Use a mixture of sawdust washed aquarium sand, and pine bed~ ding as floor covering. It is difficult to be precise about the breeding season for birds in this genus. I have had broods in April through July but occasionally also in November, December and January. It is best, however, to encourage the birds to breed from the middle of April to June. This minimizes egg binding (with the aid of a good diet and a proper room temperature, of course). Only B. aurifrons seem to have a particular courtship procedure; most other species just puff out the neck feathers. Males of the Mountain or Golden-fronted Parakeets show their interest in a partner by increased gnawing on twigs and perches, mutual feeding, and seeking out nest boxes. It is therefore important to have a choice of boxes-at least two per pair-affixed at different heights and to different walls in the aviary and shelter. Brooding, Hatching and Rearing Although I have seen copulation take place on the nest box or perch several times-P aurifrons even three times on the floor---one can assume that pairing takes place mainly in the nest box. Both birds spend a few days in the nest before the first egg is laid. They sit quietly, gnawing occasionally at the inner walls. They are very sensitive to disturbance at this time but become more tolerant after the clutch is complete. Once the birds start incubating, they are quiet and stop gnawing at the inside of the nest box. The female can sometimes lay a remarkably large clutch, but the average is four to five eggs; incubation starts after the second or third egg is laid. The young hatch...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1009</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 2 (1996): MARCH-APRIL 1996; 17-18</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1009/989</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
