<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2665</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-20T07:32:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Macaw Society of America</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Frances, Robert</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Macaw Society of America (MSA) was formed in the middle of 1990. This national organization was founded to promote the continued education of all its members, breeders, owners or others interested in the care, breeding, ownership and preservation of all macaw species. Its purpose is also to continue to promote the domestic breeding of the endangered species while discouraging the practice of hybridization of all species. It promotes the restriction of importation of macaws, limited to breeders for the establishment of new gene pools for the domestic pet trade, thereby reducing the pressures on the limited populations in their native lands.The Macaw Society of America publishes a bi-monthly newsletter which provides the information about macaws or macaw-related items. This newsletter includes input from various avian experts, breeders, owners and veterinarians. Through its newsletter, it is the objective of MSA to provide all the latest information on the developments in the areas of avian research along with providing updates on current illnesses and diseases affecting macaws.For more information on the Macaw Society of America, please contact Robert Francis, President, MSA, P.O. Box 90037, Burton, Michigan 48509-0037 or call (313) 736-5059. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2665</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 3 (1991): JUNE-JULY 1991; 14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2665/2646</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
