<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4006</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Target Training</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wolf, Anita</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 1 (January/February 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.by Anita Wolf Photos courtesy of Amanda Hoffman For this article we are going to assume you have taught a bridge or marker. This is a word or sound that tells the animal that what it did in that moment is what you wanted and that a reward will follow. It marks the moment and bridges the behavior with the reward. I start by making a list of things my animal finds reinforcing. Then I rank them from most rewarding to least. I save the best rewards for big leaps in training and the lesser ones for small baby steps.In training terms, a target is anything that your bird/animal needs to touch in order to get a reward. Touch how. Touch where, touch with what? Well that is up to you. The best is to start with a nose or beak, and a target pole. I have often used a tennis ball or a golf ball on a stick. You can buy target poles from training tools websites.Why? Why would you train your animal to target? It is the building block on which we can shape other behaviors. Think of a dolphin jumping up and out of the water and touching its rostrum to a ball hanging above the water. That is a target behavior. This target behavior allows the trainer to shape so many other behaviors, swimming in a specific direction, spin, come out of the water, by guiding the animal while it is touching its rostrum to the target. It also allows new trainers to work with an animal since the animal is focused on the behavior rather than who is holding the target stick. It teaches youranimal not just to touch the target but it teaches your animal to learn and learning means more positive interactions and more fun. They don’t see the target as a positive when they first see it.That doesn’t mean it is negative, it&amp;#x27;s just a neutral object. Instead it is our job to teach them that it is not only positive but it leads to more positive interactions. Luckily most parrots will want to touch anything you present near their beak. They may touch it aggressively or playfully or out of curiosity. It doesn ’t matter. What matters is that they touch it and that you give them their bridge then reinforcement for touching it. If your bird is afraid of the target, move it close enough that they don&amp;#x27;t retreat whileholding it still and then bridge and reinforce for not retreating. Eventually the bird will want to get closer since the presentation of the target means they get a reward. Remember that we need just baby steps. No one learns to run immediately, first you learn to crawl, then walk, then run. Small steps in the right direction is what we are looking for. Small steps ensure we are setting the animal up for success not failure. If they fail too many times they could become completely resistant to training, and you lose trust.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4006</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 1 (2024): Watchbird January/February 2024; 12-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4006/3966</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
