<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/815</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Avian Diversity of Galapagos</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wallner, Liza Marie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The evolutionary isolation of the1 '6alapagos Islands has produceda rich diversity of unusual avifauna,many species being found nowhereelse in the world.Fifteen major islands comprise thearchipelago which is located approximately600 miles west of the Ecuadoriancoastline in the Pacific Ocean onand around the equator. I was able tovisit 12 of these on my two week sailingand hiking exploration of theislands, observing at close hand manyof the birds I am about to list anddescribe.Endemic or unique birds to theGalapagos Islands include 13 speciesof the famed Darwin's Finches, fourspecies of mockingbirds, two speciesof gull, the Galapagos Hawk, flightlesscormorant, Galapagos Penguin, and a single endemic species each of dove ,flycatcher, ma1tin, heron and rail. TheGalapagos Waved Albatross is almostconsidered endemic with the exceptionof two or three pairs which breedon small islands off Ecuador's coast.The islands a re probably bestknown for the three resident boobyspecies; howeve r, other interestingbird species also reside in Galapagosincluding two species of owls, twospecies of frigatebirds, flamingos, VermillionFlycatchers, Red-billed Tropicbirds,Brown Pelicans and AmericanOystercatchers to name just a few.Natural behavior observations andclose-up viewing of the birds on Galapagosis an easy matter as animals ofthese re lative ly young islands havenot developed a fear of humans. It isan amazing thing to simp ly walkthrough a b reeding colony of birds,many of w hich a re on eggs or w ithchicks, and cause no reaction whatsoever.The most s pectacular bird seen onmy trip was the Waved Albatross Diomedeairrorata . The entire colony of 12,000 pairs, with the exception of theseveral pairs mentioned in my introduction,nest exclusively on HoodIsland, Galapagos. This magnificentbird, with its bright yellow beak,cream colored head and brown bodyfe a thers , is known for its uniquecourtship display involving clicking,freezing, head bobbing and beakcrossing. This ritual is repeated eachyear at the onset of breeding season toreaffirm each pair's lifelong bondbefore mating takes place. Nestingoccurs from May to December afterwhich the young are fledged and thewhole colony leaves Hood Island tospend the rest of the year out at sea.I was in the Galapagos duringDecember 1993 and January 1994 so Iwas able to see the adult Waved Albatrosswith almost fully fledged chicks.They were all huge, impressive birdshaving wingspans of up to 10 feet andbody weights approaching 11 pounds.My adventure also allowed for aspecial hike and two nights campingon the rim of Isabella Island's AlcedoVolcano. This is one of the best placesto see the Galapagos Hawk Buteogalapagoensis.Adult birds are solid brown withyellow cere, talons and legs while thejuveniles have cream colored breastswith a brown mottled pattern. Thefemale birds tend to be larger and theytake on more than one mate at a time.All parents then help in the raising ofthe young.Immature hawks were seen up toone dozen at a time along Alcedo Volcano'srim. They would swoop downinches above my head, occasionallylanding on a nearby rock or shrub.Another fascinating encounter I hadwith a Galapagos Hawk happened onRabida Island which is known for itsred sand beach. It was along thisshoreline that several brown pelicannests were spotted in some shrubs,one with three abandoned eggs. As Iapproached a second nest, I saw ahawk perched atop it with its kill, adown-covered pelican chick. Thesehawks feed on everything from smalllava lizards to young goats if they canget them.This intriguing raptor has been eliminatedfrom many of the islands bydirect human predation in the past.Although now protected, this species'total population has been reduced toabout 100 pairs. They have no naturalenemies, which would explain theircurious and fearless natures.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/815</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 60-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/815/797</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
