<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3258</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-02T17:36:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA 2011 Convention</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Culp, Alexandra</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">t the 2011 AFA convention, with the theme "Jewels in Aviculture," AFA is busy changing to meet the demands of the future of aviculture -not only in who is attending the AFA convention, but in what they'regaining and contributing to the convention experience. Take for instance Lynn Hall, a veteran attendee with over 20 years of AFA conventions under his belt ... "I noticed the enthusiasm, and I liked to see that," he said in reference to this year's convention. With having been to different animal and bird events, "the enthusiasm is gone," Hall said. At AFA however, the enthusiasm is alive today, which he believes is important.Also on Hall's mind was more talk about bird breeding. "I've gone to bird events where there's nothing but pet bird people." With an eye toward the future of aviculture, he said he hopes for "a future for the birds." "Seeing they don't get regulated out." At one time, Hall opposed the importation of birds. His current opin-ion on the matter has changed. "Yes, you can still bring them in, but they (should) have to go through the breeders, not the hobbyists, not the pet stores or anything else. There's enough captive breeding to put into market; if we have the patience to work on it." Hall is an avid bird breeder and aviculturist, as well as a Lifetime Member and supporter of AFA.With a different perspective in the bird world is Athena Wilson, an avian keeper with the San Diego Zoo. "For me a big thing has been networking" she said about her first AFA convention. "My boss is the one that recommended I come here" she said. Though nota bird owner herself she said that manv of the keepers who typically attend these kinds of programs also breed birds. "It wouldbe nice to attract other keepers that don't do that onthe side" Wilson said. "There's a lot of information out there that can be learned for us, too." With emphasis on private breeding and pet birds, she said, "I can't really apply that to my job, but it's still interesting."Having found it challenging to find topics pertaining to her line of work, she envisions future AFA conventions having topics, "that would attract more zoo people." For instance, she said, "with a zoo setting, you have to make it as natural as possible, so we can't provide general rainbow toys and things like that. Guests don't want to see that." By having vets, and aviculturists with a background or degree in zoology, talk on subjects with a broader, more generalized scale in mind allows her to gain more education to apply towards her work with the birds at the zoo.AFA Visits the Oakland ZooDuring the convention field trip to the Oakland Zoo the participating attendees could be seen hiking though the uphill and downhill slopes familiar to the San Francisco area as they hurried to see the small zoo's exhib-its. An aerial ride offered a unique view of some of the exhibits, including the mature male lion who watched the riders like a dog watches a child's ice cream cone from below, waiting for some to drop off. Though not boasting many birds, the zoo featured a few aviaries for viewing and a flock of flamingos. Keeping flamingo lady, Carol Stanley, in mind as I wandered the gift shop, I couldn't help but make note of where each flamingo item lay in the store and whether it might be of interest to Carol. Sure enough! On her way in as I left the shop, Carol asked if they had anything flamingo, to which I replied, "They sure do!" </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3258</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 38 No. 3 (2011): Number 3 2011; 28-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3258/3242</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
