<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/897</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:18:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The AFA's Position</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Berry, Robert J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The American Federation of A viculture (AFA) is a nonprofit grass roots organization of bird breeders and pet owners with a membership base of over 5000 individuals. The AF A is also a federation of approximately 200 affiliated bird clubs representing over 50,000 aviculturists nationwide.We serve our membership primarily as an educational organization promoting advances in avicultural knowledge and awareness.Our Mission is: To preserve avian species on a worldwide basis.In order to fulfill this mission, the AFA is involved in various activities with goals that support this ideal: conservation, noninvasive avian research, cooperative breeding initiatives, education, publications, conferences, and monitoring state, national and international legislation and regulation.The AFA recognizes that habitat destruction on a global scale is the greatest single threat to avian species. In terms of our conservation objectives, more than being only dedicated to conservation activities in situ, the AFA is dedicated to the preservation of avian species both in the wild and in captivity with the purpose of maintaining their genetic stocks for future generations.While it is true that many individual aviculturists in the United States would probably prefer no regulation, as a professional organization, the AFA recognizes the positive potential of considering voluntary standards for this expanding cottage industry. We feel strongly, however, that any voluntary standards considered, should be developed within the avicultural community. And, that such standards should address the longterm survival and wellbeing, the humane care and management, the conservation of avian species on a global scale and the establishment of genetically stable, long-term, self sustaining populations in captivity.COMMENTS:WBCA, Section 114. Exotic Bird Conservation Assistance.Part (a) ASSISTANCE.The AfA already has several programs available and projects underway that support the WBCA's conservation objectives.Plans have been formulated to establish an advisory panel of avicul tural experts from our membership to offer their technical assistance to conservation efforts worldwide.Areas where we feel their services will be of value include: • Species identification.• Management protocols and husbandry techniques.• Aviary construction, materials and design.• Humane handling and transport of specimens.• General avicultural practices that are already proven, there is no reason to reinvent the wheel.• Access to avicultural support services including genetic profiling and avian medical diagnostics.• Availability of avicultural equipment and supplies with recommended vendor sources.• Biosecurity considerations.Our bimonthly journal, The APA Watchbird, published over the last twenty years, contains a wealth of information on various topics including general husbandry, nutrition, species specific avicultural requirements, etc. We are selecting some of the more informative of these articles and making them available with translations into appropriate languages. This project was generated specifically to assist personnel in foreign countries in developing their conservation programs and enhancing their understanding of the captive breeding requirements of species or families of birds that are under their care.In addition to our organization's ongoing recovery program for the Venezuelan Red Siskin (Carduelis cucullata) initiated in 1986, the AF A is currently seeking funding for implementing the second phase of our field project for the evaluation of the status and recovery of the Redfronted Macaw (Ara rubrogenys) in Bolivia. Both projects involve CITES APPENDIX I species. Abstracts of these grass roots initiated and supported conservation projects are included in this report as are listings of twentyfive field studies and other conservation related projects outside the United States for which AF A has provided funding. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/897</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 3 (1995): MAY-JUNE 1995; 20-22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/897/879</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
