<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4104</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:20:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Nyasa Lovebird</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Waugh, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (January 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.By David Waugh Loro Parque CorrespondentIn the southern part of Africa there is a huge (519,000 km2) area dedicated since 2011 to help bolster harmony between humans and wildlife, with a particular focus on nature tourism. This is known as the Kavango Zambezi TransfrontierConservation of Nature) Red List as ‘Near Threatened’ in response to the range of threats the wild population faces. The species naturally occurs in south-eastern Africa, with approximately 60% of the geographical distribution located within the KAZA boundaries in Zambia and Zimbabwe, although the proportion in KAZA of the total population (estimate of less than 20,000 individuals) might not be the same. The key habitat for the Nyasa Lovebird is mopane woodland (Colophospermum mopane), especially during the breeding season, but unsustainable harvesting of mopane trees for charcoal production and timber is having a negative effect.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4104</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 1 (2023): Watchbird January 2023; 12-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4104/4064</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
