<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1488</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-03T20:40:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Pointe-A-Pierre Wild Fowl Trust, Trinidad</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">ِِِDuring a recent trip to the island of Trinidad I had the pleasure of spending the afternoon with Ms. Molly Gaskin and Karilyn Shephard of the renown Pointe-A-Pierre Wild Fowl Trust. For years AFA had a bumper sticker that read "Aviculture is Conservation Too." If there was ever an example of aviculture as conservation it is the Wild Fowl Trust.The Trust was originally founded in 1966 by Richard Deane, a hunter who believed in the need for captive breeding and release of waterfowl as a management tool. From the beginning the Trust has had a strong link to the Wild Fowl Trust at Slimbridge. In fact the logo was designed by Sir Peter Scott of Slimbridge.After Deane's retiring the Trust was reactivated by Ms. Molly R. Gaskin, an untiring aviculturist and outspoken conservationist. The Trust currently encompasses two lakes and about 25 hectares of land within a major petrochemical complex, PETROTRIN.I arrived at the Trust with ornithologist Floyd Hayes and Michael Gartside, treasurer for the Center for the Study of Tropical Birds, Inc. Upon our arrival we were immediately impressed with the flowering trees and shrubs that adorned the grounds. Walking down the driveway we soon reached the "Leaming and Interpretation Centre." My eye immediately went to the bird feeder in the front of the. Centre. Perched upon a tree near the feeder was a brilliant Yellow Oriole, a Blue-gray Tanager, a Palm Tanager, and a Kiskadee Flycatcher. Within a minute my eye went to the feeder itself as a wild Muscovy Duck landed upon it.A brief tour of the facility included their wild Muscovy breeding pens, a Scarlet Ibis aviary, and a large pond with numerous Black-bellied Whistling Ducks. Behind the scene were several pairs of Blue and Gold Macaws set up for breeding and a rehab Yellow-headed Caracara.Breeding successes at the Trust include:• Black-bellied Whistling Ducks 574 released 0967-1992)• White-faced Whistling Ducks 40 released 0988) 16 0993)• Fulvous Whistling Ducks 208 released 0 985-1992)• White-cheeked Pintail 44 released 0993) 47 0994)• Wild Muscovy Ducks 160 released 0985-1992) 82 0993) 83 0994)• Scarlet Ibis 030991)060992) 11 0993) 130994)Their small resident flock of 15 Blue and Gold Macaws started breeding in 1993. Some interest exists in a release program for the macaws in the vicinity of Nariva Swamp where they were believed to occur naturally until the 1970s. Some consideration has also been made to translocating birds from the mainland. Before such an effort would have any lasting impact, a strategy to limit the illegal taking of birds from their nests would have to be implemented. Strolling around the...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1488</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 1 (2000): Jan-Feb 2000; 30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1488/1465</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
