<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2421</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T14:47:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Fife Fancy</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Olszewski, Anthony B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The current concern over size is nothing new to enthusiasts of the border fancy canary. After World War II, "Norbords " began to appear on the British show benches. These were Norwich-border mongrels being exhibited as borders. The supposed advantage of this pairing was an immediate increase in head size. Of course, the overall size also was increased. Feather lumps also became a problem.By 1957 many border breeders became compelled to leave the mainstream of the sport. They declared that they were raising a different breed, the Fife fancy canary. The standard remains the same as the border's in all respects except for size. Four and one quarter inches is the maximum allowed, one and one quarter inches smaller than the border.The proponents of this variety maintain that they raise the true border, the wee gem. Occasionally, Fife-border crosses are used. Fife fancy cocks are paired to small border hens. This is done at rare intervals to improve type.Fife fancy canaries occur in all the usual type colors: yellow, dominant white, brown (cinnamon), dominant white ground brown (silver fawn), dominant white ground blue, green and yellow or dominant white variegated. Of course, hard and soft feather versions of each color exist. The overwhelming majority of Fife fancy canaries are yellow variegated. Clear yellow and any form of white are comparatively rare.Until the late seventies interest in this breed was meager. At the 1978 English National show only sixty-six Fifes were benched. Up till then Fife fancies were almost a curiosity. From that year the popularity of the breed has skyrocketed. At the 1981 National show over three hundred Fifes were exhibited.Why this sudden gain in stature? This youngest of the canary breeds is perceived as the only kind that suits both beginner and expert alike. Production of a winner always is a challenge. Fifes are relatively easy to procure and raise. Prices are reasonable. Initial stock is not difficult to find. No particular problems are encountered with this type canary. Feeders are definitely unnecessary and the Fifes do not suffer from feather lumps.Unfortunately, the Fife fancy canary is uncommon in the states. Hopefully, this situation will soon be remedied. Perhaps Fifes might be used in the production of the American singer!All thanks must go to Mr. A.T.Anderson of England who supplied the information contained in this article. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2421</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 2 (1986): APR-MAY 1986; 50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2421/2394</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
