<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2569</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-16T21:48:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Sandgrouse, A Review</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dierick, Etienne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article will be primarily directed toward the Pallas Sandgrouse, Syrrbaptes paradoxus. However, since sandgrouse are a rather obscure family, it might prove fruitful to review the family as a whole.The family Pteroclidae contains two genera and sixteen species of pigeon-sized birds which inhabit the arid regions of Africa, Asia, Europe and the Middle East. It is generally included in the order Columbiformes, pigeons. However, recently some authorities placed them in Cbaradiiformes, shorebirds, while others give them ordinal rank. The genus Pterocles consists of 14 species while Syrrbaptes has two members which are found in the cold deserts of Asia.Sandgrouse are compact, stocky, terrestrial birds with pigeon-like heads. The greys and browns cryptically dappled with orange, chestnut,black and white help them melt into their semi-desert surroundings. Their short legs are feathered to the toes as in the true grouse. They are incapable of perching since the hind toe is vestigal in 14 species and absent in the remaining two Syrrbaptes.Because of their extremely rapid flight and distinctive appearance resulting from their short, deep bodies and long, pointed wings, they cannot be confused with any other bird in flight. So swift is their flight, experienced observers state hunting falcons are incapable of catching them in level flight.The usual clutch of three eliptically shaped eggs vary from buff to brown with blotches of yellowish-brown to reddish and underlying grey. The prec ocial young hatch covered with down and are able to feed themselves soon after leaving the nest.Their food consists of seeds and greens, especially of chenopods and legumes.Historically, sandgrouse have not been well known to aviculturists; thus relatively few captive breeding attempts have been made or were successful. Probably the first to raise sandgrouse was the Danish breeder Winge who, in 1892, reared the Pallas Sandgrouse. Shortly after, the English aviculturists Meade-Waldo and San Quintin bred the White-bellied, P. alchatta, Black-bellied, P. orientalis, and Chestnut-bellied, P. exustus, Sandgrouse. In the 1960s, Dr. Frisch of West Germany again raised the White-bellied Sandgrouse, while Dr. Grummt of the East Berlin Zoo; Hans Assink, Rotterdam Zoo; and the Dutch breeder De Vries, all "raised the Pallas Sandgrouse. It is to be sadly noted that, as far as is known, all Pallas in private breeders' and western zoo collections are progeny from the same importation. The last new species to be bred was the Yellowthroated, P. gutteralis, by Mr. L. Grueber in 1985.Presently I am working with Yellow-throated and Pallas Sandgrouse. The latter I have bred successfully since 1983 from stock I received from the previously mentioned De Vries. The Yellow-throated have not as yet bred since I only received them in the winter of 1988-89.Pallas are bizarre little birds (10 ounces), inhabiting the region from the Caspian Sea to eastern Mongolia, from which they make sporadic eruptions into western Europe as far as Spain and Faroe Islands. Their habitat's extremely hostile climate has caused them to undergo several evo- 1 u tionary adaptions such as thick abdominal skin, very short legs, small rabbit-like feet and one of the most efficient high speed wings found in the bird kingdom.The Pallas are kept in a covered, unheated enclosure, each pair having an area measuring six feet by 16 feet. The Yellow-throated are kept in similar sized pens, though heated to maintain a minimum of 45 °F. It is particularly important to keep the Pallas dry at all times. The pen floors are mostly sand covered with some dirt for dust bathing and designed to allow the birds some sun each day.Sandgrouse food requirements are both simple and inexpensive, consisting of game bird crumbles and the following seeds: milo, canary, flax, mung beans and safflower seeds. It is desirable to give them green food. Crushed oyster shells should always be available to them since their diet is low in calcium.Pallas' courtship begins in early March at which time the males become quite amorous, pursuing the females after the manner of mallards. The female's invitation to copulate is a submissive sitting posture with the head held low and slightly stretched foward. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2569</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 5 (1990): OCT- NOV 1990; 22-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2569/2539</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
