<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2644</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-18T20:08:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Red Siskin Project ... Conservation Pilot Program for CITES Appendix I Birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gorman, Kevin M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionThe AFA Red Siskin Project has made great strides in 1990, thanks to the financial and moral support of you, the AFA members. We have worked toward several avenues of growth. We have streamlined the program and structured the organization so that it would be attractive to persons who would like to participate, and at the same time we could maintain a certain degree of control over the transfers of the endangered siskins which we are stewarding.Since the Red Siskin (Spinus cucculatus) is a species which is on CITES Appendix I and on the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Endangered Species List, there are certain controls which both state and federal governments put on the transactions of this species. The AFA Red Siskin Project is a program which will serve as a pilot program for other endangered bird species. Once all the groundwork (i.e. program structure/strategies) and limitations (i.e. international trade, endangered species law requirements) are established with the Red Siskin Project, then the AFA can plug another CITES Appendix I species into the slot and have another program of similar nature. The following article will outline the 1990 accomplishments of the Red Siskin Project.Publicity I EducationAs with any volunteer program, there must be a certain amount of publicity and education of the public. Without this, no one will know about the program and new members and support will not be there for you. In 1990, several members of the Red Siskin Project wrote magazine articles to inform the public about the Red Siskin:·2•3•4 and of the importance of careful breeding of endangered finches:In January of 1990, a monthly newsletter, "Siskin News;' was initiated. The purpose of this newsletter is to inform members about the Red Siskin and the developments in the project. It is used as an education tool to teach persons about the care and breeding of the Red Siskin, its natural history, laws involving endangered birds, shipping, diseases, etc. The newsletter helps to keep all members informed, on a regular basis, about siskin project news events and what other siskin breeders are doing. Siskin News gives members a forum for asking questions and receiving answers from their co-breeders. Most importantly, this newsletter keeps the project members focused on the common goals of the Red Siskin Project. Therefore, no one should feel alone once they receive AFA Red Siskins. To date, Siskin News has a circulation of 90 persons across the United States, Canada, Puerto Rico, West Indies, England and Italy. Another publicity tool was the design of a beautiful, colored pamphlet which explains the purpose and goals of the Red Siskin Project. This pamphlet contains information on how persons can support the program. The pamphlet was laid out and final artwork performed by M. Jean Hessler (graphic artist for APA Watchbird). These pamphlets will be circulated to bird clubs across the United States in early 1991.Ray Shaw of California generously donated his artwork to the AFA by designing the colorful Red Siskin Project t-shirts which were first unveiled at the August 1990 AFA convention. All of the monies received from t-shirt sales go directly into the Red Siskin Project account.We had begun asking for endorsements from a few bird clubs across the U.S. in late 1990 and will continue asking for more widespread endorsements in 1991, when we can utilize the colored pamphlet. To date, three very influential bird clubs have given us their endorsements: The National Colorbred Association (NCA), the National Institute of Red Orange Canaries (NIROC), and the National Finch and Softbill Society (NFS).Federal Permits Not Required The Red Siskin is an endangered species and, therefore, regulated by the U.S. government. This very fact inhibited the early stages of the project because no one knew exactly which transactions could be lawfully performed with the Red Siskin, and which permits, if any, were required for these transactions.In April of 1990, the Red Siskin Project chairman drafted a questionnaire for the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Office of Management Authority (USFW OMA). This questionnaire asked for specific answers to our questions about which permits were required for transactions performed within the Red Siskin Project. Shortly thereafter, we received written documentation from the chief of USFW OMA stating which transactions needed permits. The following information summarizes that letter: If Red Siskins (i.e. endangered species) are transported across state lines in association with transactions that are NON commercial (i.e. money is NOT involved, such as trades, breeder loans, or donations) then no permits are required by the federal government. The reason is that these transactions are not performed for commercial gain, but are for the purpose of propagating and preserving the endangered Red Siskin. However, the person donating or loaning the siskins must give the AFA a signed affidavit stating that the birds were raised by them, or were legally obtained from another breeder.However, if a CITES Appendix I ( endangered) species is transported across state lines in association with a commercial (money) transaction, then one of the following are required: Captive-bred Wildlife Registration or a Federal Endangered Species Permit. A Captive-bred Wildlife Registration (CBWR) is purchased for $25 from the USFW OMA. This registration is good for a two year renewable term. The holder of a CBWR can only buy and sell birds with other CBWR holders who are registered for the same species (i.e. Red Siskin). The Federal Endangered Species Permit (ESP) is obtained only for single transactions with endangered species. The ESP is also $25 each time you apply. Applications for both the CBWR and the ESP can be obtained by writing The USFW OMA at 4401 North Fairfax Drive, Room 432, Arlington, VA 22203, phone (703) 358-2104.The Red Siskin Project is able to perform interstate transactions with Red Siskins without requiring any federal permits as long as all transactions are non-commercial and no money changes hands. The fact that federal permits are not required by persons participating in the Red Siskin Project gives us the ability to freely transport siskins all over the United States. However, transactions are limited only to bona fide breeder loans, trades and donations. This is why it is essential that persons donate siskins, or give siskins as breeder loans to the project. These three methods are the only ways we an legally bring new Red Siskins into the project.The only other method of obtaining new siskins for the project would be to have a bird club raise money and purchase siskins from a siskin breeder who is in the same state, and subsequently donating these purchased siskins to the AFA Red Siskin Project. This exact thing was done in 1989! The Missouri Cage-Bird Association purchased a pair of Red Siskins for the Red Siskin Project in 1989 when the project was in its infancy and Paddy Lambert was named as the keeper of these birds (The Missouri Cage-Bird Association has been supporting us for a couple of years now. Thank you· all, you kind-hearted MCBA people!).  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2644</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 2 (1991): APR-MAY 1991; 55-59</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2644/2614</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
