<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3610</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-25T18:15:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Tribute to Susan Clubb, DVM</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferragamo, Concetta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In this edition of the AF A Watchbird Journal our "spotlight" shines brightly on a multifaceted "Wonder Woman". Not only is she an avian veterinarian, but a breeder, pet owner, business owner and mother as well. She is recognized as a long-standing member of the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. (AFA), and Association of Avian Veterinarians (AAV). This dynamo has served in various official positions or on committees for each of these organizations over the years.She is a highly sought after educator who has traveled to over 17 different countries around the world to assist as a consultant for zoos, conservation programs, breeding programs and private aviculture. She has co-authored 2 books: Psittacine Aviculture, Prospectives, Techniques and Research, published by the Avicultural Breeding and Research Center (ABRC), and Avian Medicine, and Surgery published by Saunders. She has also published over 75 scientific veterinary/avicultural articles during her career, and easily another 100 articles in lay publications involving the pet industry, aviculture and avian medicine. This Watchbird edition shines its avicultural spotlight on the charismatic and very interesting -Susan Clubb, DVM.Susan grew up surrounded by animals but was never able to keep birds in deference to her father's allergies. It wasn't until she was a veterinary student that she was able to act on a passion that led to one amazing avian adventure after another. Susan's first bird was a White-crested, Black Polish rooster named Harry. This chicken sparked an interest that led her to research parrots and seek out those who bred them. Susan met Dr. Bern Levine, who she described as her mentor and who ignited her passion for the world of psittacines (parrots).Susan recalls that it all started with a trade. She used to breed ferrets (long before they were popular). Dr. Levine was interested in acquiring ferrets and Susan wanted a parrot. She then traded a group of ferrets for her very first pet parrot, T orro, the wild-caught, Spanish speaking, Yellow-naped Amazon, originally from Central America. Susan went on to share her import story.At the time, 1977, the natives of Central America would often capture wild parrots or take the chicks from wild nests, and then tame them. Importers from the United States would then buy these "pets" and bring them to the U.S. through the import stations. This meant that the United States import stations often ended up with tamed, Spanish speaking parrots, ready for sale or trade. Susan was blessed with the opportunity to pick out her pet Torro from the Pet Farm wholesale outlet.Beginning in 1974 importing parrots, or any other birds, into the United States had very stringent rules associated with it. Privately owned quarantine stations and USDA owned stations all had strict protocols to avoid the introduction of exotic New Castle's disease into the U.S. poultry industry. Proper quarantine procedures were adhered to, such as the traditional 30 days of isolation where they were treated for psittacosis and tested for New Castles Disease. Only authorized persons were allowed contact with these quarantined birds. Veterinarians or other authorized people were required to shower upon entering and exiting the quarantine stations. At that time a business in Miami, Florida, called Pet Farm had a series of quarantine stations and an outlet store where wholesalers could visit and pick out birds. Those who had the chance to visit this outlet, like Susan, were often inspired by the experience. This "warehouse" of parrots inspired Susan and kindled the passion for breeding parrots that went on to earn Susan award winning achievements.When asked about a mentor, Susan stated that she holds great admiration for her friend and mentor Dr. Bern Levine. When Susan graduated from vet school she did her internship for Dr. Greg Harrison in Lake Worth, Florida. During that time she was able to visit Dr. Levine at Pet Farm. Susan ended up working for Dr. Levine for eleven years at the Pet Farm facilities. During her tenure with Pet Farm, Susan learned a lifetime of avian medicine, with hands-on experience. The facility often imported over 100,000 birds annually. Susan described the experience with exhilaration as she stated, "We literally worked with over 1,000,000 birds! Take 100,000 birds times eleven years and it equals over one million birds!" Eventually the wild bird conservation act of 1992 passed and Pet Farm was no longer needed, as importing wild parrots became a thing of the past.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3610</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 40 No. 2&amp;3 (2013): Number 2&amp;3 2017; 17-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3610/3593</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
