<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1519</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:52:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Five Popular AttStralian Grass Parakeets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vriends, Matthew M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bourke's Parrot Neopbema bourkiiNatural Range: The inland of southern and central Australia.Synonyms: Neopsepbotus bourkii pallida, Euphema bourkii. (Neophema:Neas = new, pheme = voice; bourkii = after Sir Richard Bourke, a former Governor of New South Wales.)General: After their discovery in 1835, and observations in New South Wales at the beginning of 1900, it became apparent that this species was gradually becoming scarcer, and after the second world war it was considered by some that the species had become extinct in the wild. Although there were fairly large numbers of the birds in the aviaries of fanciers in Europe and Australia, the wild birds had become really endangered and the relatively few remaining lived only in the dry, almost uninhabited regions of the interior. During the lengthier dry spells in various parts, the birds would disappear, only to tum up again when conditions improved. During the last few decades the status of wild Bourke's Parrots has improved greatly and they have extended their range west-wards, almost to the coast.During the day, the birds rest in the sparsely foliaged trees, foraging only in the mornings and evenings, sometimes among the acacias, sometimes on the ground, searching for the seeds, buds and leaves of grasses and broad-leaved plants. Scarcely before the sun has set, they fly to their drinking places and may not go to roost until 10 P.M. Long before the sun rises they may also go to water. On the ground they walk quickly and easily, for seemingly long distances. They are not particularly shy and can be approached fairly closely.When they finally take to the wing, they land again after a short distance either on the ground or in a tree or shrub. During the flight they utter trilling notes. The flight is fast with short wing beats, that are interspersed with short rest pauses, making a somewhat fluctuating flight path.The birds nest in the hollow limbs of shortish trees. The hen lays 4-5 white, roundish eggs, one approximately every 48 hours. The eggs usually rest on a bed of wood pulp. The incubation period is 19 days and the young leave the nest four 'Weeks after hatching. They are fed by the parent birds for a further two weeks after fledging. Breeding seasons vary, depending on favorable rainfall and the resulting flush of food plants. During the breeding period, the cock stays close to the nest and feeds the hen regularly. The hen leaves the nest only for occasional short periods to eat and drink.The species first arrived in Europe in 1867 at the London Zoo, .but specimens were soon to be seen in other parts of the continent. Newly arrived birds were somewhat tender, but they soon became acclimatized to the extent that they could be kept in outside aviaries with a night shelter.The Bourke's Parrot is one of the most endearing and attractive aviary birds that will live quite amicably together with other species. However, if you wish to breed numbers of them, it is best to house each pair separately. They are very mobile birds that need plenty of flying space. It is good to have grass and other plants growing on the floor of out-side aviaries, so that the birds can forage naturally. It will be necessary to cultivate the earth floor at regular intervals. To provide the necessary shade, a Polygonum or similar climbing plant can be grown over the aviary.The seed mixture should consist of two parts canary and millet seeds, and one part rolled oats, plus a small amount of sunflower seeds and hemp. In the breeding season, seeding grasses, germinating millet sprays, and adequate green food must be given. Soft food consisting of soaked bread and hard-boiled egg should also be given, but apples are not always accepted. Some birds show a preference for particular food items, while others will ignore them. River sand, grit, cuttlefish, and minerals must be available. The birds like to bathe regularly.Bourke's Parrots should be given a choice of two or three nestboxes. You should place a layer of damp sawdust or peatmoss in the base. When the young hatch, you must inspect the nest at weekly intervals and remove excess droppings as the hen is not particularly "houseproud." In general, Bourke's Parrots make good parents and can also be used to foster the young of other species. There are a few mutations, including isabel, cinnamon, yellow, red varieties, and a sex-linked lutino.The first breeding results reported were in 1875 by the Dutchman de Comely; a year later by Kessels in Uccle in Belgium, then by Russ in Germany and Gedney in England. Today, they are bred regularly and in such color varieties that they can be regarded as almost domesticated.It is strange that to date no cross breeding with a Bourke's Parrot has occurred. The crossing mentioned by Annie P. Gray in her book Bird Hybrids (between a cock Budgerigar and a hen Bourke's) is highly unlikely.Bourke's Parrot is actually so different in color pattern from other members of the genus Neopbema, that is would perhaps be better to give it its own genus - perhaps Neopsepbotus, as it was formerly called.Splendid Grass Parakeet Neopbema splendidaNatural Range: The interior of South AustraliaSynonyms: Euphema splendida, Neophema splendida balk. (splendida = splendid).General: Splendid Grass Parakeets inhabit areas where spinifex grass and Eucalyptus trees grow among other thick scrub. After the discovery of these birds by John Gould in 1840, no more was heard about them until their sudden rediscovery in 1941 in Western Australia, where they had previously not been seen. later, large numbers of these beautiful birds were seen in southeastern Western Australia, and they soon colonized gardens and parks in the towns and settlements. The birds "live a fairly nomadic existence which is indicated by their sudden appearances and disappearances.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1519</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 2 (2000): March-April 2000; 45-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1519/1496</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
