<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/539</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Spectacled Eider Ducks</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elgas, Bob</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of the various species of orthAmerican waterfowl , one of the mostbeautiful is Somateria fischeri, theSpectacled Eider Duck. It is also oneof the least well known , and one thatis seen but infrequently by observers.The lack of familiarity is due to theirremote distribution . During thebreeding season they inhabit the lowcoastal tundras adjacent to the BeringSea, especially the Yukon/KuskoquimDelta or southwestern Alaska. This isa vast area of low, open tundra characterizedby thousands of small, shallowponds and lakes. Vegetation isshort, turfy grasses and low arcticshrubs. It is an area that teems with wildlife, and some of the SpectacledEider 's neighbors are such species asEmperor, Cackling , White-frontedand Pacific Black Brant Geese, Tundra(Whistling) Swans, Lesser SandhillCranes, myriads of shore birds, andvarious other wildlife forms . It is theonly area in North America whereone can see the Bristle-thighedCurlew. Due to the remoteness of thearea , other than the few nativeEskimos, it is infrequently visited byhumans. One of the ornithologicalmysteries surrounding North Americanwaterfowl is where the SpectacledEider spends its winters. Oncethe birds depart the breedinggrounds, little if anything has beendocumented. It is presumed they mayspend their winters somewhere onthe Bering Sea, perhaps on the iceshelves at the edge of the ice pack,but as yet this remains unproven.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/539</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 58-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/539/523</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
