<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2736</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-26T09:29:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Nine Years of AFA-sponsored Research</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">1982 ...1. Estimation of the population parameters of the Green-cheeked Amazon (Amazona viridigenalts) in northeastern Mexico - ]. Clinton-Eitniear, McAllen TX.Results presented at 1983 AFA convention.Clinton-Eitniear, J., Status of the Green-cheeked Amazon in northern Mexico. Watchbird, Dec/Jan 1986, pp. 22-24.2. Seasonal evaluation of excretory sex steroid hormones in juvenile psittacines; non-invasive applications to a functional appraisal of sexual identity of mature birds - A. Bercovitz, San Diego Zoo, San Diego, CA.Bercovitz, A.B.; Frey, F. Jr.; and Bain, J.; Endocrine fecology of immature birds. Watchbird, Apr/ May 1984, pp. 38-44.3. Detection of Chlamydia psittaci infection in exotic birds - ]. M. Gaskin, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL.Gaskin, J., Avian Reoviruses: Are they for real? Watchbird, Dec/ Jan, 1988, p. 24.4. Development and efficacy of a live budgerigar fledgling disease virus vaccine for use in breeder budgerigars (Melopsittacus undula tus) - P.D. Lukert and R.B. Davis, University of Georgia, Athens, GA.Luckert, P.D., and Davis, R.B., Psittacine papovavirus, AFA Watchbird, Aug/Sept 1984, p. 14.5. Solid food requirements and water tolerance of cockatiel chicks from hatching to five weeks of age. C.R. Grau and T.E. Roudybush, University of California, Davis, CA.Results presented at 1983 AFA Convention as well as Western Poultry Disease Conference.Roudybush, T.E., and Grau, C.R., Solid food requirements for handrearing cockatiels, AFA Watchbird,June/July 1984, pp. 40-45.1983 ...1. Breeding biology of the Bahamas Parrot (Amazona leucocephala bahamensis). R. Gnam, City University of New York, New York, NY.Gnam, R., Breeding Biology of the Bahama Parrot, Watchbird, Aug/ Sept 1986, pp. 58-61.2. Exogenous factors affecting the natural population of Amazona viridigenalis and a determination of its natural diet. ]. ClintonEitniear, McAllen, TX.Clinton-Eitniear, J., Greencheek Amazon Update, Watchbird, Aug/Sept 1988, pp. 28-29.3. Lysine requirement of cockatiel chicks. C.R. Grau and T.E. Roudybush, University of California, Davis, CA.Results presented at 1984 AFA veterinary seminar.Grau, C.R. and Roudybush, T.E., Lysine requirement of cockatiel chicks, Watchbird, Dec/Jan 1986, pp. 12-14.4. Follow-up study on psittacine papovavirus funded in 1982. P.D. Lukert and R.B. Davis.Wainright, P.O.; Luckert, P.O. and Davis, R.B., Update on papovavirus infection in fledgling psittacines, Watchbird Feb/Mar 1987, pp. 34-37. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2736</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 6 (1991): DEC 1991- JAN 1992; 47-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2736/2716</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
