<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/997</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Successful breeding of the Orange~ breasted Fig Parrot at Lora Parque</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sweeney, Roger G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Orange-breasted Fig Parrot L Opopsitta gulielmiterti occurs naturally on New Guinea, including Salawati in the Papuan islands, and also the Aru islands, Indonesia. Seven different subspecies have been described, although this figure may be in need of a slight revision. Perhaps the most distinctive subspecies is Opopsitta gulielmitert: am abilis, which occurs from the Northeastern region of New Guinea. This subspecies differs very noticeably from other subspecies by the fact that the adult male bird lacks the distinctive orange coloration of the breast and upper abdomen, which is instead a pale yellow. The male bird also lacks the black marking on the ear covens that is usually present in other subspecies. The female bird by comparison has the black ear coverts and also the rich orange breast and upper abdomen coloration, making sex identi- fication for this subspecies the reverse of the nominate description and most of the other subspecies.The Orange-breasted Fig Parrot has been represented in the Loro Parque collection by the subspecies O.g.a111ctbilis for several years, although in recent years these birds have not been on public display but are accommodated in one of our offexhibition breeding areas. One pair of 0.g. a m abili s managed to successfully hatch and rear a chick during the early part of the 1994 breeding season. Some of the notes recorded are given as follows;The breeding cage is situated in an off exhibit area which is not accessible tO members of the visiting public. The breeding cage measures 2.93 m. (10 ft.) in length, 1.00 m. (3 ft.) in width and 2.36 m. (8 ft.) in height. One end of the cage is covered and has solid walls, while the middle and far end of the cage is of a more open wire framework design. The birds do have visibility into the adjoining cages, but the pair of 0.g.amabilis in question are not housed within visibility distance of other Op op sitt a pairs.The same dietary mixture is fed to the adult pair twice a day throughout the year, once early in the morning and again during the middle of the afternoon. A main dish provides a mixture of various chopped fruits and vegetables, alfalfa, palm fruits and fresh figs. A second dish contains a commercial dietary pellet, a mixture of small dry millet, niger and canary seeds, a canine pellet, a special supplement cake which is made at Loro Parque and live food in the form of meal worms. Throughout the year the diet is supplemented with a general vitamin/mineral powder, plus a small amount of additional Vitamin K in powder form. When the time is approaching for chicks to hatch then the diet is supplemented daily with Lact ob acillu s in powder form sprinkled over the food, which is continued until the chicks have fledged. I have now used similar dietary guide lines to these to successfully rear both species of Opopsit t« and all three species of Psittacul iros- iris in captivity.A choice of three different nesting sites was provided within the cage. A small conventional shaped nest box, an Lshaped nest box, and a third nest made from a hollowed section of palm log. In this case, the pair selected the conventional style nest box which measured 30 cm. (12 in.) in height and 15 cm. (6 in.) in bothwidth and length. The entrance hole had a diameter of 5.5 cm. (2 in.). This nest box is situated in the more secluded end of the cage, while the palm log and the Lshaped nest box were located at the opposite end of the cage which is more exposed. Wood shavings are used exclusively to provide a nesting medium within the nest box.On 23 February 1994, the nest box was inspected and was found to contain two eggs. These eggs were incubated for the full term by the parent birds and were not unduly disturbed for inspection until they had become overdue, on the removal of the eggs from the nest box they were examined and found to be infertile.The next breeding attempt followed in April when the female again began brooding and the nest box was inspected and was found to contain an egg on 18 April. Two eggs were laid in this clutch which were incubated without any cause for concern in the behaviour of the adult pair. Care was taken during this time to keep any disturbance of the cage to a minimum. On 12 May one chick hatched, the second egg failed to hatch and was removed from the nest box.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/997</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 1 (1996): JAN-FEB 1996; 61-65</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/997/977</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
