<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3139</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-12-31T16:02:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Conservation efforts of Nido Adoptivo</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rickman, Laney S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">With an eye on expanding its Saving he Blues™ domestic conservation efforts in situ, Bird Endowment developed and initiated in 2007 an original annual funding project in collaboration with the Armonia/Loro Parque Fundaci6n Blue-throated Macaw (Ara glaucogularis) Conservation Program in Bolivia.Named Nido Adoptivo™, the exclusive nest site supplementation project enables domestic aviculturists and bird lovers to participate in in situ conservation. In recognition, each donor is honored as an El Beni-Factor™ during the period of their participation.IntroductionThe critically endangered Blue-throated Macaw is native to only one place on Earth: the Beni Savannas of Bolivia. This complex ecosystem of grasslands, marshes, forest islands and gallery forest was, until recently, almost entirely in the hands of cattle ranchers. As a result, untold habitat is degraded every year through intentional burning for pastureland.It is one of the most threatened bird species in the world (BirdLife International 2007). Armonia's Blue-throated Program coordinator Mauricio Herrera reports that more than 30 separate nesting sites have now been located, with an estimated population of 300-350 Blue-throated Macaws.It is believed that one of the principal factors affecting the population size of this species is the lack of available nest sites and the inter-species competition with the more common and abundant Blue and Gold Macaw (Ara ararauna) that shares the same ecological niche.In 2005 the Asociaci6n Armonia/Loro Parque Fundaci6n Blue-throated Macaw Conservation Program experimented and placed 20 artificial nests in the southern zone of the species distribution. These studies demonstrated a lack of cavities in trees and palms in the Llanos de Moxos habitat could be a limiting factor in the reproduction of many species of birds including the Blue-throated Macaw.The following year, Bird Endowment introduced the "Nido Adoptivo" project for adoption of artificial nests. Armonia agreed to provide certain services to Nido Adoptivo for each $250 donation from Bird Endowment. This includes construction and placement of a nest box with donor initials on it, regular visits by field biologists, along with two reports per season (this legalese makes the donation to the 50l(c)3 Bird Endowment taxdeductible with IRS in the United States).Design of the nestsThe design of the model for the nests was taken from information obtained in the field of a successful natural nest, found in a hollow of a palm where two chicks were hatched and raised. Several aspects were taken into consideration such as latitudinal location, suitable depth-both vertical and horizontal-entrance shape and diameter, etc.The artificial nest consists of a rectangular box 1 m x 30 cm, with an entrance hole 12 cm in diameter, or 12 x 25 cm in other cases. On one side of the box there is a small inspection door to facilitate the monitoring of the reproductive process.The nests are constructed with the wood of Palo Maria ( Calophyllum brasiliense) and Ocho6 (Hura crepitans) and are placed at a height of 5 m above ground. The majority of them have been situated in Total palm trees (Acrocomia aculeata) in areas where Bluethroated Macaws have been seen frequently. The Palo Maria wood is more difficult for them to destroy and for that reason we have chosen to use this material.Monitoring the artificial nests occurs along with that of natural nests. Nest box inspections occur every 15 days. Data is collected in a predetermined schedule.Results of first year...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3139</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 36 No. 4 (2009): Number 4  2009; 37-41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3139/3123</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
