<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3097</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-18T09:38:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Vet's Corner, Parasitic Diseases</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cooper, Ralph</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">CONTROL OF IMPORTANT PARASITIC DISEASES OF BIRDS In six separate cases today, I found air sac mites in some Lady Gouldian Finches, gizzard worms in a Shaftail Finch, gizzard worms again in a Cordon Bleu, and roundworms, coccidiosis, malaria, and trichomoniasis in three separate flocks of pigeons. This may serve to dramatize the fact that parasitic diseases must be controlled in your flock if you wish to have healthy birds and good performance-For the purpose of this discussion, I would like to list some of the more important parasitic diseases according to the following convenient format.I. Protozoa, the lowest division of the animal kingdom, consisting of one celled animals.A. Having flagella, by which to move.1. Trichomoniasis, seen in many species including pigeons, finches, etc.2. Hexamitiasis, seen in some game birds and budgies.3. Histomoniasos, seen in turkeys and other game birds.4. Giardiasis, rare but seen in budgies and a few other birds.B. Sporozoa, having no locomotor organs in the adult stage and reproducing by sporulation.1. Coccidiosis, found in most spec-· ies.2. Malaria.a. True malaria due to Plasmodium sp., in many domestic and wild birds.b. Pigeon malaria, due to Hemoproteus sp., in pigeons, doves, and quail.II. Helminths, intestinal worms or other wormlike parasites.A. Flukes, trematodes, usually flat and leaf shaped with suckers.B. Tapeworms, cestodes, flattened, tapelike, and composed of separate segments.C. Roundworms, nematodes, usually relatively long and thin, such as the ascarid.III. Arthropods, articulated animals such as ticks and lice.A. Ticks and mites, arachnids, flattened bodies with four pairs of legs.B. Mosquitoes, flies, and lice, insects, having three pairs of legs.HOW TO A VOID PROBLEMSI. Start with clean, healthy birds.A. Try to buy only from clean flocks.B. Always isolate the new bird for at least one month.C. Have the bird examined for parasites by an experienced veterinarian.II. Start with a clean, adequate environment.A. Provide adequate nutrition.B. Minimize stresses.C. Many parasites are transmitted through the droppings. Minimize the opportunity for contamination of feed and water.D. Certain parasites require insects for their spread. Eliminate those insects if at all possible.HOW TO SOLVE PROBLEMSI. Identify the cause as soon as possible.A. Find a veterinarian who is willing to help you before trouble strikes.B. A well trained layman can identify certain parasites with confidence.II. Treat the disease with the most effective drugs which are available.III. Sanitize or modify the environment to minimize the chance of recurrence.IV. Certain diseases are best controlled byperiodic, preventive treatment.HOW TO DEAL WITH THE MOST COMMON PARASITIC DISEASESI. Protozoa A. Trichomoniasis is spread from bird to bird during feeding or through contaminated feed or water. It causes heavy losses among pigeons and finches and less frequently among hudgies and other birds. It is most dangerous to the young and may cause gasping or diarrhea before death. Microscopic examination of material from the digestive tract is necessary for diagnosis. It may be controlled by the use of one level teaspoonful of Emtryl per gallon of drinking water for a period of five or six days. Strawberry Finches don't seem to tolerate Emtryl for more than four days in a row. The drug Flagyl may be substituted for Emtryl at a dosage of 250 mg. per gallon for five days. It is said to be only about half as hazardous. Certain treated individuals may remain as carriers. Some flocks may require preventive treatment just before each breeding season.B. Coccidiosis is found in many species of birds and may cause heavy losses or remain unnoticed according to the species involved. It is spread through the droppings. A microscopic examination of the droppings will usually reveal the presence of the eggs or oocysts of the organism. In some cases of acute losses, the oocysts may not appear in the droppings and examinations of scrappings from the intestine of a dead bird may be needed. Of the readily available drugs, Vetasulid offers some advantages over the other sulfas. It may be given at the rate of 'l4 teaspoonful per gallon of water for a period of five days. Other sulfa drugs are usually safe and effective when given according to the directions for chickens.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3097</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 6 (1977): DEC 1977- JAN 1978; 26-29 + 38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3097/3081</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
