<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/804</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Cockatiel Connection Establishing a Cockatiel Aviary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The cockatiel has long been a favor- 1 i;e pet, exhibition, and aviary bird,frequently reproducing when other psittacineswill not. Generally hardy in aviarylife, cockatiels come in an ever-growingnumber of both subtle and eye-catchingcolor mutations, and handfed young canmake ideal pets.Generally sweet and docile, cockatielsshould never be housed with larger, ormore aggressive birds, since they seldomadequately defend themselves. Evensmaller, more quarrelsome species suchas budgies, some varieties oflovebirds andcertain finches, especially in mated pairsor flocks, should be maintained separatelyfrom cockatiels. Such species, andother larger birds, could effectively monopolizefeed and water dishes,preventing the less assertive cockatielfrom obtaining adequate nutrition.Should the cockatiel find itself forcedfurther down the established peckingorder by other species, and increasinglydenied adequate food and water, suchcontinuous abuse could lead to malnutrition,dehydration, and a lessening ofresistance to disease. Additionally, theconstant stress from fighting over territorywithin a pen or aviary could imposefurther stress-related disease, in additionto the more obvious risk of injury, andeven death. Although the major factorin such situations is usually the height,and especially the length of the flight,providing enough space for cockatiels toescape bothersome individuals, even themost spacious of aviaries may not be adequateto deter known, or suspected,aggressors.Housing Small CollectionsGenerally, most fanciers precede theirlarger collections with the acquisition ofeither a few pets, or pairs of cockatiels,kept in cages. This may be sufficient fora period of time until the numbers beginto grow, which is not difficult toachieve if one is captivated by the varietyof color mutations, or should one begin to successfully raise a few clutches ofyoung.Standard cockatiel cages are quite suitablefor one or two pet birds who areroutinely allowed out of cages for dailyexercise to enhance their chances of livinga full life span. Of prime importanceis to secure cages equipped with cockatielbar-spacing, which will prevent acockatiel from forcing its head betweenthe vertical bars to become trapped, oftenwith devastating consequencesranging from injury to death. The slightlycloser bar-spacing on specially designedcockatiel cages prevents such tragedies.Additionally, an increased number ofhorizontal bars positioned along the verticalbars will allow a cockatiel to climband effectively gain a secure foothold,again preventing fatal accidents.The removal of the bottom grid, positionedjust above the tray, will alsoeliminate worry over whether an inquisitivecockatiel may lodge its head betweenthe grid spacing, as it retrieves items fromthe cage bottom, or even catch an openleg band on the grid, both of which havebeen known to happen. In general, brass,chrome, or similar materials which allowfor adequate disinfecting practices shouldbe sought out. Some plastics might bedifficult to sterilize in hot temperatures,while older, painted cages could containtoxic lead paint, which can prove fatal ifswallowed. Utmost consideration shouldbe given to cages with more length, andnot just height, since cockatiels fly backand forth, not up and down; and withenough space to allow each bird to comfortablystretch its wings and movearound.AviariesOnce population starts to increase,large caging will become necessary. Thereare now a number of excellent manufacturerswho offer modern, easy to assembleenclosures, requiring simple maintenanceand upkeep. Many are on casters and canbe wheeled effortlessly to any location,and may be dismantled and reassembled should the need arise. Such pens may bestackable, or come in double or triplesupporting frames, for fanciers with evergrowingcollections. Custom cut doors,or self-cut side openings for nest boxes,may be easily accomplished with attentionto blunting any jagged edges to thenewly cut wire.Another option is to build your ownaviaries using clean, welded wire, or othersafe materials. It is not unusual for breederswho have been raising birds for manyyears to go through a metamorphosiswhen designing their aviaries. The authorevolved through many changesbeginning with large, 11' long, walk-inflights, composed of l/2"x1/2" weldedwire mounted on wooden frames. Eventually,6' long aviaries were installed,suspended off the floor by sturdy twelvegauge wire legs, with custom cut doorscreated for ease in servicing flights. Inrecent years, walk-in flights by CornersLimited were installed, which were alsochosen for their ease in maintenance, servicing,and disinfecting, since allmaterials are nonporous.As the cockatiel is a swift, strong flyer,it must be given adequate room to exerciseand maintain general good healthand condition. Therefore, as much spaceas possible should be afforded to pairs,especially to promote a lengthy, reproductivelife. Due to their flying ability,emphasis should be placed on both thelength, and height, of flights. While thedepth of a flight need only be a minimumof 8', it is recommended to raiseflights to at least 6' to 8' to help buildchest muscle when birds fly upward, andperhaps 10' to 20' in length, if space isavailable. Although the author has keptcockatiels in pens only 6' long for thelast several years, it has not appeared tobe a deterrent to reproductive life, however,the birds would no doubt be happierin larger accommodations.Materials should be selected carefully,with good disinfecting tactics kept inmind. For example, the author's originalwood-framed, wire aviaries were eventually torn out in favor of all-wire andaluminum construction, as wood, beingporous, could potentially harbor harmfulbacterias, etc. Additionally, white pinechips used over the years were abandonedin favor of thoroughly dried, uncolorednewspaper, merely for easy of use andincreased frequency in cleaning measures.Certainly other materials such as cedarchips, the newer crushed walnut shells,or corn cob bedding can be used to lineaviaries, however, the latter material mustremain dry and free from moisture.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/804</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 26-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/804/786</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
