<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4083</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:20:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Two Women, Two Continents, One Mission: Saving Super Hero Raptors</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Darden, Jennifer</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 2 (April 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Two Different Women Implement Two Distinct Strategiesby Jennifer Darden Pet Bird Association of VirginiaHelen Dishaw, Curator of Bird Programs Tracy Aviary at Liberty Park, Salt Lake City, UtahTime to take the condor for a walk is not something that most people have ever heard. But for Helen Dishaw, Curator of Bird Programs with Tracy Aviary at Liberty Park in Salt Lake Citypublic garden, and leader in environmental education with their conservation science program. It’s home to over 400 birds and features daily shows, exhibits, feedings, keeper and free flight flying demonstrations.“The only thing older than Andy here are the trees,” says Helen. About 12 years ago, she noticed that Andy seemed laid back and comfortable with people. At the time, he lived on exhibit and received basic care. But Helen saw potential for this four-foot tall, 22-pound condor, with an 11 foot wing span, to live a bigger life. Beginning that September, she baby-stepped him out on walks with her, then graduated to meet and greet with board members, at times when the aviary was closed to the public. By November, he began meeting his adoring public and is comfortable being within a few feet of visitors. Andy Condor had found his calling and Tracy Aviary had a new ambassador with a very important job; to engage with park guests and educate them about vultures in an entertaining way. Andy’s accomplices in this endeavor include, two black and two turkey vultures.Continued on page 6 Special thanks to Helen Dishaw at Tracy Aviary in Salt Lake City, UT, for the wonderful pictures. Additional pictures and information about Tracy Aviary and VulPro can be found in the April digital issue of Watchbird ,Afternoon stroll with Andy, the 64 year old Andean condorClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-04-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4083</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 2 (2023): Watchbird April 2023; 4-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4083/4043</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
