<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/535</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cryogenic Preservation of Budgerigar Semen</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hargrove, Tim</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Popularity of pet birds has increasedtremendously in recent years,resulting in the importation of largenumbers of birds, especially psittacines.During this same time period,there has been an unprecedentedincrease in the rate of habitat destructionin the tropics. The combinationof these two factors has caused adecrease in the number of individualsin many wild psittacine populations.It would be very beneficial to findways of increasing the productivity ofcaptive birds and, simultanec usly,increase their genetic diversity. Cryogenicsemen preservation is one wayof achieving these goals. A frozen sperm bank could ensure the maintenanceof a large degree of geneticdiversity, should individuals be lost,and it is cheaper than maintaininglarge, captive populations. A spermbank would also decrease the need toimport large numbers of individualsand thus aid in maintaining wildpopulations. A few individuals couldoccasionally be captured to supply" new blood" to the captive flock or,if possible, semen samples could becollected from individuals in the wildinstead of importing the birds.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/535</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 40-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/535/519</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
