<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4030</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Rainbow of Quaker Parakeets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nelson, Bob</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 2 (April/May 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.In 1971, I was offered a pair of green, &amp;quot;wild -type&amp;quot; Quaker Parakeets that had &amp;quot;paired off&amp;quot; in a group cage in a pet store.... The store owner said that based on the behavior she had observed, they were obviously a true pair. (we didn&amp;#x27;t have the sexing techniques available back then that we have today!). She offered the pair to me in trade for 2 hand -fed baby Cockatiels (wholesale value $15. each) She thought tame Quakers would make delightful pet birds, and agreed to buy any I could raise.The pair quickly settled into their new surroundings in a small flight in a Lovebird aviary, and started nesting in a few short weeks! That first clutch of 5 fat babies was removed for hand feeding at about 2 weeks of age... and the &amp;quot;love affair&amp;quot; with Quakers began! They would bob and gyrate, and make cute little &amp;quot;chuckling&amp;quot; sounds, quite unlike the noisy demands of the other psittacine babies in my large collection.... With that experience, I soon added more Quakers to the flock.In 1989 we acquired 2 pairs of the Blue mutations from the late Tom Ireland of Florida. The birds were small in size, and Tom said they had not been particularly good breeders. Those birds were separated and paired with strong wildtype (actually wild caught) green birds to produce nice large splits. We could then pair the unrelated splits to produce large viable Blue mutation birds.In 1993, we were able to import some &amp;quot;Cinnamon&amp;quot; stock from Belgium before the Wild Bird Conservation Act restrictions were implemented. Thanks to Jim Chou, and his expertise in dealing with Government officials!Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4030</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 2 (2024): Watchbird April/May 2024; 24-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4030/3990</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
