<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/380</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:18:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Handrearing Palm Cockatoos</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sheppard, Christine</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Turner, Mendy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The palm cockatoo (Probosciger aterrimus) is a large, black parrot found primarily in New Guinea. Its range extends into parts of Indonesia and Australia (Forshaw, 1978). Named for its fondness for palm fruits, the species is notable for its beak, larger, both absolutely and proportionately, than that of any other parrot. The beak allows consumption of hard shelled nuts in addition to fruits and seeds. However, although very little data exist, it does not appear that palm cockatoo diets differ significantly from those of species with less formidable bills. The forces leading to the evolution of the beak are, therefore, not known. The species has been recorded in captivity, although rarely, since early in this century. Although captive pairs have laid eggs, they were generally reported to have deserted or destroyed them. Successful breeding has not been common and until recently handrearing has been entirely unsuccessful (Young, 1986). Smith (1985) reported the first successful handrearing in England, which occurred in 1984. In 1986, two palm cockatoos were hatched and handreared by the New York Zoological Park. A bird hatched at Paradise Park, Honolulu, was also successfully handreared by Joyce Ferguson. A chick from a pair in Denton, Texas was handreared by Rosalie Snell and an additional chick was reported in Miami. Development of replicable handrearing techniques for this species is important. Like most psittacines, the palm cockatoo is threatened by trapping for the pet industry and by habitat destruction. The palm cockatoo has been selected for long term propagation and management by AAZPA and a significant number of these birds have been registered in the studbook. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/380</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 2 (1988): APR-MAY 1988; 44-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/380/367</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
