<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1300</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:34:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">the Enjoyment of   Breeding Cockatiels</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nichols, Janet</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he world of reproducing Cockatiels is many years old and with the new mutation additions within the past few years, it is even more exciting. Being a hobby breeder does not mean that I cannot develop good cross mutations or large birds; in fact it enhances the chances for improving ~ any Cockatiel mutation or individual ~ line of birds. This is because with an ~ average of a dozen pairs of Cockatiels, i- I can spend the time that is needed to ~ develop good birds. I can purchase a very good stock from other great breeders or keep back the top birds from my own breeding stock. Aviary Building and Cages I live in a temperate climate on the central coast of California and have avocado trees on the property. With avocado trees around, one knows that there will seldom be a hard freeze. My Cockatiel breeders can, therefore, be housed outdoors in an open-sided building with canvas tarps that snap down in case of heavy wind. This building has a covered roof. Within the building cages are set up for individual pairs of birds. The Cockatiel cages measure 3 feet long by 18 inches wide and 2 feet high. I cagebreed my Cockatiels this way to control the breeding and reproduce the mutations I wish. All birds are banded and meticulous records are kept on each bird. The most important thing for me is to develop good size and excellent conformation. Non-discriminate breeding only delays a good Cockatiel program. Nest Boxes A 12 inch cube wooden nest box is hung on the front of each cage over the feeding station. The nesting material is made up of thick chunky pine shavings, which is good for chewing. These are much better than the fine curly type, as it packs much better. in the bottom of the nest box and is similar to what would be found in the wild. The curly type has a habit of being fluffy and when there are large clutches of babies, the smaller ones tend to get lost in it. The parents often will not dig out the smallest or last baby to hatch because it is so buried in it. Besides, the curly type is often very dusty with fine particles of wood slivers that may get in the babies' eyes or mouth. The common-walled Cockatiel cages I use are constructed so they are side by side with out a divider or solid partition. The cages form a long row with common auto misters, waterers and perches. Even though I have seen other breeders use double wire between the pairs, I see no problem using the single wire for 'tiels. Feeding Station The feeding station, comprised of a zerk feeder for grains and one combination sprout/veggie dish, is situated in front of the cage for easy access. The food station is built out (boot style) and under the nest box so no fecal matter can drop into the food. There is a pull-out feature for ease of serving. No perch is placed directly over these dishes. Either the front perch is hung just back of the food and water dishes or I place a natural perch at an angle where one end is fastened into the corner of the cage where the nest box is hung. The feed and water dishes are placed away from this corner. The parent bird can easily enter the nest box by walking along the perch to the corner, which is very close to the opening of the nest box. The automatic watering system and misters are located at the opposite ends of each cage. Diet My diet is made up of a good grade of Cockatiel mix and whole grains to which is added additional canary, black sunflower and corn in the winter for carbohydrates. I believe in sprouted seeds and beans for Cockatiels so I use the best that I can find. The sprouting product I use is purchased from China Prairie (Fred Bauer) and is very fresh, clean and organic. To this I add seasonal vegetables. When there are babies in the nest, whole wheat grain bread is also added. A vitamin supplement C'Fresh Addition" from China Prairie) is added to all the soft food. I supply cuttlebone and a mineral block to all the birds. There are times when the consumption of cuttlebone is enormous and I always make it and powdered calcium available. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1300</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 2 (1999): MARCH-APRIL 1999; 28-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1300/1279</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
