<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/811</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Spix's Recovery Meetingto .be Heldat Loro ParqueThe Vice-president of the CPRAA Spix's Macaw Recovet·yCommittee in Brazil, Dr. M!!_ lolita Bampi, has recentlyconfirmed that the Sixth Official Meeting of the Committeewill be held at Loro Parque during the Third InternationalParrot Convention from 14-17 September 1994.All the committee members are in agreement with thisdecision and Loro Parque is delighted that so many prominentfigures in aviculture will be congregating in Puerto de Ia Cruz,Tenerife for this extremely important double-event. RepresentingIBAMA (the Brazilian Institute for the Protection of theEnvironment and Natural Resources), apart from Dr. Bampi,will be Marcos de Re, the biologist who has been carrying outfield work in the area of the last remaining wild Spix and PauloAntas who will be informing on the Reintroduction Project.Obviously this is yet another plus for the Loro Pat·queFoundation which, to date, has donated the sum of U.S.$123,000 towards this project, with more commitments beingconsidered for 1994. The Foundation will be playing animportant role at the Convention and with the sale of souveniritems such as T-shitis, posters, pins, stickers, etc. from ourFoundation "Eco-Shop" and with the auction of an originalpainting by Eric Peake of the Spix's Macaw with Young,amongst others, we hope to be able to again raise aconsiderable amount for parrot conservation projects.Speaker Highlight - EEP's for ParrotsYet another exciting addition to the Speaker Programme ofthe Third International Parrot Convention is that of the Chair ofthe EEP Parrot TAG, Dr. Roger Wilkinson and Drs. KoenBrouwer of the EEP Executive Office in Amsterdam who willbe co-authoring a paper entitled "European E~dangeredSpecies Programmes for Parrots." Once again, this is a uniquechance for European aviculturists to make contact with suchextremely prominent people in the parrot world.Convention RegistrationThe response to the Convention so far has been tremendous.There are already 220 participants from Germany; Italy hasfilled their allotment and requires more places; and the U.K.,Switzerland, Belgium, Austria and Scandinavia are all doingextremely well. Even from as far afield as Australia we havetaken 25 registrations not to mention the five Japaneseparticipants!The majority of the delegates who have already registeredparticipated at the second convention in 1990 and some even atthe first one in 1986. This is certainly "a feather in LoroParque's cap" as regards the success of their conventions andthe reason why the limited amount of spaces will soon all befilled.For more infom1ation contact Loro Parque, Parque SubtropicalEspecializado en Papagayos, Puerto de Ia Cruz (Tenerife),Spain; phone (34- 22) 37 38 41-37 40 81 or Fax 38 73 21. •Creation of a National Parkfor the EndangeredBahama Parrotby Rosemarie GnamAlexandria, VirginiaI am pleased to inform you that the Prime Minister of theBahamas, Hubert Ingraham, has declared the creation of anational park on southern Abaco for the endangered BahamaParrot. I know many of you will share my joy today.When I began my research project into the breeding biologyof this parrot on Abaco in 1985, the overall objective of thisproject was "to develop a sound biological understanding ofthis parrot upon which a conservation program could bebased." In 1985, this park was a dream and today it is a reality.I thank all of you who played a role in this research project.My field assistants worked enthusiastically to collect data thathelped to conserve this parrot. In addition, this project wouldnot have been possible without the many persons whosupported this project and conservation efforts for the parrot. Aspecial note of thanks to the organizations who financiallysupported this project. Their members share in our joy today.Last, I applaud the Bahama Parrot Education Committee, theBahamas National Trust, and the Rare Center for TropicalConservation for their efforts to increase conservation awarenessfor this parrot's plight and their educational campaign inthe Bahamas which they started in 1992. Their diligent effortshave helped achieve the desired result - a national park onAbaco.With most of the Bahama Parrot's nesting habitat nowprotected on Abaco, attention can be focused on the managementof this parrot population and plans for its recoveryimplemented. The future looks brighter for one of the world'sendangered parrots. More importantly, this development demonstratesthat parrot conservation can succeed in the wild! Toooften, we give up hope. So, for today, let us congratulate theBahamas and celebrate with them!•</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/811</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/811/793</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
