<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1892</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-22T04:15:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Presentation to American Pigeon Fanciers' Council</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baer, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I thank the Council so much for inviting me to speak to you on behalf of the American Federation of Aviculture, of which I am President and to tell you why I am so enthusiastic in promoting its cause.Let me state that I feel somewhat at a disadvantage talking with you because I am a stranger to all of you and I am not a pigeon fancier. But, I am a bird breeder - and, to me, there is a common bond between all bird breeders.As a stranger, let me establish my seriousness of purpose through the logic of a few questions which you may each ask of yourselves: First, ''Why has this man taken of his time and expense to come to St. Louis to talk with us?" "Has he anything personally to gain?"I am a retired veterinarian, a hobbyist who enjoys his birds. If I had to gain a livelihood from my aviary, I can assure you, I would have been bankrupt the first year. I have nothing to sell. Why then am I here? I am here because I want our children and our children's children to enjoy birds in their day just as you and I enjoy ours in our day. I believe in the right of everyone to have any kind of legal bird he chooses and I am convinced that the American Federation of A viculture is the strongest organization we have today to protect that right.What is the American Federation of Aviculture? First, let me tell you what A.F.A. is not: It is not an association nor a club. It is not dominated by any one group or clique. The dictionary defines FEDERATION as a union or league. The A.F.A. is a union of some seventy avicultural organizations, associations, and clubs, plus thousands of independent members. This league of some seventy affiliates, together with its many thousand independent members, consists of fanciers who vary from canary breeders to game bird breeders; they range from owners of a single bird to owners of hundreds; and include commercial establishments and zoological gardens.The Federation is a non-profit organization. It is governed by delegate representation from each of its affiliates and only they decide on actions and policies. Majority rules. All Board meetings are open to the general membership.The A.F.A. is dedicated to the conservation of bird wildlife through encouragement of captive breeding programs, scientific research, and education of the general public. In the pursuit of the conservation of birds through captive breeding, A.F.A. has been in the forefront in the protection of our bird populations. It actively defends the rights of all of us to own and keep any birds of our choosing within the limits of the law.Exotic animals, including birds imported into this country, have not always been properly cared for, either in shipment or at their final destination. Some domestically bred birds and household pets have also lacked proper treatment either through ignorance or neglect. Legislation has been proposed by conservationists, ecology groups, humane societies and legislators, who feel there is a need for laws to protect wildlife and domestic stock. The A.F.A. recognizes those needs and disagrees only with poorly written or discriminatory legislation. This it actively opposes. The A.F.A. is against any regulations or unjust zoning laws that would take away or limit our right to own, breed, and enjoy birds.The Federation has a code of ethics in which it explicitly states its policy against those who would violate Federal and State laws or be inhumane in the treatment of birds. It is the official policy of the A.F.A., as stated in its code of ethics, to disqualify or expel from membership or ban from advertising in its publication, THE WATCHBIRD, any applicant, member, or advertiser, who has been convicted of violation of any Federal or State law concerning the importation, interstate shipment, possession or inhumane treatment of any avian species. Our organization does not hesitate to impose its censures for violoations of its code of ethics.Your publicity director, in a recent letter to me, described A.P.F.C.'s function as a kind of "umbrella" for the benefit of all kinds of pigeon people. The A.F.A. endeavors to serve as an even larger "umbrella" to serve the interests and defend the rights of all ethical and legal bird keepers. The successful defense of these rights requires the active cooperation of all of us bird keepers. It has been alleged that AF.A. does not serve all bird interests; that it is orientated towards the cage and exotic bird breeder. Let me correct this allegation by acknowledging that the Federation does receive its greatest support at this time from the cage and exotic bird breeder, but its intent and orientation still is towards involvement of all aviculturists.At one time A.P.F.C. was an affiliate of AF.A., but, unfortunately, during its entire affiliation it sent a delegate to only one or two meetings and did not par - ticipate in any AF.A activities. Now, we, as bird breeders, all know that it is the chick that peeps the loudest that gets its crop filled. So it is in all organizations. If one does not take an active part and voice his problems, he is not likely to receive attention. The A.F.A. resolutely seeks allies among other avicultural groups. However, if such allies affiliate and do not take part, the affiliation is ineffectual and benefits neither the Federation nor the affiliate.What are the accomplishments of AF.A.?At this point in time we are finalizing litigation against U.S.D.A. which has cost us $40,000.00. We are securing an out-ofcourt settlement of the dispute and obtaining a Newcastle disease policy, in writing, which guarantees and protects the rights of every bird breeder in the country in the event of any future outbreak of V. V .N .D. This includes the pigeon breeder. How many individual organizations can afford to spend $40,000.00 in government litigation?From the Interior Department we are effecting the deregulation of captive-bred self-sustaining populations of endangered species. Cost to AF.A.: Over $6,000.00 in legal fees. The beneficiaries of this deregulation are the exotic and game bird breeders.This past year we prevented U.S. Public Health Services from imposing a ban on the importation of psittacines. This saved the day for the psittacine breeder and the pet industry.We, again, came to the aid of industry just recently in a successful, forceful, mailgram campaign to get the quarantine stations reopened. Industry graciously acknowledged AF.A's impact in this instance in an article on the front page of THE PET BUSINESS, June 1979 issue.Through the efforts of myself as President of AF.A., a sub-committee on birds was established by the United States Animal Health Association - an achievement that must benefit all bird breeders. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-10-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1892</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 6 (1979): DEC-JAN 1979; 11-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1892/1863</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
