<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1201</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Mutations of the Indian Ring-necked Parakeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bastiaan, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">{Editor's Note: We are delighted with tbe contributions (both artide and photographs) receiied from jack Bastiaan. Since there is considerable confusion about the nomenclature of mutation colors mid their combinations. we bate included some explanations to some of the color combinations i11 this article. We are breaking uetu ground with some of the new color combinations so some may be difficult to understand. 771e European and American conoenuon often do not match with respect to which color comes first. We are not intending to be the authority but only wish to enhance the understa nding of our readers. All italics in the srnallerprint size are the editor's and not tbe author's. Bastiaan 's book Ringnecked Parakeets and Their Mutations can be ordered from A VIAN PUBUCA 770NS phone/fax (USA) 1-800-577-B!RD (2473), (outside USA) Z-612-571-8902. DR7JI first became a breeder of Indian Ring-necked Parakeets (Psittacula lerameri) in 1979 as this was when I became fascinated with this species and its mutations. I started my collection with two pairs of lutino Ringnecks. After reproducing from these two pairs of birds I later exchanged their youngsters for a goldenolive [cinnamon-graygreein hen. I then clecided to breed this hen with a normal green male and with this mating I received two grey-green youngsters. I traded these two grey-green birds for an albino Indian Ringneck.Trading out- your youngsters to upgrade your mutation stock is a sound way to increase your flock without putting out a lot of money, thus lightening the immediate financial burden for the beginning aviculturist.In 1985 I received my first turquoiseblue lt1mp1oisel cock bird that was split to lutino. When I mated this bird with an albino (from the mating of a turquoiseblue and a crerne-ino) I received very good results. From these birds I have received all of the different colors I have produced to this date-45 different mutations.At the present time, I have the series: cinnamon (sex-linked), greencinnamon iaomtnant ci111za11101zl (recessive), yellow-headed cinnamon, lacewing, yellow-headed (recessive red-eyed), yellowheaded-yellow-tailed, fallow, cobalt, opaline, green-overlayed yellow and 14 turquoise mutations. This year I have reproduced the first turquoisecobalt yellowheaded-yellowtailed bird in my aviaries and I am ve1y proud of it. This bird gives me the possibility to produce the whiteheaded-whitetailed cobalt and the creamheaded-whiretailed rurquoisecobalt in the near future.I am satisfied if I can reproduce one new mutation every year as this gives me something to look forward to. I also believe this is the most satisfying feeling a mutation breeder can receive.rt is, however, very important to he responsible when breeding mutations. We must he aware of the problems that we can run into if we are not careful and become confused with the genetics of our mutations. It is extremely important to first know what the inheritance is on every single bird we have in our aviaries-whether it is sex-linked, recessive, dominant or intermediate. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1201</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 5 (1997): SEPT-OCT 1997; 19-20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1201/1180</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
