<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/649</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Illegal Wildlife Tradeand AvicultureI received a telephone calJ one night from an outraged aviculturist.No, he wasn't complaining about something I said nor abird he bought, but rather his excitement was due to an ad in thelocal paper. Toucans were being advertised, at a rock bottomprice, and he was outraged as they were "obviously smuggled:'My advice was, of course, simply don't buy them! When askedwhat can we do to stop the activity, I replied "file a complaintwith the local USFWS law enforcement agent."The fact is, we really don't know how many birds enter theUnited States illegally. I've seen figures everywhere from25,000 to 250,000. Like the drug trade and other contraband, theexact amount entering the U.S. really isn't that important. Thefact is, however, that such activity is a direct threat to our aviculturalactivities.Illegally imported birds not only pose a health threat to yourbirds but are contributing to endangerment of parrots in thewild. The Green-cheeked Amazon (Amazona viridigenalis) is agood case in point. The species has been added to the newlyrevised Red Data Book as in imminent danger of extinction.Every illegal bird that crosses the Rio Grande contributes to itsendangerment. For those who are not concerned for the speciessurvival in the wild, another threat exists. Given that it is difficultto actually observe individuals crossing the border withparrots, the use of'' sting" operations are needed. (See article tofollow). Additionally, state legislation requiring the registeringand regulation of commonly smuggled species is likely on thehorizon. The avicultural community would prefer not to have todeal with either situation. The answer is simple, stop the smuggling.This means a changing of attitudes. AFA has made stepsin this direction through the printing and distribution of an antismugglingposter. Additionally, a short public serviceannouncement has been produced for local television stationsthat suggests you either know the breeder (source) of your birdwell or purchase closed banded (or microchipped) birds. As afinal step, the AFA president, legal counsel and CITES chairhave begun a dialog with the various government and nongovernmentalindividuals with an interest in trade. Thus far, thishas involved not only discussions with USFWS and APHISofficials in Washington D. C. but with local USFWS lawenforcement officials at the border itself.How can you help? First, get the word out that avi culturi stsare ''sick and tired of smuggling and are not going to tolerate itany more" . Do this through sales of the anti-smuggling T-shirt,distribution of the poster and viewing of the PSA on your localstation.Finally, if someone tries to sell you a bargain bird or mentionsthat they have purchased smuggled birds, respond to them thatyou are emphatically opposed to the activity.Self regulation is always preferred to governmental regulation.This is one situation where, as the old Indian proverb goes,"When cobwebs unite, they can tie up a ti ger:· We need to gettogether and change the apathetic tolerance of this activity to ademonstrated, active intolerance. If we don 't, both avicultureand the birds will lose.ForT-sh irts and posters, contact the AFA business office. ThePSA (Public Service Announcement) is available by telephoning1-210-828-5306.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/649</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 47-53</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/649/632</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
