<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3669</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-26T05:20:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Message from the President</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Speed, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Incredibly, forty years ago a small group of individuals met on the courthouse steps and formed an organization they named "The American Federation of Aviculture, Inc." (APA). Their mission may have seemed lofty as we look back in time, but it has allowed us to be where we are today. It was a time for taking action to fight those determined to literally exterminate our birds. And fight they did.Although the face of our adversaries may have changed over the years, the challenges before us are just as monumental, threatening our ability to keep and breed birds. For forty years APA has strived to educate and maintain fair and equitable legislation on your behalf. And, your continued support has been invaluable.Each year APA holds an educational conference in conjunction with our House of Delegates meeting. It is a time of fellowship, networking and learning how to be more proactive in aviculture to meet the challenges which may be very different from those faced at our inception, but just as critical if we hope to have a future with birds.Please be sure to attend this celebration, where we exchange ideas, knowledge and experiences for the betterment of aviculture. And as we recognize those who have carried the torch on our behalf and made avicultural advancements, let's come together and share the unique camaraderie that we all share from our own unique, common interest. We also welcome all the new faces who are eager to learn and become active in AFA's mission.Our conference this year will be held July 30th -August 2nd at the Holiday Inn Portland Airport. The House of Delegates meeting will take place the morning of July 30th and we will visit the Portland Zoo that same afternoon. Thursday, Friday and Saturday will be filled with speakers and other activities that will be educational and entertaining. It all begins Thursday morning with the Keynote Address given by legendary Quaker Parakeet Breeder, Bob Nelson. The Lory League will host a bird show on Saturday and on Sunday we will attend the World Famous Rose Gardens. Be sure to view our website AFAbirds.org to register and for additional information.I'm looking forward to seeing old friends and making new ones as it has been many years since we have gathered in the northwest. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3669</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 3 (2014): Number 3 2014; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3669/3652</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
