<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3325</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-08T20:36:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Bird Shows are Fun and Educational</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Corwin, Julie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">he Lory League hosted the two back-to-back bird exhibition shows this past August in San Antonio, Texas. Triangle Bird Club and Feather-ing Crest Aviary were cosponsors, and supported by the Alamo Exhibition Bird Club.The shows included novice and advanced exhibitor classes as well as a junior class. Both shows were easily accessible to the AFA Convention attendees as the events were in the same area of the Omni Colonnade Hotel. A highlight this year included a surprise visit by "Elmo" at the beginning of the first show.Show programs included a biography for each Judge, and the listing of sponsors for the awards and the show program. The program lists the divisions, sections and classhow the birds are categorized for judging. Information was also included about AFA and its affiliated organizations.Again this year, there were many different species represented in the shows - a rainbow of color and lots of surprises. The exhibition shows are more than just competitions for spectacular birds, they are also educational events. The bird shows offer convention attendees the opportunity to see rare bird species and learn more about these birds and the proper conformation for each.The judges make a point to educate the audience with commentary on how and why they choose certain birds over others. It's a wonderful process that helps both novices and seasoned exhibitors fine-tune their bird training and presentation skills.Those participating in the competition also have the opportunity to learn about and participate in the American Federation of Aviculture's annual conference and network with other enthusiastic aviculturists.The shows follow the mission and purpose of AFA by promoting the advancement of aviculture through educational programs. Kids 16 and younger are allowed to exhibit in the Junior Class for free and are encouraged to participate in the main show as well. This is in keeping with AFA's dedication to the theme of "A Future With Birds."Judges were both SPBE panel judges.Jim Heffernan of Michigan judged the first show and Linda Rubin of Massachusetts judged the second show, which was designated as a double point show.Exhibition judges are trained to look for details when judging the birds:• Conformation-mostly genetics and hereditary factors• Condition-feather quality and overall health.• Deportment (behavior)-training for showing, and a calm demeanor.• Color-especially in mutations, but can relate to diet or environment• Presentation-condition and cleanliness of cage or show boxMany of the exhibitors entering the shows in San Antonio were novice exhibitors and pet owners, so the judging gave them a chance to have their bird evaluated as an example of the species and as compared to other birds showing at that time. Linda Rubin also spent some time discussing the details of how to cage-train for future shows.Exhibitors have the opportunity to earn colorful ribbons and trophies as a testimonial to all the hard work it takes to get, and keep a bird in top condition. There's a lot more to showing than what most people know or understand. It takes a lot of work and patience to get the birds in perfect health, feather and train them to strut their stuff in strange surroundings for the judges. The exhibitors spend a lot of money and time preparing for shows, because they love what they do, and most importantly, they love their birds.Junior Exhibitors earned ribbons, sponsored by AFA4Kidz Medallion Awards sponsored by GinnyHeptig1st Place-Emma Lopez, 11, Lutino Peach Face Lovebird2nd Place-Savanna Lewis, 10, American Yellow Pacific Parrotlet Novice DivisionJudge Jim Heffernan, first showRosettes sponsored by Lory League1. Green Quaker exhibited by Ben Garza2. Iris Lorikeet exhibited by Rick Jordan3. Umbrella Cockatoo exhibited by Vicki Edgerton4. Abyssinian Lovebird exhibited by Scott Stringer S. Umbrella Cockatoo exhibited by Mary Duma6. American Yellow Pacific Parrotlet exhibited bySavanna Lewis7. Green Cheek Conure exhibited by Ben Garza8. Green Quaker exhibited by Jan &amp;amp; Dean Cheney9. Lutino Peach Face Lovebird exhibited by Emma Lopez10. Red Rumped Parakeet exhibited by Ben GarzaTop BenchJudge Jim Heffernan, first show 1st-10th SPBE rosettes sponsored by Mary Wilson1st-3rd Medallion Awards sponsored byJulie Corwin1. Canary Wing Parakeet exhibited by Julia Howard2. Green Quaker exhibited by Ben Garza3. Iris Lorikeet exhibited by Rick Jordan4. Umbrella Cockatoo exhibited by Vicki Edgerton S. Abyssinian Lovebird exhibited by Scott Stringer6. Umbrella Cockatoo exhibited by Mary Duma7. American Yellow Pacific Parrotlet exhibited bySavanna Lewis8. Green Cheek Conure exhibited by Ben Garza9. Green Quaker exhibited by Jan &amp;amp; Dean Cheney10. Lutino Peach Face Lovebird exhibited by Emma LopezBest Novice-Ben Garza, Green Quaker SPBE Best Novice Rosette sponsored by Janet BrubakerSecond show, a double points show Judged by Linda RubinJunior Class winners1st Place-Emma Lopez, 11; Lutino Peach Face Lovebird.2nd Place-Savanna Lewis, 10; American Yellow Pacific ParrotletEngraved trophies sponsored by Lory League were presented to the winners inthe second show as follows:Youngest Exhibitor-Savanna Lewis, 10 Audience Favorite-Umbrella Cockatoo, Vickie EdgertonMost Rare-Abyssinian Lovebird, Scott Stringer Oldest-13-year-old Umbrella Cockatoo, Mary Duma </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3325</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 39 No. 4 (2012): Number 4 2012; 12-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3325/3309</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
