<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/545</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Showing Budgerigars: breeding with the power birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pilkington, Terry</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pilkington, Clare</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Editor's Note: The following isfrom a presentation given at theAFA convention in San Francisco.Its contents depict the attitude andcharacteristics of what is needed tobe a top winner in showing budgerigars.Terry and Clare Pilkington arecurrent top budgerigar breeders inthe United Kingdom. They startedbreeding budgerigars over 20 yearsago. They won the BudgerigarSociety World Show in 1982. Thisaward is classed as the ultimateachievement on the British Budgerigarscene and the prestige and satisfactiongained is everlasting. Theynot only won the Best in Showaward with a Grey Green BreederCock, but managed to take an additional11 trophies. In 1984, theywon Best Opposite Sex Breeder atthe Budgerigar Society World Showwith a Grey Cock.Breeding with the Power Birds. Tobegin with, what is a " Power Bird"?This is an American expressionwhich is now being used in theUnited Kingdom to describe the sortof budgerigar which is most soughtafter by .the top breeders both hereand abroad. This expression has onlyjust come into our budgerigar"lingo", but I think that the wordsPower Birds really describes what weare trying to get across. Power is abird of great influence which isappealing to the eye. What does thismean? My own interpretation is thatyou are walking between staging atthe show and are looking at theclasses and just glancing at the birds,the "power birds" are the very goodspecimens. They are the birds thatstand out among the others and theymake you stop and look again.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/545</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 3 (1992): JUNE-JULY 1992; 18-21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/545/529</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
