<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4100</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:20:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Legislation 101</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mock, Adrianne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (January 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.by Adrianne Mock AFA Legislative VPIn recent years, animal ownership in general, and exotic animal ownership in particular, has become a primary target of legislative efforts to restrict or completely ban the keeping, breeding or businesses related to animals. Number limits and species (or in the case of dogs, breed limits) restrictions are happening in more and more cities. Outright bans on selling any animals other than those in the possession of so-called “rescues” has been prohibited in many cities, and you may not even own the animal, but are simply “leasing” it from the organization, which may take it back at any time for any reason.As more and more individuals become aware of these legislative efforts, it becomes clear that a few loud extremist organizations are at the heart of the issues. The (misnamed) Humane Society of the United States, which does not run any shelters or humane societies and is NOT a government entity is the primary one, with annual income over 100 MILLION dollars. Yes, you read that right. And, sadly, less than 1 percent of THAT goes to actually helping animals anywhere; instead, it is used to promote and sponsor anti-animal keeping legislation.PeTA (people for the ethical treatment of animals) claims that ANY animal ownership is “slavery” and should be abolished. Other organizations include DxE (Direct Action Everywhere) whose members trespass on farms and other facilities (including those of sanctuary organizations!), taking animals to “save” them but due to lack of any knowledge of true animal welfare, killing them instead.Animal RIGHTS is not the same as animal WELFARE, as some would try to lead you to believe, instead animal rights is an extreme philosophical agenda that considers any animal ownership or “use” as cruelty and to be eliminated. One member of HSUS used the phrase “ until there are none” and this is the end goal. NO animals in human care. Period.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4100</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 1 (2023): Watchbird January 2023; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4100/4060</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
