<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/418</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">How You Can Help Save Dominica's Parrots</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Low, Rosemary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Many bird breeders and aviculturalsocieties have been generous enoughto make donations to the DominicanParrot Project sponsored by ICBP(International Council for Bird Preservation).Since I started to raise fundsfor this project in August 1986 theyand, more recently, zoos in the UK,also Loro Parque in Tenerife, have providedvirtually all the funds for thisurgent conservation programme.The current situation regarding theparrots· of Dominica is, therefore, ofinterest to many. For those who havenot read of the plight of Dominica'sparrots let me briefly outline the situation.Dominica is a mountainousrainforest-covered island in the Caribbeanwhich measures about 29 by 16miles (46 x 25 km). Only in the last 30years has widespread forest clearanceoccurred, mainly for agriculture.It is remarkable that there are twoAmazon parrots endemic to the island,that is, found nowhere else in theworld: the magnificent imperial ( Amazonaimperialis), the largest Amazonin existence, and the red-necked (Amazonaarausiaca). Both species arenow concentrated on the northwesternslopes of Morne Diablotin inthe north of the island.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/418</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 4 (1988): AUG-SEPT 1988; 18-19</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/418/404</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
