<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/931</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Notes on Lory Aggression, Diet and Housing</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Casmier, Sharon R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AggressionHaving read several articles by other authors on colony selection of mates, Sharon Casmier placed three sexed female and three sexed male Goldie's Lorikeets together in a flight 7 ft. long, 6 ft. tall, and 4 ft. wide. This flight contained a number of perches, branches and separate feeding stations. The alpha pair bonded within weeks and their band numbers were recorded. Several days later one male was dead. Upon necropsy no bacteria or viruses were isolated.Days later, a second male was found trapped by his wings in the cage wire. Even when Casmier entered the flight with wire cutters, these budgerigarsized lorikeets continued to dive bomb and strike their victim. Luckily, she was able to save this male and decided to abandon any attempts at colony breeding or colony mate selection in the future.It is critically important to remember that bonded or breeding pairs of lories can and will protect their territory with great vigor.Sam Tucker and Robin Stockton, editors of the "International Loriinae Society Bulletin," recently published an article describing the loss of their Black-capped Lory hen, L.l. erythrothorax, due to aggression by the male.Both birds were handfed, long term pets. The male was six years old and aggressive while the hen was two and a half years old and submissive. The birds had been placed side by side in separate cages for many months. The two birds were then brought into the house and caged together where they could be closely observed. The two had been together for over a month when the male became aggressive towards his owner during routine feeding chores.All seemed to be going well between the two birds although the male continued to be territorial with his keeper. After four months of observation they were moved to their new outdoor flight which was 4 ft. wide, 10 ft. tall, and 8 ft. long. Although all of the above precautions were taken, the female was killed within two hours.Such violence has been reported with other species of lories on numerous occasions A similar situation occurred with a pair of long term bonded Red Lories, E.b. bornea, owned by a local breeder.She purchased these birds as a proven pair and, since they were not banded, it was assumed they were wild caughts. However, this could not be verified.They had been obtained during the winter and caged in the house in a small cage, 3 ft. x 2 ft. x 2 ft., with a small nest box in which they slept together at night. No breeding attempts were made and no pair aggression noticed.In mid-summer they were moved outdoors to a new flight ( 4 ft. x 4 ft x 5 ft.) with a large Z-style nest box attached. Shortly after, the hen was found injured and brought into the house and treated for foot wounds. It was thought she had caught a toenail in the cage wire.While the hen was being treated the male became very aggressive towards his keeper and would strike, drawing blood when the bowls were changed during routine chores. This occurred numerous times making the servicing of his cage a dreaded and unpleasant task.Once the hen had healed she was returned to the outdoor flight. The male was removed to a holding cage which was placed beside her. After several days he was re-introduced to the flight with his mate. A few days later she was found dead in the nest box. Necropsy showed massive trauma to the throat and neck area.We have learned to take several precautions with lories. We observe behavior on a daily basis when servicing our birds. We are particularly concerned about abrupt behavior changes even in long term, proven pairs and are cautions when our lories are subjected to changes in their environment, especially when they are moved to a new flight or when a nest box is added.It is important to understand that lories are easily bored and very excitable. Therefore, breeding birds should be provided with large flights and outside distractions so they can release pent up energy. Toys such as rings, chains, and ropes are very appropriate and lories enjoy them tremendously.Consider age and temperament when introducing potential mates. Always identify the aggressive and submissive individuals. Cage the birds side by side before introducing the submissive bird to the flight. Place the aggressive bird in a small holding cage inside of the larger flight for several weeks. When conditions are right clip the wings of the aggressive bird and release it into the flight. This should be done when time permits close observation. The aggressor should be returned every evening to the small holding cage until the birds appear to be compatible. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/931</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 5 (1995): SEPT-OCT 1995; 37-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/931/912</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
