<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/490</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the European Serin</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kulhavy, Vladimir</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The European serin (Serinusserinus) is one of the most attractivemembers of the serin genus, though iti not commonly encountered in orthAmerican collections. It is the smallestof the European finches , though it isnot the smallest serin. In the wild it isfound both in the countryside and intowns. It ranges over most of Europefrom as far north as Britain, ScandinaviaPoland and the U. S.S.R. and is ayear round resident of southernEurope and north Africa. The serin isthe clo est relative of the wild canary(Serinus canarius) and hybrids of thetwo species are fertile. At one time theywere even considered to be subspeciesof the same species.The European serin measuresapproximately 11 centimeters or 4- 1/2inches in length. It is brownish andgreen in color with heavy striations onthe breast of the hen and to a lesserextent on the male. The birds are obviouslydin10rphic. The male is brightyellow on the breast, head and rumpand the intensity of the yellowincreases just before the onset of thebreeding season. The male is a persistentsongster and I find his song verypleasing to my ear. It is definitely awild bird's song, somewhat resemblinga grey singing finch yet not as clear,reminding me of the song of the Europeanskylark though not as glorious.L. W. Restall, in his book " Finches andOther Seed Eating Birds;' calls the serin"a delightful bird ;' however, he warnsthat the serin requires a careful acclimatizationafter which it ''becomeshardy and ultimately long lived~ '</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/490</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 31-32</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/490/475</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
