<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1934</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-10-31T05:20:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From The Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dear SirRecently, in another avicultural publication ("Bird World") I have seen the flat assertion, "There are no birds endangered as a direct result of the pet trade" reiterat- , ed twice by M.A. Cunningham of the Los Angeles Zoo. I would question this for the Hooded and Golden-shouldered Parakeets (distinct subspecies) and the Red Siskin which are on the endangered species list.The parakeets have historically been quite rare and restricted in range but a marked decline in the numbers of both has become apparent in the years since World War II. While a species decline is often due to multiple factors, I would contend that the prime recognizable reason for the precarious status of these two birds has been trapping (for most of the time illegal) for the bird trade. Both are prized avicultural subjects which command very high prices and intensive trapping for them is well known to have occurred in the last three decades. The Hooded Parakeet has disappeared from parts of its former range and such areas are the most accessible to trappers. Evidence for other causes of decline, i.e. habitat change, competition from other species, etc. is not readily apparent for these birds.The Red Siskin is another species for whose present low numbers it is difficult to implicate reasons other than the well documented intensive trapping to which the species has been subjected for years. It is probable, in fact, that the favored habitat of this bird, shrubby grasslands, has actually increased due to extensive forest clearance within its range. Recent observers have noted very few or no birds in areas where the species was considered quite common over 25 years ago and the blame is put squarely on intensive trapping. In the recently published "Birds of Venezuela", no exact localities for this species are given because, "the bird is much persecuted by birdcatchers due its popularity as a cage-bird.''Apart from the above where entire populations are threatened I would also contend that some species and subspecies, while still perhaps holding their own in parts of their range, have suffered greatlyin other areas due to the depredation of the pet trade. A case in point is the situation of some of the large Central American psittacines.In Central America the main cause of the decline of many bird species is undoubtably habitat (forest) destruction due to the burgeoning human population. However, in many of those areas of still extant suitable habitat where they were previously recorded as common, birds such as the Scarlet Macaw and the Yellownaped and Double Yellow-headed Amazons have disappeared or become very scarce. Ornithologists with extensive field experience of the region to whom I have spoken blame this situation primarily on the large scale taking of the birds for the pet trade and secondarily on pot hunting. It is conceivable that the two Amazons mentioned, which are restricted in range, could become endangered in the near future unless curbs are put on their exploitation for the pet market.L. Clack, Morgantown, W.VA.Inasmuch as your doctorate is in wildlife biology and you spent years in Australia I am persuaded to agree with you. The vast majority of aviculturists, including many professionsals in the zoos, are ignorant of the true status of birds in the wild. Fortunately there is a rising concern among American aviculturists regarding conservation.During the last decade or so bird keepers, whether in the zoos or out, have become much more concerned with building up viable genepools among captive birds. I think we all are beginning to realize that there is not an unlimited supply of rare birds "out there":The A.F.A. is at this moment working on a program to record all the data available on the rare and endangered birds in collections in this country. Mr. Larry Shelton of the Philadelphia zoo is heading the committee and will publish pertinent data as the program unfolds. Our aim is to collect and manage pertinent data that will expedite the breeding of rare and endangered birds so that not one need be lost unnecessarily. Mr. M.A. Cunningham of the Los Angeles zoo is fortunate enough to have several pairs of the rare hooded parakeets in the zoo collection. These birds were confiscated by U.S. Customs when they were smuggled into the States a few years ago. The birds were smuggled in from Australia and may be some of the illegally trapped birds you mentioned.Many thanks for bringing this to our attention.ED.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-10-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1934</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 2 (1980): APRIL-MAY 1980; 42-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1934/1905</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
