<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2857</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-07T21:34:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Raffle 1979</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This year's annual raffle is already shaping up to be the biggest and the best ever. Preliminary donations gathered by our ambitious Chairperson, Judy Hofferman of Virginia, show us an exciting list. Just a few of the already confirmed prizes are: Pair of Albino Cockatiels2 Pieces of custom Sterling Silver Jewelry Pair of Dyhl ThrushesPair of BourkesPair of RosellasPair of Grass Parakeets 100 lbs. Topper Seed Mix Pair of Pearl Cockatiels Home Video Tape Machine Pair of CockatoosPair of AmazonsPair of Game BirdsPair of Cherry Head Lady Goulds Pairs of Mutation Love BirdsAn Albino Peach Face Love Bird Pair of Moustache Parakeets (Prizes may be substituted for items of equal value)Judy tells us that this is only the beginning, many more prizes are to be added.The raffle is always an exciting event at the convention, even more so if you are a winner. Remember you need not be present to win. Tickets will be mailed to members - if you want more tickets contact Judy Hofferman, she is listed in front of the Watchbird under committees.Please remember this is our way of raising funds to help A.F.A. Be a WINNER. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2857</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 2 (1979): APR-MAY 1979; 35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2857/2841</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
