<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2020</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-26T04:45:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From The Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Editor's DeskThe Watchbird staff is interested in compiling a comprehensive list of data regarding captive breeding of birds in the U.S.A. This data is vital to the growth and continued success of American aviculture.It is the responsibility of successful bird breeders to pass their experience and knowledge along to the thousands of devotees of the art that are joining our ranks each year. The number of imported birds has diminished drastically during the past year. The time may well come when our borders wzll be closed completely. In that event, all of our replacement birds will have to come from breeding stock currently in the country. We must improve our techniques and teach those who follow us. We must get all of the birds that we can - now, and put them to work.All of you who have successfully raised birds should report your success to the A.F.A. Breeding Registry and record your techniques for publication.The Watchbird staff has prepared a four page checklist that you can use to write an informative article.You can follow the guidelines set forth and we wzll rewrite your data into a suitable article for the benefi't of our thousands of readers. They may profi: from your experiences and the number of birds bred in the U.S.A. should increase.If you are reluctant to publicize your breeding successes, we wtil print the article anonymously. But we do need the data. I, your humble servant, will kick off this program by publishing an article in the next Watchbird on my wife's success breeding the beautiful Amboina king parrots. And I'll gladly accept the accolades even though she did the work. We are interested in all kinds of birds.If you have raised any birds at all (budgies, cockatiels, zebra finches, and peach-faced lovebirds excepted) please send to our new home office for the Watchbird Breeding Checklist, address:A.F.A. Home Office 2208 ''A'' Artesia Blvd. P. 0. Box 1568Redondo Beach, Ca. 90278 Telephone: (213) 372-2988And now, dear reader, read the following letter with care. The philosophy contained therein does not bode well for aviculture. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2020</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 3 (1981): JUNE-JULY 1981; 29-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2020/1991</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
