<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2668</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-20T07:32:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Status of Macaws in Aviculture</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clubb, Kevin J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clubb, Susan L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">If current trends prevail, the 1990s will be turning more to the decade of the environment. As aviculturists, our contribution should be obvious. Throughout Central and South America, deforestation and trapping has put a tremendous strain on wild populations of macaws. This is compounded by a reported lower productive rate in the wild which could hinder rapid recovery if pressures are relieved. This is especially evident with the larger blue macaws such as the Hyacinth, Lear's, Spix, and Glaucous. The survival of the last three may rest in the hands of aviculturists. Unfortunately, with the exception of four Lear's, these species are not known in the U.S. This does JJOt dilute the responsibility we American aviculturists have to assure the survival of the rest of the macaws. In the not so distant past, breeding of macaws was limited. Today with improved breeding, incubation, and handfeeding techniques, production of macaws has increased greatly. Hopefully, with new advances in research and avicultural techniques, the future may be brighter for the survival of these species in captivity. The following information was put together using personal experiences and data from TRAFFIC, USA.Hyacinth Macaw (Anodorbyncbus hyacinthinus)The Hyacinth Macaw is the largest and most spectacular of the macaws. In the wild, it is found almost exclusively in Brazil with a small population found in the northeast corner of the Bolivian Pantanal. In the early 1980s, Hyacinths were exported in small numbers from Bolivia. An estimated 650 birds were imported into the United States between 1982 and 1988. Bolivia stopped exportation in 1984. In 1987 the Hyacinth was listed on Appendix I of CITES (Congress on International Trade in Endangered Species of wild fauna and flora). Despite this protection as well as local protection in Bolivia and Brazil, an extensive illegal trade still exists. The bird's curious nature makes it easy prey for poachers.In aviculture, the Hyacinth is breeding in small numbers. Due to their high expense and low numbers in captivity, there are probably not very many pairs set up for breeding. The reason for its low production in captivity is unclear. It has been reported that the species also has a low reproductive rate in the wild with few productive pairs and those pairs rarely fledging more than one chick annually. It has been proposed that long lived species generally have lower reproductive rates. This may have some bearing in this case. It should be noted that we have heard of some pairs in captivity producing 15 chicks in one year. This is the exception rather than the rule. These same 15 in the wild could easily be equivalent to the total life time production of a successful pair. We have seen in past seasons that they seem to have almost a two year cycle where one year a pair breeds well and fails to lay the next year. They are the only macaw that seems to have a craving for coconuts. Robert L. Wilson of the Metropolitan Boston Zoo has established a studbook for Hyacinths.Scarlet Macaw (Ara macao)The Scarlet Macaw is, in our opinion, the most spectacularly colored of all the macaws. This coloration has helped in the demise of the species. Not only is it coveted for its feathers by natives but also by the local pet trade. There are two recognized populations of Scarlets, the yellowwinged or Central American population and the South American population which has more green and less yellow in the wings. Most of the Scarlets which came into the U.S. prior to 1980 originated in Central America and Colombia. In the early 1980's, Bolivia exported large numbers of them until trade ceased in 1984. Also in 1984, Guyana began exportation until 1985. During the first half of the 1980's, approximately 3,000 Scarlets were imported into the U.S. In 1985, the Scarlet was listed on Appendix I of CITES. The existing legal trade in wild caught Scarlets is between Suriname and Switzerland, which both held reservations to the listing.In aviculture, the Scarlets are one of the most productive of the macaws. In some instances they are too productive to the point that they will probably hybridize with any ocher species of large macaw.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2668</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 3 (1991): JUNE-JULY 1991; 21-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2668/2649</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
