<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2013</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-26T04:45:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bird Purchasing Guidelines</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Svedeen, Kendal P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">What should I check for when purchasing new birds?In my opinion, there are three major criteria to check for when purchasing new birds - particularly the larger parrot-type or psitticine birds. To the average owner, this type of bird usually represents a major investment, and deserves some extra attention at purchase time. The three criteria are: Health, appearance and temperament.Here is a health checklist to follow.1. Fluffed feathers - When a bird is awake, its feathers should not be fluffed as they often are when they are asleep. It indicates that the bird has a chill or a fever and is using air between the feathers as insulation.2. Eyes - Check for any discharge or irritation. Certain birds can be aged or sexed by eye coloration such as the African Grey Parrot and most cockatoos.3. Nostrils - If there has been a discharge, the feathers above the nostrils are usually matted and discolored. The nares can also be "plugged" with dried discharge.4. Breast - The breast or pectoral muscles should be nearly "even" with the keel. If you can grasp the keel bone with your fingers, the bird is underweight.5. Abdomen - If there is any distention or "bloating" of the abdomen, choose another bird. Whatever the cause, it's apt to be serious.6. Vent - Examine the feathers around the cloaca. They should be clean and dry. If they are soiled and I or wet, your veterinarian.7. Feet - Check for excessive scaliness (an indication of mites), missing or injured toes and nails. Long nails can mean that the bird is older.8. Skin - Any growths or eruptions other than obvious injuries should arouse suspicions of possible tumors, avian pox or cutaneous tuberculosis.9. Respiration - Observe the bird for signs of open-mouthed breathing or ''flicking'' of the tail with each breath. 10. Activity - A bright and active bird is usually healthy. Don't confuse sleep with lethargy.The reason I regard a bird's appearance so highly is that it is a direct reflection of the bird's general state of health and nutrition. The feathers should be rather glossy and smooth, the colors vivid, and the shafts straight. Appearance is also a direct reflection of the kind of care, housing, and nutrition the bird received previously. One wouldn't expect a bird out of quarantine to look as good as one from a private breeder, but there are a few things to check carefully.If a bird has many broken or bent feathers, examine unbroken feathers for any "stress" lines. These are lines where one or two barbs were not properly formed during the feather's growth period and the shaft is weak at that point. The cause is usually stress and/or nutritional deficiency. A magnifying glass can be very helpful in examining feathers and skin for lice and their nits. Feathers must be examined microscopically for mites.Most Amazon parrots smell "musty" if they have not had regular baths. This is due to the normal secretion of oil by the uropygial or oil gland at the base of the tail. They are used to daily baths in the wild and we should try to duplicate that, being cautious that they aren't chilled after the bath.If Amazons are misted with an indoor plant mister two to three times weekly, it will stimulate them to preen themselves and keep their feather coat in good condition. Cockatoos and cockatiels require less frequent baths because they take dust baths in the wild. A light misting once every week or two is sufficient.Temperament is a wide-open subject.Generally speaking, the more aggressive birds train more readily • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2013</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 3 (1981): JUNE-JULY 1981; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2013/1984</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
