<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2904</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-10T17:00:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">1979 AFA Raffle Winners</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">l""MILCHome Video Tape Machine Pr. of CockatoosPr. of Necklaced Jay Thrushes Tame Panama ParrotHand Raised Sun Conure Baby Hand Raised Sun Conure Baby Yellow Naped MacawPr. of Fulvous Tree DucksBlue Front Amazon ParrotDomestically Raised Baby Double YellowHead Amazon (MUST BE PRESENT I SurpriseCustom Designed Sterling Silver Stick Pin Custom Designed Sterling Silver Tie Tack Pr. of Siamese Fireback PheasantsPr. of Moustache ParrakeetsPr. of Blue Eared PheasantsPr. of Lady Gouldian FinchesPr. of Diamond SparrowsPr. of Mutation Love BirdsPr. of Mutation Love BirdsPr. of Mutation Love BirdsPr. of Albino CockatielsPr. of Dhyal ThrushesPr. of Bourke ParrakeetsPr. of CockatielsPr. of RosellasPr. of Grass Parrakeets50 Pounds of Topper Seed 50 Pounds of Topper Seed Pr. of Pied CockatielsCopy of Parrots of the World Pr. of Grass ParrakeetsPr. ofTurquoisinesPr. of Gold Mantle Rosellas Pr. of Lady Gouldian Finches Pr. of CanariesPr. of Galapagos Doves$100 Cash PrizePr. of Lady Gouldian Finches 10 Pounds of Spray MilletIO Pounds of Spray Millet6 Pack of 4 ft. Duro-Lite Bulbs Years Supply of AvitronPr. of Fire FinchesSet of Bird Books written by Dr. Matthew Yriends Hand Painted Egg picturingSlaty Head Parrakeets Pr. of PheasantsCarton of Spray MilletPr. of Brazilian Crested Cardinals Pr. of Albino CockatielsPr. of Pearl CockatielsPearl-Pied CockatielPr. of Yellow Red Rump Parakeets Pr. of CanariesParrot T StandBaby Pearl CockatielPr. of Lady Gouldian Finches Pr. of Red Factor CanariesPr. of Cherry Head Love Birds Pr of Normal Cockatiels DONOR A.F.APet Farm, Inc. H&amp;amp;JAvianMagnolia Bird Farm, Frank Miser Ramon Noegel - Life Fellowship Ramon Noegel - Life Fellowship The Parrots Beak - Mark Reader Tropical Jungle - Francis BillieSmith's Exotic Aviaries, Inc.Kevin SmithJohn and Diane Nero )RA WING TO WIN) Joy Bird ImportsTim and Ro Dahle Tim and Ro Dahle James GundersonDr. Raymond Jerome Craig HendeeNorshore Pets - Bill WilsonWalnut Acres Aviaries - Jerry Jennings Dr. Richard BaerAgapomis Acres - Lee Horton Washington Feather Factory - Cliff Witt Bill HardinghamVilla De Chaya - Judy Hofferman Tuwana Aviaries - Tom Ireland Nancy ReedFortune Glen Aviaries - Gene HallFortune Glen Aviaries - Gene Hall Toppers Bird Ranch - Richard Topper Toppers Bird Ranch - Richard Topper Dr. Barry AdlerGaithersburg Pet Center - Buzz Neely Mark RunnalsSmitty's Turquoisine AviariesRalph Smith Philadelphia Bird Co.Cochron Aviaries - Peggy Cochron Janice PritchardPhiladelphia Zoological GardensLarry Shelton, Curator of Birds Jim SmithHerschel FreyCarlson Specialty Seed - Walter Carlson Carlson Specialty Seed - Walter Carlson Duro-Lite Lamps, Inc.Lambert-KayRoman GrochowskiDr. Matthew V riendsEggery - Laura JonesMickey OllsonLee PhillipsDick Vaughn and Richard Winter Dr. Greg HarrisonGinger RussellMr. and Mrs. Wayne Thoman Mr. and Mrs. Rodger Heroux Mr. and Mrs. Cliff Baum Critter Shop - Rodger Kenney Nellie HerryA.F.A. Orlando Members Marko AridaChris Estep and Smitty Hinkle Chris Estep and Smitty Hinkle WINNERPerla Iglesias, Jacksonville, FL W.P. Bonsal, Charleston, SC Steve Silver, Deland, FLDr. Robert J. Altman, Merrick, NY Shirley Snyder, West Palm Beach, FL Hubert Morris, Henderson, NVDan Watson, ABI - TXDr. Andre &amp;amp; Sherrill Capi,Ft. Lauderdale, FLMary Rust, Brooksville, FLJoe DeAguiarMr. George J. Schweiger, Jacksonville, FL Sandy Stennett, Key West, FLMr. &amp;amp; Mrs. Authur Jett, Los Angeles, CA Lloyd Lacy, Laramie, WYTom Ireland, Lake Worth, FLDoug Schulz, Phoeniz , AZRoger Kenny, Tampa, FLL.P. Moran, Shingle Springs, CA Joanne Magsulit, Escondido, CA D. Lipelt , Whittier, CAChuck Shifflett, Palatka, FLDavid Hilberg, Silver Spring, MD. Nat Glorit , Ft. Lauderdale, FL Marge Rand, Norco, CARoger Heroux, West Palm Beach, FL The Avicultural Society of America,West Covina, CAM.W. Hill, Olivenhain, CA H. Masters, Alpine, CAMarie Earl Olssen, Naples, FL Arthur Douglas, Dallas, TXDavid Arthur, No. Platte, NBBarron &amp;amp; Testa, Dallas, TXHazen Williams, Knoxville, TNH.L. &amp;amp; Dorothy Smiley, Nuevo, CA Bob Cootz, Orlando, FLGary Duncan, Atlanta, GAPam Hill, Venice, FLTasty Foods, Cincinnati, OH Bill Mackey, Vista, CAIris Hanson, Anacortes, WA Rick Trein , Keokuk, IAE.W. Albrecht, Jacksonville, FL Kathleen Karlen, Landover, MDWilliam S. Tenpas, DVM, Corvallis, OR Gino Abbate, Elizabeth, NJSarah Wood, Raeford, NCDon Beeves, Harbor City, CAJ.C. Baty, Munday, TXGeo. &amp;amp; Betty Morrow, Raymond vi lie, TX Eberhard, Northridge , CAMartha Medlar, Oxnard, CAMrs. Vera Pell, Richmond, VAG. Perkins, Pacifica, CARoss Anderson, Sandy, UT Silversong-Northwcst, Seattle, WA Kethleen Karlen, Landover, MDPam Hill, Venice, FLJames L. Scott, El Cajon, CA Mary Kay Calvert, Miami, FL David Ramsey, Jacksonville, FL </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2904</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 5 (1979): OCT- NOV 1979; 30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2904/2888</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
