<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2783</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-02T16:16:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA VISITS: The Aviaries of Bob McDonald</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In 1983, while visiting a local pet store, Bob McDonald was convinced by the shop owner to purchase a pair of Peach-faced Lovebirds. Being somewhat of a newcomer in the world of exotic birds, McDonald followed the advice of the shop owner. With the purchase of the lovebirds came the promise of a ready market for any youngster reproduced from his pair of lovebirds. The shop owner said he would purchase any offspring and sell them through the shop. McDonald took the lovebirds home and placed them in a breeding situation. Sure enough, they reproduced. But when he took the offspring back to the bird shop he quickly found there was no ready market for the babies.What did result from this disappointing promise, however, was that Bob McDonald persevered and developed an increased interest in breeding exotic birds. This early beginning with a pair of lovebirds then expanded into a collection which is now comprised of 350 birds. This collection includes 14 species of Aratinga and Pyrrhura conures.Bob McDonald's birds are housed outdoors year around in central Florida. The aviaries are placed under large, ancient oak trees that allow only dappled shade to cover the aviaries, a very pleasant environment for the birds. The property extends to a small lake that provides high humidity for the birds.Although many of the conure pairs are housed together, most are mingled amongst cages of Amazons, Pionus, small cockatoos, African Greys, Senegal Parrots and Eclectus. There are also a group of small Australian parakeets (Scarlet-chested Parakeets and Golden-mantled Rosellas) and a pair of Black-headed Caiques.All of the cage breeding units are suspended above the ground. The cages are constructed, depending upon the species using them, of wire measuring 1/2 in. x 1 in., 1/2 in. x 2 in., or 1/2 in. x 3 in. All wire use is galvanized after welding. Most of the cages themselves measure 3 ft. x 4 ft. x 4 ft. and are raised approximately three feet above ground level. There has not been a problem with snakes entering the cages or nest boxes although there are snakes (ratsnakes) present in the area. There is a minor rodent problem but several free-range turkeys remove most of the food that falls or is spilled on the ground.All the cages have roofs that completely cover the cage including the nest box. Only one nest box is placed at the rear of each cage. They are made of either wood or metal depending upon the chewing ability of each species. All perches consist of natural materials and frequently the bark is left on the branches for the bird to enjoy.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2783</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 1 (1998): JAN-FEB 1998; 23-24</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2783/2767</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
