<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/645</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE:Let's Talk Wing Clips</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A short while ago, a valued customercame into our shop in Santa Fe tohave her pet Green-winged Macaw'swings trimmed. She told me a frighteningstory.It seems she had been to visit a localveterinarian to request the samegrooming service. While spreadingher well-behaved macaw's wing forthe simple task, he had advised her,"If I merely clip your pet's flightfeathers, they will grow out againshortly and it will cost you to have herredipped. I would recommend pullingout the flight feathers instead. Thatwill effectively ground her."Fortunately, our customer, who alsoowns a Yellow-naped Amazon, aBlue-fronted Amazon and an AfricanGray Parrot, was intelligent enough torealize the unsoundness of this adviceand replied with a firm "no".Yet, it was with frustration that Iadded this tale to my growing list ofparrot grooming misdemeanors. Thefield of psittacine grooming is strewnwith strong opinions, hazards andpractices which border on theinhumane.Take the common wing trim, forinstance. In many cases, a baby birdstill in the midst of its hand-feedingstage is clipped by the breeder or petshop prior to sending it off with a newowner. Or, the instant a young fledglingtakes off on its first wobbly crashflight out of the holding tub, theowner will rush to get the scissors andclip flight feathers for the baby's"safety."Stop a moment and think what thismeans. A fledgling psittacine is deniedhis full wingspan during the earliestdevelopmental stage of his normalbird behavior. Why, I have knownten-, twelve- or fifte e n-year-oldparrots which have never flown.Needless to say, they have not learnedthe more important lessons of landing,either!Ever wonder why your hookbill petwalks everywhere? Wonder why heleans forward with "begging wings" tobe picked up from only eight inchesaway? Wonder why you cannot gethim off that out-of-reach perch ordown from the tree he has climbedinto?He's terrified, that's why. Look to hisfledgling training and you will likelydiscover the answers. Early wing clip.No training.Psittacine fledglings left with theirfull wing span will quickly learn control.Especially important are theweeks prior to weaning when baby fatis lost and an immense wing span tobody mass ratio results. Full musculardevelopment has not taken place; thatcomes with normal flight activity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/645</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 29-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/645/628</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
