<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/504</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Care and Management of Sunbirds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">VanDegrift, Nanci</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">What bird flies like a finch, looksand eats like a hummingbird, and singslike a canary? The sunbird!Sunbirds occur in Asia and Africaand fill the same ecological niche asthe hummingbird does in theAmerican continents. There are 115varieties of sunbirds, but very few havebeen kept in captivity. In recent years,several species have been imported intothe United States and are now beingsuccessfully kept and occasionallybred in captivity.My first experience with sunbirdsbegan about four years ago when afriend of mine had purchased a pair ofBuff Throated Sunbirds (Nectariniaadelberti) from an importer andwanted me to pick up the birds at thequarantine station, keep them for afew days and then forward them tohim in San Francisco. I had never seena sunbird before (in fact, had neverheard of them) and the idea of keepinga "hummingbird" alive for anylength of time scared me to death. Ispent a few frantic hours readingeverything I could find on sunbirds.This reading material consisted of onesmall paragraph on sunbirds andseveral very old articles on hummingbirds.When I received the birds they werein terrible feather, having all theirfeathers stuck together from being insmall cages without bathing facilities.Both the male and female hadreasonable weight on them, but werevery stressed from being in such poorfeather condition.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/504</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 4 (1989): AUG-SEPT 1989; 12-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/504/488</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
