<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/710</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Sea Ducks</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Elgas, Bob</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One of the most interesting groupsof North American waterfowl arethose referred to as sea ducks.Included in this group are the variouseiders, three species of seaters, OldSquaw Ducks, Harlequin Ducks, andthe extinct Labrador Duck. With theexception of the three varieties ofseaters, which are sombre black incolor, sea ducks are quite spectacularbeing among the most striking of all waterfowl. As the name implies, theyspend much of their time at sea andare rarely encountered inland. As aresult they are less well known thanother waterfowl. Most breed in the farnorth and nesting is normally near saltwater. When the young hatch themother soon takes them to sea. Malesdo not assist in rearing the young.Once the female begins incubationthe male departs and males thengather in groups of their own genderto molt and grow new plumage. Thenew plumage, which lasts through thesummer and early fall, is known as theeclipse. It is quite different from thebreeding plumage, being much lessspectacular, and decidedly subdued.Sea ducks feed almost exclusivelyon animal matter, shellfish and musselsbeing favorite fare. They are powerfulswimmers and can dive to considerabledepths for food. As onemight imagine, the diet imparts astrong flavor to the flesh and they arenot highly regarded as food. NewEngland gunners refer to seaters ascoots. A favorite recipe among the oldtime gunners for coot stew was as follows,"Take one freshly killed coot,nail it solidly to a hardwood board,boil until tender, throw away the cootand eat the board." I cannot verify thisfare from personal experience. However,I have eaten dried eider with theEskimos in Alaska, and can attest tothe fact that on a rating of one to tenthe flavor would at best be perhaps anegative seven. They are incrediblyfishy and quite disagreeable.There are three species of seaters -Surf Seaters, Black Seaters, and WhitewingedSeaters. They are much lessspectacular than other sea ducks,being almost entirely black. The SurfScoter has some interesting white andyellow markings on the head and bill, but is otherwise black. As the nameimplies, the Black Scoter, indeed, isblack. The White-winged Scoter has asmall white patch behind the eye, andthe wing speculum is white, otherwiseit, too, is black. The Surf Seater ispeculiar to North America, but theother two are also found in Europeand Asia. Sea ducks are not easilymaintained in captivity. Seaters in particularare rarely encountered in collections.Not only are they difficult toacquire, but because they are difficultto maintain, and are not colorful, littleeffort has been made to establish themin captivity.As a group, the eiders are one of themost spectacular of the northern hemisphereclucks. Males are predominatelyblack and white, with theunderside being largely black and theupper portions white. There are somedelicate pastel patterns on the headand bills tend to be brightly colored.Exclusive of the tiny Steller's Eider,which is little more than teal size, eidersare large and powerfully built.The Steller's Eider has a white head,with a slight colored crest at the nape.The eye is dark and surrounded by ablack ring. The throat is black as is theback. A band of white extends alongeither side while the breast is cinnamon,which merges to black at theposterior part of the body. All eiderfemales are an overall rich brown withconsiderable dark barring. Althoughfemales are somewhat less spectacularthan males, they are none-the-lessquite beautiful in their own right.Eiders have long been famous fortheir luxurious down, which is one ofthe finest insulating materials known.In Iceland and Norway, where eidersnest in colonies, the down has longbeen collected by eider "farmers".These farmers care for and protect the colonies, and, in exchange, collect thedown for commercial purposes. Thepractice is not legal in North America,so commercial eider down comeslargely from those countries. Thedown is a rich brown in color and isincredibly light and fluffy. I have seenhatched eider nests on the Alaska tundrathat, when abandoned after thehatch, would puff up like giantmushrooms all about the tundraponds. Quite a remarkable sight.There are five races of eiders whichare generally grouped together, andare referred to as the common eiders.They are widely distributed acrossNorth America and Eurasia. They consistof the Pacific Eider, the American,Faroe, Northern, and European Eider.All are similar in plumage, but haveslight differences in bill shape andcolor, and there is a variation in size.Males in breeding plumage are whiteabove, with black undersides. Headand neck is white with a black caprunning from the base of the bill,across the crown to the back of thehead. There are pastel patches ofgreen at the back of the head and thechest is a pale pinkish buff. The eyesof all eiders are black, and commonlyalmond-like in shape. As stated above,all female eiders are a rich brown withclark barring. The group is typicallymarine, nesting on islands and coastalareas. Once hatched, the youngaccompany their mothers to sea. Theyfeed largely on animal matter, especiallymussels and shellfish.Two other forms, the Spectacled andKing Eiders, are unique. They are representedby a single species each, andthe plumage pattern, particularly thatof the head, is distinct from other eiders.The King Eider has the forwardportion of the body white, with apinkish buff coloring on the chest.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/710</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 40-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/710/693</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
