<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1172</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:32:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Cockatoo Soup Mixing Four Different Speczes of Cockatoos</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bockheim, Greg</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IngredientsTwo wild-caught Medium Sulphur-crested Cockatoos ( Cacatua galerita eleonora). Thought to be a pair by the previous owner, these two birds were housed together for several years. One of these birds (M2) being the dominant bird, aggressively lunges at its "mate" or any other approaching bird. The other (Ml) is very passive, cowering to the cage floor when threatened or approached by other birds or humans.One mature male Goffin's Cockatoo (Cacatua goffim). This secretive and shy bird is the "plucker" of the group, removing all the feathers on its chest, abdomen, and upper wing coverts.One adolescent male Lesser Sulphur-crested Cockatoo ( Cacatua sulphurea sulphurea). This is a charming semi-tame little bird, flying to the keepers shoulder upon entering the aviary.One mature female Umbrella Cockatoo ( Cacatua alba). Afraid of most of the staff, hissing and threatening anyone approaching her cage. IntroductionRare is the opportunity to introduce such a variety of parrot species in one aviary setting. The above personality characteristics were observed while the birds were housed in separate cages during a four month quarantine. Individual behaviors were noted to help in predicting compatibility and aggression patterns before the birds were to be brought together.During the third month of quarantine the Lesser Sulphur-crest and the Goffin's Cockatoo were allowed to fly freely about the room. Their interac- tions appeared to be friendly and curious as they played during their free hours. It was felt that free time would give these two smaller birds the opportunity to become acquainted so that they might become companions when introduced to the much larger and more aggressive birds. The Umbrella, being a large, robust, and unfriendly bird made us believe that she would keep to herself.PreparationAll of these cockatoos were to be exhibited together in a large indoor/outdoor aviary. Their first introduction would take place in the interior, off exhibit portion of their new flight which measures 1. Sm deep by 2m wide by 3m high ( S x 61/2 x lOft.). This flight has access, through a guillotine window, to a large exhibit aviary measuring 3m x 3m x Sm (10 x 10 x 16ft.).The birds would spend the first sev- era! days in the smaller flight indoors, familiarizing themselves with the cleaning and feeding routine, and then he given access to the large outdoor flight through the window.Five feeding stations were installed from ground level to the highest perches near the ceiling. One water howl was offered. A maze of natural tree branches were installed from the cage floor to the ceiling offering the birds a wide variety of potential territories and provide for individual distance. Because many psittacines prefer to climb, vertical limbs were provided in addition to horizontal limbs, allowing the birds to climb and fly out of each others way.Although most species of white cockatoos are social "flock" birds in the wild, reports of multiple species remaining in continuous contact, or flocking together, are rare. In Australia I have observed large numbers Rosebreasted Cockatoos in the company of Bare-eyed Cockatoos, and an occasional Long-hilled Corella (thought to he released pets in Sydney) happily feeding among a flock of Greater Sulphur-crested Cockatoos.Within captivity it is often feared that aggressiveness between individuals, let alone differing species, may result in injury or death. Because of this we clipped the right wing of what we felt was our most confrontational bird, Medium Sulphur-crest (M2), in order to slow him down. We also had concerns for the safety of the smaller cockatoos, the Lesser and the Goffin's, but felt they were agile enough to stay out of the larger birds way. Because all of these birds would be newly introduced, we felt that it would be difficult for one aggressive member to relentlessly pursue any single bird without being distracted by the others in the flock. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1172</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 4 (1997): JULY-AUGUST 1997; 9-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1172/1151</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
