<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3989</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T20:18:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Update on Avian Bornavirus</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">DVM, Sharman Hoppes,</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (October/November 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Introduction Proventricular dilatation disease (PDD) was first recognized in the late 1970’s in macaws imported into the United States and Germany. It is also known as Macaw wasting disease, neuropathic ganglioneuritis, lymphoplasmacytic ganglioneuritis, infiltrative splanchnic neuropathy, psittacine encephalomyelitis, and most recently as Avian Bornavirus. Parrot bornavirus is more specific to the infected psittacine. Due to the wide array of clinical signs and the pathology present, this disease state previously known as PDD may be more appropriately termed avian ganglioneuritis (AG), as this better defines the disease process and takes the focus off the proventriculus.Causative agent Multiple etiologies have been proposed for PDD/AG, but in 2008 Avian Bornavirus was determined to be the etiological agent. ABV infection is prevalent in captive parrots throughout the world (15 -45% of birds in a flock), but clinical disease is less common. Many positive birds are clinically healthy and remain so for decades.Pathology / Pathogenesis PDD is characterized by lymphoplasmacytic ganglioneuritis, with inflammatory infiltrates occurring in both the central and peripheral nervous system. Nerves of the gastrointestinal (GI) tract, spinal cord, brain, peripheral nerves, nerves of the heart, adrenal gland, and kidney are affected.Clinical signs of infection The clinical signs of PDD include gastrointestinal issues: weight loss, crop stasis, diarrhea, polyuria, regurgitation and proventricular, ventricular or intestinal dilatation. Signs associated with central nervous system disease include loss of balance, weakness, tremors, seizures, blindness and abnormal head movements. Central nervous system signs can occur with or without gastrointestinal signs. Clinical signs may develop slowly or come on rapidly.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3989</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 4 (2023): Watchbird October/November 2023; 8-9</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3989/3949</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
