<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1921</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-10-31T05:20:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">World Conference III on Breeding Endangered Species in Captivity</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Laughlin, Cory</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Some of the world's most accomplished scientists and naturalists gathered together in San Diego on November 12, 1979, to present their proposed solutions to the steady decline of many animal species. The Conference, which ran from November 12 to 15, was sponsored by the Zoological Society of San Diego and the Fauna Preservation Society.The main theme of the conference was the propagation of endangered animals in captivity with the hope of reintroducing select groups back to the wild. Thirty speakers addressed over 350 delegates and the following report outlines some of the valuable research being done.One of the most successful and progressive people in this field if D. J. Brand, Director of the National Zoological Gardens of South Africa. His lecture and slide presentation included his work being done with the cheetah. Nineteen wildcaught cheetahs have been kept in a one hundred acre enclosure. They are kept as wild as possible and visitors are not allowed to view the animals. This program begun in 1969, has been so effective that twenty-three cubs were raised in 1975. The major question which arose before reintroduction was whether these animals could survive a life in the wild after a captive bred existence. lt was with great relief that the first group released was observed to bring down a giraffe within three days. Mr. Brand's work is invaluable as it may well ensure the survival for one of the most fascinating of all cats.Up until only a few years ago, many people believed that the breeding of birds of prey in captivity was a next to impossible endeavor. Thomas J. Cade, Professor of Ornithology, Cornell University, has been involved in a program which has proven beyond a doubt that this is a viable undertaking. He told conference delegates that each year the rare peregrine falcon, the prairie falcon and the gyrfalcon are among the fifteen falcon species being bred in captivity. Over one thousand birds of prey have been bred in North America over the past five years. In 1970 the Peregrine Fund began a research program on propagation of peregrines in captivity with the intention to introduce the offspring back to the wild. The first twenty peregrines were produced in 1973. Since then, four hundred and thirty-four young have been raised from forty-six laying females. Three hundred and forty-one have been released since 1974. Dr. Cade stated that the three methods of reintroduction used are fostering to wild peregrines, cross-fostering to prairie falcons and the use of hacking stations. Out of these methods, the largest percentage of birds that survived were released at hacking stations. At this sites, young are placed one week before they can fly. They are fed by human attendants until they are. self sufficient, usually six to eight weeks after they begin flying. Twenty-five to thirty percent are lost or killed each season, approximately the same ratio that perish in the wild. One of the main factors contributing to their demise is predation by the great horned owl. Others are shot, lost in storms, and attacked by other raptors. Each year a greater number of peregrines are being successfully released back into the wild, painting a brighter picture for the continued existence of this species.Another success story presented to the conference was from Major lain Grahame, Secretary, World Pheasant Association, Burres, Great Britain. The cheer pheasant has disappeared from its native Pakistan due to habitat destruction and illicit hunting. lt was last sighted in 1976 and is regarded as extinct in the wild. Fortunately, this species is well represented in captive collections. Major Grahame stated the five elements that are the keys to a successful release program. First, the area selected must be in the former range of the species in question. Secondly, the habitat must be capable of supporting birds when released. The third requirement is that the area must be free as possible of human and other disturbances. Fourth, the birds themselves must be capable of survival and reproduction under such circumstances. Finally, the progress must be monitored at the time of release and for a number of years thereafter, i.e., long-term program. Previous release efforts with various pheasant species have met with limited success. The main problem being that the birds were accustomed to an easy life in captivity and unable to adapt to harsh conditions in the wild. The World Pheasant Association had concentrated their efforts on adapting the bird to its area of release immediately upon hatching. In 1978, extensive field· research was done by an American and Pakistani representative of the W.P.A. and by mid-May of last year an ideal release site was selected - the same area, in fact, where the last wild cheer pheasant was sighted. There is an abundance of dense cover for the birds and no human interference such as agriculture or hunting now exists. In the spring of 1978, one hundred and seventy-four eggs were flown to Pakistan. Only twelve birds survived and these few were wing-tagged and released. In the spring of this year, over two hundred eggs were sent to their native land. In July, eighty-nine pullets were reported to be alive and well. Thirty of them had moved voluntarily from their enclosure into the wild. They have frequently been heard and seen and have ventured seven hundred feet higher up into the mountains. There are few predators present in this area and Major Grahame feels they have a fighting chance for survival. Fifty birds have been withheld for a captive breeding nucleus. Major Grahame concluded his presentation with a plea to zoo directors to consider future loan agreements with private aviculturists. He stated that so-called "backyard" collections may be less sophisticated than zoo exhibits but have continually produced startling results in the past. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-10-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1921</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 2 (1980): APRIL-MAY 1980; 5-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1921/1892</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
