<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/656</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE: Once a Gray, Always a Gray ...</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">'~ cat made her lodgings in one ofthe nest boxes and brought up her kittensin it, and two of the gray parrotswho had not been industrious enoughto lay eggs and have a family of theirown were seized with the idea thatthese kittens were their children; theykept up a constant warfare with theold cat, and whenever she left the boxone of them used to get in and sit withthe kittens, and they were constantlyin attendance even when the motherwas home."Charles Buxton, England, 1880sIt has been over 270 years since thefirst documented breeding of a pair ofAfrican Gray Parrots by a western aviculturist.Millions of hookbill keepershave maintained a lasting love affairwith this intriguing old-world psittacine.Demand for these vulture-lookinggray parrots with the perceptive eyeand the virtuoso voice seems tobecome only stronger with the years.Locating new sources for handfedbaby grays in a market never saturatedis like trying to obtain male canaries inSeptember. "Sorry, all sold, thankyou!" With recent breeder successamongst hundreds of Timneh GrayParrot pairs set up during importbooms the past ten years, one wouldthink things a bit easier. Not so. Wehave customers in our area who owntwo or three parrots, yet still come indeclaring, "I've always wanted a petgray. I'm only waiting for the prices tocomedown."It may be a long wait. Even handfedtimneh prices have risen the past fewyears to a level comparable to redtailedbirds. The last lingering criticismof timnehs as "junk parrots" amongunenlightened dealers near southernquarantine stations has all but disappeared.It's about time."Timnehs were always consideredthe poor man's gray," ventures DonWells, one of southern California'smost experienced hookbill breeders."Yet we find our timneh chicks can bethe nicest gray babies. They are outgoing,comical, more voiciferous thanour red-tailed grays - less likely tojust sit there.""I find the timneh personality calmer,less neurotic," said Bonnie Zimmerman,owner of a small, impeccablefacility near Los Angeles. "Half my breeders are domestic bred, half wildcaught.The domestic birds may notproduce as many babies for me, butthere are no thrashings in the nest likeduring an earthquake."Though it is too early to presentconcrete evidence, some aviculturistscharacterize the Timneh Gray as lesslikely to turn to feather picking inunhappy situations. Picture this: babygray comes into his new home, is cuddledand fawned over by the familyfor weeks. Then begins a transition.Routine settles back to normal; perhapsthe kids go back to school. Thenew gray is like a toy whose firstattraction has worn off. Extra food,treats and attentions are lessened. Hespends more time in his cage. Presto!Boredom and frustration followed byfeather picking. We've had adorablered-tailed gray babies who are soldinto seemingly agreeable pet homesreturn with plucking habits barely 18months later! Why grays, everyone isasking? And why the larger red-tailedsin particular?Randy Snow, a reputable breederand aviary consultant in the WillametreValley, Oregon, explains the situationthis way. "You have to rememberthere are a tremendous number ofgrays out there" he said. "In Amazons,if one bird in ten plucks, we think littleabout it. But, in grays, if ten birds in100 pick, or 100 birds in 1000; then wecall it a problem." These psittacineshave been under scrutiny so often andso long that pet owners and breedersare constantly debating their habitsand propensities.For example, are African Graysmore intelligent than many other parrots?They certainly have been givenopportunity to display talents. IrenePepperberg's test gray "Alex" is onlyone of a host of grays with suspectedcognitive powers. The truth is, hadscientists chosen to work with Yellow-naped Amazons, Green-wingedMacaws or Black-capped Lories, thecontinued years of training wouldprobably bring the same exclamationsof intelligence in these species. Sincetheir first "discovery" by Frenchmentraveling to the Canary Islands in the1400s, the African Gray Parrot hasbeen given the best of chances to struthis stuff!The past three years, FeatheredFriends of Santa Fe, New Mexico hasmade a conscious effort to specializein Timneh Gray Parrots as pets.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/656</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 10-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/656/639</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
