<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2971</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-06-23T16:59:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Represented at 96th American Orinithologist's Union</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baer, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The American Federation of Aviculture accepted an invitation from the American Ornithologists' Union to be represented at their ninety-sixth stated meeting which was held at the Univ. of Wisconsin, Aug. 14-18, 1978.Dr. Richard E. Baer served as spokesman for A.F.A. and gave the presentation on our Federation.Dr. Baer, assisted by the state coordinator for Wisconsin, Paul Miller, also set up an improvised display for A.F.A. He reports that his presentation was very favorably received by those attending the meeting and that much interest was shown at the A.F.A. display and many subscription brochures were given out.(The following presentation was giJ1e11 by Dr. R.E. Baer at the Ninety-sixty stated meeting of the American Ornithologists' Union, The Un. of Wisconsin, Aug. 14-18, 1978.) THE AMERICAN FEDERATION OF AYICULTURECompared to the American Ornithologists' Union, The American Federation of Aviculture is still in its infancy.The A.F .A. was formed in February 197 4 by members of several cage and aviary bird orientated organizations. Less than five years old, it has grown to become a Federation of over fifty clubs and some 4000 registered independent members. Through its affiliated associations and independent membership, the Federation represents over 50,000 aviculturists. Members are located in all fifty states and A.F.A. has established a system of state coordinators across the nation.The Federation is governed by delegate representation which decides on actions and policies.The American Federation of Aviculture is dedicated to the conservation of bird wildlife through encouragement of captive breeding programs, scientific research and education of the general public. It is a non-profit organization.Exotic animals, including birds imported in to this country, have not always been properly cared for either in shipment or at their final destination. Some domestically bred birds and household pets have also lacked proper treatment either through ignorance or neglect. Legislation has been proposed by conservationists, ecology groups, humane societies and legislators who feel there is a need for laws to protect wildlife and domestic stock. A.F .A. recognizes these needs and disagrees only with poorly written or discriminatory legislation. This we actively opposte.The Federation has a code of ethics in which it explicitly states its policy against those who would violate Federal or State Jaws or be inhumane in the treatment of birds. It is the official policy of A.F .A., as stated in its code of ethics, to disqualify or expell from membership or advertising in the Federation's publication any applicant, member or advertiser who has been convicted of violation of any Federal or State law concerning the importation, interstate shipment, possession or humane treatment of any avian species. Our organization does not hesitate to impose its sanctions for violations of its code of ethics.The official publication of the American Federation of Aviculture is its bimonthly magazine, the A.F.A. Watchbird. The Watchbird has been acclaimed not only as the finest publication in the United States in its field, but it has been repeatedly stated that there is no equal to it in any other country for quality. The Watchbird has a guaranteed readership of over 33,000 people. Circulation is paid and its subscribers are composed of breeders, veterinarians, zoologists, wholesalers, retailers, hobbyists, and just plain people interested in birds.It is the purpose of A.F .A. to work cooperatively with industry, governmental agencies and all other interested groups whenever necessary to enhance the status of bird populations, captive or free. We propose through the encouragement and promotion of captive breeding programs of the rare and endangered bird species to save them from extinction. We endeavor to publish information on the successful breeding of these and other species. We hope to sponsor scientific research on the conservation and care of birds; and we try to educate the general public to the better care and treatment of all caged and aviary birds and to the enjoyment of keeping birds.(Editor's note: A display for A.F .A. should be set up by the club delegates at all bird shows this year and subscription brochures should be distributed at all shows. Cloth table and back drops are being prepared by our art department for this purpose and hopefully will be ready in time for all shows. They can be obtained by requesting them through the chairman of our show display committee. Brochures can be obtained from the home office committee chairman.).  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2971</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 4 (1978): AUG-SEPT 1978; 23-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2971/2955</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
