<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2774</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-14T02:01:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Visits The Aviaries of Bill Bennett</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Marshall, Thomas C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Where in the world would you expect to find the most successful flock of endangered Hyacinth Macaws? The Pantanal region of Brazil? Strongholds in Bolivia or Paraguay? Not so. A thriving flock of this magnificent species is located in southwestern Virginia, in a beautiful, rural setting just outside Christiansburg. Here not long ago I discovered aviculturist Bill Bennett, who specializes in Hyacinth Macaws exclusively. His devotion to a species has allowed him to realize a higher production from his birds than what could be predicted in nature.Field biologists' studies indicate that only 15 to 30 percent of adult Hyacinths attempt to breed in any given year. In addition, not all breeding pairs of Hyacinth Macaws fledge young, and those that do almost never fledge more than one bird. Thus, a hypothetical wild flock of 100 mated pairs of breeding age macaws may only produce between 7 to 25 young per year, a less than successful reproductive rate, especially for an endangered species subject to the combined pressures of habitat destruction and illegal trade."Hyacinth Haven", with an average of 25 breeding pairs at any one time, produces more young than do 100 pairs of their counterparts in the wild. This is a very successful flock of Hyacinths, for not only does it produce a large number of offspring, but the captive young raised provide an alternative to wild-caught birds, thereby helping to reduce the pressure on wild populations and thus improving the species' chance for survival.I had the good fortune recently to visit with Bill, and his daughter and son-in-law, Ellen and Clay Vest, to see firsthand this superior flock in a brand new aviary designed just for Hyacinths. The aviary building, measuring 120 feet by 20 feet, is an all metal construction manufactured by Wedgcor of Nebraska, which is kept warm and cool by a 5-ton airconditioning and heat pump unit. Two huge, eight-speed fans, each which can run in unison or separately, depending on the job, are located at ends of the aviary building.There are 38 flights in the building and 38 paired flights outdoors, giving the birds access to a more natural environement during the months from April to October. The inside and the outside connecting flights are constructed of heavy 4-gauge wire which is purchased in 16 x 5 foot panels. To build one of the two paired flights, Bill and Clay take two 16-foot panels and bend each in two places at approximately five feet from each end. They then place the bent panels so that they intersect at 90 degree angles, forming a cube with dimensions just over five feet. The panels are attached to each other with 1-1/ 4 inch rings manufactured by the Valentine Company and then hung from metal hooks on the sides of the building. This construction approach acknowledges the difficulty in working with such heavy wire and takes advantage of the way in which this material is being marketed. The aviaries are hung high in the building and are seldom entered, thus giving the macaws a genuine sense of security. If the need arises to enter the flights, a trap door in the bottom facilitates any intervention or repair that is required.The inside flights are separated by metal dividers so that adjacent pairs cannot see each other, although they can see the birds across the aisle. Thirty gallon cans are used as nest boxes and, like the feeding stations, are located in the front of the flights. Bill fastens wooden fronts to the nest box entrances to simulate more natural conditions and to satisfy the macaws' need to gnaw. A large slab of wood is bolted to the inside of the nesting chamber for the same purpose. Above the nest boxes on top of the flights are metal roofs designed to block light from the interior of the nest box.Bill has not added a misting system in the building since the birds will have access to the outdoors and, most importantly, because of his concern that misting will cause the vaporization of bacteria and viruses normally confined to the floor. It is his feeling that creating humid conditions in an enclosed area is tantamount to creating trouble for birds.Bill has abandoned the use of highpriced Vita-Lites in favor of fullspectrum fluorescent lights which are easier to obtain. Lighting engineers with whom he has consulted indicate that the less expensive lights are just as good or better for his purposes. All the lights are enclosed by a sealed globe to prevent dust from cutting down on the intensity of the lights, which apparently can be a serious problem. The lights in the aviary are kept on 16 hours per day as Hyacinths are opportunistic...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2774</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 2 (1992): APR-MAY 1992; 54-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2774/2754</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
