<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1695</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:15:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">BUILD YOUR OWN BIRD EQUIPMENT or Budget-wise Training Stands, Shower Perch, and Portable Playgrounds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roberts, Linda</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Remember being told that the difficult challenges of life are often blessings in disguise? One such blessing for me has been, through necessity, the ability to improvise, do things myself or make them myself - this includes clothes, home improvements and, most recently, pet bird equipment.Whenever I see something that is a want or a need, my first thought is, "Can I make it myself?" For many years, my love of birds was restricted to a family pet bird of either a Budgie or Cockatiel. When it was finally possible to get a "big" parrot, a whole new world opened up to me and, at the same time, that new world kept opening up my wallet!There had to be a way to cut some of those costs so I developed a few items that are simple, functional, durable, and affordable to make. Each of them is something we need for our pet birds - an $8 table-top training t-stand, an $8 floor training t-stand, a $9 no-slip shower perch, and a $9.50 portable play-basket. Once you have your materials, most of them take less than 30 minutes to assemble (the play-basket takes about an hour.)Important Note: The above t-stands are training stands, not play stands. A training stand is used only for short periods of time when an actual training session is in progress (which means the bird is on it for usually no more than 5-15 minutes once or twice a day). A play stand must have what I call "play value" - with several perches or levels for climbing, toys to play with and chew, and something to shred, as well as a food and water cup. My portable play-basket fits those qualifications and is a great tool for providing a designated area for pet birds, as well as a safe place for them to chew, eat, and drink. Your bird can be nearby on his playbasket, while you have your hands free for things like checking the kids' homework, clipping out coupons, or washing dishes. (More on the play-basket below.)Before we discuss actual instructions, you must understand that I'm not a carpenter; however, I am a firm believer in the full service of the small independently owned neighborhood hardware stores. I can't emphasize strongly enough how important it is to establish a good customer relationship with your local privately owned hardware store. You will get the right items the first time, and you will get that extra advice to make your project go smoothly. Whether it's replacing rotting trim on my porch posts, replacing a blown electrical outlet, a leaking faucet, or making t-stands and props for my pet birds, when I go to my local Ace Hardware store, there is someone who personally stays with me as I select each and every item needed for my project. The service continues as they cut the wood to my specifications (often helping me calculate those specifications), give me tips to make the job easier and, yes, even refer me somewhere else if they don't have the tool or item I need!All the wood, PVC, and hardware prices given below are based on purchases made on February 25, 2001, at an Ace Hardware store in my area. The clerk not only cut the wood to my specifications (including the dowels), but the screws were sold singly, so I do not have a partial package of items that I will never use for anything else. Okay, enough of that - here we go:Tabletop Training T-stand:These dimensions are for a medium size bird (Eclectus, Greys, cockatoos); but the diameter of the dowel can be increased or decreased for larger or smaller birds.Dimensions.12" x 12" base, 14" high and 14" wide perchMaterials List:PriceBase: 1" x 12" pine (cut into a 12" x 12" square). $1.39Vertical post: 1 1/8" diameter dowel (14" long) $3.80Horizontal perch: 1 1/8" diameter dowel (14" long) $3.80Base screw: 3/16" x 1 1/2" flat head wood screw $0.07Perch screw: 4/16" x 1 1/4" screw $0.25Tools Needed:Drill, pliers, and screwdriver Two drill bits, assorted sizes Wood glue(Optional: counter sink tool - attaches to your drill) </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1695</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 1 (2002): Fourth Quarter 2001; 63-66</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1695/1672</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
