<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3399</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-01-21T03:48:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">No Business Like Show Business</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Molenda, Sandee L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Why Show Birds?Mention the words blrd showtand most aviculturists think of bird expos or marts where birds and related items are sold. However, these are fairly recent developments in the world of aviculture. For many years, indeed, centuries in some cases, birds have been exhibited for the purpose of improving birds by selective breeding. While most breeders are simply happy to produce healthy offspring; people who show their birds want to produce the best possible bird of that species.Showing birds also has other rewards such as introducing people to many species and color mutations of birds they have never seen before. Showing can also in tuence the type of birds owned by a breeder and most successful exhibitors specialize in a certain species or genus of birds so they can have the ultimate control of their breeding operation program.Going to bird shows has taught me more about parrots in general and specitcally what constitutes an ideal specimen. When I decided to attend my rrst show, it was mainly to have fun with my friends and get an appraisalD of the quality of my breeding stock .. Since then, I received quite an education.- one that continues to evolve and is constantly being improved. Today, when I hold back breeding stock, I look for great bone structure rrst, tightness of feathers second and strong, bright color along with a calm disposition. This way, I have gorgeous show birds AND sweet gentle pets. It's the best of both worlds.Exhibiting birds is not just for breeders but can be great fun for pet owners as well. There is none so excited as a trst time novice chewing their nails off while little Kiwi is being judged. Watching a beloved pet do well on the show bench is like watching your child's piano recital or school play. The best birds also enjoy it very much and will strut and turn to show off their best side.Where Do I Find a Bird Show?There are many bird shows sponsored by local bird clubs all around the US and Canada. One can go to web-sites published by the various exhibition organizations or look in the back of Bird Talk magazine to rnd the dates and locations of various bird shows. There are also two national shows in the U.S. The Great American Cage Bird Show or GABS, is the only national show that gives cash awards to the winners. The oldest national show is the National Cage Bird Show.. The National is considered the Westminster[Of bird shows and hundreds of exhibitors bring thousands of birds to compete for the coveted, Scannell Award for the Best Bird in Show. These shows are held in different locations throughout the country and are sponsored by a local bird club. The 2005 Great American will be held in Punta Gorda, Florida October 8-9, 2005. The National will be held November 18-19, 2005 in Dallas, Texas.What Is A Bird Judged Upon?To put it simply, bird shows are beauty contests. It is strictly judged on how the birds look. All birds are judged on Standards, which are spectre sets of guidelines that are used by the judge to pick the best bird. Although there are more than 350 species of parrots alone, these Standards are focused on the most important aspects for each species regardless if it is a Senegal or a Princess of Wales parakeet. It is also important to remember that the birds are not only being judged against the birds present at the show, but also on the judge's impression of that particular bird against all the others of that species that judge has placed before. In other words, they not only compete against one another but against every other bird of that type seen by that judge. Very high standards indeed, but when you are talking about future generations of the highest quality birds, high Standards are a necessity. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-01-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3399</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 32 No. 3 (2005): Number 3  2005; 9-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3399/3383</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
