<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2034</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-06-28T03:05:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Announcement of new Ornithological Service: NON-INVASIVE SEXING OF PSITIACINE TYPE BIRDS (BY FECAL STEROID HORMONE RADIOIMMUNE ASSAY)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">CENTER FOR REPRODUCTIVE STUDIES is a San Diego based reference laboratory offering this unique service. Prior to this time, this alternative to surgical sexing was offered only by the research divisions of the London and San Diego Zoos as a courtesy to other zoos. Now, for the first time, this service is available commercially to veterinarians, bird breeders and individual bird owners.Further information on methodology and documentation, pricing and discounts ts avazlable on request to CRS.Michael M. Multer, Ph.D., DirectorWildlifeImporter SentencedBert R. Slocum, owner and operator of one of the largest bird import operations in the U.S. , was sentenced to serve l year in prison and fined $18,000 by Judge James W. Kehoe in U.S. District Court in Miami, Florida, on June 5. He was one of five persons found guilty recently on multiple violations involving the importation and quarantine of birds. Louise V. Slocum, his wife, was fined $1,000 and placed on 2 years probation. The other three included his son, Ray B. Slocum, and two employees, Francille Miller and Doris Fuller who were placed on probation for 2 years.Slocum, his son, and the two employees were found guilty of conspiring to enter and maliciously breaking into a U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) quarantine facility; removing birds, mainly parrots, from U.S. Customs custody which had been exposed to exotic Newcastle disease; and mixing them with healthy birds at Slocum's warehouse. Louise V. Slocum was found guilty along with the others of conspiring to violate quarantine regulations. Ben R. Slocum who owns the Qualiry Bird Company in Miami, Florida, was also found guilty of presenting the USDA with a fraudulent claim for $290, 383 for diseased birds that had to be destroyed by USDA after he was responsible for exposing the birds to the disease.The transmittal of exotic Newcastle disease is a constant threat to the multimillion dollar poultry and pet industries. Imported birds can transmit the highly contagious viral disease to poultry and other fowl. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2034</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 4 (1981): AUG-SEPT 1981; 41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2034/2005</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
