<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/588</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Artificial Incubation Basics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Klea, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">First, let's ask ourselves why we want to pursue using artificial incubation techniques. For most of us the answer is quite simple, we are able to increase production of young birds and we are in control of the destiny of the egg. There is a great deal of satisfaction in assisting a new life to enter this world of ours. In the past 17 years, I have had the very great pleasure of using artificial incubation to hatch hundreds of birds (mostly exotic pheasants). It is a very satisfying and enjoyable experience if you are successful but for those who are not successful it can be a most heartbreaking and unpleasant experience. I do remember my very first experience and it was most disappointing. I did not hatch a single bird but as I look back, it was a valuable learning experience. It caused me to dig for information on how to improve my incubation techniques because I love a challenge and basically want to be successful at everything that I choose to undertake. One of the directions I tried was to join a bird club (CGBA). I remember attending meetings and set about picking the old timers' brains. I can now laugh at some of the advice I was given in those conversations. I really should have been more selective and only sought advice from people who were successful bird breeders because I did get some very poor advice from breeders who were knowledgeable about birds in general but weren't knowledgeable about artificial incubation. So for those of you who are having difficulty in the artificial incubation process I suggest you seek advice from successful breeders and take notes. Over the years, I have had the opportunity to listen to many breeders' tales of woe and have formed some distinct opinions about incubators and the people who use them. Since I have learned a great deal about the incubation process, I will attempt to relay what I perceive to be the most important aspects of the incubator and your operation of it. Before discussing the incubator and its operation, let's examine the operator's personality. I am convinced that the use of the incubator to increase production and raise birds is not for everybody. Why would I be so bold to make such a statement? The answer is simple - some people do not wish to pay attention to details, winging it is a way of life for them. For these people, allowing the parents to incubate and rear their young is definitely the best course to follow. Many of us are too wrapped up in our jobs, family life and other outside interests to be attentive to the needs of the detailed operation required with incubators. Please do not misunderstand this comment, I'm simply trying to warn those who do not have time to pay attention to details that they may be better served not to try artificial incubation. For those who want to be more successful, I will attempt to explain some basics of this exciting hobby. I have had the opportunity to repair and modify a number of incubators for people over the years. In doing so I can safely identify a number of improvements for you. The incubator and hatcher that I am currently using can best be described as basket cases before I was able to modify and improve their operation to my satisfaction. First, let's think about the very most important aspect of an incubator. I'm sure many of you can think about what is important in the way of cost or size, but I'm talking about the environment for these precious eggs of ours. What we are attempting to do is create an environment equivalent to that of the parent bird. Notice that I used the term "equivalent" as opposed to "identical:' Most of us will use a forced-air incubator and not a still-air incubator (much more difficult to control a thermal gradient than a constant, uniform temperature). The egg under the parent or surrogate creates a rather constant and consistent thermal gradient across the egg. Heat is transmitted to the egg by conduction and radiation. Since the breast cannot completely cover the egg, the portion in contact with the breast will be warmer than the opposite side which is in contact with wood chips or similar materials. This side which is not in contact with the heat source is actually losing heat and therefore a thermal gradient will exist. This has been as much as 6°F on relatively small eggs. The forced air incubator transmits heat to the eggs by convection (heated moving air) and creates a uniform and constant thermal temperature environment. The key to successful hatches is keeping this temperature uniform, constant and by all means at the proper level. The number of incubator manufacturers and models available is on the increase and it is not the purpose of this paper to guide you toward one model or one manufacturer over another, but to help you decide what to look for or how to improve yours. Please be careful not to procure some old chicken incubator just because it was a bargain. Many old incubators are fine for chickens but not for the exotic bird eggs we are wanting to put into them. These old incubators (family keepsakes) do not have some of the improved temperature controls or reliability of some of our more modem types. The biggest flaw of many of these incubators is the very poor heat distribution and thermal gradients within them. You may find several degrees' difference in temperature between two adjacent trays. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/588</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 5 (1992): OCT-NOV 1992; 12-16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/588/571</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
