<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3260</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-02T17:36:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Keynote Address</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clubb, Susan L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The history of the pet bird industry and aviculture has been molded by events- tipping points-which have dramatically altered it's course. Many of these formative events were based on disease outbreaks or regulatory changes. Our indus-try is now facing a new tipping point- one based on economic and social issues. Aviculturists are facing issues such as declining sales in recent years, pressure or criticism from animal rights groups and rescue/sanctuary groups, legislative challenges, and economic pressures such has increasing costs for feeds and supplies.These trends are also affecting Avian veterinarians.While not directly affected by trends such as declining retail bird sales, avian veterinarians are indirectly affected as the numbers of patients and bird owning clients decline in a given geographic area. While there will always be faithful bird owners needing our services- will it be enough for veterinarians to concentrate our efforts on avian medicine in a changing economic climate?Brief OverviewPrior to 1992, the history of the industry was tied to the importation of birds into the U.S. Records dating back to 1901 indicate a steady stream of imports rarely dropping below the 300,000 birds per year mark, except for a period between 1943 and 1967, during which no records were available. Psittacine imports were banned during this time because of a pandemic of "Parrot fever" human chlamydiosis-which was traced to parrots.Psittacosis was named by a French physician, Morange, who described "parrot fever" in 1892, as a disease of humans and parrots. In 1929 pandemic psittacosis occurred in the U.S. with a concurrent worldwide outbreak again traced to parrots from Argentina. Worldwide investigation during the 1930s deleniated the etiology and epidemiology of psittacosis. Imports of psittacines into the U.S. were banned in 1942. In the 1960's, researchers at the Hooper Foundation developed treatment protocols in conjunction with the U.S. Public Health Service for pre-entry treatment using chlorotetracycline medicated feed. In 1968 treatment centers were established overseas where birds were held and treated for 45 days prior to importation.The import of wild or delicate species was facilirated by the adventof air transportation following World War II. Prior to this passage by ship was difficult for many species, but was still used for many birds well into the 1960's.The second disease to dramatically impact the pet trade was Exotic Newcastle Disease, or Viscerotropic Velogenic Newcastle Disease. Psittacine birds traveling aboard sailing ships were thought responsible for the spread of the disease from it's suspected point of origin in Java to Europe and South America between 1926 and 1942. An epornitic of a very virulent strain of VVND reached every continent between 1968 and 1972. lnl972 an epornitic of VVND in California resulted in the first test of disease control by eradication on a national basis. USDA undertook a massive depopulation effort of poultry and exotic birds. The fear of re-entry resulted in the establishment of the USDA quarantine system for all imported birds in 1974 and the Public Health Service Program of foreign treatment centers was abandoned.In 1974, the United States joined CITES, an international treaty, currently with 175 signatory countries. CITES regulates international trade in species listed on their appendices I, II and III. International trade for listed species requires permits. In 1981 all psittacine species except peach faced lovebirds, Cockatiels, Indian ringneck parakeets and Budgerigars were listed in either CITES Appendix I or II resulting in monitoring and control of international movement of most parrots. For more information visit CITES.org.In the years between the creation of the USDA quarantine system for imported birds in 1974 and the passage of the Wild Bird Conservation Act of 1992, 300,000 to 900,000 birds were imported into the U.S. each year, approximately 75 percent of which were exotic wild-caught birds. The almost limitless supply of birds lead to explosive growth in aviculture in the U.S.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3260</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 38 No. 3 (2011): Number 3 2011; 33-36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3260/3244</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
