<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/935</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Is that a Dead Branch or a Tawny Frogmouth?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Chris</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">suppose you confronted a creature with the following description: a disproportionately large head, large glowing yellow eyes, a wide mouth with a short hooked beak; a short body with small twig-like legs, and plumage that resembles tree bark. Although it may appear to be one of Jim Henson's muppets, this is actually a general description of the Tawny Frogmouth Podargus strigoidesFrogmouths are related to nightjars (two better-known species of nightjar are the Whippoorwill Caprimulgus vociferus, and the European Nighthawk C. europaues), All of these birds are classified into the order Caprimulgiformes. The members of this order are characterized by wide gaping mouths, short beaks, cryptic coloration, and nocturnal lifestyles. N ightjars are usually small, have long narrow wings, and feed during flight Frogmouths, on the other hand, are much larger than most nightjars and have short, broad wings. Frogmouths are subdivided into the family Podargidae.Podargidae consists of 12 species of frogmouths. The Tawny Frogmouth is one of the larger species, weighing from 300 to 600 g. Jn captivity, specimens frequently weigh in excess of 600 g. Average length ranges from 33 to 47 cm, while the wingspan usually ranges from 65 to 100 cm. There are seven known subspecies of Tawny Frogmouth.The plumage of the Tawny Frogmouth is colored with a variety of browns, grays and rusts arranged in a pattern that gives the bird an appearance of a tree branch or bark. Males and females are similar in appearance. One small difference between the sexes is in eye coloration. Males may have an orange-brown ring surrounding their iris, while this ring has not been known to appear in females.The Tawny Frogmouth is native to Australia and Tasmania, and can be found throughout the continent. It is also found on several of the larger islands sur-rounding Australia, including Kangaroo, Groote and Fraser Islands. There arealso unconfirmed reports in southernregions of New Guinea. These birdsprefer woodlands and forests in whichthey can conceal themselves, even thoughadult Tawny Frogmouths are rarelypredated upon. One known predator,however, is the Barking Owl Ninoxconnivens. Larger snakes will also occasionallyprey upon them.The Tawny Frogmouth has shown apreference for eucalyptus trees . The camouflagedplumage of these birds allowsthem to blend in with their surroundings.When startled, they assume anupright posture by raising their heads and straightening their backs. This posturegives the bird the appearance of adead branch which is so effective theTawny Frogmouth is rarely seen in thewild , even by well-trained ornithologists.Many zoo visitors are unable to locate abird only a few feet away from them.The natural diet of the TawnyFrogmouth consists mainly of insects,small reptiles, amphibians, mammals andoccasionally includes small fruits .Frogmouths can catch food while in flight,like the small nighthawks but they usuallycatch prey by chasing it on a branchor by ambushing it by jumping on it froman overhead branch. These birds alsoscavenge for dead insects on road surfaceswhich results in many TawnyFrogmouths killed by traffic.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/935</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 5 (1995): SEPT-OCT 1995; 48-50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/935/916</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
