<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3020</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-16T09:58:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Raising the Australian Black Swan</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McConnell, Ken</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Cygnus atratus , the Australian Black Swan, is described in the Encyclopedia of Aviculture as follows: The main color is greyish-black, relieved only by white flights. lris deep red; bill red with white band towards the tip; legs and feet black. Although this is a very accurate description, it falls far short of doing justice to this magnificently beautiful bird. The feathers are not only greyish-black, but ruffled as well to add a Little extra touch of elegance. The sleek white flight feathers provide a startling contrast.The deep red iris is bright and full of lustre. The red bill, especially in breeding season, is a brilliant red. Their very long neck and head is carried in a manner that can best be described in "proud":Black swans have a high-pitched. very musical bugle that takes many forms in various situations. Their courtship involves a great deal of talking, bobbing and diving and is culminated with a highpitched cry of sheer exhuberance , They are completely monogomous and extremely affectionate and devoted to each other.Fortunately for those of us who choose to keep and raise these beautiful birds, the Black Swan adapts well to a wide variety of climates and situations and is successfully raised in all parts of the United States and Europe. Those of us who live on the West Coast are particularly fortunate as our generally mild climate provides a prolonged breeding season without the necessity of providing shelter against the cold of the northern winters.Keeping Black Swan on a pond, lake, or reservoir is the most convenient and certainly the most beautiful method one could hope for. The natural vegetation found on the banks of the pond and the water plants and their roots will provide the bulk of the food the swans require. As this is their natural food, it is probably also the best.The nutritional value of this vegetation does vary from one location to another so a supplement of mixed grain or pelletized feed or a combination of both should be available to them to be sure of adequate nutrition. Most of the large feed companies prepare a Game Bird Feed which is very good. A 16% to 18% protein, with vitamins and minerals added is an ideal diet.Those of us who do not have such ideal conditions must put a Little more effort into building a suitable pond for our swans. Of alt the swans, the Black Swan is satisfied with the smallest area of water. A cement pond, six by twelve feet is ample water for a pair of Blacks. They should have at least a ten by twenty land space, and more if it is available. It is perfectly possible to raise Blacks successfully in any average back yard.Provisions must be made for draining and re-filling the pond with clean water. It is best to do this daily. Sanitary living conditions are as essential to the good health of your swans as for yourself.There is some disagreement as to the value of feeding lettuce trimmings to confined birds, but I feel that it has considerable merit. Although lettuce has very Little nutritional value, it is a natural type of food for them and they thoroughly enjoy it. It provides bulk and fiber which aids in digestion and elimination. It occupies time and energy which relieves boredom. Lettuce trimmings usually can be obtained at a local market and cost nothing but the small amount of time involved in getting and feeding it.Breeding season for Black Swans living in the northern hemisphere begins in fall, usually late October or November and continues on through late spring. Jn northern California this is also the beginning of the rainy season which does have a definitely stimulating effect on the birds. I've noticed that in drought years when the rains were late in coming the birds were also late in laying.The male is the nest builder, building a large nest three to five feet in diameter and a foot high if enough nest material is available to him. I've found that hay is considerably better than straw as it isn't as slippery and it doesn't break up and compact as easily. The hay remains intact and doesn't become so matted that rain water can't run off or through.As soon as the pair of Swans has selected their nesting site the cobb will start gathering up bits of grass, leaves, twigs, or whatever is available and it starts building. The hay should be provided at that time, not directly on the spot but near enough that it can be easily picked up by the cobb and placed as he would like it. Some pairs will accept a nest house, others will not.The pen (female swan) will lay her first large greenish colored eggs within a very short time after the nest has been started and continue laying every other day until she has completed her clutch of five to eight eggs. Six eggs to a clutch is the average. I've observed that each individual pen has her own average so if she has established a clutch size of five, six, or seven eggs, she will continue to lay that number each time she lays. The eggs are incubated 36 to 37 days, and all of the eggs in a clutch will usually hatch within forty-eight hours.Unlike other species of swan, the Black Cob takes his regular turn at incubating the eggs so that the pen can bathe, feed and drink without leaving her eggs unattended.If one wishes to raise more than one clutch of cygnets from a pair, the cygnets may be removed from their parents as soon as they have been hatched. Usually within thirty days the adults will be building a new nest and laying a second clutch of eggs in one season.Although swans are very good parents who aggressively and conscientiously care for their young, we take the cygnets as soon as they are hatched and place them in a brooder. The size of the brooder box isn't too important so long as it is large enough to house a clutch of six or seven cygnets for a couple of weeks. A regular brooder light provides the heat and should be adjusted so that the temperature directly under the light is 95-100° for the first week, then should be lowered to 80° after that. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3020</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 1 (1977): FEB-MAR 1977; 28-29 + 44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3020/3004</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
