<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3367</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-04T01:29:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Convention 2001 All That and a Bouquet of Flowers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ewell, Stacey Y.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I can honestly say that I have never, in all my life. attended a group gathering such as the AFA Convention 2001 and returned with such a feeling of success and jubilation. Prior to my attendance at the convention, I was concerned as I did not expect to know many people there. When I read the Wa!chbird article by Jenni Jackson of Loxahatchee, Florida, I felt totally consoled as all my anxieties had been relieved. In her article, published in Volume XXVIII, Number 3, 2001, Jenni had touched a place close to my heart with her description of her circumstances and anxieties prior to and during her attendance at the last AFA convention. She related that in a phone conversation with her husband from her hotel room, she realized "My feeling of isolation had been my own fault - it was my doing and no one else's." Jenni's remarks gave me the determination to attend the convention with an open mind and the drive that would carry me forward with a positive attitude.It all began on Tuesday outside of the Galveston Room of the JW Marriott Hotel during a break for the AFA Board of Directors Meeting. I extended my hand, along with an introduction of myself, to Benny Gallaway, AFA President and Janis Clark, AFA Vice President. I apologized for my intrusion into their conversation and explained: "Hello, I am Stacey Ewell of Suffolk, Virginia and I am a 'first timer.' I wanted to make sure and introduce myself after having read an article published in the aja. Watchhird. I am very interested in becoming more active in the AFA organization and hope to be working with you both at some point in the future."Sitting here writing this short synopsis of my experiences now, this introduction still seems more than forward on my part, but I can assure you it was welcomed and accommodated over and over again in the days that followed.My next big adventure was to approach and introduce myself to Darryl Styles, M.S., D.VM. l explained that in addition to being a member of AFA, I was on the Board of Directors for Bird Clubs of Virginia who will be holding their annual convention in March, 2002 at the Renaissance Hotel in Portsmouth, Virginia. I had recently contacted Dr. Styles by e-mail with an invitation to speak at our convention to which he had graciously accepted. I was very happy to make his acquaintance in person and looked forward to his upcoming visit to our convention. Dr. Styles expression immediately lit up with a huge smile and a welcoming handshake.I continued throughout the convention to greet people and introduce myself. This led to many heartwarming experiences, one after the other, which built my confidence and erased my anxieties. My dream of becoming a member of the AFA fam.ily was realized' This is what AFA has become for me, a family of many different people from all walks of life, sharing common interests and goals in aviculture. Thank heavens this is a short article so "you guys," (okay. I am from the south) don't have to be subjected to the story of every introduction I made at the convention. As I am writing about my experiences now, the memories of the "gush and joyful experience" bring tears to my eyes.When I returned to my room that evening, I found... </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-01-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3367</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 4 (2001): Number 4  2001; 24-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3367/3351</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
