<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2735</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-26T09:29:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA's Conservation Commitment</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Listing and brief descriptions of projects receiving AFA Conservation Fund grants from 1987-1990.Breeding Biologyof the Mariana Crow Investigator: Gary A MichaelsOf the 40 true crows in the family Corvidac, the Mariana or Guam Crow (Corvus teubaryt) is one of the least studied and only the Hawaiian Crow (Corvus hauiaiiensis) is rarer. Due to the introduction of the Brown Tree Snake (Boiga irregularis) on the island of Guam, the Guam Crows and other avian inhabitants of the island have been suffering abnormal mortality rates. In 1984 the crow was one of five species and subspecies endemic to the island which were added to the U.S. Federal Endangered Species list. At that time the population was estimated to be around 50 birds. In September of 1985, Gary Michaels traveled to the island of Guam to conduct a two months study of the species. During his study he documented the species' vocalizations and prenuptial behavior although the one nest observed failed to produce young. The population was estimated, using recordings of crow vocalizations, to be approximately I 00 individuals being composed of as few as three immature birds. Gary's current plans arc to return to the island and further document the species' reproductive behavior and investigate the possibility of establishing the species in captivity. A special subcommittee of the Conservation Committee has been established to deal with this latter clement of the program.Development of a Field BasedPropagation Program for theHispaniolan TrogonInuestigators: Steve Amos, Ke11 Reininger, Jose Dtten uralder.Tacle Clinton-Eitniear and William Hassellispaniola has T:, species of resident land birds, the largest of any island in the West Indies. Twenty species arc endemic to Hispaniola. Charles Woods, Ph.D., a researcher from the Florida State Museum, has conducted extensive research on the I laitian portion of the island and lists nine species of greatest conservation concern. Of the nine, eight arc softbills, the exception being the llispaniolan Parrot. With the majority of species that inhabit tropical forests being softbills, it is of great concern that our ability to deal with them aviculturally is years behind other avian groups such as parrots, waterfowl, pheasants and raptors. A propagation facility centered at the Parque Zoologico Nacional in Santo Domingo will address this issue using the endemic Hispaniolan Trogon (Priotelus roseigaster) as a subject. Birds will be captured under the supervision of Jose Ottenwalder, Director of Zoology, Research and Conservation. A specially designed aviary will be constructed off exhibit near the zoo's spacious walkthrough aviary. Data will be collected as to the ability of the species to adjust to captivity as well as its requirements as they relate to captive propagation. A similar effort began in Belize under the - auspices of the Belize Zoo. It is currently on hold until the relocation of the zoo is completed.Breeding Biologyof the Bahama ParrotPrinciple Investigator: Rosemarie GnamAvian research grants were awarded to Rosemarie in 1984 and 1986. She continues to investigate the ecology and population dynamics of the species and is involved with the development of a comprehensive conservation strategy for the species.Conservation of the Java Hawk-eagle Principle Investigators: Sebastianus Van Balen, Robin ChancellorThis eagle inhabiting the island of Java is unknown to science in terms of its breeding biology (no nest or eggs have been discovered), population dynamics, and ecological requirements. Perhaps only 50 exist in the wild according to a recent short expedition to the island by the principle investigator. Funds provided will allow further investigation as to the species' status and ecological requirements.Status and Conservation of theCape Parrot in Southern Africa Principle Investigator: Andre Basho.ffThis species is considered "vulnerable" in the South African Red Data Book - Birds, and may prove to be an endemic species of South Africa. Funds provided will allow Andre to present his data on the species' status and conservation at the Parrot Specialist group meeting in Brazil as well as to continue his needed studies on the species in the wild.Determination of Preferred Habitat Characteristics of Ocellated Turkeys in Tikal National Park, GuatemalaPrinciple Investigator:Maria Jose Gonzalez FusterThe Ocellated Turkey is a monotypic species with a relict distribution in Yucatan Peninsula (Mexico), Belize, and northern Guatemala. Despite the fact that it is a big, showy bird and a tourist attraction, there is little information on this species' habitat requirements. Its situation is now critical, since Ocellated Turkeys are considered endangered because of habitat destruction throughout its range, and because of their high susceptibility to domestic poultry diseases. Maria will evaluate Ocellated Turkey habitat in Tikal National Park, El Peten, Guatemala. Tikal presents the major types ofvegetation associations that are found in northern Pcten, and harbors the only large, protected population of turkeys in Guatemala. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2735</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 6 (1991): DEC 1991- JAN 1992; 45-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2735/2715</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
