<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4132</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T23:43:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Four-banded Sandgrouse</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thirkhill, Luke</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 48 Number 1 (October 2021).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Captive Breeding of the Four-banded Sandgrouse (Pterocles quadricinctus)There are 16 species of sandgrouse described in the current literature. They range throughout Africa, Madagascar, parts of Europe, The Middle East, India and the central &amp;amp; south Asian plateau countries. They are generally a bird of arid desert, high desert and semi-desert regions and open grassland country. The four-banded sandgrouse (Pterocles quadricinctus) is described as common in the east and west African countries of Mali, Niger, Chad, Sudan, Ethiopia, Ghana, Nigeria, Cameroon, Uganda and Kenya. Few species of sand grouse in general are kept in collections and zoos in the USA. The fourbanded sandgrouse is a rare bird in captivity in American aviculture, and so there have been few opportunities to attempt to reproduce this grouse in captivity and learn more about the bird and its reproductive biology. Perhaps about two dozen birds have been imported into the country in the last...chestnut-bellied sandgrouse (Pterocles exustus) has been kept at the San Diego, Saint Louis and Toledo zoos. Once in captivity, I think it is important to clip the birds’ wings. They will fly straight up when frightened, hitting their head with great force on the ceiling of an enclosure, and then fall to the ground dead, or nearly so. Little breeding data has been recorded on four-banded sandgrouse in the wild. One of the better references in print on all the sandgrouse species, is the book: Pheasants, Partridges &amp;amp; Grouse by Steve Madge and Phil McGowan. More natural history and range maps exist in this book than in many of the field guides to African birds that are out there. In their book, Madge &amp;amp; McGowan say there are only two wild nests described in east Africa, “eggs salmon buff, spotted with orange/brown, one nest had 3 oval eggs and another two”.Hopes for Successful Breeding In 2014, I acquired a pair of the birds from the second group of imports. The three pair imported inMale Note the black &amp;amp; white bands on the head and chest2013 all went to the Tulsa zoo under the care and management of Josef Lindholm III, curator of birds and a friend and colleague of mine. We shared a keen interest in these birds. I set up my new sandgrouse pair as the only ground birds in an African finch aviary and provided a few living bushes, rocks and logs, both horizontal and vertical, to hide under and near. A mixture of small seeds, suitable for doves and finches, were provided along with a typical plastic gallon water jug used for poultry. Small cut pieces of fruit and greens were offered to the finches at ground level, however, I never saw the grouse feed upon fruit or vegetable matter. Only small seeds were taken, such as red and white millet, milo and wheat. In nature they are known to feed on legumes as well, some of which are not “small seeds”. In the spring of 2015, after 8 months in my collection and perhaps a year after...more than on it, and anytime I approached they left the nest. I was unclear if they were still incubating them. The nest was a shallow depression on the ground, behind a large vertical log perhaps a foot in diameter and 6 foot high. They did not nest under a small bush that would have given them more seclu-sion. I later pulled the eggs for artificial incubation. Later they proved infertile or died early during development due to a lack of consistent incubation. The next year in 2017 brought a few more eggs in May with a repeat of what happened the previous year, poor incubation and no hatching. In the breeding season of 2018, eggs were pulled and placed in the incubator with hatching of chicks 24 days later! But I could not keep them alive more than a week, and the following data will describe my various attempts to keep the chicks alive in a brooder with other species as surrogate siblings to stimulate feeding and drinking responses from the tiny sandgrouse chicks.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4132</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 48 No. 1 (2021): Watchbird October 2021; 12-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4132/4092</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
