<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3218</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-31T11:10:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Memorials</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Joseph Roderick Baker Illby Margrethe WardenJoe Baker was born on Sept. 26, 1947 to Joseph Jr. and Lois Patricia (Pat) Baker in Middletown, Ohio. He held a BS in Math from Rensselaer Poly Tech 1969. After graduation, he served four years in the Navy, achieving the rank of Lieutenant. He worked as a systems representative for Burroughs Corp. in Honolulu, HI, until 1980. He then became Date Processing Manager for Kenault, Inc. in Honolulu. He also held management positions with Software Solutions Inc. and DataPhase Corp.In 1987, Joe started Birds of Paradise Aviaries in Kurtistown, Hawaii, and became a well-known name in aviculture. He was a member of the American Federation of Aviculture and for many years served as the State Coordinator for Hawaii. He was also a member of the National Cockatoo Society, Amazona Society, Pionus Breeders Association, Eclectus Society and several others. Joe kept and bred many bird species. His collection included Moluccan, Umbrella, Goflins and Sulfur-crested Cockatoos; African Grey Parrots; Mitred and Finsch's Conures; Scarlet, Blue and Gold, Hahn's and Severe Macaws; numerous species of Amazons; Seriegals; pionus parrots and Hawk-headed Parrots. The Hawk-headed parrots were among his favorites although he had a great desire to work with Blue-eyed Cockatoos. When it came to birds and aviculture, he was a fountain of knowledge that he generously shared with others.When Joe wasn't working with his birds or helping aviculturists with their questions online, he enjoyed playing Bridge. He was a member of the American Contract Bridge League and ran a Bridge group locally every Sunday. He was also a die-hard Moody Blues and Beach Boys fanatic and maintained a large collection of their music and memorabilia. During the last few years, Joe was proud to be a substitute teacher at Keaau High School and Pahoa High School.Joe passed away unexpectedly on February 18, 2009. He is survived by his mother, Pat Baker, an uncle, two aunts, some cousins and his dog, Max. Private services were held in Ohio and his ashes will be scattered in Hawaiii at a later date. He was a devoted son and good friend to many and will be missed.Diana Holloway by Wanda ElderDiana Holloway, a Life Member of AFA, passed away recently.She lived in Bryan, Ohio, and occupied a three-story Victorian home filled with antiques. The third floor was dedicated to her breeder birds. People think of her as an Amazon person and she truly was but had also raised Macaws and Great-billed Parrots. Orange-winged Amazons were her bird of choice.Diana was a retired clinical psychologist but remained active on a family and child advocacy agency. One of her pet projects was a home for battered women. She was extremely proud of the fact that she was a councilwoman on the Bryan, Ohio, City Council for eight years. She would laugh and joke about the "men" who ran against her and lost.She attended her first AFA Convention in 1995 and later served as Regional Director for AFA. Upon the death of James Murphy, she took over the Amazona Society and not only served as President but also made sure the quarterly was produced. She served on the board of the Tanygnathus Society. She was a much sought after speaker on the topic of Amazons or Tanygnathus.She is survived by her husband Bill, and avid golfer and three sons:John,Jacob and Robert. Her first grandchild was born during the 2000 AFA Convention. Both events took place in Los Angeles. She was thrilled to be present for the birth.Aletta Long by Dick SchroederI was quite saddened to learn of the passing of Aletta on March 7, 2009. She was in failing health, and the last time I saw her, actually had lunch with her, at the ASA installation banquet earlier this year, I doubt she recognized with whom she was talking, Alzheimer's having taken control. She was born in south Los Angeles in 1923.Aletta was a great friend to me and to aviculture. We first met in the mid 70s at the AFA convention in San Francisco. I can recall the fun, being led byex-AFA President Lee Horton, as a group ofus wandered the streets of San Francisco looking for a great dinner.Aletta got me to join the Long Beach Bird Breeders, a meeting place 45 minutes from my home in L.A., instead of the IS-minute drive to the South Bay Bird Club. In short order she even had me give a talk on lovebirds to the club, scared to death, the first time I'd spoken to a large group. Before long, I was a board member, eventually becoming president as well as editor. She had a way of convincing people they could do what they did not think they could.Aletta was a great cook and loved to entertain. Long Beach Bird Breeder board meetings at her home were almost a party. The work did get done, but we all ate and drank well.She served many years as AFA Regional Vice President in Southern California, hitting the road to attend as many bird club meetings as she could, touting the benefits ofbecoming an AFA member, both as a club and as an individual. When she finally retired from AF A, she became President of ASA and remained active with the Long Beach club as well.Aletta was a regular at every L.A./Pomona Bird Mart, either working a booth for AFA, and later, for ASA. Her broad smile was as much a part of the place as were the birds. Sel, her husband of 45 years, three children, several grandchildren as well as a number of great grandchildren survive her. Aletta will be missed by the Southern California bird community as well as by all of her friends at "The River," Lake Havasu, AZ, where they had a second home. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3218</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 35 No. 4 (2008): Number 4  2008; 12-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3218/3202</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
