<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/627</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">breeding the Red--rumped Parakeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Miller, Gerda</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Red-romped Parakeet is a finechoice for the bird breeder whowould like to move up from raisingbudgies. There are a few reasons forthis opinion. First of all they are beautifulbirds. The male and female caneasily be distinguished from oneanother, so pairing is quite easy. Themale Red-rump is green and blue onthe head and wings, with a yellowchest, and of course the distinctivered on the rump. The female is muchduller in color, being an olive greenwith no red on the rump.They are quiet and can be raisedeasily in the city without any troublefrom neighbors. They are easy toraise and make good foster parentsfor other birds in their category.Their cost is reasonable, being about$50.00 each from a breeder.Here are a few tips to finding thebest breeding stock possible. It isimportant to buy your birds in earlyautumn so that your stock can beproperly acclimated to their new surroundingand, of course, to their newmates. Buy your birds from a reliablebreeder. Finding a reliable breedercan be helped greatly through yourlocal bird clubs or a veterinarian whospecializes in birds. It's a good idea tolook at the condition of the cages ofthe breeders from whom you considerbuying your stock. They shouldbe clean! You should buy maturebirds of about 9 to 10 months old.Another very important tip is tomake sure your birds are of unrelatedstock.The birds should be healthy. Theeyes of a healthy bird are clear andtheir feathers should be shiny withno signs of plucking. A broken tailfeather or clipped wings are perfectlyfine. These will not affect the breedingcapability of the birds. Thereshould not be any signs of a runnynose or of uneven breathing thatmight be signs of a cold or congestion.The beak of both the male andthe female should show no sign ofovergrowth and should be straight.This is important for the feeding ofthe brood as both parents will feedthe young. The beak should also befree from any scales. -If the breastbone sticks out, this can also be anindication of a sick bird.Now that you have found your newbirds, you are ready to take themhome. I feel that it's a good idea toquarantine any new birds which Ibring home for a short time. If thereis any sickness in these birds, youdon't want it to spread to your presentstock.Their cage should be about 3' wideby 6 ' high by 6 ' long with a wiredflight , pfus draft and rain-free sleepingand nesting area. Except inextremely cold areas, these birds cannormally be wintered outside withoutthe need for special heating.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/627</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 25-26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/627/610</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
