<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1068</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:21:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">QuestionWhat is the benefit of using lactobacillus products for birds while on antibiotics? I am especially interested in this for baby birds. Can it be harmful? How much of which product should I use and how often ? Thanks for your help.S. Tucker, New jerseyAnswer#l:The main benefit of using lactobacillus products for birds is in the profit to the seller. There is no scientific proof that lactobacillus has any benefit to the bird other than creating an acid environment in the intestinal tract. Using a little apple vinegar in the drinking water would work equally well at much less cost to you.James M. Harris, DVM Oakland, CAAnswer#2:The use of lactobacillus products in animals and birds has been controversial. Numerous studies indicate that in some instances giving animals beneficial bacteria is helpful. The most dramatic affects occur when live, speciesspecific bacteria (bacteria that originates from that species) have been given to animals that have compromised immune systems and that have been exposed to pathogens.How these conditions apply to many captive birds, including baby psittacines: we suspect that they are immuno-compromised due to subtle malnutrition and intense management schemes Clots of birds in a small space leading to stress and increased exposure to pathogens). Baby birds, especially those hatched in an incubator which were never fed by their parents, may be especially susceptible to alterations in their intestinal "microflora'' as they are not receiving food from their parents which contains species-specif- ic bacteria. This is because baby birds hatch with no bacteria in their intestines and are susceptible to infections from opportunistic bacteria because they have no beneficial bacteria to combat these "bad guys."Giving baby birds antibiotics can further compromise the bird because antibiotics can reduce the normal level of good bacteria in a bird's intestinal system allowing potential opportunistic bacteria a fertile ground to multiply. In these cases it will not hurt a bird to receive lactobacillus products, unless the product also contains vitamins and minerals which could lead to hypervitaminosis and hyper mineralization. It may not help either as most products contain non-species specific bacteria, especially in the most severe immunocompromised animals under poor management. Possible recommendations include:1. Use viable lactobacillus products (contain live bacteria). 2. Use lactobacillus products that do not contain vitamins or minerals.3. Do not rely on lactobacillus products to "solve all problems."4. Use correct management andnutrition.5. Only use antibiotics when necessary. Do not expose birds unnecessarily to pathogens. (Closed aviary concept).Kim J. Joyner, DMV, MPVM Raleigh, NCAnswer#3:There have been a few studies done in past years in regards. to the efficacy of lactobacillus in birds. The studies basically concluded that lactobacillus products were of no apparent benefit to birds. From these studies and from my own clinical experience and the experience of other clinicians and aviculturists, lactobacillus products can not be recommended as necessary or helpful in birds. It also appears that the use of lactobacillus is not harmful to birds, so if you choose to add it to your treatment regime it should not· be detrimental to the birds either.Amy B. Worell, DMV,. ABVP West Hills, CA </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1068</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 5 (1996): SEPT-OCT 1996; 15-16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1068/1048</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
