<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1963</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-22T04:12:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">las Vegas Convention</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The A.F.A. 1980 annual convention is history. Like any other historical event, each participant will look back and see things in the light of his or her own perspective. The following perspective is that of S.L. Dingle, your humble servant (whose perspective was materially brightened when his wife won a major raffle prize).The affairs of the convention can be divided into rwo parts. First the actual convention activities, meetings, speakers, luncheons, workshops, business, banquets - and second, the off-duty action in the outrageous entertainment capital of the U.S.A., the lights, gambling, fantastic shows, stars, entertainers, wining, dining, dancing.In the latter category Vegas is filled to bursting with luminaries both neon and human. As a frequent Vegas visitor, I learned years ago to favor the neon. I go as an observer and watch the kaleido- the greatest assortment of businessmen, hippies, highrollers, hookers, down-andouters, beautiful women, wide-eyed bumpkins, cowboys, millionaires, and celebrities ever assembled in one place on earth. Puck's pronouncement, ''What fools these mortals be'' was never so aptly illustrated.I acknowledge my failure to participate in this world. Most of my time is spent out in space, as it were, observing the affairs of earth. The real people of this world, on the other hand, enjoyed to the hilt the shows, the grand productions, the excitement of gambling, the sharing of experiences with friends, and the total excitement only Las Vegas can evoke. Such involvement serves as a well earned catharsis to wipe away the mundane cares of every day plodding. Whatever one's pleasure might be, Las Vegas satisfies. The convention goers had a marvelous time in Vegas and the off duty time was well spent. So was most of the Back in the meeting rooms and the banquet halls the convention proper was an equally great success. The committee reports were all expedited with only a little pushing and pulling for fine tuning. The board agreed to some minor A.F.A. reorganization which will be refined in committee and put into effect in 1981. The various budgets were squeezed a little here and trimmed a little there to ensure the financial health of the organization. And, believe it or not, after all these years a Ways and Means committee was formed under the chairmanship of a very capable Mr. Glen Haddock. The A.F.A. is gradually shaking itself into a really strong, healthy national organization that is a definite power in behalf of American aviculture.To my mind the highlight of the whole convention was the luncheon during which representatives of five major organizations met together to focus on areas of agreement regarding birds. The A.F.A. is deeply indebted to Dr. Val Clear for making such a momentous meeting possible. Dr. Clear, representing the A.F.A., presented awards to Mr. Marshal Meyers of the International Bird Institute, Dr. Jesus Estudillo-Lopez of the World Wildlife Fund, Dr. Joe Fontaine, president of the Sierra Club, and Mr. C. Eugene Knoder, director of the Western Environmental Science Program of the Audubon Society.These gentlemen representing millions of concerned people met in private session to work toward a mutual understanding and to focus on areas of accord. Although some differences in method do exist, all agreed that conserving the world's natural environments and wildlife has top priority. A crucial dialogue has been opened that bodes well for the future.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1963</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 5 (1980): OCT-NOV 1980; 16-19</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1963/1934</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
