<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3078</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-18T08:43:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">State Coordinators - Reed and Runnals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baer, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To begin our series of presentations of State Coordinators, I am starting up in the northeast corner of the United States and introducing two of our capable Coordinators from the New England States.Nancy Reed, the Coordinator for the State of Connecticut; and Mark Runnals, the Coordinator for the State of Massachusetts.These two Coordinators are presented together for, like the Bopsey Twins, where you see one at meetings, shows, or other avian functions, you will usually see the other. They have been -taken for everything from sister-brother (flattering to Mrs. Reed considering Mark's extreme youth) to mother-son (not so flattering).This cooperativeness between the two extends to their A.F.A. activities and they are two very good reasons why A.F.A. can be confident that our affairs are being competently handled in their respective areas.Nancy, under forty still (a woman does not reveal her age) is the mother of three children; Co-President of the Conn. Association for A viculture; editor of the National Cage Bird Show, Inc., Bulletin; an authority on Cockatiels; and active in the American Cockatiel Society.Besides the Cockatiels, she has other parrots and an envious collection of trophies which her birds have won for her.At present she is writing a comprehensive book on Cockatiels.Nancy's husband's hobby is photography and we credit him for the accompanying picture.Mark is our youngest Coordinator (twenty-four); a bachelor; President of Western New England Cage Bird Society; and assistant head Horticulturist at Mount Holyoke College greenhouse.His aviculturist interests lie in his collection of Australian Parrakeets, namely: Yellow and Normal Bourkes; Pennant and Golden Mantle Rosellas; Scarlet Chested and Turquoisine Parrakeets; and Pied Cockatiels.A.F.A. members in Connecticut and Massachusetts should feel free to call upon these two representatives of our organization at any time. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3078</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 5 (1977): OCT- NOV 1977; 15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3078/3062</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
