<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2943</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-03T20:21:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Visits a Member's Aviary, Gene Hall</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clause, Sharon F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A nine-acre bird ranch nestled among orchards and rolling hills just west of the Vista/San Marcos area - bears the name Fortune Glen Aviaries. It's hallmark - the remodeled seventy year old barn now serving as an office and display area - is visible from most parts of the glen. Aviculturists living in San Diego's North County speak of its reputation for fine birds and its owner - Gene Hall.AF A visited Gene Hall at his beloved Fortune Glen last Thanksgiving weekend in an attempt to know him as an aviculturist. His accomplishments since settling in San Diego County in 1972 are many. He served as president of the Avicultural Society of America in 1974 and 1975. He was awarded the A VY Award by the AFA in 1977 for his breeding success with Rosellas.As we talked in his office located in the loft of the old barn, Gene reflected on the events which led him to Fortune Glen. Born and raised in Anaheim, California, Gene can't remember a time without birds since his mother always kept at least one pet. He recalled the experience which sparked his own interest in birds: seeing a Walt Disney movie, Bill 'n ' Coo, in 1947. The film included a cast of thousands - of parakeets and peach-faced lovebirds - and starred a pair of black masked lovebirds. Gene left the theatre, and found the object of his search, perhaps the most ancient pair of black-masks Anaheim had to offer. His interest continued through his entire eighteen years in the industrial laundry business.By the time he had raised birds on his residential lot as a backyard hobbies! for eight years, he and his wife, Claudette, recognized that he would only be happy turning his avocation into his vocation. Gene went to Frank Miser of Magnolia Bird Farm, and in effect became an apprentice to the commercial side of aviculture. Finally ready, he and Claudette located their present home, a former chicken breeding farm.Gene believes that he and Claudette founded Glen Fortune together - their teamwork made the realization of their dream possible. For the next eighteen months, Claudette managed the aviaries alone five days a week while Gene worked at the San Diego Wild Animal Park as a gorilla keeper. Meanwhile, five Hall children...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2943</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 2 (1978): APR-MAY 1978; 32-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2943/2927</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
