<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/538</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Desmarest's Fig Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lasarzig, Bill</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This whole fig parrot projectstarted in 1985 and '86 when a friendof mine told me he had acquired fromquarantine some beautiful little birdscalled Desmarest's Fig Parrots. Afterseeing his pair, I immediately madearrangements to acquire a sexed pair.Upon receiving the pair, I had culturesdone and treated them for E.coli. At the same time they weregoing through my 45-day quarantineof all newly acquired birds. I purchasedtwo more pairs in 1986.It is my understanding that thereare basically three subspecies of theDesmarest's found in captivity: P.d.desmarestii, P. d. intermedia, andP.d. occidentalis. I feel it is almostimpossible to differentiate betweenP. d. intermedia and P. d. occidentalis.We can, however, visually identify thedifference between P. d. desmarestiiand the other two subspecies. Thisdifference shows up as a blue coloredband approximately 118 to 114 inchwide across the back of the neck.Technically, this band runs across themid-neck area between the nape andthe hind neck and from shoulder toshoulder.Not knowing too much about thesebirds and their habits, I contactedDale Thompson and we decided thata relatively isolated spot, where thepair would be undisturbed, would bebest. I constructed a 4 ft. by 4 ft. by6 ft. flight of 112" x 3" 12 gauge galvanizedwire. The flight is three feetoff the ground and is supported by2" PVC pipe legs at the corners. Onehalf of this flight is sheltered withplywood on top, sides and back.Perches are at each end and are of3/4" eucalyptus. A multi-anglebranch is placed in the shelter area;this branch has many various sizedperches at various angles and goesfrom floor to ceiling.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/538</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 56-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/538/522</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
