<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/778</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-04T03:20:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Four and a Half Inch Giants of the Parrot World</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Coshow, Nancy R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Parrotlets - the description that 1-most people seem to catch on to is a full-sized Amazon parrot shrunk down to four and a half inches. In a nutshell that's what these unique little guys are. There are several species available in the United States. The two most common are the Pacific (also called the Celestial) and the Green-rumped. Also available, but not in such numbers are the Mexican (also referred to as Turquoise-rumped) and the Blue-winged. Spectacled, Sclater's and Yellow-faced are very rare, if available at all, in the United States. All are small, all are mostly green with size ranging from four and a half up to five and one eighth inches. I have kept (or been kept by, depending on your viewpoint) Greenrum ped Parrotlets for seven years. I started with imported pairs because "back then" I couldn't find any parrotlets, much less domestic, available in the central part of the U.S. The original home of Green-rumped is the northeast portion of South America. This fact is important in taking care of the birds. In the wild, they don't have much variation in seasons or food supply. Their range also overlaps with several other species of parrotlets. As mother nature intended, there seems to be little, if any, hybridization in the wild. In captivity, however, different species can successfully breed with each other. Since we are controlling their lives, including partners for breeding, it is important that we make sure that pairs are set up consisting of the same species. With a type of bird not that well known, there can be confusion. Please research before breeding any bird so that you know you're conserving the gene pool for later aviculturists. In keeping with that thought, let's describe the Green-rumped Parrotlet so you can identify it. Body length is 12 cm (around 4-1/ 2 to 4-3/ 4 inches); the body is a clear green. Males have true blue on their wings, but is placed so that you either have to see them fly or handle their wings to appreciate what a beautiful blue it is. The females do not have the blue on the wing, but the green is basically the same color and she has a yellow wash above her beak. The beak is horn colored with no gray. Sex can be determined as early as the first set of pinfeathers on the wings. With a little practice, you can even sex the babies before the feathers open. The blue is such an incredible blue, it can be differentiated from green while the feathers are still in the pin stage. Green-rumped Parrotlets make wonderful pets. They are small, quiet, eat almost anything, can learn to talk and are happy playing alone or with their people. Caging requirements are simple. Use a narrow bar spacing cage, and, as with any bird, purchase the largest you can afford and will work in your home. Include toys...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/778</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 3 (1994): MAY-JUN 1994; 17-19</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/778/761</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
