<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/34</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-27T19:59:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">DISEASES OF THE RESPIRATORY TRACT A Tale Of Three Sites - Part I</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kray, Raymond</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Anatomically, this system may be divided into 3 sectionsbased on obvious tissue differences ~ upperrespiratory, middle, and terminal sections. The pathologicconditions afflicting these areas, however, are norespectors of boundaries and freely move back andforth as they invade one area, are defeated, retract toanother to increase their strength, and reinvade tocontinue the fight. The invading forces take manyforms, from the almost invisible viruses which mustenter a cell to reproduce, to the prolific bacteriawhich multiply their numbers and swell their ranksby dividing their bodies to form two perfect individualsevery few hours. The fungi and molds (anothernemesis) extend invading tentacles of vegetativebranches to cover an area and then send up fruitingfronds which burst into thousands of air borne sporesto continue an air borne assault on distant tissues.Armored foot soldiers ~ the eight-legged mites, penetrateto the furthest reaches of air saces and pneumaticbones to create pathology and irritation, sneezingand gasping.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/34</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 2 No. 1 (1975): February 1975; 3</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/34/25</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
