<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3649</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-26T04:33:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Message from the President</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Speed, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It seems the winter is slowly losing its grip on the south. The naturalized daffodils on the farm are in full bloom and dot our pastures with the promise of spring. The clover is gaining strength and promises to give my Kubota a real work out the first time I mow. The amazons wonder why I have not gotten their nest boxes ready. And at times I wonder why I put boxes up for pairs that rarely manage to eek out a fertile egg. For me, it is all part of the cycle of breeding birds.APA is busy with spring activities also. We have heeded the continued requests of aviculturists in I 11~he northwest and are very excited to bring our annual educational conference and HOD meeting k ~ t.o Portland, Oregon. This year it will be held July 30-August 2 at the Holiday Inn Portland Airport. The room rate is very reasonable and the hotel offers free Internet, complimentary shuttle service and other amenities. Registration is available online by visiting AFAbirds. org.We will have an exciting and educational slate of speakers. Bob Nelson, legendary breeder of the Quaker Parrot (Myiopsitta monachus) will give the keynote address. He has also received two Avy Awards for first breedings of Poicephalus species. Mr. Nelson presently serves as state coordinator of Oregon.Our convention coordinator is working hard to coordinate Wednesday night activities. Our offsite tours will include the Portland Zoo and the World Famous Rose Garden. As usual, the Lory League will host another successful bird show. APA has a growing representation of young aviculturists and we encourage them to participate in all activities.If you have any questions involving the convention, please contact First Vice President Jamie Whittaker, who also serves as our convention coordinator.I hope to see you in the City of Roses!  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3649</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 1&amp;2 (2014): Number 1&amp;2  2014; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3649/3632</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
