<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/727</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Successful Breeding of the Plum,crowned Pionus in South Africa</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, G.M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Plum-crowned Pionus (Pionustumultuous tumultuous) is a verybeautiful bird, and can be found invery few collections worldwide. As faras I could ascertain, only a handful ofbreeders have been able to reportbreeding activity.In March of 1991, I noticed an advertisementin a local avicultural magazinefor three hens of this species.After a few phone calls, I learned thata group of ten of these birds had beenimported into this country some yearsback. Within a few days, five had succumbedto heat and high humidity. Ofthe remaining five, four turned out tobe hens. The cock was killed later onby flying into the aviary's wire onenight.I bought the hens, and thenlaunched a futile search worldwide inorder to find some cocks. I expectedthis would be difficult, but I neverenvisioned that it would prove to be afruitless venture. Rosemary Lowinformed me about the Pionus BreedersAssociation in the U.S.A., and, aftercontacting Bill Arbon, I learned that afew lone cocks were kept at a fewfacilities. Loro Parque had, for a fewyears, been searching for a hen fortheir lone cock. American legislationmade it impossible (at the time atleast) for an exchange of birds to beeffected.In the meantime, Tony Silva, thenthe curator of birds at Loro Parque,gave me some very valuable informationabout the natural habitat of thePlum-crowned Pionus stating it to bean extremely cold, high-altitude areawith low humidity. I had to make afew adaptations, because the part ofSouth Africa where I live is a semidesertenvironment of about 850 m(2,800 feet) elevation with searing hotsummer days of between 35° and 43°centigrade (95° to 105°F) andextremely low humidity apart from. our rainy months, which are March and April.The birds were kept in a 10 x 1 x 2 maviary, of which half is completelyenclosed with brick walls, a fiberglassroof and an asbestos door. Adjacenttrees and a high hedge blocks directsunlight on 75% of the aviary for halfof the day. An air-conditioner wasinstalled in the closed section, for usein the summer months. A micro-mistspray system provides daily showersfor 30 minutes. They enjoy it all theway.While my worldwide searchwent on, I visited a parrot breeder inJohannesburg, Francois Meiring andhis son Antonie. They have over 400aviaries in their facility. A pair ofPlum- crowned Pionus was shown tome, as well as a few hybrid offspringfrom the cock. At the time they onlyhad a cock, it was paired to a maximilianihen. Francois offered me ahybrid cock in order to have something,and I introduced him into thehens' aviary, a decision that I came toregret and which caused some selfreproach.After co-habitating peacefullyfor seven days, a commotionbroke out one afternoon with all threehens attacking the cock, and, in theensuing fracas, before my eyes, onehen was bitten by the cock and sheflew straight into the wire and diedinstantly. I immediately removed thecock and housed him in an adjoiningaviary. Neither of the hens evershowed any inclination towards him,and I noticed that a ve1y strong bondexisted between the two females.I approached Francois again andmade an offer for the pair of Plumcrowneds.Because his pair had beentogether for some years without showingany interest in each other or thenestbox, he magnanimously acceded- above petty selfishness as his pairwere the only other specimens in thiscountry . </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/727</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 26-28</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/727/710</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
