<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1409</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:53:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Convention Crner</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Davis, Kelly</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">El Nifio has been blowing the United States some nasty weather but those winds are also filling the sails of many aviculturists who are planning to attend the AF A Convention '98 in Baltimore's Inner Harbor. This year promises to be one of the best AF A Conventions ever, as well as one of the major bird events of 1998.The Convention will start with AF A's House of Delegates meeting the morning of Wednesday July 29.The afternoon will offer a tour to the Baltimore Zoo. Air-conditioned busses will take you to the zoo where you will enjoy a barbeque lunch and unique, behind-the-scenes tours of the "waterfowl brooder room" and the African penguin exhibit.Afterwards, enjoy visiting the many other interesting exhibits all afternoon, since admission to the zoo is included in the $25 fee. You'll love the famous outdoor exhibits (home to over 1,200 exotic birds, mammals and reptiles), lush walkways, Victorian gazebos, and an internationally acclaimed children's zoo. In the African Aviary, you will find spoonbills, egrets, storks, and unusual waterfowl. In the Marsh Aviary you'll find many varieties of herons, mergansers, ducks, waterfowl, turkeys, quail, and an assortment of owls. Busses will return you to the hotel when the zoo closes at 5:00 P.M.Zoo tours always offer overwhelming fun and excitement. Register early as the buses fill quickly and no one will want to be left behind on this "safari."Help celebrate Thursday morning at the Ribbon Cutting in the exhibit hall. See and learn about the latest and greatest new products and services that our many exhibitors have to offer. This is the place to see and learn about new equipment, toys and food items. The AFA exhibit hall will have it all.On Thursday night, the AFA is going English. The Wharf Rat Restaurant andBrew Pub is an authentic "English Pub" where locals have always come to meet friends, share ideas, and enjoy wonderful food ... AF A plans to do the same. Come and join us at the Wharf Rat, Thursday July 30th, for a traditional British pub-style buffet dinner and an original "Oliver" Beer. Tickets are $25 and are going fast.The Wharf Rat is owned by Bill and Carol Oliver, both true bird loverseven the restaurant logo is a Greenwinged Macaw. The Wharf Rat is also famous for its own "Oliver Ales" that are brewed on the premises in the age-old English tradition while you watch.Our speaker line up is incredible.AF A will offer the best in both private and institutional bird breeders. And many of our affiliated specialty organizations have graciously sponsored speakers on behalf of their special interests-including Jack Bastiaan all the way from Holland. He is sponsored by the Asiatics Breeders Association. See the following insert for more details on speakers and their topics. Friday night all are invited to the meetings of the Specialty Affiliates of AFA. Many organizations and groups will be hosting two-hour sessions to discuss their favorite family of birds. Looking for networking contacts? This is the place to be.Saturday will be combined with Multi-track seminars and the special Pet Bird Day Seminars, which is being offered for the first time in years. This track will be specially geared toward the pet owner, novice breeder and the aviculturist of tomorrow.To bring Saturday to an end, the Saturday Night Banquet will set the stage for Convention '99. Avy awards will be presented to this year's recipients, and the Grand Auction and Super 10 Drawing will be held. You don't want to miss any of these often one-ofa-kind items offered at the banquet.Sunday will conclude Convention '98 with the PIJAC Avian Certification Seminars from 8:00 A.M.-12:00 noon.Can't wait for more information?Check out our Web Site: www.afa.birds.org/afa/ </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1409</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 3 (1998): MAY-JUNE 1988; 32-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1409/1387</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
