<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1640</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:50:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The "Aru " Eclectus (Eclectus roratus aruensis)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">MacDougall, Linda</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Most aviculturists are aware of the commonly available Eclectus parrot subspecies - the Vosmaeri, Solomon Islands, Grand, and Red-sided Eclectus. Many never have heard of the "Aru" Eclectus, Eclectus roratus aruensis.The Aru Red-sided Eclectus originated solely from the Islands of Aru. The Aru group of islands to the south of New Guinea consists of one very large central island with a number of smaller ones scattered around it. It is an irregular, oblong-shaped island about 80 miles from north to south, and 50 miles from east to west. There are numerous smaller islands, most of which are on the east side surrounding the main island, some up to 10 or 15 miles from the main Island. The Islands of Aru are covered in lofty, dense forest.During phone conversations with a well-known and respected Eclectus breeder, I was told that some of the Aru were brought to the U.S. by missionaries who captured them on the Island of Aru. A few of these original pairs are still in her aviary.Because the E. r. aruensis is listed as a subspecies in Parrots by juniper and Parr, Forshaw's Parrots of the World, and in the Handbook of the Birds of the World- Volume 4 edited by del Hoyo, et al., I accept the Aru as a valid subspecies while recognizing some authorities deem it doubtfully distinct from E. r. polycbloros.The aruensis, on a whole, closely resembles the Red-sided, Solomon Island, and Biaki subspecies. It is only subtle differences in each subspecies that sets them apart.The male Aru is a large bird, rivaling the Vosmaeri subspecies in both weight and length. He is an emerald green, with a slightly lighter hue than the New Guinea Red-sided with subtle blue tints to the head feathers. One of the most impressive differences is the color of the eye on the mature Aru male. It is quite distinct and bold with its almost fiery red color. My Aru male's eyes are noticeably reddish.The Aru male has a longer, stocky body with a rather long tail being tipped with at least half an inch of well defined pale-lemon yellow, while the New Guinea males, on average, have a smaller yellow tail band. The average weight range for the male Aru is comparable to that of the male Vosmaeri, approximately 450-600 grams.The E. r. Aruensis hen is a most magnificent creature. She shares the same basic markings as the New Guinea hen, although her plumage tends to be a bit brighter, even a bit more vibrant, if that is possible. The bright red on her rather flat topped head and her hreast feathers extends downward on the front of the breast to form a deep hih. The feathers below the bib are a bright but deep shade of royal blue, and the females from some areas have a subtle hint of purple. Her creamy white eye is ringed with tiny blue feathers. Aru hens are 100-150 grams heavier and have a longer, stockier body build than the slimmer New Guinea female.About 10 years ago, I decided to acquire a pair of Eclectus Parrots. I knew ve1y little about the species at that time other than how beautiful they were. Over to the hreeder's we went where l walked through their large aviary of mostly macaws and cockatoos, holding my breath until they showed me the pair of Eclectus that was for sale.Sitting on his perch was the most beautiful male Eclectus Parrot I had ever laid eyes on - he literally took my breath away. The sun was shining through the trees as his majesty, appropriately named King Tutt, basked in the bright, warm light. His feathers glowed like fine emerald fur. His beak was an incredibly deep, rich orange and yellow against the green of his face. And then I noticed his eyes - dilated pinpoints of irises glistening in the sunlight, a fiery red hue with highlights hinting of mischief With a graceful flap of his wings he landed on the side of the cage, letting out an ear piercing warning followed by a friendly "Hello." His mate climbed out of her nest box, studying our every move. She too was beautiful although missing her lavender breast feathers. There was no mistaking her Vosmaeri markings with tell-tale tail band of golden yellow. I only knew that these birds were meant to be mine:Once home with my feathered treasures, I got a crash course in incubation with the first fertile egg arriving within just three weeks of their arrival:With fear and wonder that I have rarely felt in my entire life, I placed that little fertile egg in the incubator and did not sleep for the next month. How hlessecl I am that the little embryo grew and hatched under my ever watchful hut inexperienced eye.Little did I know that in a few weeks as the feathers emerged I would discover their offspring was not a pure Yosmaeri Eclectus. The beautiful little female did not resemble her Yosmaeri mother with the daisy yellow tail. Devastated that I probably had hybrid babies, I started looking into the history of my pair. Fortunately they were both easy to trace through the leg hands and I was relieved to learn that both were indeed pure subspecies Eclectus - just not the same subspecies.Beauty is a wild caught Yosmaeri whose age is estimated to be over 25 years, and King Tutt, who sports a Busch Gardens hand, came from a Red-sided Eclectus pair at Busch Gardens. Sadly, on further investigation, Tutt's parents were sold with no records found.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1640</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 2 (2001): MAR-APR 2001; 36-38</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1640/1617</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
