<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/699</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the editor's desk: "B ac k to Basis "</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This issue of Watchbird magazine isthe beginning of a new change for thisavicultural publication. We will bestriving to publish articles on thoseavian species that are of interest to thebeginner aviculturist as well as thoseaviculturists who want information ona more "challenging" species.The Watch bird will begin with thisissue to change its format to graduallyinclude those species of exotic birdsthat are often considered as "breadand-butter" or "domesticated" species.Examples include budgies, cockatielsand lovebirds; Zebra and SocietyFinches, Australian finches and canaries; common Australian parakeets(Neophemas, Red-rumps and rosellas);common doves and pigeons and othermore common parrots and parakeetsas Ring-necked and other commonPsittacula parakeets , conures andlories. We shall also include a rticleson related subjects includinghandfeeding techniques , showingbirds and useful preventitive andhow-to articles.We invite all aviculturists to sha retheir reproductive techniques of these"common" species with others in thismagazine. A guideline for article contentsis available for prospectiveauthors. Please send your articlesand/or requests for article guidelinesto the Watchbird Editors, P.O. Box56218, Phoenix, AZ 85079-6218.Please do not feel we are making acomplete format change. The majorityof each Watchbird magazine willinclude a standard fare of large parrotand zoo articles, exotic finch speciesand softbill articles, endangered speciesand conservation efforts and theother articles and information forwhich Watch bird magazine is noted.We will continue to print specialissues concentrating on certain subjectsor types of birds. The next threespecial issues are: Doves and MixedSpecies Flights (Feb/ Mar 1994), Conures,Brotogeris and Parrotlets (June/July 1994) and Setting Up Aviaries forBudgies, Cockatiels and Lovebirds(Oct/ ov 1994). Editorial copy deadlinescan be found at the vety end ofeach issue of Watch bird magazine forthose who wish to contribute.We certainly encourage your inputand hope you will receive benefitfrom articles on the more "common"avian species. •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/699</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/699/682</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
