<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/469</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the editor's desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The newly approved Watchbird staff (JackClinton-Eitniear, jerry jennings, Dale R.Thompson - editors; Mary jean Hessler- artdirector) wishes to thank those many peoplewho supported us through the recent transition.We have an excellent team with a widerange of expertise. We shall be incorporatingold and new concepts into the Watchbird and,hopefully, we will broaden its scope of aviculturalinformation. We plan to provide asmany special avicuttural interests as possible.Although we will still have an abundance ofpsittacine articles, we plan to have a minimumof one article on the subjects of finches,canaries, gallinacious birds, softbills, dovesand/or pigeons, avian medicine, pet birds,and avian conservation in each issue.This is in addition to the standard informationalready published. These include VeterinaryViewpoints, letters to the editor, centerinsert updates, AFA visits, AFA News andViews, and the classified ads. There will alsobe many additional concepts that will appearin upcoming issues.We invite our readership, all interestedaviculturists and bird lovers to submit aviculturalarticles on the avian subject of yourchoice and interest to the editorial staff Wewould ask for double-spaced, type writtenmaterial with one or more photographs ifpossible. This will greatly aid in our editing.We are looking for the full spectrum of articlesfrom information to aid the beginner todetailed information on specific aviculturalsubjects. We will strive to make this magazinemeet the need or interest of every reader.We have the Board's approval to expand theWatchbird by eight pages in the upcomingissues and ask for your support in making theWatchbird, the best American aviculturalmagazine, even better.Dale R. Thompson, co-editor</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/469</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 2 (1989): APR-MAY 1989; 22-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/469/454</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
