<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/719</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Goldie's Lorikeet</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vanderhoof, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Goldie's Lorikeet is a favoriteamong aviculturists for a variety ofreasons. They are striking with theirbrilliant red cap, plum colored cheeks,and light yellow-green front with darkgreen vertical stripes. The back, wingsand tail are an irridescent forest green.In addition to their beautiful color pattern,these little gems make excellentaviary subjects which may be mixedwith other pairs of Goldie's and/or anassortment of finches, doves andsome softbills. This is a charmingaspect of keeping and breeding Goldie'sfor the vast majority of Loriidaespecies must be housed each pair separatelyin order to keep them fromfighting and quite possibly killingother aviary occupants.Originating from New Guinea, thislittle work of art prefers a tropicalenvironment if possible. However,they are notably hearty. The pairs inmy collection reside outdoors yearround.The temperatures may reach 108° Fahrenheit in the summer and alow of 20° Fahrenheit in the winter.Obviously, they will become acclimatedgradually if given the opportunity.Personally, I handfeed all of theyoung Loriidae produced from anyspecies in the collection. The chicksare parent-fed for 14 to 20 days atwhich time they are removed forclosed banding and handfeeding. Ipersonally do not prefer to feed fromday one unless absolutely necessary.If a pair abandons their nest or will notincubate their eggs then fine, but birdsthat are not given the natural immunitiesand enzymes, etc., from theirparents should not be used as breeders.Another method which I usewhen required is to foster to anotherpair and they will feed the youngstersfor a couple of weeks.Goldie's will begin breeding atapproximately one year of age. In myopinion, the initial problem in succeedingis the difficulty in acquiring atrue pair. Goldie's, as with most Loriidae,are essentially monomorphic.This makes it a real guessing gamewhen trying to tell the difference intheir sex. They need to be surgicallysexed, feather-sexed or DNA-sexed,whichever you prefer. After this hasbeen determined, they will bond andbegin to show signs of reproductiveinterest such as feeding each otherand mutual preening.They will utilize a budgie type nestbox,lovebird size or something ofsimilar size. I prefer to give them an Lshapedbox that measures 5" x 5"square by 12" deep and then measures10' over horizontally for the bottomof the L. The normal clutch sizefor Loriidae is two with a third eggonce in a great while. After 24 to 25days of incubation, if fertile, one ortwo little white fuzzballs will hatch. Bythe way, do not always begin countingthe days of incubation when yousee the first or even the second eggappear. Often times a pair will notcommence to incubate until two tofour days after they finish laying theireggs. I have found that young pairswill usually lay one or possibly twoclutches in a 12 month period. Adultpairs will often give up to five clutchesin a year. Keep in mind that with Loriidae,the breeding season is yearround.They will produce any monthof the year even though hatchingtakes place predominately during thespring and summer months.Goldie's will breed indoors, which isa necessity in most states, but I feel itis best when they are exposed to thenatural elements. They dearly love tobathe and will do so several times aday if given the opportunity.The diet consists of a wide range offoods. They relish fruit of any kind,with some individual likes and dislikes.Nectar is always consumed,especially when feeding young. Theywill eat the dry 1 ory diet as well as avariety of seeds. They are quite fondof sprouted or germinated seed. I'msure that many reading this willexpress surprise when seed is mentioned.The small variety of Loriidaeincluding Goldie's, Meyer's, Iris andMusschenbroek's eat seed and shouldhave some available to them at alltimes.When feeding youngsters by hand, Iuse the commercially available lorydiet that states it can be used as a nectar,fed dry and used as a handfeedingformula. There are several methodsand tools used in feeding the babies.We find, after trying syringes, spoons,etc., that the easiest, fastest and most sanitary way is to use three ounceplastic cups. In each brooder, which isa small plastic aquarium, there arethree or four birds, depending on species.One cup is used for eachbrooder. The cup can then be discardedor placed in a disinfectant tobe used during the next feeding.Handfed Goldie's make exceptionalpets due to their laid-back personalityand calm nature. They will quicklybecome very trusting and, unless mistreated,will continue this bond withhumans for years. The average lifespanfor Goldie's is approximately 12years, although there are alwaysexceptions where some individuals inthe bird kingdom greatly exceed theaverage.In summary, the Goldie's Lorikeet isa quiet, colorful and demure littlecreature whose antics will amuse forhours. Their small size, similar to acommon budgie, and tolerant dispositionallows for easy companionship ina community aviary. Since they are soeasy to care for and prolific in theirbreeding, no mixed collection of avianspecies should be without theselovely parrots. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/719</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 8-9</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/719/702</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
