<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/701</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE: Ten Most Common Pet Bird Accidents (and how we may avoid them)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In this age of birds as popular pets acommonly asked question is "Howlong does this particular species live?""Perhaps years," we will answer, "ifyou provide him with proper nutrition,exercise and watch out fordeadly accident possibilities in hislife."Truly, domestic pet birds live in aworld fraught with danger. The moreimprinted and trusting the babies weraise, the less "wild savvy" they retainto warn and protect them from lifethreatening situations. Here then areour 10 most frequent accidents basedupon nine years experience and thousandsof pet bird encounters.1. Dogs, Cats and PredatorsOutside and inside the house dogscan be instant bird killers. A neighbor'sdog came into the yard. Theporch screen door was ajar; and thebaby Sun Conure was exploring onthe floor. Oops! A free-flying LesserSulphur Crested Cockatoo swoopedlow over a neighbor's fence for thehundredth time and was plucked fromthe air by a new German Shepherd.Oops! Dogs are quick biters and thereforemore dangerous than cats whichmay quickly harm small flutteringpets, but will engage in longer pitchedbattles with a squawking, clawing, bitingparrot that rolls onto its back forself defense. Beware of any dognearby when you have your parrot onthe shoulder. Remember that parrotsliving in a home with a trained,friendly dog are less able to distinguishdangerous dogs. "Bad doggie"(ggrrowlll) is one of the first words Iteach my baby psittacines. Oftensmaller nervous dogs such as dachsundsor cocker spaniels are moredangerous than the larger labradors,shepherds or dobermanns. Malamutesand canines with inbred wildness aredifficult to train around birds. Theseare only guidelines, of course, not fastrules. Puppies and kittens brought uparound birds are quite trainable.One of the most common results ofa bird/cat confrontation is a claw ortooth wound inflicted upon the avianpet. Cats are known for these painful,festering scratches. Even a mediumsized parrot may become sick overnightfrom such a wound; proper veterinarianattention immediately cansave your bird's life. Remember, suchscratches may not be visible at firstglance. Get medical aid.Other predators include raptors(African Grays plucked from the patioperch!), racoons (opened the pet'scage and entered!), mongoose, owls,feral cats and snakes (entered the nurseryand attacked a baby conure in thefeeding tub!).If you have a parrot who spendstime outside in the yard, he will besafer and more secure on a secludedperch or tree with nan.Jral foliage tohide in. Parrots are very insecure withfull open sky above them - eveninside a cage. Pick a leafy bough andplace it on top of the cage for camouflageor hang the cage in a tree.Remember, placing birds in an outdoorsetting is marvelous for theirhealth and well being only if youwatch them closely or train them towatch themselves. Our mle of thumbis one year of training and experiencebefore any unsupervised "tree time."Still it is risky! This is advanced birdkeeping...2. Flying Away-LostThere are two types of lost bird situations:birds kept in doors who escapeand disappear; and birds taken outdoorswho "bolt" or wander off anddisappear. As often as we receive callsabout this; it seems neither mishap is100 percent preventable in today's aviculture.Our choice, therefore, is toprepare our pets as much as possiblefor this eventuality. We teach themcorrect landing and flying skills beforetheir first wing clip. It is amazing howmany times an avian pet will fly off ina beeline away from home simplybecause that is the only flight heknows. He has no skill to hover or flyslowly, no skill to turn sharply; nopractice to keep from gaining altitude;no braking skills; no landing skills.Keeping a parrot without these teachingswhen he is young and in thehouse is an invitation to lose him if heever escapes.Our second lesson is to place thepet's cage outside at an early age sohe can familiarize himself with ourhome environment - sights like thepanorama and horizon, sounds, lighting,colors, wind patterns, etc. Such sensory input awakens the "wild bird"instinct in a young pet. We immediatelynotice an increased attentiveness,observation and caution in ourfledglings - an awareness of greenery,clouds, insects, wild birds, trafficnoise which is indespensable to theirtotal well being. Many times a pet withcage experience in the back yard willescape the house only to be found in afamiliar spot in the yard. One of ourfive-month old Cape Parrot babiespicked the lock on its cage one dayand disappeared. We found it calmlysitting in the back yard on "his" picnictable. Remember that pets who seeenvironments from only one viewpointwill not necessarily recognize afamiliar tree, cage or clothesline fromanother angle. Place your Cockatielcage in six or eight spots around theyard to give her a full spectrum of"knowing" the area.3. Stepping On Bird,Slamming DoorA vast number of our pet birds areraised feeling safe roaming about thefloor of their home. Folks who havethis kind of situation in their homehad better learn to tread lightly! Toomany times will a pet psittacine creepup behind a set of human heels seekingattention or treats. One wrong stepis all it takes. Guests in the home areeven more dangerous. We cage ourparrots when there is a gathering offriends in their accustomed floorspace. It also helps to have an oriental"shoes off in the house" policy;unshod feet are more sensitive andless dangerous to feathered pedestians.Slowmoving, clumsy and severelyclipped birds are vulnerablebecause they cannot move as quicklyto avoid a heavy footfall.Hand in hand with parrots allowedto roam the house is the danger ofhaving a door closed on them. Automaticand spring doors, bathroomdoors, automobile doors all may beabmptly shut on an unsuspecting bird.We've even known flying pets whobecame shut in a door when theirowner was leaving a room and thebird took off to follow. Our parrotshabitually love to perch on tops ofdoors in favorite rooms; so we mustbe aware of both floor level and ceilinglevel hazards.4. EntanglementWith the new generation of "ropetoys" growing in popularity, the needfor caution here is stronger than ever.Parrots love to chew, fray and burrowin ropes, twine, old socks, fabric andfibers. I truly support the makers offine rope chewing toys for the healthand preening habits they encourage indomestic pet birds. It is up to the petowner, however, to be aware thataged and severely frayed rope andcloth playthings are serious threats toour pet birds. Monitor carefully, trimmingoverlong or tangled threadpockets on your bird's playthings. Itonly takes one sharp toenail becomingentangled in a binding thread tostart a twisting motion which canentrap your bird's leg, neck and torsoin the fabric. Wash with fabric softenerwhen necessary; comb and clip. Ourparrots normally sleep in cardboardnestboxes with cloth liners. We usepillow cases, t-shirts and linen linersto avoid nasty frays - especiallyamongst the chewing species such asconures, quakers, poicephalus, etc.Remember any thread nesting materialfor canaries, finches, lovebirds andthe like must be short lengths to avoidendangering these nestbuilders.s. Rolling Onto Pet During SleepIt takes a tmly light sleeper to sharea bed with a pet bird. It is absolutelyessential that a bird be protectedagainst crawling in closely near theirowner and being suffocated. I haveslept with certain baby or ill psittacinesover the years, but I am a lightsleeper with one ear open for rats orpredators in the aviary. These pets arealways kept in a sleeping box upabove my pillow or on a night tablewith a large bath towel over the box toprevent their escape. There is just asmuch joy having your pet bird nearbyyour bed in a cage when youwake up, without the very real dangerof a sorrowful mishap. Even personswho snuggle with their pets for anafternoon siesta must be aware that adrowsy owner lying with an aviancompanion presents a threat to thebird.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/701</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 15-18</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/701/684</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
