<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2878</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-09T15:26:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">American Pigeon Fanciers' Council Celebrates 10th Anniversary This July</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chrisler, Tanner S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Program speakers and meeting arrangements for the Tenth Annual Conference of the American Pigeon Fanciers· Council were announced by Co-chairman, Dr. Earl Hanebrink of State University, Arkansas.The sessions will begin on Friday evening. July 27. 1979, at 7:00 p.m. and conclude on Sunday morning at 11:00 a.m. July 29. Location is the Ramada Airport Inn on Natural Bridge Rd. near LambertSt. Louis International Airport.This Tenth Anniversary conference will have strong international content and will be richly illustrated, Dr. Hanebrink said. Of unique interest will be "A pigeon pilgrimage to Turkey," presented by Dr. W.F. Hollander of Ames, Iowa. Accompanied by the well-known breeder, Bob Pettit. Dr. Hollander spent the month of October in Turkey. exploring the pigeon keeping hobby there - from the larger cities and seaports to the smaller-backcountry towns. Having had a preview of Doc· s color pictures. I can only say that this presentation will be a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity for all serious pigeon students and a real eye-opener for those who pride themselves on knowing about the various breeds of the world. Most of what Dr. Hollander will have to show and tell about will be completely new to American viewers. Pigeons in Turkey are a whole new game, really!Bob Pettit of Geneseo, Illinois, will present "German Fanciers and Lofts" with color slides made on his way back from Turkey. Having previewed these also, I can promise you a fascinating visit to a number of the finest lofts of show pigeons in many breeds - numerous varieties of Pouters, Modenas, Kings, Saxon Color Pigeons, and others. And Mr. Pettits photography is of extraordinary quality.Dr. John Ervin, who spent the last four years in Germany with the U.S. Army, will present "Pigeon Shows in Germany." Known to many as the "Questions and Answers" columnist in the APJ, Dr. Ervin became familiar to the fanciers in that country as the Kojak of pigeons. American fanciers will recall that Dr. Ervin was one of the founders of our Rare Breeds Pigeon Club, and it is fair to assume that he will have a fine collection of photos to show and tell about.For those interested in color genes, David Rinehart of Tallmadge, Ohio, will make an illustrated talk on "Indigo Coloration - Usual and Unusual Cornbinations." Mr. Rinehart is editor of "Pigeon Science and Genetics Newsletter," so you can be assured of a higher level of expertise in his presentation.The list of speakers is not fully completed; however, the following men will be on the program, discussing the topics named. Dr. John L. Skinner of Madison, Wisconsin, "Wisconsin's Approach to Informational Programs for Pigeon People." Ron Davis of Peoria, Illinois, "Common Pigeon Sense." Dr. L.E. Hummel of Bonne Terre, Missouri, "Pigeon Experiences in Foreign Lands." Mr. Guenter Wenzel of Grant Park, Illinois, "Importing and Exporting Pigeons." And Mr. Tanner Chrisler of St. Louis, Missouri, "The History and Purpose of the American Pigeon Fanciers' Council."The names and topics of six additional speakers who will be on the program of the American Pigeon Fanciers' Council's Tenth Annual Conference were announced by Dr. Earl Hanebrink of Arkansas State University. Co-Chairman. The APEC is the organization brought together by Frank Hollmann and Thelma Snyder at the suggestion of Wendell Levi, in 1970, to serve the interests of all branches of the pigeon fancy.Of special interest to his many fans will be the appearance of Joseph W. Quinn, Atwater, Ohio, former editor of "Pigeon Genetics Newsletter" and author of "The Pigeon Breeder's Notebook - An Introduction to Pigeon Science." Mr. Quinn, who gave one of the most inspiring talks in the annals of the APFC in 1973, has come out of hibernation, so to speak, to take part in this Tenth Anniversary program. His subject will be "Feathers and Things to Corne;" but those who know Joe Quinn - even slightly - know that he will fulfill the role of a keynote speaker. Those who don't know Joe Quinn - or maybe never heard of him - should be informed that to hear Quinn do his thing at a podium is worth a thousand mile trip, regardless of all the other attractions on the program.And there will be many other attractions. One speaker will appear twice:LaYerne Schumann of Davenport, Iowa. Mr. Schumann's topics will be: (I) The Schumann Family Loft and (2) Pigeon Fanciers of Belgium, Great Britain, Taiwan, Thailand and Hong Kong, which fits into the international flavor of the presentations announced earlier. The "fanciers" Mr. Schumann will discuss are racing pigeon breeders. and his talks will be illustrated with slides.Johnnie Blaine, well known columnist and publisher on Tumblers, will present one of his favorite subjects, "Pigeon Color." Mr. Blaine has a real gift of being able to explain the technical part of color breeding in layman's language, and what he has to say is just as applicable to other breeds of pigeons as it is to his.Clair Hetland, who is familiar to many breeders as the proprietor of Foy· s Pigeon Supplies, will discuss "Pigeon Medications." Mr. Hetlands expertise on the subject comes not only from many years as a succesful breeder of Bokhara Trumpeters, but from his training and career as a professional pharmacist.Richard Burger of Laurel, Maryland, one of the founders of the American Dove Association and long-time columnist, will present his subject "Doves." Mr. Burger has a depth of experience in fancy breeds of pigeons, and it will be interesting to learn from him the similarities and the differences between domestic pigeons and wild doves, as he has experienced them.The latest speaker to join the APFC's Tenth Anniversary conference is a · 'junior " by age; however, his subject and what he has learned about it are certainly as mature as anything else on the program. Todd Gavin, 18, of Mankato, Minnesota, is a breeder of Homers, Kormorners and Rollers, and he had been experiencing a drop in fertility, which he believed was due to many generations of inbreeding. He kept careful records over a three year period, giving a commercially produced · 'complete ration" with and without a heavy dosage of vitamin E. The first year, no supplement. The second year with the supplement. The third year without the supplement. After organizing the data, he presented his conclusions in the form of a paper and exhibit at his high school's Science Fair. He won a top award and was invited to bring his exhibit to the state competition. The winners of the state were asked to go to the International at San Antonio. At the time of this writing, Gavin's exhibit had not made the top twelve from his state, but he had been invited to make the trip to the International Science Fair, anyway, as a notable honor, expenses paid.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2878</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 3 (1979): JUNE-JULY 1979; 40-41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2878/2862</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
