<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/720</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Understanding Your Doves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vriends, Matthew M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Doves in the WildPigeons and doves belong to theavian order Columbiformes and, withthe exception of the polar regions,they inhabit almost every comer of theearth, though the "headquarters" ofthe group seems to be the Orientaland Australasian regions. There is noparticular scientific basis for the separationof the words "pigeon" and"dove" though the former is often colloquiallyapplied to the domestic andlarger species, the latter to the smallerspecies. Of the 305 or so describedliving species, size varies from littlelarger than a sparrow to larger than anaverage domestic hen. There aresmall, dainty seed eaters and plump,robust fruit eaters. However, all doveshave many anatomical features incommon and the group is quite homogenous.Looking generally at a dove, forexample, the head is relatively smallin relation to the body. The beak isalso relatively small, short, narrow,and slightly bent down at the tip. Thesoft, sensitive, fleshy cere at the baseof the bill is devoid of feathers. Onlyin the fruit eating doves are thenostrils in the cere wide open and easilyvisible. The legs and feet usuallyhave three forward, sturdy toes andone smaller hind toe each providedwith short, strong nails. The legs andfeet are usually clearly scaled. In general,doves are either long and slenderor short and plump, depending on thenatural habitat. Various dove speciespossess so-called powder feathers.With the beak and the head, theycover their outer feathers with a verythin layer of protective powder. Alldoves have a well developed crop,but the gall bladder is absent; the appendix is rudimentary or altogetherabsent.The choice of habitat varies fromspecies to species, ranging fromdense, tropical rainforest to dry, ariddesert or the temperate regions ofEurope, Asia and North America.The range of colors is also quiteremarkable: from milky white withblack tipped flight and tail feathers(Nutmeg Pigeon, Ducula bicolor) toblue-gray and white with a strikingred breast-patch (Bleeding-heartDove, (Gallicolumba luzonica). Variousspecies are extremely attractive intheir pastel or metallic shades of gray,fawn, blue, pink, green and yellow.In spite of these variations, allspecies have many characteristics incommon. The whirring sound of thewings on takeoff is a trademark of alldoves, as is their ability to suck upwater through their short beaks in along draft, rather than scooping andthrowing their heads back as mostother birds do.Doves feed largely on seeds, berriesand other fruits, green leaves andshoots, spiders and various insects.They often travel great distances foragingfor food for their young. Thegreen pigeons (Treronidae) and thefruit eating doves (Duculidae) (whichare seldom kept in captivity), arewholly specialized in eating fruits andberries, while the tropical grounddoves (Gallicolomba), to which theBleeding-heart Dove (G. luzonica)belongs, forage for insects, spiders,worms, slugs and other invertebrateson the forest floor. The consumedfood accumulates in the crop, a part ofthe alimentary canal that, in doves,forms a double sack. The main func tion of the crop is food storage but it isprobable that pre-digestion also takesplace here. During the breeding periodwhen young are being reared, anourishing material is produced byrupture of the surface cells of the croplining. This so-called "crop milk" isessential for the rearing of the youngsters.Doves possess two stomaches; afore stomach or proventriculus, and amuscular stomach or gizzard (or ventriculus).The gizzard grinds up theharder seeds with the help of grit. Thefruit eating species have a speciallydeveloped digestive tract in which thefore stomach is extremely large, thegizzard thinly walled and the intestinesrelatively short.Pigeons and doves are fairly muscular,and thickly covered with a coat offeathers that, however, are looselyattached in the skin. The base of thefeathers is downy to provide goodinsulation. Unlike many birds, dovesdo not tuck the head under the wingwhen resting, but pull it downbetween the shoulders.All members of the Columbiformesare monogamous which is to say thatthey mate for life and remain true totheir mates unless they are separatedpermanently by some unforeseenevent. Their flimsy nests consist of aplatform fashioned from a few twigsplaced loosely among the branches ofa tree or shrub, or on a rocky ledge. Inmost cases, the clutch consists of justtwo eggs, sometimes only one. Theeggs are usually a glossy white, but afew species lay tinted (brownish)eggs. In most species, both cock andhen share in nest-building and incubation,but the hen usually performingmost of the latter. The time of incubationvaries from 13 to 19 days. Thehatchlings are blind and naked andare fed by the parent birds on a specialdiet known as "pigeon or cropmilk" which consists of a mixture ofpartially digested food and a curd-likesecretion from the crop lining (thedove's crop lining thickens duringincubation). It takes 12 to 20 days forthe young to develop sufficiently forfledging.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/720</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 10-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/720/703</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
