<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/691</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bulbuls</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rishman, Grant</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Few birds can have made such acontribution to softbill aviculture asthe 120 species belonging to thebulbul family. They are very hardyand are quite easy to manage. TheRed-whiskered Bulbul is undemandingand. makes a perfect bird for thebeginner, while there are also muchrarer species to interest the moreexperienced aviculturists.Bulbuls have a wide distributionthroughout tropical Africa and Asia,with some species venturing as farnorth as China and Japan in the eastand southern Turkey in the west. Theyare usually found inhabiting lowlandand hill jungles, gardens and evergreenforests. Some species ascendthe mountains to about 13,000 feetwhere they are often found movingthrough the trees in mixed speciesflocks with small babblers. Some speciesare very familiar, living in parksand gardens, while others are verysecretive living in dense forests.The African bulbuls are just as commonas their Asian cousins in the wildbut appear to be much rarer in captivity.The exporters from Africa tend toconcentrate on the more beautifulfinches and exotic reptiles.When compared to other softbillsthe bulbuls are quite somberly colored,many have crests and showshades of brown, olive and yellow.However, it is their industrious,inquisitive and friendly nature thatmake them so popular in captivity.Many have pleasant little songs, whileothers are quite noisy and chatter constantly.When not breeding, thesmaller species can be safely housedwith other birds and I have evenhoused them with small finches.Someof the larger species, such as the BlackBulbul, need to be checked foraggressiveness in almost any mixedspecies flight.Bulbuls are classified as "fruitbiasedomnivores" and will thrive on adiet that includes various soft fruits,berries, soaked mynah pellets, insectilemix and insects. Some fanciersargue that they are frugivores and only require fruit, however, I feel theywould all suffer from malnutrition ifmaintained purely on fruit for anyextended length of time. They do notlike descending to the ground so allfood and water should be offeredfrom a platform a few feet up.Members of this family are amongthe easiest softbills to breed but theyshould not be compared to the seedeaters.Although their breeding stimuliare still largely unknown, more informationwill hopefully become availableas more aviculturists specializewith this family. One major problem isthat they are almost impossible to sexvisually. As a general rule, the malesare slightly larger and broader thantheir mates. This is not a very reliablemethod as it does not take intoaccount the various subspecies.When serious breeding is attempted,it is best to house each pairseparately in a planted aviary. As themale displays he can be seen sittingnext to his mate with his crest helddown against his head and with hiswings and tail lowered. The sound hemakes could be likened to the"meow" of a cat. If they are housedwith smaller birds, in the breedingseason the male bulbul may becomeoverly aggressive and if they arehoused with larger birds they areoften intimidated themselves.My bulbuls have always built ashallow nest near the aviary roof(about seven feet up). The nest is aloose structure consisting of grass andcoconut fibre. There are some reportsof nest boxes being used, but this hasnot been the case in my experience.The two or three, sometimes four, offwhiteeggs are almost one inch longwith the blunt end being covered indark reddish markings. The hen doesmost of the incubating but the malemay relieve her occasionally. Thebrooding bird lies very low in the nestwith its crest held flat against the headand may easily be overlooked.The eggs hatch after 12 to 14 days.For the first two or three days theadults will feed only livefood which isswallowed and then regurgitated tothe chicks. From three days onwardsthe livefood is carried back to the nestin the parent's bill and is fed direct tothe chicks. Large quantities of suitablelivefood (mealworms, crickets, caterpillars,etc.) should be supplied at thistime. The young develop quickly andfledge after two weeks. At this timethey are being fed the adult diet andremain dependent on their parents foranother 2-1/2 weeks. When they areindependent they should be removedfrom the breeding aviary before theyare attacked by the adult male. Two orthree nests in a season are notunusual.The following paragraphs containdescriptions and other information onsome of the interesting members ofthis family.Red-whiskered Bulbul(Pycnonotus jocosus)Eight inches long; bill black; headand crest black; cheeks white with ared ear patch superimposed; upperpartsbrownish grey; throat white;undertail coverts red; legs and feetdark grey. Sexes similar.This common bulbul has five differentraces coming from India. Threehave white tips to their tail while theothers lack these markings. It is themost frequently bred member of thisfamily and usually raises its youngwithout too much difficulty. They arevery hardy and can overwinter withminimal heat. Other names: Red-earedBulbul.Red-vented Bulbul(Pycnonotus cafer)Eight inches long; bill black; crestand throat black; cheeks brown;upperparts and breast dark brown, thefeathers are edged with white whichgives a scale-like appearance; abdomenwhite; vent area red; legs and feetdark grey. Hen is slightly duller.Another ideal softbill for the beginner,they are very hardy and easilymaintained. These birds are cheerfuland confident, quickly becoming tameand confiding. Their song is the same- cheerful and confident - and not toomelodious! This spec-ies may use awooden box or basket when breeding.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/691</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 56-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/691/674</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
