<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4076</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:17:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Philippine Cockatoos and Other Parrots in Palawan</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Waugh, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 1 (January 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Philippine Cockatoos and Other Parrots in PalawanRare is the short-term conservation project, because most situations which call for conservation measures are only tackled effectively with a long timehorizon. New obstacles constantly appear which must be surmounted with a fusion of tenacity, ingenuity and resources to fit the task. Such is the case with the endeavor to save the ‘Critically Endan-rule, genetic diversity is lost from populations which at some point in time have been reduced to small numbers of individuals, and this can endure even after a population has subsequently increased in size. This is called a genetic bottleneck. Until recently, no genetic studies aimed at quantifying genetic diversity in the populations protected by the PCCP hadbeen undertaken. However, a recent study (Que et al., 2020) by the KFI team and colleagues at the University of the Philippines has genetically analysed blood and feather samples obtained from the four sites in Palawan, and has added information from a previous genetic analysis of material originating from a museum specimen. They examined two genes, called ND2 and COX1, found in the DNA located in the mitochondria (mDNA), which is passed only from mother to offspring. For ND2, 101 individual Philippine Cockatoos were analyzed, and the museum specimen result added. This analysis found eight haplotypes. A haplotype is a group of DNA variations, or polymorphisms, within an organism that are inherited together from a single parent. For COX1, 103 individuals were successfully analyzed, revealing only three haplotypes. Integrating the analysis of ND2 and COX1 for 100 individuals resulted in...The Philippine Cockatoo , also known as the Red-vented Cockatoo, is about the same size and shape as the Goffin’s cockatoo but has a distinctive red patch under the tail feathers known as the undertail coverts.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4076</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 1 (2022): Watchbird January 2022; 28-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4076/4036</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
