<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/606</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Arizona Seed Crackers Society Halfmoon Conure Breeding Consortium</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clifton, Gary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">What makes the ASCS HalfmoonProject unique isn't the structure ofthe consortium nor the species beingbred. Indeed, the pet trade almostregards Halfmoons as a junk species,and the zoological community hashad great successes in organizinggroup efforts based on the consortiumconcept. What sets the ASCSproject apart is that this appears tobe the first time a small, local birdclub has taken on a project of thismagnitude. The project is intendedto maintain a viable , geneticallydiverse population of Halfmoon Conuresin captivity over a minimumperiod of SO years. During this periodwe hope to supply surplus birds forthe pet trade and interested aviculturistswho wish to work with this speciesoutside of the closed populationunder consortium management. Inspite of numerous ' ' interesting challenges"that have included bothavian TB and macaw wasting syndrome,in just over a year the projecthas gone from brainstorming sessionsto producing its first offspring.Probably the best place to begin iswith a bit of background on ASCS,then answering the obvious questionsof ' 'Why Halfmoon conures?"and ''What's a consortium?" ArizonaSeed Crackers Society is a small, localbird club that meets monthly inMesa , Arizona . The membership isaround 100, consisting primarily of" backyard" breeders who take a vicultureseriously even though it isn 'ta major part of their income. ASCSdoes care about conservation and, asa club, began to feel the need to ''dosomething" ourselves rather thansimply raising money for someone else to throw at the problem.Some things were obvious from thebeginning. No one in the club is acompetent field biologist, few if anymembers could afford to travel out ofthe country to do field work, butmost members had experience raisingsmall hookbills. A long-termbreeding program seemed the idealchoice as something ASCS could dothat would utilize the experience andabilities of its members. The only rolemodels we could find were the AFARed Siskin project and the AAZP ACuban Amazon Consortium. Weborrowed heavily from the CubanConsortium in structuring our groupand how it would operate, thenbegan the task of determining aspecies to be the subject of ourefforts. We finally settled on the HalfmoonConure Aratinga canicularisclarae.We considered a number of factorsin choosing the Halfmoon Conure,particularly the A. c. clarae subspeciesas our subject. We wanted aspecies that was common enough tobe available, yet rare enough to havean uncertain future in American aviculture.We did not limit our considerationto those species immediatelychallenged by dire threats in the wild.Price of initial stock was also a considerationas we were and still areoperating with limited funds. Obviouslythe cheaper the bird, the morewe could afford. We felt it mandatoryto select a species that at least somemembers had direct experience withbreeding, just as we felt the selectedspecies must be one with which westood a reasonable chance of successfulbreedings. We felt we had tochoose a species that would allow asmany members as possible to participate,that is we ruled out anythingwith unusual dietary or maintenancerequirements as well as particularlyloud species. Many of our participants,for instance, could not accommodatea breeding pair or p_airs oflarge macaws without seriouslyoffending the neighbors.We contemplated African finchspecies, Gold-capped Conures, RedthroatedConures, Sierra Parakeets,parrotlets, Goffin's Cockatoos and afew other suggestions, but finallydetermined the Halfmoon Conurecame closest to meeting our requirements.We felt we didn't have sufficientexperience nor interest amongour membership to work with thefinches, nor enough room andmoney for cockatoos. Some of theparrotlets appeared to be at leastbarely established, others unobtainable.Several of our members hadexperience with Halfmoon Conures,and a few still worked with the species.We also noticed a few morethings about Halfmoons. They havelost popularity in the pet trade, beingdisplaced by more colorful and moreglamorous species such as suns andjendays.Halfmoons are also a popular specieswith the smugglers; there areusually a number of Halfmoons availableat auctions when USDA sellsconfiscated birds. An examination ofthe literature from years gone byrevealed the Halfmnoon's popularitywhen huge numbers were legallyimported from Mexico, and mostauthors were quick to praise the species'pet qualities. When Mexicohalted exportation, other inexpensivespecies were imported to fill thevoid in demand but few aviculturiststook an interest in breeding Halfmoons.The result has been a steadydecline as the years have gone by.The ASCS Consortium has found thatprice averages around $100.00 perbird, and that stock is available periodicallyif one is willing to hunt for it.While A. c. clarae doesn't appear tobe facing serious threats in the wildat this time, no one knows what thefuture holds. In captivity, we feel ourconsortium will be the determiningfactor that ensures long-term survivalof this species in the U.S. Once wehave obtained enough founder stockand generated enough first generationpairs to bring our total populationup to a stable size, we expect togenerate surplus birds yearly. Weexpect to sell this surplus into thepet trade to help fill a market demandthat is currently being met, at least inpart, by smuggled birds.Having covered a little backgroundon ASCS and "why Halfmoons?" thenext areas to address are ''What is aconsortium?" and "How can othergroups start one?" A consortium isbasically a cooperative group efforttowards a common goal. In the caseof the ASCS Halfmoon Project, theConsortium is a little bit like a corporationwholly owed by the cluband operated as an independent subsidiary.ASCS owns the initial founder stockand the Consortium, the Consortiumowns half the progeny. The Consortiumis operated and managed by itsparticipants rather than the ASCSBoard of Directors. Participants elect a management group who makesdecisions regarding the operations ofthe project. All birds in the populationare under the direct control ofthe management group, though participantsare free to do as they wishwith their share of the offspring. Thisis perhaps the most critical issue tothe successful management of a captivepopulation. The populationmust be group owned rather thanbeing a collection of privately ownedbirds.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/606</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 15-17</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/606/589</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
