<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1065</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:21:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Stunted Macaws</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abramson, Joanne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Stunting is the most common problem seen in handfed parrots today. Many aviculturists, for a variety of reasons, are not able to recognize this insidious development in their handfed nestlings until much more serious problems have evolved. Stunted birds are most likely immunologically weakened and more susceptible to infectious disease than normally developed birds. Permanent physical deformities may plague the bird for the remainder of its life, including inadequate or deformed skeletal systems, beak deformities, inadequate psychological development, damaged or poorly developed internal organ systems and questionable reproductive capabilities.When a bird is stunted from inadequate amounts of food or the lack of a nutritional food, the head grows disproportionately large for the rest of the body. Thin extremities (toes and wings) are a common pediatric symptom. Hyacinth Macaw adolescents have been seen the size of young Scarlet Macaws. One bird was at least 450g undersized for a Hyacinth. There are variations in size of birds (just as in humans) but there should not be a huge difference between the nestlings and their parents. Hyacinths, Green-wingeds and Buffon 's are commonly seen stunted birds due to their higher weights. Novice handfeeders or those used to smaller macaw species are especially likely to incur stunting, but it can occur in any handfed bi.rd.Macaws should be increasing the amount they are eating every few clays or, minimally, each week while in their growing stage. As their weights level out and they start eating weaning food, the amount of formula they need decreases. On the large macaws this does not occur until they are over 50 to 60 days old, and in the case of a Hyacinth 70 to 80 days old. We do not know yet whether stunting has any effect on the bird's ability to reproduce.The human induced metabolic condition is the result of one or all of the following conditions:1) Nutritionally deficient diets.2) Insufficient amount of food; Low volumes of formula. Inadequate number of feedings per day.3) Medical condition preventing the normal dige tion and absorption process,low grade toxicity (visceral or articulargout, vitamin D3 toxicity),bacterial infection (Candida, E. coli),viruses (papova, chlamydia) andtrauma, e.g., burned crop.The Three Stages of StuntingEarl y stage: These birds are not beingsupported nutritionally (or possiblymedically) to allow them to reach theirgenetically predestined size. lf theircondition is recognized in time, their retardeddevelopment ca n be correctedand they will achieve their normal size.Early detection of stunting can be determinedby experienced hanclfeederswho review their bird' weight recordsdaily and compare them with previouslyrecorded normal growth datafor th e species being handfed. Unfortunately,inexperienced handfeeders maynot keep weight records or have no datato compare their bird's weight with.Consultations with other aviculturistswho have bred the species will be essentialto newcomers who might otherwisefail to catch stunting in this earlystage.Intermediate stage: Characteristically,the head and feet remain close to normalsize but the body size is more seriously affected.111e body is stunted in both lengthand girth. Most intennediate stage birdssurvive. Not being adequately fed producesbone structure that does notreach its genetic potential and is oftenaccompanied by distortion of the skeleton.The majority of this ection will dealwith this group of birds.Advanced stage: These birds are soextremely underfed that they are grosslydeformed. Severe nutritional problemshave occurred which might also be accompaniedby opponunistic secondaryinfections such as Candida or E. coli.These birds generally die befo re theyreach the feathering stage.Stunting can occur in any species,however the likelihood increases in thelarger parrots such as Amazons, cockatoosand macaws because of the largervolumes of food required for normalgrowth. In the hands of inexperiencedhandfeeders these birds are oftenweaned many weeks before nature intended.For instance, 22 to 26 weeks isaverage length of time to wean a HyacinthMacaw at Raintree Macaws.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1065</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 5 (1996): SEPT-OCT 1996; 10-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1065/1045</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
