<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/512</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Notes from the Aviary... Breeding the Goffin's Cockatoo</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Murphy, James J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I was first captivated by this smallwhite cockatoo in the late 1970swhile attempting to gain some insightinto their social behavior. This modestbeginning left an indelible mark. Iwas amazed at what I observed inthese birds and decided to make theGoffin's cockatoo a long termproject.This little cockatoo is slightly sexuallydimorphic. The iris of themature male remains the juvenileblack, while the adult female has areddis':l brown iris. In addition, themandibles of the male are noticeablylarger than those of the hen. Thelarger mandibles of the male arenoticeable at only a few months ofage.Although Goffin's cockatoos arestill imported in large numbers, theirsmall island habitat is being rapidlyaltered by humans and their chainsaws. The remaining natural habitaton the Tanimbar Islands, north ofAustralia , is rapidly diminishing.Captive propagation is the only wayto ensure their continued long termsurvival.The following information is notmeant to establish a standard butrather a description of some of whatwe have done and observed over thepast dozen years.The little Goffin's cockatoo hasfrustrated many accomplished aviculturistsattempting to breed them. Aswith many difficult to breed species,the problems are often buried deep inthe evolutionary social structure ofthe species. Without the minimalexpression of critical social patterns,reproduction is often nil. This verycomplex and controversial arena isoften, understandably, ignored orglossed over by many top zoologicalfacilities.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/512</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 4 (1989): AUG-SEPT 1989; 36-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/512/496</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
