<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/712</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">EX LIBRIS: Parrots: Their Life in the Wild</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Arndt, Thomas</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A unique parrot book. Parrots -Tbeir Life in the Wild was first publishedin German in 1986 by HorstMuller-Verlag Walsrode. The authorwas Thomas Arndt, an author of manyparrot books and editor of Papageien(translated Parrots), an excellent Ge rmansubscription magazine on parrotsboth in captivity and in the wild.Both Dale Thompson and RainerErhart were given copies of the Germanversion of this book and bothrealized that this book was writtenstrictly on parrots in their natural habitats.It had information that was notcommon knowledge to most avicul turistsand parrot lovers . They bothfelt it should be translated to English.A team was then formed to translatethis book from German to English andlater "Americanized," as straight Germanto English translation can bequite confusing. Two translators ,Rainer Erhart and Renata Decher,were used with Dr. Erhart doing thebulk of the work. Dale Thompsoncoordinated the team with Janet TasjianHanson doing the vast computerwork. The English translation of thisbook became available in the U.S . inDecember 1992.Parrots - Their L?fe in the Wild givesa vast amount of information on parrots' natural feeding , nesting andmany other behaviors in the wild . Itincludes many other types of informationsuch as "Why are parrots so colorful?"Each chapter is, indeed , verydetailed. For example, the majorchapter on "What is the breedingbehavior of pa rrots?" This chapterincludes sections on choosing a partner,the Casanova , the first clutch,courtship display, the nest and theeggs, nesting in tree cavities, parrotsnot nesting in trees , nesting inmounds, nest builders, ground nesters,the clutch, the nursery and poorparenting. This chapter alone hasgreat insight to natural nesting thatcould be very helpful to aviculturists.Just about every type of parrot, fromlories to Amazons, is mentioned inthis book. The concluding chapter ison "Why are parrots endangered?"including several species profiles. Thefollowing is a quote from the primarytranslator of this book who would certainlyknow it well.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/712</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/712/695</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
