<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3290</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-06T16:46:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Message from the President</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Speed, Nancy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">What hat do you wear best? Have you ever thought about the different hats you wear in life? I have a variety of hats on my hat rack. There is one for the family; one for the birds; one for the dogs; one for the horses; one for the lawn mower; one for church ... the list continues. Each hat brings with it a different task and expectation.At times I am forced to prioritize and choose one hat over the other. The birdhat always has priority during baby season. Sometimes I even delegate and lend certain hats out to responsible helpers. At times I actually try to wear more than one hat ata time. Ifl attend a dog event and have neonates, I have to find room on my head for two hats.AFA, too has many hats on its ever-revolving hat rack. When I am at AF A board meetings, I visualize hats of all types and sizes worn by our dedicated board members. There is the CFO hat; the education hat; the legislative awareness hat; the conservation hat; the disaster relief hat; the convention hat; the publications hat; the membership hat; the media services hat and the specialty organizations hat, just to name a few.The table holds hats that have yet to be named. Sometimes a board member may try a hat that doesn't fit well. If a hat is too tight it causes a headache. No one can be productive with a headache. If a hat is too big, the brim falls over the eyes and a great thought or idea becomes clouded in blindness. It might take find a hat with a really good fit. A hat with an excellent fit usually reflects the passion and interest of the person wearing it.As an AFA member, you might have occasion to try on a few of our hats. One we must wear at all times is the one that promotes aviculture. Because we all share a genuine admiration and respect for birds, the hat that promotes aviculture is a hat with just the right fit. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3290</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 39 No. 1 (2012): Number 1  2012; 4-6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3290/3274</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
