<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/735</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE: Parrots for Dollars: A Peek at Parrot Marketing</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of all the tasks associated with theAmerican parrot trade, perhaps themost frustrating and difficult is themarketing of successfully raised psittacinebabies.We aviculturists can be extremelyproud of the progress we have madethe past decades in the production ofhookbill offspring in captivity. Certainly,recent entries into the fascinatingworld of psittaculture owe aheartfelt "thank you" to the dedicatedexperts who have freely providedtheir wisdom and guidance that wemay all be able to keep and raiseexotic bird species.Looking to the future, it appears weare entering a golden period when theavailability of parrots to the hobbyistand pet owner may reach record proportions.Realistically, we cannotexpect this to last very long as genepools are shrinking before our veryeyes. One of the highest goals of true bird lovers is now being realized withthe phasing out of commercial wildbird importation. Whether we like it ornot, aviculturists can agree that theelimination of imported birds, now forthe pet trade and later completely, is amark of true unselfishness in a businessfraught with moral and ethicaldilemmas!To quote a popular phrase, "We'vecome a long way, baby."The implications for marketingdomestic-raised parrots are profound.As more hobbyists and new breederssucceed and expand, seasonal speciesgluts and shortages are going tobecome increasingly common in thepet trade. Scarcely a week goes by atour shop without phone calls fromsmall breeders who have exhaustedtheir sales possibilities direct to thepublic and wish to ease their pressureand enter the wholesale market.As a successful exotic bird shop, Feathered Friends is encounteringthose who want us to buy their "extrababies" while they advertise locally atprices 25 to 50 percent lower than wecan possibly retail. "Support yourlocal bird shop" is becoming a rallyingcall amongst many pet store ownerscoping with rising rents, a sluggishluxury economy, and massive breederadvertising in national magazines.To be sure, pet stores spend hoursshowing, explaining and troubleshootingfor customers in the parrottrade. They push new products,answer medical questions and referveterinarians, work to eliminate oldfashionedmethods of feeding andcaring for birds, and take much pressureoff of breeders who face enoughphone calls already!We believe that the entire birdmarket is interconnected in a fragilenetwork that makes it succeed at present.What's to come in the days aheadis anyone's guess ....Supply and demand may causehavoc in some species. Many smallbreeding operations are only nowbeginning to realize significant numbersproduction. In two or three years,we expect to see increases in easyto-breed and commonly importedspecies. However, if these birds donot meet acceptable home pet standards,the market will not accept thenumbers. Such trends could lead tobreeders "dumping" unwanted pairson the market in favor of more saleableparrots.Let us caution ourselves now. To"dump" any breeding pair because ofdifficult marketing is both unprofitableand detrimental to the entire aviculturalindustry. Short-sighted economicdecisions do nothing for a stable market- nothing for a species we allthought desirable five or 10 years agowhen we took thousands from thewilds. I praise the breeders I have metwho have realized their dreams ofbreeding parrots and now devote 10or 15 percent of their annual incometo be used to maintain needy pairs ofparrots whose offspring have verylittle saleability at all. God bless thosewho use imagination instead of strictfiscal decisions when appraising theiraviary programs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/735</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 42-44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/735/718</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
