<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/680</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Observation of a Male Strawberry Finch (Amandava amandava)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wiegel, Gary W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This articl e summa rizes 20 hours ofo bse rv a ti o n , Octobe r 13, 1991 toNovember 23, 1991, on a male Strawberry Finch (Amandava amandava)in the Co llege o f Natural Resourcesavia1y at th e Univers ity of WisconsinStevens Po int. The Univ e rs ity ofWisconsin-Ste ve ns Po int has had anavia ry fea turing exoti c fin ches andna tive fish and re pti les for o ve r tenyea rs . The s pec ies of fin ches th atinflu e nced the behav ior of the ma leStrawbe rry Finch we re the Java RiceFi nc h , owl fin ches, Cord on Ble us,pa rrot fin ches, Goulclians, Red-earedWaxbills, Orange-cheeked Waxbills,Star Finches , o ne female StrawberryFin ch and , in la te Octo be r, a babySt raw be rry Fin c h . The exhi b it isloca ted in the first fl oor lobby of theCollege of Natural Resources building.This exhi bit provides opportuni ty forstude nts majoring in Biology, Wildlife,and Captive Wildli fe Manageme nt togain valuable hands-on ex pe rie nce inthe husbancl1y of these animals.The Strawbe rry Finch has a va rietyof oth e r commo n names which includeReel Ava clavat, Bombay Avaclavat,and Tiger Finch (Bates 1970). TheStrawbe rry Fin c h is in the waxbillg roup and fa lls into the fa mily ofEstrildids. This bird is small and foundin India and p a rts o f So utheast As ia(Goodwin 196o). Strawbe rry Finches occur in la rge fl ocks amo ng reedyma rshes and wet g rassla nds (Austin196 1). They a re trad ed commo nlybe tween Indi a and o th e r countriesbecause they tame eas il y and a rere la ti ve ly easy to ra ise in captivity(Austin 1961).The males can be distinguished ve1yeasi ly from the fema les beca use theya re sexu a lly dimo rp hi c . The ma le,when in his b re eding plumage, isalmost all red with the exception of abl ack stripe fro m bea k to each eye .His lower breas t, flank s, wings andrum p are spotted white. The female isdull e arth brown with a re el rumppatch (Goodwin 196o).Ingestive BehaviorInges tive be havi o r is the behavio rassoc iated with eating and d rinking.The male Strawbeny Finch ate mainlymill e t and dry seed . He a lso atesoa ked see d , me alwo rms, g reensprouts, and cottage cheese. Accord ingto Goodwin 0 982), Estrilclids generally ea t la rge qua ntities of dry seedbut the mill et tends to be eaten in thela rgest amo unts. He ate the mill et offthe ground or by pecking at the hangingmill e t s prays . He did no t spendmu ch time eating o ut o f the di shwhich contained the bird seed . Hepre ferred to hop around on the sandand wood chips to look for and peckat seed s . When he was ext remely hungry, he jumped into the seed bowlbut this was usually done in the morningwhen fresh food was first madeavailable. When eating the dry seeds,he held the seed between his upperand lower mandibles. He then raisedhis lower mandible two or threetimes to crack the seed before it wasswallowed.When eating mealworms, the StrawberryFinch always grabbed the wormby the end and squeezed out theinsides, thus leaving the exoskeletonbehind. Once or twice, he ate theremains after squeezing out theinsides. This was also observed byGoodwin (1960) when he was watchinghis Strawberry Finches. The StrawberryFinch I observed started eatingat 10:00 a.m. after the fresh food wasset out and continued eating all day.Drinking behavior was observedmany times. The male drank aboutonce an hour. He usually drank out ofa pool of shallow water located on anisland in the middle of the aviary pool.He also drank water from the rockwall ledges of the waterfall and waterfrom a large bowl used by the turtlesfora bath.Estrildid finches exhibit two kinds ofdrinking behavior: tip up drinking andsuction drinking (Heldweiller 1990).The male finch exhibited tip up drinking.He dipped his head down andtook some water into the bill and thenraised his head to swallow. The majorityof Estrildids drink by dipping thebill into the water and then lifting thehead to allow gravity to let the waterflow down the throat (Goodwin1982).Shelter-seeking BehaviorShelter-seeking behavior is thebehavior of seeking out optimumenvironmental conditions. The structuresthat the bird used most oftenwere a potted five-foot tall NorfolkIsland Pine tree and a grapevine perchover the water. The male StrawberryFinch made the greatest use of theperch over the water. Whenever hewas frightened by people on the outsideof the aviary, he flew to this perchfor security. If the perch was beingused by diamond doves, he wouldtherr·seekshelter in the Norfolk IslandPine in the corner of the aviary. Hisuse of the perch for security is probablya reflec.tion ~f his ~cclimating tocaptivity, smce, m Indta, StrawberryFinches live in reedy marshes and wetgrasslands. If he were in a natural setting,he would probably select thickgrasses for cover instead of an openperch.The finch was never seen sleeping.He probably slept in the nest with thefemale. He stayed in the nest for up totwo hours during the day. We couldnot locate him at night because it wastoo dark in the aviary.Agonistic BehaviorAgonistic behavior is the behaviorassociated with conflict between twoindividuals. The Strawberry Finch'sagonistic behavior involved conflictswith several birds in the aviary. Therewas also conflict with the baby StrawberryFinch when it was old enough tofly. The Strawberry Finch alwayschased the other finches away fromhis perch. These were the Java RiceFinch, owl finches, Cordon Bleus,parrot finches, Red-eared Waxbills,Orange-cheeked Waxbills, and StarFinches. The only birds he did notevict were the Diamond Doves, probablybecause of their size. He chasedthe finches off by flying at them andpecking at their rump feathers untilthey flew away. Once they started tofly away he chased them a few morefeet and then flew back to his perch.When he flew to the food dishes hisbehavior was more submissive. Hewas frequently chased away by theGouldians and the Cordon Bleus.The conflict with the baby StrawberryFinch occurred when the babylanded on his perch. The young birdwas chased away just like any otherbird, except there seemed to be a lotmore pecking involved. Whenever thebaby was eating, the male hoppedover to the baby and chased it awayfrom the food. He only chased awaythe baby after it was old enough to eaton its own.The male also defended his nestsite. He always chased away the otherspecies of finches from the plant inwhich his nest was located. Again, theonly birds he could not chase awaywere the Diamond Doves. All theother birds were chased away thesame way they were chased from theperch. We did not observe any aggressionor conflicts between the male andfemale.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/680</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 19-21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/680/663</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
