<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3771</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-20T02:49:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Remembering Scott Lewis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The avicultural community has lost another leader and educator, Scott Lewis, 66, of Austin, Texas passed away suddenly, September 6, 2016, after a courageous battle with cancer. Scott was born on April 10, 1950, in Little Rock, Arkansas and grew up in the small farming community in Hereford, Texas. Scott’s true passion and dedication was Aviculture. It started with a couple of margaritas with his wife, Linda at El Rancho Restaurant after which they bought their first African Grey parrot. From there it blossomed into a full- scale parrot operation; together, they raised and cared for over 20 different species and over 75 pairs of parrots in their backyard in East Austin. He could often be found, in the late night hours, diligently hand-feeding baby parrots in the Nursery out behind the house. Scott, along with his wife Linda, founded “Old World Aviaries” where they kept and bred a collection of parrots predominantly of African origins. From Cape parrots to Congo and Timneh Grey parrots, Scott had a keen interest in parrots and shared his knowledge with anyone, breeder or pet owners alike. Scott contributed to the Avian Community by sharing his knowledge of keeping, breeding, incubation, and hand-rearing of the many species he maintained. Scott always found time to share his personal insights with...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-04-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3771</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 43 No. 3 &amp; 4 (2016): Special Double Issue; 6</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3771/3746</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
