<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/724</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">President's Message</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Desborough, Laurella</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Where are we going in the '90s? Themain challenges facing aviculture inthe '90s will be the threats posed byavian viral diseases and by proposedand present restrictive regulations andlaws. As we face these threats andwork together to solve our problems,a new era of cooperation is beingestablished in American aviculture.Avian viral diseases have been withus a long time; we just have notalways been able to identify them,prevent them or cure them. Veterinaryresearch on viral diseases hasadvanced to the stage where manyviral diseases have been identifiedand, hopefully, tests for their presenceand vaccines for their prevention willbecome available. What can we aviculturistsdo to assist in speeding upthis process? Funding is the criticalelement needed to solve the problemof viral diseases. Bird clubs and individualscan donate directly to researchprojects. Aviculturists can participatein fund-raising events where the proceedsare donated to research.Restrictive laws and regulations arepresent in many cities, counties, statesand now nationally. We do expectfurther restrictive legislation to beproposed on the state level as variousanimal rights organizations push forwardtheir agenda: no exotic pets! andno birds in cages/We also know that alawsuit has been brought in federalcourt against the U.S.D.A. to forcethem to monitor/ inspect rats, miceand birds. (The belief is that their concernis mostly for those in laboratory research or in public exhibitions.)On the local level, individual aviculturistsand club members need tomonitor proposed changes in theircity and county ordinances as there isan active movement towards changingthese ordinances to be very restrictivein terms of defining what kinds ofpets and how many pets can be kept.This includes property from condominiumsize to five acre farms. Constantvigilance on the local level willbe needed to preserve your right tokeep and breed birds.The AFA will be monitoring stateand national legislation through themany eyes and ears of the state coordinators,vice presidents and watchfulindividual aviculturists. One of theconcerns that has been voiced is thatof the rise in smuggling due to therestrictive nature of the Wild BirdConservation Act and due to theincreased opportunities presented bythe changes resulting from the implementationof NAFTA. AFA is concernedabout smuggling from twostandpoints: it is a threat to the healthof our exotic birds; it brings the threatof more restrictions on aviculturists(proposed by USFWS in attempts tocontrol smuggling). We expect continuedattempts on the part of variousgovernment agencies and organizedanimal rights groups to place restrictionsand regulations on the owners ofexotic birds, whether they are pet birdowners with two or three birds orbreeders with large collections. Inpreparation for the continued onslaughtson aviculture, the Board ofDirectors of AF A voted unanimouslyat their fall meeting to establish a legaldefense fund to be used to protect theinterests of aviculture through whateverlegal means becomes necessary. As we face the problems of viral diseaseand restrictive legislation, wealso find ourselves in a new era ofcooperation among aviculturists. Thispositive situation has been generatedout of the recognition that if we aregoing to have viable populations ofbreeding birds of various species inthe future, we must work togethertoday to achieve that goal. Suddenly,aviculturists who have avoided recordkeeping have begun to keep records,to band birds and to microchip birds.Identifying an individual birdbecomes important for selecting anon-related mate, thus maintaininggenetic viability for future breedingstock. Aviculturists breeding similarspecies are working together in breedingprograms, sharing stock and sharinginformation (for example, the newAmerican Lory Association). Seriousbreeders continue to seek new informationin their concern about nutrition,breeding behavior, and improvementof management practices. Manyof these breeders attend avian seminarssuch as the Midwest A vi anResearch Expo. An interest in maintainingand meeting standards ofexotic bird care is displayed by manyaviculturists and exemplified by thosecertified by the Model A vicultureProgram. In order to provide a neededservice, the AFA is preparing anational registry which will make itpossible for individuals to registertheir exotic birds, whether pets orbreeding birds. Also, AFA is preparinginformation for individuals and clubswho wish to participate in a cooperativebreeding program for a particularspecies. These programs will meet theneeds of positive identification forindividual birds and provision of agenealogy on breeding birds. •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/724</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 22</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/724/707</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
