<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2390</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-03T21:51:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Elusive Caninde</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Riviere, Scott</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clubb, Susan L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clubb, Kevin J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It would seem a macaw must be rare when, until recent years, it was known only from four museum specimens. This rarity may stem from a limited range in an isolated area of Bolivia, and also from confusion with a similar species. Taxonomy is in dispute over the caninde macaw, Ara can.in.de, which has recently been referred to as the blue throated macaw, Ara glaucogularis. This bird was thought to be a variety of an immature of the blue and gold macaw, Ara ararauna, thus the Portuguese name "caninde" meaning blue and gold macaw was applied. This bird is now considered to be a distinct species with the proposed name Ara glaucogularis. Its distinguishing characteristics are the blue throat, rather than the black throat of the blue and gold, and a protruding beak that is longer and narrower. The body color is more aqua than blue and the caninde is a slightly smaller bird. The bare facial area of the caninde is less extensive than that of the blue and gold, with broader blue facial feather lines crossing the cheeks. The blue and gold has black feather lines crossing the cheeks. NATURAL HISTORY OF THE CANINDEInformation on the caninde's range and natural history is lacking in ornithological literature. An interview, however, with a Bolivian resident familiar with the trapping and export of macaws, provided basic information pertaining to range and habits of the caninde. Confirmation by an ornithologist would, no doubt, provide for a more complete understanding of the bird.The range was described as being a strip approximately 60 by 200 miles in the Department (state) of El Beni in Northern Bolivia. He doubts the existence of these birds in Argentina, Paraguay or Brazil.El Beni is a large state about the size of Kansas. It is sparsely populated. Although 70% of the land of Bolivia is tropical lowland, only 20% of the population of six million inhabit these lands. The region is tropical with average temperatures of 23°-27°C and an average annual rainfall of 60 to 80 inches. The topography is mostly a flat plain at an altitude of 500 to 1,000 ft. It is drained by several large rivers which are tributaries of the Amazon. These rivers are banked by jungle strips five to ten miles wide, which comprise the birds' habitat. Beyond that are miles of pampas which are used for cattle ranching. Roads are uncommon in the region and access is primarily by boat and airplane, contributing to the seclusion of these birds for many years. The range extends between the cities of Reyes and San Nicolas. Blue and gold macaws occupy the entire range and green winged macaws, Ara cbloroptera, are also found in the eastern section. Some of the highest concentrations of canindes are found in the regions near San Nicolas and Santa Rosa. Breeding occurs, as with blue and golds, generally in December and January, during the rainy season.Flocking has not been observed with canindes, as with blue and golds, and the two species cannot be distinguished in flight or at a distance due to similarity in appearance. These factors make true population estimates impossible. However, by comparison of numbers of canindes trapped to that of blue and golds, the caninde population is estimated to be as high as 5,000 to 7,000. In capturing macaws, a caller bird is commonly used to lure freeflying birds into trees where snares have been placed. It appears that canindes were not captured previous to 1979 because their range was unknown and only blue and gold callers...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2390</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 1 (1986): FEB-MAR 1986; 6-9</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2390/2363</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
