<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3705</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T03:05:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">News Highlights, Record Breeding Year for Rusty-faced Parrots: In Colombia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Waugh, David R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Native to Colombia and Venezuela, the Rusty-faced Parrot (Hapalopsittaca amazonina) is categorized in the IUCN Red List as 'Vulnerable', primarily due to the small size of its population and the loss and fragmentation of its natural habitat caused by the expansion of the agricultural frontier in the Andean forest.We have a historical record of the Rusty-faced Parrots (Hapalopsittaca amazonina): 6 active nests with up to 3 chicks between March and June. In late March the first occupation was recorded, and the first chicks were recorded in early June. In May, the count of 79 individuals was performed in the usual monitoring site in the Colibri del Sol Bird Reserve. They never had numbered that amount before.After three successful years with the occupation of 4 nests between 2012 and 2013, and after maintenance work in 2014, we doubled this figure with 6 occupied nests.The maintenance tasks include changes in the shape of the nests and location sites of these places, trying to find the right height. Changes were performed in the size and shape of the cavities that allow entry to the nest, and annual maintenance, where the sawdust inside is replaced at the end of the breeding season so that new couples find them suitable.For their protection, in 2005, ProAves created the Colibri del Sol Bird Reserve, with the support of American Bird Conservancy.The reserve is located on the western flank of the Western Cordillera in the geographic system Paramo de Frontino, in the municipality of Urrao, Antioquia. It was created to conserve the habitat of the Dusky Starfrontlet (Coligena orina) and other endemic birds in the Paramo del Sol area. It consists of an area of 1,806 acres of forest and high Andean paramo, between 2,400 and 3,750 m.This reproductive success is thanks to the initial support provided in 2008, by The Zoological Society For The Conservation Of Species And Populations (ZGAP) that....</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3705</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 4 (2014): Volume 41, Number 4, 2014, Volume 42, Number 1, 2015; 64-68</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3705/3688</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
