<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/641</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The German Roller Canary</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McWatters, Alicia</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">HistoryThis article was written for thosewho have asked the question, "Whatis a German roller canary?" In the canaryworld, they are known as the"song canary," a bird specially trainedto become a canary of exceptionalsong quality, famous for their outstandingand superb ability for tone,range, and depth within their songvocabulary.The roller canary is an old breed,measuring about five and a half inchesand can come in a variety of colors,such as white, yellow, green, gray,variegated, and occasionally redorange.Among the song canaries, theGerman roller is the most frequentlyheard of within this group. The other,lesser known song canaries are theBelgian Waterslager and the SpanishTimbrado which deserve recognitionand attention in their own right.Centuries of hard work have beenput into developing and sustaining theroller song, and I think you'll find itsbackground quite fascinating. TheGerman roller canaries originated inthe Harz Mountains of Germany, particularlyin St. Andreasberg betweenthe 1700s and 1800s. Hundreds ofworking class German families (manyof them coal miners) raised andtrained these birds to be the wonderfulsongbirds that they are; with themales in great demand, there wasmuch profit gained. This was animportant additional source of incomefor the miners with their low wages.Their goal was to create a canary withoutthe shrill and loudness of yourcommon canary. Many canaries werebred for color and type but theycannot give us the richness of songdesired. Focus must be made on thesong alone in order to develop perfection,just as anything which is specializedand studied, given much timeand nurturing, will become a productof excellence. Initially, color was anunimportant factor in raising thesebirds with the predominant colorsbeing yellow, variegated, and green asof the wild canary. All concentrationwould be placed on improving thebeautiful song. Much later, after securingthe song, other colors would beincorporated to create variety. The canarybusiness began to boom in Europeancities and then in America towardthe mid 1800s, with literally millionsof them being exported out ofthe Harz Mountains. The early rollerswere tutored by magnificent songbirdssuch as the mockingbird, thenlater a roller organ was developed, amusical instrument specifically forsong training. Over the generations,those canaries who easily learned topick up the song were selected forbreeding and the less gifted ones wereculled and sold as pets. Their ability tolearn was so great as to establish thisspecial breed of canary with its operatic,sophisticated song.SongThe song of the German roller isnearly always sung with its beakclosed and a true roller is marked bythis characteristic. The song is sung ina soft manner, very pleasant to the earand relaxing to listen to. While reachingtheir wide range of notes, you'llnotice how the feathers of the throatrise forward with a vibrating motion asthey adjust from one tour to another.The song covers nearly three octavesand rollers are trained to excel in themusical passages known as "tours,"which consist of hollow roll, bass roll,flutes, and hollow bell, with a series ofsupplemental tours, each with a variationin tempo and resonance. Thereare 13 tours which are sung in a rollingfashion, hence the name rollercanary. Youngsters should preferablybe trained by their father, but a tapemay be used as the next best thingand is commonly utilized. Individualbirds will tend to be outstanding in afew favored tours, with each birdbeing unique. Commonly heard arethe hollow roll, bass, and flute notesas compared to the water notes, gluck,and schockel which in these days areheard infrequently; with improvedclarity and expertise in the formernotes. Rarely, would you find a birdwhich is accomplished in all of them.Development of song in youngsters(as young as six weeks of age) beginswith a few shy, twittering notes, firstsung in fragments. Eventually, afterbuilding their confidence, they willprogress into the structuring and thelengthening of their song into the variousrolls or tours. It is a gradual processwhich can take up to 18 monthsto fully mature into the more complexstages. Although, much earlier thanthis, one can judge the future potentialby closely listening to each youngsteraudition, as later described. A lot ofthe roller song is thought to be inherited.There are those who belive theroller needs no formal training at all inthat they will develop the song all ontheir own. The majority of othersbelieve in tutors, as birds who remainisolated at a young age usually do notdevelop their song to their full potential,while those who have had theguideance of their father or anotherproper substitute will, indeed, have anedge over one who does not. Using atape or "live" tutor, as long as it is inthe pure roller song, certainly can dono harm and probably does moregood in enhancing their natural ability.Keep in mind that birds whichhatch early in the season have theadvantage of hearing their father andother neighboring males sing for alonger period of time. Those fromlater clutches will develop the song alittle slower, be farther behind theothers, and will benefit greatly from aregularly played tape when the "live"song may no longer be available. Rollersgenerally are excellent mimics,but their capacity for learning isdirectly related to the lineage of bothfather and mother birds. Care shouldbe taken to allow only quality tutors inthe room with your young males, sothey do not pick up any undesirablenotes or faults. For example, you mustwatch out for high frequency andharshness in the bell tour and watertour.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/641</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 2 (1993): APR-MAY 1993; 8-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/641/624</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
