<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3291</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-06T16:46:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Birds Do So Much For Us</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rose, Mary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"Birds should be saved for utilitarian reasons; and, moreover,they should be saved because of reasons unconnected with dollars and cents ... The extermination of the Passenger Pigeon meant that mankind was just so much poorer ... And to lose the chance to see frigate-birds soaring in circles above the storm, or a file of pelicans winging their way homeward across the crimson afterglow of the sunset, or a myriad of terns flashing in the bright light of midday as they hover in a shifting maze above the beach-why, the loss is like the loss of a gallery of the masterpieces of the artists of old time."Theodore Roosevelt, 1916 While it is our ethical and moral respon-sibility to save birds from extinction, the harsh reality is that today many decisions surrounding which species to focus on is directly related to dollars and cents. Engaging in work to prevent extinction costs money, but it does not have to be big money. Many projects out there looking for funding need relatively small amounts and the benefits of funding such projects can be huge.Imagine funding a proj-ect designed to gather base information, which in turn leads to funding for a much larger conservation effort. Itis entirely possible, and everyone in the bird community can participate. The plan can be very simple. It's a great public relations move for your group or organization, and the intrinsic reward the participants will get is well worth the effort.Fundraising can be a lot of work depending on your techniques, but it does not have to be. Simple fundraisers can be done that achieve your goals. We'll explore one such effort step by step that was completed successfully in 2011. The fundraising plan was simple, did not require a large amount of time or effort, and best of all raised international awareness of the plight of a particular species.Why raise money for birds?And can any one person make a difference? The answer is a resounding yes to both questions! Everyone can raise funds for endangered species-all you really need is a top quality product to support your efforts and the will to go out and sell those products to benefit your chosen project.Whether you are raising funds for your own organization or an external project or organization, your choice of product needs to be relevant. The product also needs tobe of good quality and easily accessible. You need to have specific project or organization information available for all participants in your fundraising effort.Choose a dollar target and provide a breakdown of how the funds will be spent. Offer to provide a thank you note and an update to all donors of the fundraising results after your campaign is complete. This can be as simple as a thank-you email with the total amount raised during the fundraising period.This communication with your donors is a vital part of the process. It's well worth doing as you will receive so many positive comments back and it also helps to reinforce the fact that one person's contribution can make a huge difference overall. This will also keep the momentum going for any future fundraising efforts.People want to know that they are a valued member of a team that made a difference. They are winners and they need to feel it.When looking at what project or organizationyou are going to support,it's extremely important to do your research to ensure that funds will be spent as intended. It is also important to consider public relations and goodwill attached to your efforts.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3291</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 39 No. 1 (2012): Number 1  2012; 7-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3291/3275</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
