<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1002</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-19T21:22:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Handfeeding Finches and Softbills</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schulenburg, Wayne A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The decision to handrear young l b:rds has always been risky and the commitment to this process is very time consuming and often emotionally exhausting.While avian pediatrics has been in use for many years and has basically been established for the parrot breeder, finches and softbills have been overlooked, for the most part, by the aviculturist. Primarily this is because of ignorance or just simply not being interested in these species.How many times have we, as finch breeders, gone out into our aviaries and been overjoyed by the sound of babies being fed only to be overwhelmed a few days later to find the nset abandoned with dead babies or babies thrown out of the nest? Many times the babies are found on the ground and are cold and barely moving. We usually respond quickly to this scenario by setting up an aquarium and adjusting a light bulb to a comfortable temperature. We use a butter tub lined with tissue to put the young babies in and then pray a lot.As a diet for these birds, we mix protein cereals with hulled millets and occasionally offer morsels of mealworm treats. We then worry and worry and worry. After several days of following our schedule the babies seem to thrive; but then disaster occurs and all the babies die. After blaming ourselves, we swear we will never try handfeeding a finch again, or at least not until the next time!To offer a bit of consolation, I believe we need to remember a few basics when it comes to breeding much Jess handrearing finches. First, when you have discovered your adults feeding their chicks in the nest, leave the parents alone. I know the temptation is to look at the babies, but please keep your face out of the nest. You have already provided them with the proper diet and environment and promote them to nest and to hatch young. We must give our finches credit to have their own instinctive power to proliferate the species.When you do find abandoned young in the nest or those which have been tossed from the nest, you will have nothing but an uphill battle to raise them. One must remember that these young finches were probably abandoned during the night at cooler temperatures. This results in a loss of body heat and nourishment for them. Young finches tossed out of the nest may fall a considerable distance to the floor and may receive internal injuries or some unnoticed damage to them.The most important requirement is to get these young finches warm and comfortable. Please do not, I repeat, do not make your diet too elaborate. Make it simple, such as using hulled proso millet or small yellow millet that can be obtained from your local health food store. The best feeding utensils are flattened toothpicks which are· first dipped in water and then in the millet. This is then fed to the begging finches.I have had the opportunity to see the particular feeding method used a number of times with both success and failure. There is no set rule when it comes to finches. Also remember to feed only during the daylight hours as the parent birds do.It is generally easier to handrear Australian finches than African waxbills because the Australian finches do not seem to require the proteins obtained in live foods as do the African waxbills.When it comes to softbills, I am taken back to the early '60s when I first purchased honeycreepers and was overwhelmed by their beauty and unique requirements. These honeycreepers would build nests and hatch out young only to throw them out of the nest one by one. I had such a helpless feeling as I watched with ignorance as the babies died. In those days, one never considered handfeeding softbills, much less something like honeycreepers.With the wide variety of softbills having been imported into the United States in recent years, there is a renewed avicultural interest in this diverse group of birds. Although every species cannot be dealt with in this article, I would like to relate some personal and San Diego Zoological Society experiences with a few species that may be familiar to you.The intense interest in the toucan family can be attributed to one private aviculturist, Jerry Jennings. His keen interest and expertise in this group has shown us how simple the birds are to house and maintain.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1002</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 3 (1996): MAY-JUNE 1996; 9-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1002/982</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
