<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2436</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T14:48:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Plaudits &amp; Praise: AFA Volunteers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Congress of the United States has an Office of Technology Assessment (OTA). Ordinarily the OTA and the AFA would not cross paths but at present the OTA is assessing technologies that maintain biological diversity. And maintaining biological diversity is one thing the AFA is all about.There are, no doubt, hundreds of ways and many entities that are somehow involved in maintaining biological diversity but the early thrust of the OTA happened to focus on various grassroots efforts. Indeed, the OTA's first background paper is titled "Grassroots Conservation of Biological Diversity in the United States."In this paper the OTA says, "The bulk of this background paper highlights and assesses specific 'showcase' examples of grassroots individuals and groups maintaining biological diversity in the United States" The AFA, clear friends, is highlighted as a "showcase" example. This is high recognition and can only enhance the reputation of the AFA. How did this recognition come about?Several factors were involved but the key ingredient in presenting the AFA to the OTA was a five foot tall, hundred pound dynamo named Carole Wheeler. She gives credit to the workers in the bird department of the Cincinnati Zoo for originally recommending that the OTA contact the AFA. Wheeler also gives credit to Lee Phillips for providing much of the data that was supplied to the OTA. Still, these efforts were channeled through one very dedicated and steady AFA volunteer, Carole Wheeler, and this short article is to give credit where credit is due.Carole Wheeler is the pattern to follow if you want to make some more volunteer workers. She is the backbone and the work horse of a non-profit volunteer-oriented organization such as the AFA. Without her kind of input the AFA would be helpless.Wheeler began her bird-keeping activities a few years ago with English budgies and a lutino cockatiel. She now keeps at least 16 species of hookbills because she can't decide which she likes best. She has pretty good success breeding them and she likes to hand feed young birds.In addition to her family and her birds, Carole Wheeler's interests have focused on several bird clubs where her volunteer instincts have been put to good use. She served as AFA delegate from National Capitol Bird Club and then as the Virginia state coordinator which position she has held for about three years. At the same time (1983 and 1984) she was president of the Maryland Cage Bird Society and then in 1985 vice president of the same two clubs.Her interest in cockatiels involved her as a state representative for the American Cockatiel Society and later as a charter member and secretary and point registrar for the National Cockatiel Society. She writes articles on cockatiels and is qualified as a judge.Because of her interest in many species of birds, Carole Wheeler is an active member of numerous specialty clubs. She fields phone calls for the Audubon Society and a local wildlife rescue group when it comes to exotic birds.For years the AFA has had a small cadre of very hard working volunteers who have gone above and beyond the call of duty. Carole Wheeler is one of the elite few and should serve as an inspiration for the many volunteers the AFA is mobilizing at this very moment.Our thanks and appreciation to you, Carole, for bringing the AFA to the attention of the OTA, and for the many good deeds you've done that are not as noticeable but are just as important. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2436</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 3 (1986): JUNE-JULY 1986; 48-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2436/2409</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
