<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3043</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-17T09:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Convention Chirps</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pidgeon, Polly</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It's about time all you wonderful folks that are into birds get the scoop on the stars that entertained us at the last convention aboard the Queen Mary in Long Beach. First Fred, the Cockatoo will resume his costarring roll with Robert Blake, on Baretta, that very popular ABC Network series.Rumors about personality conflicts between the two superstars were really flying but the inside from Ray Berwick, Fred's manager ( owner trainer and confidante), is that the two actors' personalities are so similar that the similarity in itself, is the real cause of the conflict.News came just the other day that Lauren Chapin will rejoin her "family" on a super-dooper special dreamed up by the networks that will feature the entire cast of "Father Knows Best" and it's whispered that the series could start all over again. Great break for Lauren, who is still pursuing a singing career.Chris Costello, who really charmed the Bird Lovers out of the trees must have taken so much to the seagoing life, that it has become so much of a habit, that cruising back and forth to Mexico entertaining vacationers is becoming a monthly affair. Chris did some great things for Celebrity Revue, and the Wally George Show. She'd like to spend a little more time on land however, and is up for several network series scheduled for this fall. Wherever you are, we love you and wish you the best.We saved the best news for last. Wade Crookham has really "Kept his Eyes on the Sparrow." Bye-the-bye, Fred was really knocked out by Wade's rendition of the Baretta Theme at the convention, and Ray Berwick assures us that his tippling had nothing to do with it. Wade has been getting bigger and bigger parts in feature films plus giving his all by using his remarkably flexible voice to dub English dialogue into foreign films plus adding all those neighs and whinneys sometimes needed. Wade really is a country boy at heart and was born and raised in Caldwell, Idaho.Anyway at the time of the convention Wade was involved in doing a record for Producers Scott Seely and June Taylor, who attended that super dinner dance on the Queen Mary.They were so impressed by the bird lovers they encountered that Accent Records has offered the A .F .A. a super special arrangement to distribute "HONKER, THE MIXED UP MOTHER GOOSE" to A.F.A .. members and their children or grandchildren.It's a true story put to music about a Canadian Goose named Honker who was hatched with five chicken eggs. Because of her size the chicks mistook her for Mommy - and so did she. The chicks tried to be good little geese and Honker a good mother hen. One day Grandpa brings handsome Grand Dandy Gander to the ranch and a beautiful romance straightens everybody out so that Honker has goslings of her very own. Wade plays ten of the parts on this record and they're all different. It's already in the stores and a super hit with the kits. See you next issue for more convention "Sweet Tweets". This year we are looking forward to Scottsdale, Arizona - The A.F.A. Safari Convention 1977, September 16 thru 18. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3043</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 2 (1977): APR-MAY 1977; 44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3043/3027</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
