<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3186</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-07-28T08:22:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">2011 Call for Papers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. 37th Annual ConventionAug. 3-6, 2011"Jewels in Aviculture"Marriott San MateoSan Francisco, CAThe American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. (AFA) is a national, nonprofit educational organization established in 1974 whose purpose is to represent all aspects of aviculture and to educate the public about keeping and breeding birds in captivity.We invite you to submit a proposal to present a paper at our annual convention. Proposals should be submitted in the form of an abstract, accompanied by a brief biographical sketch identifying the author's experience with the topic to be presented and other relevant information. Please consider submitting multiple abstracts as you have the opportunity to give more than one presentation.• Abstracts will be accepted through Feb. 15, 2011. Receipt of abstracts will be acknowledged and applicants will receive timely updates from the speaker committee.• If the abstract is accepted, you will be required to sign a speaker's contract and return the contract promptly. A short bio and a current, high-resolution photograph is also required. Speakers will not be officially confirmed without receipt of a signed contract. Speakers are required to submit a paper to be published in the Convention Proceedings and in the Watchbird, the official journal of the AF A. Final papers for the proceedings must be received no later than April 15, 2011, to be included.• AF A will provide a complimentary convention registration package and one banquet ticket to each confirmed speaker. All other arrangements, including guests, transportation and hotel accommodations are the responsibility of the speaker or the speaker's sponsor.Abstracts are short summaries of the paper you wish to present and should be no more than 250 words. They must include the name of the author(s), mailing address(es), e-mail and all phone contact information for the author(s). Please include the name of your company, organization, aviary or other affiliation. If there is more than one author, please indicate if one or both will present.Presentations will be allotted SO minutes and may include a brief question-and-answer period. Audiovisual equipment will be made available and will be specified in the contract.Abstracts, biographies and final papers may be submitted by mail, as an e-mail, or as an MS Word e-mail attachment to the speaker chair, or faxed to the AFA office. Please identify it as "AF A 2011 Convention Abstract."AFA requires non-exclusive publication rights to the accepted papers to be included in the Convention Proceedings and the Watchbird, the official journal of AFA.Speaker Chairman Marshall Liger Phone: 843-697-3083e-mail: SpeakerChair@afabirds.orgAmerican Federation of Aviculture, Inc. P.O. Box 91717Austin, TX78709-1717 Phone: 512-585-9800 Fax: 512-858-7029e-mail: Office@afabirds.org </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3186</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 37 No. 3 (2010): Number 3 2010; 10</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3186/3170</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
