<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3344</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-09T10:56:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Natural Disaster Strike Hard and Heavy</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferragamo, Concetta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hurricane Sandy was one of the largest Atlantic hurricanes in recorded history, second to Hurricane Katrina. Sandy's wind span measured some 1,100 miles. Approximately 285 people were killed from Sandy's wrath which spread over seven countries. CNN reported that Super-storm Sandy clobbered 24 States in the United States spreading across the entire east coast, from Florida through the state of Maine. From there the storm went west across the Appalachian Mountains onto Michigan and then Wisconsin. Sandy had the most impact on the New Jersey shore and the New York City areas. As Sandy traveled to Pennsylvania, the super-storm dispersed and died out. Hurricane Sandy hit the United States on October 29, 2012 and did not fully disburse until October 31, 2012.As with all natural disasters, Sandy was devastating to so many. Homes were destroyed. Businesses were lost. Streets and tunnels were flooded. In many areas power was lost for up to several weeks. This meant that many people had no heat as well. The damage estimated from Sandy has been estimated at over $71 billion (USD, 2012).The American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. has a strong Disaster Relief team comprised of Regional Directors and others who are located throughout the United States. Fred Smith is the AFA Disaster Relief committee chair. The Disaster Relief team expedites response time and notifies local volunteers as need arises in any given area. If you are in a disaster area and in need of assistance with your birds, or you know of anyone in need of help with their birds, you can call anyone listed on our disaster hotline. http://www.afabirds.org/drf2008.shtml.A message from Disaster Relief Chair, Fred Smith: "I am proud of the work that was done by the Regional Directors and their helpers. By the time the storm passed, we had 'boots on the ground' with Concetta Ferragamo, Ed Maher, Terry Jones, Lanette Raymond, Diane Hyde and Lisa Bono working very hard at making contacts and assessing the need for help. Since Concetta was central in the area, I appointed her as the co-coordinator. Concetta and Eddie did a fabulous job, and along with the state coordinators and other AFA members they were able to help the public in a time of crisis. This was another instance where AF A worked to help aviculturists in their time of need". New Jersey State Coordinator, Terri Jones reported:In the wake of Super-storm Sandy,the Jersey Shore and Staten Island were devastated. Entire communities were destroyed, homes wiped away, often leaving nothing but foundations where families once lived. Many people were forced to evacuate quickly and were unable to take their animals with them. But dueto the experiences gained in past storms, many shelters now do allow people to bring in pets. The problems arose after the initial evacuation, when people were unable to return to their homes and were forced to move into hotels or look for rental units. These housing arrangements seldom allowed pets.A plea went out to the New Jersey, Pennsylvania and New York Bird Clubs for members who could provide foster care for birds, not only for the short term, but also for an unknown period of time, as many people did not know how long it would be before they could return to their damaged homes or rebuild new ones. The responses were immediate and heartfelt. I was able to develop a list of over 20 people who were willing to offer assistance. It was not only individuals that responded, but businesses did as well. Mike Abatto, from Abba Foods, called to tell me he had openedup two rooms in his warehouse and was able to take in as many birds as necessary. He would provide food and cages. Joe Aversa, Route 4 Aquarium, a pet store in Fair Lawn, NJ, rented a huge generator and opened their doors, not only to birds, but to fish, reptiles and other pets that were heat sensitive. (Remember, power was out for over a week in most areas.) Joe also politely refused free food - he said this was his way to give back to his community. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3344</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 40 No. 1 (2013): Number 1  2013; 9-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3344/3328</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
