<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4042</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:16:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ParroTrivia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schweikardt, Debbie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 3 (April 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.tives and hopefully in the near future some pairs will be established in other States.Continued from page 17 Pyrrhura Conures three different males and one common female, some new bloodlines were acquired from the zoo system which may have saved this species from a certain genetic bottleneck in the US captive population. Another roadblock to establishing this species in the US is that it is listed on the United States Endangered Species Act (USESA or ESA). This law prohibits sales or any financial commerce with the species across any state line. Unfortunately, this law is suffocating genetics in a species that needs the freedom to seek out new bloodlines in the country. Also, consider that this law makes it doubly difficult to get permits to import any specimens from other countries. It is doubtful the US Fish and Wildlife Service will approve any import programs to enhance this species here in the US. So in the mean time breeders struggle to keep lines strong and free...Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4042</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 3 (2022): Watchbird April 2022; 18</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4042/4002</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
