<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2926</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-12T15:48:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Endangered Species Reclassification</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The American Federation of Aviculture has been engaged for some time in an effort to have Captive, Self-Sustaining Populations (CSSP) status. declared for the Scarlet-chested (Neophema splendida) Parrakeet and .the Turquoisine (Neophema pulchella) Parrakeet, which are currently classified as endangered species.Under the present circumstances it is illegal to sell or transport interstate the above species. However, if a determination is made by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service that there are sufficient numbers of the above species being maintained and bred in captivity, then a CSSP classification may be applied to the indi viduals of the two species that are in the U.S. A CSSP determination means that breeders would then be allowed to sell and ship interstate the Scarlet-chested and Turquoisine Parrakeets they raise.Under the present law, a breeder must apply for and receive an endangered species permit each time he wishes to ship Scarlets and Turquoisines interstate. It is not certain that the breeder will receive a permit, and in any event, it takes three to four months to process the application. Under a CSSP classification, the breeder would obtain a permit that is renewable every two years. The CSSP permit would allow the breeder to conduct unlimited transactions with other permit holders, but would not change the regulations concerning the importation of Scarlets and Turquoisines from other countries. For importations, an endangered species permit would still be required.Obviously, the granting of CSSP status to Scarlets and Turquoisines will increase the interest in these birds and further insure that more of them are reared in aviaries. It will also allow breeders in states, where the numbers of aviculturists are relatively small, to have easier access to new blood lines - an important aspect in maintaining the genetic quality of the two species.AF A's original application was filed with the Fish and Wildlife service during the summer of 1977. Unfortunately, the data submitted had been collected by telephone, and was not entirely acceptable to Fish and Wildlife. Consequently,a printed inventory form was mailed to the original respondents and some additional breeders not covered in the first survey.Although the response from the printed inventory was less than fifty per cent, AFA did document twenty-four breeders of Scarlets and twenty-one breeders of Turquoisines. A total I of four hundred thirty-six Scarlets and two hundred fifty-seven Turquoisines were reported.The inventory forms were turned over to the Fish and Wildlife Service January 16, 1978. As soon as the information can be processed, we should look forward to having the proposal published in the Federal Register.It is unfortunate that AF A did not receive more cooperation from breeders maintaining Scarlets and Turquoisines in their aviaries. The success of our efforts can do nothing but help these breeders, who apparently don't care to help themselves.Anyone who maintains and breeds Scarlets'and Turquoisines, but has not seen or completed an inventory form, is urged to contact AF A if they would like to assist in this tremendously worthwhile project. Please direct such correspondence to the attention of Jerry Jennings. Your cooperation is vital to our success, and will be greatly appreciated. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2926</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 1 (1978): FEB-MAR 1978; 41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2926/2910</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
