<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/473</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">maintaining and breeding seed crackers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Seibels, Robert E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Prior to the 1980s, seedcrackerswere unknown to aviculture in theUnited States, although the crimson(Pyrenestes sanguineus) had apparentlybeen maintained (and possiblybred) by a handful of European aviculturistsduring the mid-1970s(Goodwin, 1982). We received ourfirst pairs of crimson seedcrackers inJune of 1980 from a friend who wasalso an importer in the midwest.After several weeks of unsuccessfulattempts to prevail upon me via telephone,he, being a persistent man, didthe next best thing - he called andgave me the flight information on thecrates of finches which were alreadyen route to Columbia. "You won'tbelieve your eyes when you seethem!" he told me. Just what I need, Ithought: some dumpy-looking littlebrown birds to take up space in myholding area. Was I in for a surprise!This is no dumpy-looking finch.Until now I had not consideredmyself to be a "finch person:' Ourcollection contained a few Gouldians,some whydahs and purple grenadiers.My friend was right: I couldn'tbelieve the intensity of the glistening,blood-red plumage. I tried to find outmore about them, but was disappointedto discover that preciouslittle was written about their behavioror management in captivity. Myfriend had suffered substantial losseswith the species during the quarantinerun and the three pairs thatarrived at Riverbanks were among thefew survivors. We had only receivedthese birds because he knew that aserious effort would be made to breedthem here. Breed them we did, eventually,but not without a struggle.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/473</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 2 (1989): APR-MAY 1989; 34-36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/473/458</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
