<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2452</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T21:50:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">First International Parrot Convention, Canary Islands</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Silva, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Location: The breathtaking island of Tenerife, in the Canary Islands. Loro Parque has a superb collection, so a trip there is a most worthwhile event with the convention being a bonus ... and what a bonus! Loro Parque has recently obtained pairs of very rare redspectacled Amazona pretrei and redtailed Amazons Amazona brasiliensi; these are only two of the many species held in no other collection that is open to the public.Travel Arrangements. A U.S. passport is required for all American citizens traveling abroad; non-citizens can travel on the passport of their country of origin. Delays in obtaining passports are normally experienced, so we suggest filling out an application available in most post offices and mailing it in as soon as possible. Visas are not required by Americans but nationals of other countries may need a visa. If you have any questions you may check with Iberia Airlines (1-800-221-9741) or Marun Travel, 11 East Adams St., #1005, Chicago, IL 60603, phone (312) 427-2128.Airfare and Hotel Reservations.The number of available rooms at the Maritim Hotel is limited, so to guarantee a room you must act as soon as possible. To make reservations, contact Marun International Travel. They accept checks or major credit cards. if your city of departure is not listed, they will be able to quote you additional information. Also, some of you have inquired about sharing a room. Please drop me a line with the particulars, smoking, nonsmoking, etc. and I will try to arrange that.Convention Registration Fee. The convention registration fee of $115.00 for members and $65.00 for guests should be in the form of a cashier's check or money order, made out to Laro Parque. See ad in this issue, page 35 • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2452</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 4 (1986): AUG-SEPT 1986; 24-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2452/2425</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
