<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1480</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:51:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">This Issue</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Many people define aviculture as a few breeding cages in which baby parrots are raised for the pet trade. Others may envision large outdoor aviaries on a bird farm in which a variety of exotic birds are raised. Then there are the canary and Budgie specialists who often don't pay much attention to any of the other species in captivity.A vi culture is extremely diverse. It also includes the pheasant and gallinaceous bird breeders, and those who focus on captive breeding for conservation, and the many breeding and public display activities in the zoos of the world. All things considered, might not we profit by widening our view of what aviculture really is? We think so.During the year 2000, we plan to present to you a plethora of birds - some common, some rare - that span the whole range of the avicultural spectrum as we see it. Of course we will continue to feature many of the regular columns you've come to expect, plus a few new ones occasionally.As a hook upon which to hang our focus, we will feature a different zoogeographical region in each issue. This issue kicks off that concept by presenting the whole world of birds - well, much of it. We have birds from scattered locations around the globe although there are some notable absences such as the Indian subcontinent, the Mid East, Europe, and northern Asia.But in this issue you will find toucans as pets and toucans in the Dallas World Aquarium - Central and South American birds. There is a wonderful article on tanagers (from Mexico, Central, and South America, depending on the species).There is an article on the Bar-shouldered Dove and one on the mutations of the Elegant Grass Parakeet, both from Australia.While we're in the area, look at the article on Stitchbirds from New Zealand. Never heard of them? They are not a bird commonly found in aviculture - indeed, this article may treat the only Stitchbirds in captivity. But they are now avicultural subjects being raised in a worthy conservation effort.We even have an article about breeding the common Mockingbird that most of you hear singing much of the year. What, you say, a bird of the U.S.A. in captivity? Isn't that illegal? Yes, of course it is - .here in the States. But these Mockingbirds are being kept in Belgium.Africa is represented by a curious story about the Whitefaced Scops Owl. And we have an article on the Speckled Mouse bird which also hails from sub-Saharan Africa ..Lories and lorikeets inhabit many of the Pacific Islands and the San Diego Zoo has a remarkable collection of species. We've chosen to illustrate the zoo's article with the beautiful little Tahitian Blue Lory.This is just the beginning of a great year. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1480</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 1 (2000): Jan-Feb 2000; 5-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1480/1457</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
