<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1340</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-03T20:24:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">President's Message</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clifton, Gary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Watchbird Magazine made its debut 25 years ago in August of 1974. In those days there were no such things as "avian veterinarian," "surgical sexing." or "DNA sexing." Handfeeding formula was all "do-it-yourself' as there were no handfeeding diets on the market. For those who were not around back then, imagine trying to set up a oair of macaws or Amazons without modem sexing techniques to know if you had a pair or just two birds.Now, 25 years later, we have surgical sexing and the non-invasive DNA technique. We have knowledgeable avian veterinarians, and we can actually buy handfeeding formula - our choice of several brands and mixes. We are producing more birds than ever before, both in overall numbers and in the diversity of species. Imported birds are now for the most part harder to find than handfed, domestically-bred birds. Never before have birds been a part of so many households all across the nation.For the next 25 years our greatest challenges will be two-fold. First, since avian importation is virtually a thing ofthe past, the steps we take today will determine the extent to which we are able to maintain genetic diversity in the populations we have as well as the diversity of species we have. The future is up to us, and depends on whether or not we can find ways to work together cooperatively to preserve this genetic diversity as well as our present diversity of species.Our second challenge will be to increase public awareness of this fascinating pursuit we call aviculture. Even today, most people might know someone who has a bird but very few know anyone who breeds birds. Not only do we need to take steps to preserve our captive populations throughout their generations, we also need to wake up and pay attention to where we might find the next generation of aviculturists. Will our kids and grandkids take up bird breeding just because we have? Or do we need to find ways to encourage interest in aviculture.What can we do to encourage those who might be inclined to make the transition from bird-owner to breeder? The future is in our hands...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1340</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 4 (1999): JULY-AUG 1999; 10-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1340/1318</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
