<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2115</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-07T18:34:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From The Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Many people fazJ to realize that magazines are edited by human beings. Nor is a casual meeting with an editor very convincing on that point.I don't remember my first editoria! endeavors - nor does anybody else - and I never thought that years later I'd stzll be at it. No one becomes an editor by design. It just happens.The calling demands a great deal of solitary pouring over many zJl-begotten manuscripts. It requires thumbing through thousands of musty pages in search of the correct Latin name. And delving in the dictionary day after day does, somehow, demean one. And it dries one out a bit, too. Indeed, after so many solitary years with naught but my books and pipe I feel rather dry - and I suspect other people find me even drier than I feel.Editing a bird magazine is a peculiar calling that is, to an extent, dusty, dehumanizing, and destructive of sound social graces. But, believe me, dear reader, behind the punctuation of this periodical and under the heading of this column there is an actual man, wizened Thanks For A Job Well DoneThis drawing of the extinct Carolina Parakeets will be familiar to those who attended AF A's 1981 convention in San Diego. It was produced by the talented hands of Robin Hill, an Australian wildlife artist currently residing in Washington, D.C. Distributed at lastyear's convention banquet, the purpose was two-fold; as a personal invitation to attend the 1982 AFA convention, and a graphic reminder of why the very existence of AFA is so important. AFA wishes to express sincere thanks to Robin Hill for donating this work. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2115</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 9 No. 4 (1982): AUG-SEPT 1982; 30-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2115/2086</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
