<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2222</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-02-25T04:09:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">In Search of the Tres Marias Double Yellow-headed Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hansen, Walt</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In 197 6 I decided to find out about psittacine birds, so I purchased a couple of elderly parakeets. Within a few months I learned from observation and extensive reading that keeping parakeets was quite easy, depending mainly on common sense, so I decided to branch out and gradually worked my way up through the more common types such as a Finsch' s Amazon, a Mexican redhead, a pair of half-moons (which produced two lovely chicks for me, thereby deceiving me into thinking that sexing parrots by observation wasn't really so difficult!), and finally on to yellow napes and the delightful double yellowheaded Amazon parrot.Along the way I joined San Diego's Hookbill Hobbyists Club and soon began hearing about the "fabulous" Tres Marias double yellowhead. I started a systematic search of the literature on parrots and soon discovered that information is scarce and sketchy regarding this subspecies of Amazona ochrocephala. Bates and Busenbark, in their book ''Parrots and Related Birds,"1 have only this to say: "Restricted to the Tres Marias Island (sic), this subspecies can be distinguished from the Mexican Double Yellow Head by its larger bill and head, and a brighter, more extensive yellow head. A faint bluish tinge transforms it into a brighter green.'' Not bad as far as it goes, this description is hardly definitive. A.E. Decoteau in his book "Handbook of Amazon Parrots"2 writes the following: There is definitely more yellow on the entire head and throat, extending down onto the neck and breast. The back and wings are lighter green than those of A. o. oratrix. The bend of the wing has much red mixed with yellow; the thighs are a rich golden yellow. The bird is larger and has a longer tail than A. o. oratrix. '' This description fits exactly the yellowhead that we in the San Diego area, at least, have been calling "Tres Maria," but is it? I'll get to that shortly.Decoteau also describes what he calls a ''Magna Double Y ellowheaded Amazon.'' He writes: ''An exceptionally large double yellowhead Amazon, two to three inches larger than A. o. oratri.x, this bird from southern Mexico rivals the Tres Marias Amazon in size and beauty. If anything, the magna lacks some of the yellow color that the Tres Marias exhibits and seems to be a darker green in general body color. Not all ornithologists consider this bird sufficiently different from oratrix to be classified as a separate species, but I think that it should be and will treat it as such."What I find of interest here is that, according to Rosemary Low in her book "The Parrots of South America"3 A. o. magna was first described by Monroe and Howell in 1966.4 Since double yellowheaded Amazons were discovered and described over 100 years ago - in 1871 by Grayson, who named the bird Chrysotis levaillantii -one wonders where the ''magna'' was hiding during all those years, especially since it is allegedly found along nearly all of the east coast of Mexico from Tamaulipas to eastern Tabasco. As for the magna' s appearance, Ms. Low writes: ''larger than A. o. oratrix. As large as A. o. tresmariae, but lacks the bluish cast to the green plumage."According to the "Distributional Checklist of the Birds of Mexico,"~ the habitat of the "standard" double yellowhead on the east coast of Mexico covers all the area listed for "magna" and then some. Joseph M. Forshaw in his book "Parrots of the World"6 does not list any A. o. magna, but does state that birds from the Caribbean slope of Mexico tend to be larger than those from the Pacific side. So it does not appear to me that the T res Marias subspecies is involved in this particular confusion. Finally, Forshaw described A. o. tresmariae as ''adults similar to oratrix, but yellow of head extending down on to neck and upper breast; upper parts slightly tinged with blue; averages larger in size and with longer tail.'' I would like to point out here that Forshaw's description of the adult standard double yellowhead (A. o. oratrix) fits almost perfectly what we in San Diego have been calling a Tres Marias. He wrote: ''Adults: Entire head and throat yellow; bend of wing pale red intermixed with yellow; carpal edge and thighs yellow; bill horn colored tinged with gray towards base of upper mandible. Immatures: Head entirely green except for a patch of yellow on forehead; bend of wing green; carpal edge yellowish-green.''Having seen many specimens, both young and old, of A. o. oratrix, I have observed that the grey in the beak is only present in very young birds, and that fledglings also always have red feathers on the bend of the wing right from the start. So even Forshaw may make a little error now and then. Finally, Arthur Freud in his book "All About the Parrots"7 says that "A. o. tresmari.ae resembles the Double Yellow Head but has a much greater area of yellow extending over the head and neck at an earlier age. This subspecies can also be recognized by its massive head and beak, generally greater length and large red markings on the bend of the wing.'' He omits the usual mention of yellow thighs. So, it is evident that every writer sees and describes these mysterious Amazon parrots a little differently, whether they have actually observed them or not.In 1982 I couldn't stand all the confusion and mystery any longer, so I made a trip to Mexico City to find out what was to be seen at the Mexico City Zoo in Chapultepec Park. Well, folks, there are quite a few fine parrots there, but NO Tres Marias double yellowheads! I then traveled to San Blas on the West coast of Mexico, the nearest point on the mainland to the T res Marias Islands, some 6 5 miles off shore. It is from this small port that E.W. Nelson and others sailed in 1897 in an expedition of the Biological Survey Division of the U.S. Department of Agriculture. More about it shortly. I found, however, that all traffic to and from the Islands now uses the large, modem port of Mazatlan, so I immediately went to that city and located the offices of the Tres Marias Agency.There I met Mr. Cristobal Castillo who was most helpful and informative. Not only did he confirm the existance on the islands of "thousands" of yellowheaded parrots, he gave me the address in Mexico City of the Department of Prevention and Social Readaptation. Since Maria Madre Island is the site of a Federal Penitentiary, it falls under the jurisdiction of the Department and travel to and from the island is, of course, very carefully controlled. Mr. Castillo seemed quite sure that I would receive permission to visit the island if I would apply for it. Some time after returning home I wrote to the Director Generalin Mexico City but, probably due to elections and changes in key government personnel, I had not received a reply by February, 1983, so I flew again to Mexico City, armed with all the documentation I had gathered regarding the islands and the parrots, plus pictures of my own birds.The receptionist at the Department listened carefully to my explanation of the reason for my visit, then immediately went to the office of Mr. Martinez Lavin who is in charge of travel control. Within five minutes the receptionist returned and ushered me into Mr. Martinez's office. During a 20 minute conversation I described the reasons for which I wished to visit Maria Madre Island, presented my documentation and hoped for the best. Mr. Martinez Lavin told me he would relay my request to the Director General, Licenciado Antonio Garcia Orozco, and that I should come back the next day. When I returned, my travel permit was ready! The courtesy and efficiency of everyone in the Department was outstanding and I wish to thank the Director General and his entire staff for their helpfulness. Not only did I receive permission to spend eight days (April 14 to 22, 1983) on the island, but I was provided with transportation out and back on a Mexican Navy vessel and housing while there. My only expense, other than round trip air fare to Mazatlan, was for meals and they were very low priced.The 125 mile trip over to the islands from Mazatlan is rugged. Twelve hours outdoors overnight on the deck of a minesweeper is not much like sailing on the "Love Boat" - but the price was right! I knew in advance to pack food and water along, but I sure could have used an air mattress and a blanket. However, as the islands came into view about SAM in brilliant sunshine, the hardships were quickly forgotten and it was with great pleasure that I stepped ashore after a night of rocking and rolling over the bounding main.The Federal penal colony on Maria Madre Islands is not confined to a few buildings but occupies the entire island and has been under new management, so to speak, since 1977. As a result, the former "Devil's Island" reputation has been dispelled. The Director, Lie. Francisco Castellanos, is a young, progressive, university-educated man who has banned from the island drugs and alcohol in any form. All plant and animal life is protected. Castellanos has instituted educational and retraining programs and has modernized and improved the housing and other facilities on the island. Television from Mexico City is available by satellite!   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2222</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 11 No. 1 (1984): FEB-MAR 1984; 14-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2222/2196</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
