<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1714</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-25T15:57:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Wayne Smyth</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Moore, Mark</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Wayne Smyth has been an accomplished professional artist for over 30 years.His work has been exhibited in galleries in the United States, Europe, and Africa. Wayne's paintings reflect a true understanding of the birds he captures, and he presents them in such a lifelike way, that it would seem you could reach out touch them. For the past eight years, Wayne has donated his fine artwork to the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. and its members. In 2001, Wayne was awarded an honorary lifetime membership to the organization for his generosity.During a visit to the Hill Country Aviaries, in Texas, Wayne Smyth was able to interact with a pair of Red-tailed Black Cockatoos in their flight cage. Inspired by the beauty and feather of these magnificent birds, Wayne created a stunning original painting that was chosen for this year's subject for AFA's 30th annual convention.Wayne was able to photograph and make mental images of the birds to be used in the creation of this original artwork. What could be more inspiring than to have these magnificent parrots flying overhead and perching in full display at only an arm's length away. Wayne Smyth has proven year after year, painting after painting, that his talent is unparalleled when it comes to capturing parrots in watercolor. In another show of his unending generosity, he has donated this artwork, Red-tailed Black Cockatoo, to the members of The American Federation of Aviculture. •!• </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1714</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 30 No. 1 (2003): First Quarter 2003; 44</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1714/1691</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
