<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2641</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-18T20:08:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA 17th Annual Convention, San Diego, California, Aug. 7-11, '91</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Commemorative San Diego '91 T-shirts for SaleTo raise funds for the 17th annual convention of the American Federation of Aviculture, the San Diego convention committee is offering T-shirts with a design by world-famous wildlife artist Gamini Ratnavira.The shirts are pre-shrunk, white, 100 % cotton with a full-color illustration of five endangered birds: the Red Siskin, Bali Mynah, Swinhoe's Pheasant, Golden Conure, and Spix Macaw. The message on the T-shirt, and a point for all to remember:Aviculture Eliminates Extinction.T-shirts are available in sizes from small to extra-extra large. The cost is $12 per shirt plus $ 2 shipping and handling. Specify size(s) and send your check made payable to S.D. Avi Convention Committee. Mail check and ordering information to 1265 Avocado Blvd., Suite 104-121, El Cajon, CA 92020. • Treat Yourself to a Carnival of Good Times The 1991 convention of the American Federation of Aviculture (AFA) will be held in San Diego, California at the Red Lion Inn, August 7 - 1 1.Three full days of seminars and workshops will feature talks by renowned aviculturists, avian veterinarians and researchers. Free public seminars are also offered on selecting and breeding birds, avian nutrition, health, and other aspects of bird care.In addition to its educational programs, the annual convention features an exhibit hall with over 70 cage and feed manufacturers, publishers, and breeders. All will have their latest and best merchandise for sale, plus plenty of information that is free for the asking.A raffle table, carnival night, evening dinner cruise on San Diego Bay, meetings of specialty organizations, and a host of speakers, books, and old-fashioned hospitality promise to keep the magic of birds alive for many years. The first registrants will also receive tickets to the Saturday night banquet and awards ceremony. Seating is limited, so don't delay.Call the AFA business office at (602) 484-0931 to reserve your perch in the sun, by the sea, in San Diego.• </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2641</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 2 (1991): APR-MAY 1991; 46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2641/2611</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
