<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2711</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-25T20:57:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Disclaimer for Red Siskin Raffle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kidd, Malinda</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To all members of AFA-Red Siskin Project:This letter is to help you better understand the macaw raffle which will be held in December of 1991.Michelle Rietz and I have jointly decided on how we could personally donate money to the Siskin Project. Because this Siskin Project is terribly important to both of us, we have decided a raffle could possibly be the answer.With that thought, Michelle had the tickets printed and I donated the largest hand-fed baby, born to Kidd's Kradle this year.It must be remembered that our only thought here is to help the project raise funds. When selling these raffle tickets, you must remember that neither the AFA nor the AFA Red Siskin Project are in any way related to this raffle. We are holding this raffle as independent individuals and will donate all profits to the AFA Red Siskin Project.Please do not misrepresent AFA in any way by using that title to sell these tickets. The sole sponsors of this raffle are Michelle and me. Hopefully this will clear up any unforeseen problems that may arise should you misrepresent AF A in any way.If you have any questions concerning this matter, please contact either me or Michelle Rietz (602) 433-9940. Remember, the Siskin Project is in need of the donations from this raffle, but not to the point as to cause any problems with any organization misrepresentation.SincerelyMalinda Fitzgerald Kidd Kidds Kradle2644 Red Pine Court Green Bay, WI 54313 (414) 434-3959 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2711</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 5 (1991): OCT- NOV 1991; 39-40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2711/2691</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
