<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1579</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:54:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Timneh Greys a Wallflower Worth Noticing</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shimniok, Rita</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">0 akridge Feather Fann has been raising parrots for over 10 years, with the latter half focusing primarily on African species. In the past two years, I have noticed a budding increase in the number of inquiries received requesting availability status of Timneh African Greys, Psiuacus eritbacus timneb. Our small aviary can never produce enough babies to keep up with the demand. If you are new to aviculture, or are considering specialization, I urge you to give serious thought to adding these African treasures to your flock.Rising in PopularityYes, it is true. Timneh African Greys do talk just as well as their red-tailed cousins, and they have personalities that are just as big, despite their smaller size. The demand for the Timneh African Grey is on the rise as more and more people are realizing all that this subtly colored wallflower has to offer.It seems much more difficult to locate an aviculturist raising Timneh babies versus Congo Greys, Psiitacus e. entbacus. I believe there are at least two reasons for this. One being that Timnehs were never imported in large numbers, especially compared to the Congo Grey from which importers could make a larger profit; and secondly, it seems, that for many breeders, Timneh Greys are not as prolific in breeding as the Congos. This is unfortunate, as some breeders attempting to breed Timnehs even become frustrated with the lack of production and sell their pairs. If everyone were to give up on breeding the Timneh African Grey, pet owners would miss the opportunity of having one of the most wonderful parrots as their feathered companion.People who are lucky enough to cater to both Congo and Timneh Grey companions, have noticed that oftenthe Timneh is a more outgoing in presence of company, compared to their seemingly more introverted, larger cousin. Timnehs do not seem to be as concerned about strangers in their presence, and go on about their leisure, playing with toys and chattering to their hearts content.Why is this? Do Timneh African Greys really have a more laidback personality? Or, does it just seem that way because so many Congo Greys are raised in production style facilities, and perhaps are not as well socialized as the Timnehs, which are often bred by the smaller, non commercialized breeder?Many breeders who raise both the Timneh and the Congo Grey, also find that the Timneh babies have a more low-key temperament, and do not seem as high-strung as the Congos. If a family with children calls me wanting an African Grey, I highly recommend the Timneh to them over the larger Congo, not only because I feel their size is less intimidating to children, but because I also feel the Timneh's personality will be better suited to a family situation. In fact, of all the African parrots we raise here at Oakridge, I trust the Timneh babies the most with my two-year-old son, who loves to help feed and play with the chicks. The Timneh babies are less inclined to explore and beak everything in their path, including little fingers offering a bird toy.Raising Domestic Timneh GreysIf one can locate a domestic handfed Timneh Grey baby he or she is likely to be smitten by these blackeyed, sometimes red speckled, charcoal gray parrots. Baby Timnehs exhibit their extroverted personalities early. At an age where Congo Grey babies demonstrate caution or mild interest towards their hand-feeder, Timneh chicks are scrambling over one another in their efforts to be the first one to "mama." These early behavior differences really do seem to justify the statement that Tirnnehs are more easy going.In a nurturing environment, Timneh babies do not hesitate to climb aboard visitors to inspect buttons, glasses and such. When our baby Timnehs are approximately six weeks old we begin the process of teaching the babies to explore. We spread bed sheets on the floor and sprinkle the sheets with baby toys and bits of cereal, hard pasta, popcorn, pellets, etc. It is fun to watch a baby spot a "must have" item several feet away, and quickly waddle its fluffy gray bottom with sprouting, bright red tail feathers over to grasp the toy or morsel in its black beak.As baby Timnehs mature, their upper mandibles become lighter, and bright red tail feathers are replaced bymaroon feathers. Just like most Congo Greys, baby Timnehs will lose the red speckles scattered amid their body feathers during their first several molts.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1579</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 5 (2000): Sept-Oct 2000; 40-41</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1579/1556</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
