<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2012</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-12-24T06:13:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From The Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dear Editor,I would like to reply to Ralph V. Smith (Dec 80/Jan 81) and address AFA and its readers.I share Mr. Smith's concern over the nutritional unknown. The problem is there hasn't been a lot of blood samples available for testing and the results compiled. The science and technology for running nutritional analysis is known. A viculturists need to make blood samples available for testing.AF A is critically needed to direct and assist in a program such as this. I would like to see AF A set the standards for a nutritional testing program by blood. For example, Protein Level, 1 ml. serum required, normal levels 3.8 to 6.0, test method; Kjeldahl Nitrogen Analysis, keep refrigerated, not to exceed 3 days old, etc ...I wanted to find out how good (or bad) my hand feeding formula was in protein, so my vet drew blood for protein testing. The results came back 4.0, low side of normal. I changed my formula (increased the meat) and ran a second protein level 2 months later and the results came back 5.2. The lab test showed me which formula gave my babies enough protein.A viculturists are needed to provide the samples and forward the results to AF A with a history of the bird, age, sex (if known) diet, and condition at the time the sample is taken (breeding, moult, sick, in- jured, etc.). AFA could then compile and publish the results. Hopefully these results will give us the knowledge and guidelines for which we are looking.Kathy VerBeck N. Canton, OHYour advice seems very good. Such a program would benefit aviculture greatly if it works as well as you suggest. I suggest you write af ormal letter to AF A president, Dr. RichardE. Baer, and encourage him to explore this concept with our scientific research committee.And since that old aviculturist, author, and rabble-rouser Ralph Smith set this thing off, I suggest that his blood be tested first. If it pans out we can go on to test his birds. portunity to speak.I can't help but wonder if, in the years ahead, the history books will record two important dates: the 1430s when Nez.ahualcoyotl collected a zoo of strange animals, the first in the New World, the 1980s when animals were no longer allowed into the United States and zoos began to die.It may sound a bit fictitious, but with no internal breeding and with importations increasing, natural populations certainly can't be expected to hold-up. Deer are managed for harvesting, but parrots must endure both native pressures of habitat destruction, pet and pot demands, and also the foreign pet trade. That noted attribute of humans, lack of foresight, will destroy aviculture in America if it is not checked now.Two points greatly disturb me in regards to the activity of AF A. First, I have been pushing for the sale of a poster (such as the great one I saw on the wall at the convention) to provide funds for projects, etc.Secondly, throughout the Christmas season I have traveled throughout Texas and some other southern states and made a point to stop in pet stores. The chances that a person entering a pet store and purchasing a pet bird will see any proof that AF A exists are very close to zero. With AF A members in most large cities, why is there no evidence of AF A's existence in places where the public buys our specialty? </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-12-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2012</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 8 No. 2 (1981): APRIL-MAY 1981; 41-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2012/1983</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
