<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2868</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-09T15:26:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Welcome to AFA Convention 1979</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ireland, Tom</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As chairman of the 1979 AFA convention, I invite you all to a Caribbean holiday in a lush, tropical setting complete with birds, beaches, fantastic tours and entertainment. And that is only part of what you'll get this year at the Fifth Annual AF A Convention.The convention is hosted by the Gold Coast Exotic Bird Club Inc. with much help from the Aviary and Cage Bird Society of South Florida, the Greater Jacksonville Avicultural Society, the Suncoast Finch Society, and the Sunshine State Cage Bird Society. It will be held at the fabulous Diplomat Hotel in Hollywood, Florida.The program will feature forty of the top aviculturalists, zoologists, ornithologists, and veterinarians to be found anywhere. For example, Rosemary Low from England will give two talks, one on pair bonding and other aspects of parrot breeding, and one on the Yellow Shouldered Amazon-its wild and captive history. Dr. Ted LaFeber will speak on stress in birds, physical and emotional. Bob Berry, curator of birds at the Houston Zoo, will address the pitfalls of aviculture. Alba Ballard will explain ways to treat sick or injured birds. The list of outstanding speakers is too lengthy to cover here. Please refer to the schedule of speakers which will be included in the membership convention mail-out package. If you're not a member, or don't receive your package by mail, write the home office, or contact me.In addition to the regular convention features, Dr. Greg Harrison and Linda Harrison will conduct a program for veterinarians on the diagnosis and treatment of avian diseases for the beginning practitioner. This will be held Sunday, August 26, 8:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m.If the above is not enough, we have several excellent tours planned including a trip to a bird importer's holding station and to the famous Parrot Jungle. These tours take place on Saturday and Sunday.Additional field trips will explore Hialeah Race Course (their grandstands.coach museum, aquarium, and aviary) and the world renowned Fairchild Tropical Gardens with their many acres of rare palms, flowering trees and orchids.The cost of each field trip or tour is $10.00 per person in addition to the convention registration fees.The Diplomat is far more than just a fine hotel. It is a resort and country club with two championship golf courses, nineteen tennis courts, five swimming pools, and a fantastic 1,200 foot expanse of golden beach.To satisfy the most discriminating gourmet we have personally worked with the Diplomat's catering manager and will provide a cuisine that is flawless. For lunch Friday there will be a large wedge of sweet melon au citron, luncheon rolls, sliced pork roast with apple and raisin stuffing, string beans amandine, and orange sherbet with mandarin sauce. The dinner menu consists of cream of mushroom soup served from silver tureens, dinner rolls, breast of capon, continental ricepilaf, brussel sprouts and water chestnuts. -,?When you are making your room reservations with the Diplomat Hotel, ~ remember to say you are registering for the AFA convention, and you want thl"-q special AF A convention room rates. Our arrangements for the special rates are:/, single $28.00, double $32.QO. ~We, here in Florida, are looking forward to your visit. We are working very hard z: :o present a program that will be remembered for its hospitality, fun, education and birds.Sincerely, Tom Ireland, Convention Chairman 4 724 Collier, Lake Worth, Florida 33463 • (305) 968-4214 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2868</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 3 (1979): JUNE-JULY 1979; 23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2868/2852</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
