<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3099</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-18T09:38:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From the Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">If you have any complaints regarding the last issue of the Watchbird please direct them to your humble servant, S.L. Dingle. During the publication of that issue I was in the process of moving. Those of you who know how absentminded and unorganized I am can envision the chaotic disaster that resulted.For a month now I've been in the new home and still haven't found my desk. The last thing anyone remembers is me raking the papers and books off of it prior to the move. Sooner or later, no doubt, one or another of the mountain of packing boxes will shift and expose a corner of the desk and we'll know where to excavate. Until then, however, I'll assume full responsibility for whatever confusion creeps into the "Watchbird".The other evening while pondering the whole mess I was rummaging around the pocket of my smoking jacket looking for a match to light my pipe (the one that was in my mouth during the move - I can't find the others) and I came upon the following letters.Dear Sir:I have recently purchased four pairs of finches. My hopes are to breed my little friends in my home aviary. Having exhausted the local library and learning almost nothing about the habits and needs of my three species of finches, I am requesting any information you may have that would be useful in my project.J.B. Shirley Annapolis, MDIn Maryland there are at least two bird clubs that belong to the A.F.A. Those clubs are listed in the front pages of this magazine. If you contact the delegates listed I'm confident they will introduce you to other aviculturists in your area and you can learn first hand about how various finches are handled in your part of the country.I'd offer some personal advise but I can't find any of my finch books right now. I'm not quite sure where my finches are either. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3099</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 6 (1977): DEC 1977- JAN 1978; 36-40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3099/3083</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
