<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/658</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Africa's Threatened Birds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Only one species of parrot is consideredat risk on the African continent,that being the Black-cheeked Lovebird.With the most restricted range ofany agapornid, the Black-cheeked is alowland bird inhabiting river valleys insouthwest Zambia along the ZambesiRiver. While Forshaw documents itssporadic occurrence at Victoria Fallsin far northwestern Zimbabwe, otherauthors claim it is now extinct inZimbabwe. As is the fate of most parrots,trapping for the live bird tradehas contributed greatly to its currentthreatened status. While not commonin aviculture in the United States,several small colonies do exist in privatecollections.While finches have been exported. in large numbers from the Africancontinent, only two waxbills and eightweavers seem not to be faring well.The Anambra Waxbill is found alongrivers and lagoons in southernNigeria. The other threatened waxbillis the Black-lored Waxbill that inhabitsthe grassy plains along the LualaqbaRiver and along Lake Upembain southern Zaire. As with the multitudeof weavers to follow, the waxbillsseem to occur in a very smallrange making tl1em extremely vulnerableto habitat destruction.Threatened African birds of interestto aviculturists (from: ICBP WorldChecklist of Threatened Birds, MisePub. No. 8 Collar and Andrews, editors):Swierstra's Francolin, WattledCrane, Northern Bald Ibis, MarbledTeal, White-headed Duck, HoubaraBustard, Black-cheeked Lovebird,Price Ruspoli's Touraco, AnkoberSerin, Yellow-throated Serin, EthiopianBrush-crow, White-breastedGuineafowl, Abbott's Starling, JackassPenguin, African Green Broadbill,Congo Peacock, Marungu Sunbird,Rockefeller's Sunbird, Anambra Waxbill,Black-lored Waxbill, Lake LufiraWeaver, Golden-naped Weaver, Yellow-legged Weaver, Black-chinnedWeaver, Loango Slender-billedWeaver, Clarke's Weaver, Bannerman'sWeaver, Bates' Weaver.Of the eight species of weavers, fouroccur in Zaire, again with smallranges. Some, such as the LoangoSlender-billed Weaver, seem to be disappearingwithout obvious threat.Few of the remaining species on thelist are known to aviculturists. PrinceRuspoli's Touraco also has a smallrange in souiliern Ethiopia. It may alsoface risk from competition from theWhite-cheeked Touraco. The MarbledTeal's range spans from north Africa toSpain, Pakistan and Iraq yet it is consideredone of the rarest of Europeanducks. It is however, consideredwidespread and well established incaptivity. The other rare African species of waterfowl also has a wide range.The White-headed Duck breeds along the western Mediterraneanand winters in north Africa. Whileconsidered declining in many areas, itis not well established in captivityexcept at the Wildfowl Trust and in afew additional collections.Additonal species of concern inAfrica include two species of serinsand sunbirds, as well as a starling,crow, penguin, broadbill, peacock(the only peacock in Africa), bustard,crane, ibis and francolin.With the exception of South Africawhich has well over a hundred professionalornithologists, the rest of Africaseems to exhibit the same wildlifeconservation challenges as mostdeveloping or third world nations.What conservation work is beingdone is coordinated through the variousuniversities, museums and zoosthat can afford such activities. The PanAfrican Ornithological Congress andPan African Association of ZoologicalGardens, Aquaria and Botanical Gardensserve to pull it somewhattogether. As with the rest of the world,birds of prey and parrots are dealtwith to a greater degree than insect orfruit eating species. Foreign speresearchersplay an important rollbringing expertise and funding to dealwith species that otherwise would notbe studied. While a great deal of conservationwork needs to be done inwest African countries, few ornithologistsare willing to risk "life andlimb" for such a cause.In South Africa both conservationand avicultural organizations are wellrepresented, the Endangered WildlifeTrust being one such forward-thinkingconservation body. Aviculturists haveboth the A vicultural Council of SouthAfrica as well as the excellent aviculturalpublication "Avizandum".With imports dwindling in the nearfuture many will likely focus on Australianand South American species.Particularly with the finches, ouractions today will determine the diversityavailable to "fledgling" aviculturiststomorrow. We can only hopethat it will always be possible to add atouch of Africa to our aviaries. Whoknows, perhaps along the way wemay develop the methodologyneeded to save a weaver or lovebirdor serin from planetary extinction as well.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/658</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/658/641</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
