<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2554</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-03T21:26:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Preventive Health Care for Aviculture</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clipsham, Robert C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Modern technology continues to creep into our lives at a rate unprecedented at any other time in history and aviculturists and their birds are not immune to this process. Computers and other electronics are being applied to aviculture and are becoming recognized as the powerful tools they are. One such example is the computer listing of the current zoo populations for the cataloging of these species and their locations. The I.S.I.S. (International Species Identification System) program aids zoos and collectors in mating single individuals or obtaining new blood lines for closed populations in order to offset decreasing world populations.This is a useful system achieved through design. I have been fortunate to have witnessed a system just as helpful for the average aviary owner that came about as a result by accident.A client of the clinic owns and operates a huge, closed aviary essentially single-handed. The aviary started experiencing a loss of expensive power equipment despite fences, locks, night lighting and a pair of rather ferocious dogs (sound familiar?). The owner installed a series of closed circuit video cameras with a bank of television monitors to observe the aviary walkways, grounds and nursery at night simultaneously. The cost of these electronics has dropped into the range of accessability for most citizens as competition pushes prices lower. Large wholesale style warehouse merchants and the buying clubs have reduced the buying price even lower. A standard video camera, monitor and cable kit can be obtained for as little as $199 (i.e., Philleps produced by the Magnavox Company).Diligence paid off for this owner and the culprits eventually were caught after a short period of time. They turned out to be day laborers hired for construction on the premises and had made friends with the dogs, probably via the lunch box method.After the thieves were caught and arrested, it seemed natural to keep the cameras in place to act as a deterrant and/or a detection method for future break-in attempts. Video recorder units had been added to the monitor systems so that a regular night's sleep could still be had with an instant playback of the night's taping in the morning. The cameras are of the type with microphones which act as audio monitors, and can be recorded simultaneously on virtually all of the new VHS machines which are so popular. The sensitivity of these microphones is impressive. A quarter dropped on pavement ten yards from the camera can be heard over the monitor as plainly as if it had landed near your own foot.As the owner continued to casually monitor the screens occasionally during the day and during the routine morning playback, it became obvious that a pattern was emerging that was entirely unseen before.Bird behavior was being recorded accidentally, with some fascinating results being observed.Prior to the introduction of the camera, the bird collection had been essentially unchanged for many years and the same pairs mated for many years. The owner was virtually the only person working in the aviary for the purposes of cleaning, feeding and nest box checks. The aviary is of excellent design and construction and considered by many prominent aviculturists in southern California to be an example of state-of-the-art avicultural management. The production had been fair to good with the normal lack of success with the usual species and particular pairs. The collection consists of several conure species, macaws, African Congo greys, most of the Cacatua species and several of the Eclectus sub-species. The birds reacted...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2554</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 4 (1990): AUG-SEPT 1990; 41-42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2554/2524</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
