<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2448</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T21:50:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Avian Influenza Battle Not Finished</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Just as smoldering embers can restart a major fire, so poultry producers in the Northeast should not count on last winter's avian influenza epidemic as being totally wiped out.Recent reports from Pennsylvania, as well as New York City, Ohio and Connecticut, indicate that the potentially deadly H5N2 avian influenza virus is still in circulation and represents far-flying sparks threatening all poultry producers in the Northeastern and Mid-Atlantic states.The 1986 outbreak is complicated by the fact that live poultry markets in the New Jersey-New York City area have served as reservoirs of infection. In this connection, contaminated shipping crates, trucks and other handling equipment used by dealers continue to be possible vectors for spreading the malady to farm flocks throughout a wide geographical area.That's the word from Edward T.Mallinson, Extension poultry veterinarian at the University of Maryland. Dr. Mallinson is an associate professor at the College Park campus of the VirginiaMaryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine.Mallinson emphasizes that specialty producers supplying live poultry markets or auctions should insist that dealers coming to their farms use clean, disinfected crates, coops, trucks, catching hooks, crowding devices, forklifts and other handling equipment. This is doubly important if the entire flock is not to be completely depopulated in one swoop.When some chicks are to be left on the farm, producers also have a right to expect that catching crews wear freshly laundered coveralls and sneakers or cleaned and disinfected boots, Dr. Mallinson declared.Unfortunately, Mallinson observed, some people seem to have trouble understanding that it doesn't necessarily require a sick bird brought into a flock from an outside source to bring avian influenza and several other infectious diseases onto someone's poultry premises. These maladies also are easily spread by particles of contaminated dust, debris and manure.Although they are invisible, infectious disease organisms can be present on these small particles in enormous numbers, he pointed out.Dr. Mallinson admits that producers may have to pay extra for insisting on sanitary hauling practices by dealers. But the benefits derived can well be peace of mind, healthier and more productive birds, and the feeling of being a good farming citizen.He notes that avian influenza does not present a hazard to human health. But it can cause high death losses among various types of poultry with severe financial loss to owners and keepers. •  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2448</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 4 (1986): AUG-SEPT 1986; 20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2448/2421</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
