<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2442</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T21:50:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">President's Message - Handwriting on the Wall</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The members of the AFA have had an opportunity over the past two years to read about the so-called "New York Wild Bird Ban Law;' the appearance of clones in neighboring states, and the arguments on both sides of the issue, in Watchbird. The impact of the imposition of a wild bird ban, state by state, throughout the U.S. is no less than a drastically reduced availability of a wide range of species through the de facto elimination of the import trade. The prospect of an end to imported stock has certainly caught our attention.The various state legislative threats have generated so much heat and smoke that a less imminent, but more insidious threat to aviculture has largely been obscured. The threat that there won't be any exporting countries to supply birds long before any de facto restrictions on imports could ever possibly be in place.Over the past half dozen years, numerous countries have closed off the export of birds, already drastically reducing the number of species, once commonly available. Where are the once plentiful species from India, Indonesia, Venezuela, Colombia, Costa Rica and Guatemala? Other countries have reduced the number and type of species they are willing to export. What happened to the eclectus parrots, triton and palm cockatoos once exported from Indonesia, or the Andean cocks of the rock and mountain toucans from Peru? Most are no longer available, not only from the source countries, but tragically from within our own aviaries.Rather than list the countries that do not export birds, an easy task ten years ago, it is far simpler to list the countries that do export. In Latin America, only Argentina, Peru, Guayana, and Honduras still export birds, and not without restrictions. Argentina reportedly no longer exports toucans, Peru no longer exports any species east of the Andes, and Guayana closes exports for the breeding season (an admirable procedure ensuring renewable resources).What does all this mean to you? It means that time is running out to fulfill any dreams you may hold with regard to future breeding programs. The notion that a plentiful supply of a species today means a good supply tomorrow is bankrupt. Tomorrow may never come for a number of species. I only wish I had bought those grey breasted mountain toucans a few years ago. They came in once, that I am aware of, from either Peru or Ecuador-both now closed. And what about those hyacinth macaws from Bolivia three to four years ago that were imported in such numbers that each load brought down the price to as low as $1450.00! I thought the price would go lower and waited. Now it's too late for a bargain, but I can, of course, invest $ 5000. 00 per bird, if I can find them. For the mountain toucans, I can't find them at any price.Now is the time to take a hard look at where you want to be in aviculture, with which species you wish to work. Not today, or even tomorrow, but in five, ten, or fifteen years from now. You might also want to think about where you would like to see aviculture ten, twenty, thirty years from now and ask yourself how you can help take it there.Don't put off tomorrow what so urgently needs to be done today. Dream your dream and make a plan that will get you there. Begin your breeding program as if today may be the last day the birds you need will be readily available. Learn as much as you can about your interest area, share that knowledge and encourage others to join with you. And, support your bird club and the AFA with your time, talent, and resources. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2442</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 4 (1986): AUG-SEPT 1986; 10</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2442/2415</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
