<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3884</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-17T03:14:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Wild Hybrids in Australia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baird, Matt</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Australia has an incredible diversity of native birds, and while most bird species don’t commonly hybridize in the wild, some closely related species within the same genus or family do.
Wild hybrids in parrots and cockatoos were once considered an extremely rare phenomenon, with some purists insisting it never happens. However, modern technology has enabled us to see that hybridization occurs more frequently than previously thought. Wild hybrids of many parrot species have now been captured on camera across the country.
Cockatoos are among the most commonly reported native hybrids. While hybridization between cockatoo species is difficult to document in the wild, it has been achieved numerous times in captivity. For instance, the galah (rose-breasted cockatoo) has been known to hybridize with several species, including the sulphur-crested cockatoo, little corella, Major Mitchell’s cockatoo, and even the cockatiel.
Hybrids occur most often where the natural ranges of different species overlap, especially in semi-arid and agricultural areas across Australia. They are also frequently documented in areas where birds have escaped captivity. As Australians increasingly landscape their homes to attract native birdlife, species are becoming more common in suburban areas, and sightings of hybrids are occurring more frequently.
Below is a list of some of the most commonly observed hybrids in the wild. Many of the photos referenced were taken of captive birds due to the difficulty of capturing clear images in the wild.
1. Galah (Rose-breasted Cockatoo) × Sulphur-crested CockatooPlumage: The pink of the galah is replaced with an apricot or orange color on the chest, and sometimes under the wings, combined with white or light grey body feathers. The crest is shorter and often reflects the orange coloring of the chest rather than the long yellow crest of a sulphur-crested cockatoo.
2. Galah × Little Corella (Short-billed Corella)Plumage tends to blend the galah’s pink with the corella’s white, producing a washed-out rose color on the chest and underparts. The wings and back are light grey to white, with minimal corella influence. Some of the corella’s characteristic facial features may be present.
3. Galah × Major Mitchell’s Cockatoo (Pink Cockatoo)Plumage is a soft pink from the galah blended with the more vivid salmon-pink of the Major Mitchell’s cockatoo. The wings are grey with white blending. The crest is longer and more colorful than a galah’s, but not as elaborate as that of a Major Mitchell’s.
4. Little Corella × Sulphur-crested CockatooThis hybrid is intermediate in size between the smaller corella and the larger sulphur-crested cockatoo. Plumage is predominantly white. The crest is usually shorter than that of a sulphur-crested cockatoo but may show a yellow tint. A bluish or pale eye ring from the corella may also be present.
5. Galah × Long-billed Corella (Slender-billed Cockatoo)This is one of the more commonly observed cockatoo hybrids in Australia. The chest and face display a muted pink or blush tone, lighter than that of a pure galah. The eye ring often has a light blue tint inherited from the long-billed corella. The crest and beak are longer than those of a galah but less pronounced than in a long-billed corella.
Peter Fuller observed and photographed wild lorikeets in the Bellerine Peninsula in southern Victoria. He found that scaly-breasted lorikeets were breeding with rainbow lorikeets in the area and documented several unusual color variations from this cross. He also noted that some birds were breeding with the smaller musk lorikeet, which is native to the region. More information and photos of these wild hybrids can be found at www.peterfuller.com.au.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3884</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 52 No. 2 (2025): AFA Watchbird Fall/Winter 2025; 14-15</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
