<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/532</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Fruit Doves and Pigeons</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pire, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I would like to add a pair of fruitdoves/pigeons to my bird collection.There are many questions I needanswered before attempting to keepthese exotic species. Are the fruitdoves/pigeons cost prohibitive to mybudget? Do I have to construct specialaviaries to house them? How hard is itto feed these specialized eaters? Howbig or small are the fruit doves /pigeons? Are they really as hard tokeep as everyone says they are?This article will hopefully answerthese and any other questions youmay be asking yourself. I have spentmany hours on the phone talkingwith the limited number of aviculturistsand several zoos keeping thesespecies of birds. I have asked manyquestions and found that everyone was very willing to share their gainedknowledge with me.I've been in the dove fancy some 12or 13 years now and have alwayswanted to add a pair or two of thefruit doves to my collection of foreigndoves and pigeons. I never purchaseda pair because of the questions Iraised at the start of this article. Thesefears have been erased. The next pairof doves added to my existing collectionof 34 different species of doves/pigeons will be the fruit doves.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/532</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 6 (1989): DEC-JAN 1990; 32-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/532/516</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
