<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2785</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-20T03:29:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Veterinary Viewpoints</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Worell, Amy B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Question #1: Several of my lutino cockatiels have feather loss on the back of their heads. Is this normal? These are pet birds that are all kept in one large cage.M. Nichols, TexasAnswer #1: Most species of birds are not completely covered with feathers. The feathers lie in tracts with featherless areas between them. Cockatiels have a featherless area on the top of the head just behind their crest. When the crest is raised this area of skin is visible. It is more noticeable in lutino and albino birds. I suspect you are observing a normal situation. If you have any doubts, see your veterinarian.James M. Harris, DVM Oakland, CAAnswer #2: Cockatiels, or any other birds for that matter, will squabble to establish a "pecking order" if their enclosure is not sufficiently large enough to accommodate what they would feel is their personal space. This problem is often manifested as feather loss from the head or back. However, you must differentiate this condition from a genetic "fault" seen in some lutino Cockatiels which is a "bald spot" on the back of their heads. The bald spot can range from small to quite large and may be easily visualized by erecting the crest. The difference between this balding and picking is that the truly balding bird will have bare skin whereas the picked bird often has the tattered down remaining. There is nothing you can do if the fault is genetic balding, and this does not affect the health of the bird. If the feather loss is due to picking, then removing some of the birds from the cage and reducing the population may help.Darrel K Styles, DVM Dripping Springs, TexasAnswer #3: When one mentions feather loss on the back of the heads of lutino Cockatiels, two major possibilities come to mind. One would be a genetic tendency in many lutinos that involves the lack of feather tracts and hence, feathers, in this area. This is most noticeable when the bird raises its crest for a variety of reasons. The other major reason for feather loss on the back of a lutino cockatiel's head when there are multiple birds housed together, would be mutilation from another bird in the cage. This commonly occurs to females when a male wants to breed with her. In this common situation, in addition to the bald spot on the back of the head, the sides and top of the head may also be picked and show evidence of varying stages of balding.Most likely from your description, you have the commonly visualized, genetically related, lutino Cockatiel back of the head balding scenario.Amy B. Worell, DVM, ABVP,-Avian West Hills, CA </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2785</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 1 (1998): JAN-FEB 1998; 26-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2785/2769</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
