<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2688</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-23T13:50:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Stud Book for Greater &amp; Lesser Parrots</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Blynn, Dave</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Coracopsis Vasa (Greater Vasa), (Vasa) Parrot and the Coracopsis Nigra (Lesser Vasa) (black) parrot are becoming threatened and may soon be faced with extinction in their primary habitat, the island of Madagascar, due to the rapid destruction of their native forests. Approximately one thousand were imported in the early 1980s and distributed throughout the United States. Many of these unique parrots have been lost to PBFD and other diseases.Successful breeding has been very limited. A Greater pair reproduced in the Philippines in early 1988, and two pair in the USA bred later in 1988. There are reports of a third United States pair breeding (1991) and two pairs raised babies in the United Kingdom in 1990. One pair in Alabama has been very consistent, producing 13 chicks since 1988. The Lessers have been bred in the USA since 1985, but I am only aware of two pairs that have bred here. There certainly are more breeding Lesssers in the USA and in other countries, but little has been reported.I have started a Stud Book for both the Greaters and the Lessers and plan to issue the registration numbers of these parrots in July or August. In addition, I will be sending out breeding reports, similar to the two in this Watchbird, and other information two or three times a year. Currently, three different parties are working on importing more of the Vasas. They can be exported from Madagascar, since over one hundred were imported into the UK about three months ago.If you have Greaters or Lessers and want to register them, or if you just want information, please write to me, Dave Blynn, 6727 Windfaire Drive, Norcross, GA 30093 - and I will send you the appropriate forms and/ or information. •  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2688</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 4 (1991): AUG-SEPT 1991; 31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2688/2669</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
