<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/910</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:18:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Importing Birds into Colorado for thePurpose of Sale or TransferSection 35-80-108-(2)-(d) states that it is unlawful. .. forany person (including Bird Hobby Breeders) ... to import (intoColorado) .. . any pet animal (including birds) for the purposeof sale ... unless that person is the holder of a valid pet animalfacility license. The type of license required may be differentif this person is selling their own birds or those raised bysomeone else.Application for a Colorado bird breeder identification numberand/or license may be made by contacting the ColoradoDepartment of Agriculture, Animal Industry Division, 700Kipling Street, Suite 1100, Lakewood, CO 80215, Attn: eitherDr. John Maulsby or Dr. Keith Roehr. Their phone numberis (303) 239-4161.A requirement for a health certificate accompanying anybird entering the state has been discussed by the department.I will furnish information on this once a decision bas beenmade.Please contact me if you need further clarification.Ray Vander Leest, P.O. Box 124. Elizabeth, CO 80107, (303) 646-0885 eCo-operative Breeding Program forToucans Approved by USFWSOn February 24, 1995 the U.S. Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife Serviceapproved the application for a co-operative breeding programfor toucans submitted by the Toucan Preservation Cenrer,a non-profit organization. This approval marks the first timethe USFWS has approved an application for a co-operativecomposed of private aviculturists, and is one of only fourapproved co-operatives overall. The other three are for birdsof prey.The toucan co-operative breeding program covers fourspecies, the Keel Bill Toucan, Toucan Ramphastos sufphuratus,the Red Breasted Toucan Ramphastos dicoforus,the Saffron Toucanet Baillonius baiffoni, and the ChestnutearedAracari Pterogfossus castanotis. The permit issued theToucan Preservation Center allows for the importation ofone hundred individuals of each species for captive breedingpurposes.The co-operative consists of eight individuals and institutions,the largest such co-operative. The members are DianeFell, Tulsa Zoo, Tim Kitchens, Kris Kuchinski, DVM, DickSchroeder, Bob Seibels, Riverbanks Zoo, Mac Sharpe, ChuckSiegel, Dallas Zoo, and Jerry Jennings, Director of the ToucanPreservation Center.The group will import its first birds under the programin April, with a group of Keel Bill Toucans, and expectsto acquire additional birds during the remainder of 1995.For further information, please contact the Center at Rt. 6,Box 14, Fallbrook, CA 92028, tel. (619) 728-2226. •Spix's Macaw Release Takes PlaceThe fax machine slowly printed out a letter of confirmationto the Loro Parque Foundation of an event which had beenanticipated for several months. The writer of the letter, Dra.Maria lolita Bampi, Vice-President of the Spix's Macaw RecoveryCommittee, reported that the long-awaited releaseof the female Cyanopsitra spixii back into nature had finallytaken place on the 17th March, 1995.This historic event is the result of years of planning andpreparation-the released bird was hatched and reared inthe wild but had spent many years in captivity in Brazil.Some six months prior to the release, the bird was installedin a large, specially-designed cage to become used to thenatural habitat environment of the site and the new foodsource which would form the basis of its diet once releasedfrom the cage. By the middle of March, the team who hadbeen carefully monitoring the female Spix for several monthsdecided that the bird had adapted sufficiently and that thetiming was right for the release to take place.The door to the cage was opened at 6:30 a.m. on themorning of March 17th and the female soon flew from thecage, initially flying about 300 metres before resting forsome I 0 minutes. It later flew a further 300 metres andrested in a Pinhao tree where it spent its tirst night roostingin liberty. The team monitoring the bird report that it hasalready been seen to utilize other food types in addition tothe Pinhao, which it had been fed during the adaptationperiod. It is not yet flying great distances but recordingsof the vocalization of the wild male Spix 's Macaw are beingplayed in an attempt to stimulate more movement from thefemale.The wild male is currently still paired with an Ara maracana,(Illiger's Macaw) at present some distance away fromthe location of the released female.News of this release has been a source of great excitementto the Loro Parque Foundation, who as the principle fundersof the Spix's Macaw Recovery Project from its very beginnings,feel that they are now seeing worthwhileachievements resulting from the effort, time and money whichhas been provided over previous years. eMarch 17, 1995Bird Regulations UpdateAttention Bird Hobby Breeders and persons out -of- tatedesiring to sell birds in Colorado.The Banding of Psittacine BirdsRequired in ColoradoThe Pet Animal Care and Facilities Act, section 35 -80-108-(l)-(i), states that any Psittacine birds in your possession ... forthe purpose of sale or transfer ... must be banded with a typeof leg band authorized by the Colorado Commissioner of Agriculture.The act states that this requirement also applies toBird Hobby Breeders who are exempt from other sections ofthis law.An authorized band must be a traceable seamless band containingthe letters CO, a Colorado bird breeder identificationnumber issued by the Commissioner, and the last two numbersof the year in which the band was used. Also allowed wouldbe a United States Department of Agriculture Quarantine Stationleg band or a band approved by another state. There are alsoprovisions for obtaining authorized seamed bands for thosePsittacine birds not banded as babies. •</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/910</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 22 No. 3 (1995): MAY-JUNE 1995; 51-52</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/910/892</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
