<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1147</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:31:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">New Angles in Aviary Design (Hard Work on Plans Results in Less Hard Work in Construction)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gaulin, Tom</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">After several proposals I finally scovered a basic shape for y new aviary that my wife and I could live with. This was my first challenge=-to sell my spouse on a workable concept. I was clearly notified that if we were going to have an aviary in our modest yard, that it must be an attractive addition and done right.I must admit, my prior history with cages on our patio left something to be desired so I knew that I would have to do everything possible to integrate a highly functional, eye pleasing sanctuary for my little friends, into a modest space. Utilizing all the features that had benefitted my breeding success in the past and eliminating the problems with waste, mess, and maintenance were my prime objectives.I am a fancier of Lady Gould Finches and have enjoyed a reasonable amount of success breeding these beautiful creatures. Many people warn potential owners of the difficulties associated with keeping Lady Gouldians. I do not recommend that a novice start bird keeping by running out and purchasing a flock of Goulds. Mistakes can be extremely costly and the needless death of birds is simply morally unacceptable.I enjoy keeping and breeding Goulds for a variety of reasons: They are extremely beautiful both in color and markings. They are reasonably quiet/less likely to disturb neighbors. After getting to understand, them you realize they are surprisingly intelligent and have unique personalities. Their beauty makes them extremely desirable, easy to sell and they tend to bring better returns.Prior to becoming involved in finch keeping, I spent over 15 years working with marine fish. Salt water fish are also considered difficult to keep as pets, but after doing so one discovers that the focus should always be on providing the best environmental conditions possible, with low pollution levels, good light, and a variety of foods and vitamins in good supply. Limiting excess population growth will result in low-stress living conditions which will lead to good health and proliferation.Back to the Aviary. My wife and I agreed on a section of our yard that would be dedicated to the project. Although it was only a 10 foot by 7 foot area, which for many breeders may seem a joke, I was determined to make the best of it. In an effort to clarify the process I followed to complete the project, I have organized the procedure into a series of steps which I considered prior to execution, and this basic outline may be helpful to you if you are considering a similar endeavor. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1147</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 24 No. 3 (1997): MAY-JUNE 1997; 8-14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1147/1126</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
