<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/548</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bowerbirds: overlooked avian jewels</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leli, Ubaldo</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bowerbirds are large soft bills of theorder Passeriformes, that inhabitNew Guinea and Australia! There are18 species of bowerbirds, distributedamong eight genera!·2 These birds arepeculiar in that they have developedtheir building skills to an extremedegree, which they demonstrate intheir courtship display object: thebower.Bowerbirds were discovered earlyafter the first European settlersreached Australia, although theywere not initially recognized as anindependent group and were classifiedwith the orioles and the honeysuckers~Traditionally, these birdshave been considered relatives of thebirds of paradise. However, recentDNA studies suggest that they aremore closely related to the wattlebirdsof New Zealand (family Callaeidae),the starlings and the Corvineassemblage?Bowerbirds are not common avicultural.subjects, but they are frequentlypresent in well stocked zoos.They are rare in aviculture primarilybecause their two main sources -Australia and Papua New Guinea -do not allow export of their avifaunaunder any cicumstance except foroccasional exchange of surplusdomestically bred stock with zoos.However, because Irian Jaya, thewester region of the New Guineaisland, is part of Indonesia, a country that does not restrict the export ofnon-endangered avian species, itshould still be possible to obtainsome of the species from there. Inaddition to the legal issues, the lackof knowledge of the breeding habitsof the bowerbirds has caused themnot to be commonly bred even in zoos, and there are, unfortunately,too few aviculturists specializing insoftbills who have given attention tothis group of birds.I have neither owned (yet) norbred any of the bowerbirds, however,during my last visit to Australiain July 1991 I was impressed to find several species of bowerbirds wellestablished in public and privateAustralian collections. I also met anumber of aviculturists who havesuccessfully bred these birds, includingStan Sindel of New South Wales,who was kind enough to give medetailed verbal accounts of his methodsof husbandry. These data, in additionto the published accounts ofbreeding that have appeared elsewhere?·6 are precious for aviculture. Ibelieve that public and private collectionsowning bowerbirds may greatlybenefit from the application of thehusbandry protocols described inthese articles. I also hope that thispaper will prompt aviculturists togive more attention to these magnificentbirds before their importation iscompletely eliminated. I am convincedthat efforts to preserve speciesdiversity will be futile if as manygenera as possible are not establishedin captivity within a short time.Except, perhaps, for the cockatoos,birds from southeastern Asia andNew Guinea are more exposed thanany other group to danger of extinctionfrom habitat destruction andhuman disturbance than from trappingfor the pet trade. Placing aspecies on the C.I.T.E.S. appendix I(endangered species list) hardlyprotects it from the damage derivingfrom destruction of its naturalhabitat.1. Frith C.B., Bowerbirds and Birds of Paradise.In the Encyclopedia of Birds (Perrins C., andMiddleton L.A., eds.) Facts on File, Inc.,New York, 1985, pp.436·441.2. Beehler B.M., Pratt T.K., andZimmerman D.A., Birds of New Guinea.Princeton University Press, Princeton, NJ,1986, pp.219-223.3. Chaffer M., In Quest of Bowerbirds. RigbyPubl., Sydney, 1984, pp.45.4. Simpson K., and Day N., Field Guide to theBirds of Australia. Penguin Books of Australia,Ltd., Ringwood, Victoria, 1986,pp.337.5. Sindel S., Breeding the Regent BowerbirdSe1·icutus chrisocephalus. Australian A viculture(1989), 43(6): 149-154.6. Sindel S., Breeding the Green Catbird Ailuroedusc1·assirostris. Australian Aviculture(1991), 45(6): 139-145.7. Schuchmann K.L., Kolibris. Haltung untPJlege. Biotropik Verlag GmbH, Frankfurtum Mein, 1979, pp.65-(i8.8. Communicable Disease Center. 1967.Pictorial Keys to Arthropods, Reptiles,Birds, and Mammals of Public Health Significance.Communicable Disease Center,Allanta, GA.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/548</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 3 (1992): JUNE-JULY 1992; 24-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/548/532</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
