<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1589</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:54:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Cuban Finch</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hill, Doug</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Common Names: Cuban Grassquit, Melodious Grassquit.Distribution: Cuba to the Isle of Pines and Jamaica.Visual Sexing: The sexing of the Cuhan finch is by visual means. The Cuban does not have an eclipse plumage. The cock has a black face and throat. The back is an olive green, starting on the top of the head and extending down to the rump and the tail is a darker olive than the rest of him. The chest is black and blending to grey as it progresses toward the vent and tail coverts. The cock gets darker with age. The hen is similar to the cock with the colors much more subdued. The black is much paler and the grey much lighter.Housing: Cubans are best kept in aviaries, whether they are small or large open types. It doesn't really matter They do not do as well in cabinets. It is essential that they he protected from cold winds and draughts. Compatibility: Pugilistic. Some individuals are very peaceful, and some extremely violent. I suppose it depends on the strain that you acquire. There are all sons of stories of the cock Cuban killing all sons of species. If you want to keep Cubans it is entirely up to you.Breeding Season: These birds are said to he free breeders in Australia now, as they will readily go to nest if the aviary conditions are right, regardless of the Lime of year. Cuban pairs should not he separated, as they may not go to nest again. Cubans can have up to six nests a year.Nesting Receptacles: Cubans will readily breed in any type of receptacle, be it woven cane nest baskets, tins, and half-open nest boxes. Their favorite nesting site is in shrubbery attached to the walls of the aviary. They do not build a roosting nest. The nest is made up of just about anything they can find. I have had them use November grass, cotton wool, feathers, teased hessian, plant fibre, spider webs and shredded paper. I think they will use anything that is on hand. The nest is usually large and untidy.Breeding Diet: A good diet of finch mix, seeding grasses, gentles and/or termites is all you need to breed these birds. Also needed is fresh clean water daily, as these birds like to hath frequently in hot weather. They are also fond of sprouted seed and milk thistle.Austerity Diet: Just a good finch mix with plenty of grit and cuttlebone is all that is needed in the non-breeding season. To give them a treat once or twice a week you can give them some seeding grasses.Eggs and Young: Two 'to four small spotted oval eggs are laid. Incubation is usually 14 days depending on the time of year. The young nearly always appear to come out of the nest prematurely. They are independent of their parents after a further four weeks and should he removed from the breeding aviary to a holding aviary at this time.Common Ailments: Feather plucking may he found with some individuals. If your birds are prone to this conduct, it would be wise to replace the offending culprit. A good worming program is also very beneficial.Life Expectancy: Cubans have a life expectancy of around seven to eight years.General Comments: A delightful little bird with a delightful song. Given the right circumstances the Cuban is a joy to watch flitting around the aviary. ~ </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1589</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 6 (2000): Nov-Dec 2000; 4-5</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1589/1566</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
