<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/685</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the Celebes Hanging Parrot (Loriculus stigmatus)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weish, Larry R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weish, Kathy L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">On September 17, 1990, we receivedfour pairs of Celebes Hanging Parrotsfrom our friend David Coenraad, thenowner of Three Star Enterprises ofPico Rivera, California. On February 5,1991, and on September 21, 1991, wewere ab le to acquire o ne moreCelebes hen and two more cocks fromDavid. All the birds we re very immature,only showing the slightest hint ofred on the heads of the males.These five pairs and the one extracock we re set up in a flight five feetlong, three feet deep by five feet high.We left them in this flight to matureand build up to top breeding shape.The birds lived in this flight longerthan we had planned. We were buildinga new avia1y and didn't want to setthem up to breed until they could bemoved into the new avia1y.During th eir stay in the flight, we fedthem a di e t that Kathy and I haddevised according to everything wefound written on the genus Loriculus.The flight was fed a d1y nectar thatconsisted of sugars, vitamins, mine rals,protein and amino acids. This wasfed in a ten ounce s ize stainless s teelcup hung on the side of the flight. Aten ounce size stainless steel cup wasfilled with clean fresh tap water andhung next to the one with the d1y nectar. This allows the birds to get the irtongue wet and stick it in the dry nectar,and it sticks to the tongue. In thismanner they can make nectar forthemselves. Always make liquid nectarand have it available at all timesuntil they stan eating the d1y real well,then start cutting back on the liquiduntil you do n't need it any more.We also fed them fresh fruit, vegetablesand pasta in a separate cup. Oneof their favorite fruits is grapes, whichthey will hold in one claw and eat theinside until it's gone. They also lovecorn on the cob or cut off.Keep some spray millet in the cageat all times. They seem to like eating it.Celebes Hanging Parrots will usuallyeat small mealworms and ant eggs if you offer them. One thing that wefound, they must not be fed parakeetseed. Instead, use finch and other softseeds. Never keep Hanging Parrots onseed only diets. In the wild they eatbugs, unripe seed in milk stage, fruits,vegetables and flower buds bothclosed and open.In late August 1991, we started tomove all the birds into our new avia1yand set them up to breed. The newaviary has fluorescent full spectrummodel T-10 Vita-Lites. The Vita-Lites are hooked to a lighting compute r.The lighting computer turns on two fiftywattincandescent lights slowly tosimulate the rising sun. It then turnson the fluorescent lights and turns offthe in candescent lights. At night thelighting compute r reve rses the o pe ration to simulate sunset. At the time theCe lebes Hanging Parrots went to nest,the lights were on from 5:30 in themorning until 10:30 at night.The new aviary also has a s te reosystem that pl ays thunde rstorms , ababbling brook, ocean waves and frogtapes.The tapes add to the pleasantnessof the e nvironment in the building.The re are a lso two b abblingbrook wate r fountains running all thetime to add mo re pleasant sounds andfo r humid ity. We have la rge humidifiers running all the time to raise thelevel of humidity in the breedingbuilding.We decided to set the hanging parrots up in groups of three pairs to acage. The cages are six feet lo ng, 24inches high and 24 inches wide. Eachcage has a feed cup ho lde r at eachend that accommodates three stainlesss teel ten ounce cups . These we fillwith dry necta r, pla in ta p water andfruit with vegetable mi x . The finchseed is in a sta inless steel cup set onthe floor in the middle of the cage tokeep s tray seed in. Pe rches a remo unted at each end of the cage forbreeding and courting.Colllting is vety inte resting to watch.The male will let his wings droop lowso that his red back shows and he alsomakes his tail fan o ut. He then w illpuff out his re el throat pa tch whilerunning along the perch and sings toth e hen in ho pes of a ttract ing hisfuture mate. He will t1y to feed the hena couple of times before attempting tomate with her.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/685</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 4 (1993): AUG-SEPT 1993; 31-34</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/685/668</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
