<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/555</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:28:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Baby Psychology</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clipsham, Robert C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As a result of over a decade ofprivate practice and the developmentof a format for preventive medicalmanagement program for individualpet bird owners and aviculturistsalike, the following information ispresented as a means of effective diseaseprevention. Just as surely as ournation has come to recognize thatthe fundamental origin of problemsin society have their roots in childcare, the development of infant andjuvenile baby birds ' minds and bodiesis the key to lifelong success.What could be simpler, more naturaland cost effective than setting thestage for the life of a baby during itssensitive and critical early months,when both mind and tissues are readilyinfluenced for their long journeyahead? It has proven to be an irrelevantmatter as to how long a psittacine'spotential life span is if it is cutshort by poor care due to lack of educationon the part of the owner.Unfortunately, the reality remainsthat the numbers of pet and aviarybirds over ten years of age remainswell under ten percent of all patientsseen in practice. This means that allof the remaining patients in theUnited States are under ten years olddespite a massive number of birdsbeing imported during the last 20years.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 3 (1992): JUNE-JULY 1992; 52-54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/555/539</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
