<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/810</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Canaries A Life-long Hobby</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hays, Gerald</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"'l V ~en the days begin to growwb~ighter and the world showssigns of wakening from winter, somethingstirs within. It's the old desire toparticipate in the process, an urge tobe somehow a part of the eternalpromise of new life. I used to tellmyself that next year would be different.We would take a trip and not behome-bound all spring. But every yearthat same old feeling returns, and Ican't help wondering what this or thatcombination will produce. No use tofight it. I've decided simply to yieldand enjoy it. Once again, the birds arepaired up and I'm sticking close tohome for the season.At the urging of a friend, I haveattempted to record a few things thathave worked for me. These are thingsthat I have learned, mostly the hardway, over the last 50 years. Thesehabits have brought me satisfactionwith my backyard hobby. (It took onlyone season in the house to convincemy wife that the hobby should bebackyard, not spare-bedroom!)My bird house consists of threemajor parts. On either side of thecenter walk-in storage area are twowalk-in flight pens that are 8' x 10' insize. The roof covers all and extendswell beyond the walls to add furthershade and protection. The back wall issolid. Three sides are partially coveredwith wood that extends from the concretefloor up 3-1/2'. This protects thebirds from our bird-hunter cockerspaniel. The outside open part of thehouse is covered with screen for protectionfrom mosquitoes which canand do bring a pox if they get to thebirds. The screen makes it more difficultto see the birds, but I consider it anecessity. I have used a vaccineagainst avian pox, but find the screenmore satisfactory.On the inside of the flight area, andseparated from the screen by three orfour inches, I use common 5/8" aviarywire. This works well to keep thebirds off the screen in which their toesmight become entangled. The space between the screen and the wire alsokeeps the birds away from any catsthat get past the cocker spaniel. Catsmay be trusted to be interested inbirds! Their fish-hook claws can snaga bird against aviary wire and tear it topieces.I am very careful to guard againstanything on which the birds maycatch a claw or snag their seamless legbands. Small, stiff wire ends, if longenough and in areas where birds lightand hop around, may result in a bird'sensnaring itself and twisting off a legin an attempt to become free.The center section entry, whichleads to either of the flight pens, is alifesaver and prevents the loss of birdsthat might dart out an open door. Italso is handy for storing seed andother items used in the flight pens.When it's time for identifying youngmales in late August or September, Iset up a series of cages in which I putthree or four young birds that aremarked or colored differently enoughfrom each other that I can identifywhich ones I hear and see singing.These I mark with a blue plastic bandon the left leg, then return them to theflight pen. My memory being whatit is, I find it helpful to make a diagramof the cages being watched and torecord which birds have sung. Thisgets us started. The process goes onthrough the fall. It usually works forme. Of course, in breeding season thevents of the sexes begin to showmarked differences. I usually checkthese. The vent area of the cock birdprotrudes markedly and in oldercocks is rather easily identifiable. Thefemale's vent area is broad and flatand, as laying time approaches,resembles somewhat the area of thelaying chicken's vent and abdomenbroadand full. I have never had successwith needles on strings and someof the other gimmicks by which someswear to tell sexes. For me, the onlysure way is to hear and see the malesing. Of course, if a singing hen(almost a non-happening) lays an egg,one would need to rethink the matter!One needs to remember that cagedbirds can feed their babies only fromthe foodstuff made available to themby their keepers. They will not reproduceeffectively if they are not properlyfed. Along with a good roller mixof seed and cuttlebone, I offer mybirds a formula given to me by GreatAunt Clara about 40 years ago. Themix included two finely choppedhard-boiled eggs, shell and all; twoheaping tablespoons of finely rolledbread crumbs; two heaping tablespoonsof any kind of dry baby cereal;one heaping tablespoon of wheatgerm and about one-quarter spoon ofsugar (optional). These I mix well inquantities large enough to last four orfive days and store in covered containersin the refrigerator. I feed as muchas the birds will clean up, twice a day.This varies according to the number ofbabies; I start with one tablespoon at atime. I also feed a round slice (quarterof an inch thick) of boiled carrot, a bitof broccoli flower and chickweed, inseason. The birds are fond of romainelettuce, raw cabbage, orange andapple. I have not had a problem withapple as some people report they'vehad. My birds seem to like the softervarieties of apple better than firm onessuch as Granny Smith. A quarter of anorange, especially in hot weather, isanother way of giving your birds theliquid they need.For nests, I have offered a variety ofcup-like containers including tunacans and cottage cheese cartons. NowI use commercial plastic nests ontowhich I sew or tape a bit of flannelcloth for a bottom liner. If screen nestsare used, cloth covering is especiallyimportant so that the birds do notcatch their toenails and hang themselves.I shred 3" x 4" squares of burlapand give them to the birds so thatthey can fashion their own nests. Theyalso like to use horse hair and makebeautiful nests from it. In the pastwhen I kept Shetland ponies, anabundance of hair was readily athand.Banding, as well as identifying,gives your birds a sort of class. Thebabies' feet will be right for bandingsometime between five and eight daysold, depending on the kinds of birdsyou have and the rate at which thebirds are growing. Some parent birdsare better feeders than others, andtheir babies do grow better than thosefrom poor fe eders . Some breederslook for the little feathers forming onthe wings as a sign for size for banding.I simply watch the feet. In largeclutches, not all babies from the samenest will be ready on the same day. Ifyou band too soon, the band comesoff and may be lost. If you wait toolong, you may injure the foot or not beable to band at all. Pushing three toesforward and through the sea mlessband and pulling the band over thefoot , and over that toe that extendsbackward, and up the leg until thatlast toe slips through, requires dexterityand skill. The reward comes laterwhen you spot a bird and think ,"That's my bird." Sure enough, theband confirms it (or blows a hole inyour self-confidence).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/810</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 46-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/810/792</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
