<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2271</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-10T22:34:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">1984 Watchbird Photo Contest</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hessler, Mary Jean</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Biggest, best ever, a good way to describe the photo entries displayed at this year's convention, Orlando, Florida. The contest chairman, Chuck Saffell, Snead Island, Palmetto, FL., and his assistant, Louise Auger, did an outstanding job of caring for the many details involved with logging in, displaying, and return mailing the entries.Seven judges spent several hours trying to select winners from a large display of "winners'.' Those seven,nwith photographic and or artistic talents of their own were: Larry McPhail, Ft. Lauderdale, FL.; John Stoodley, Broadhalfpenny Down Conservation Sanctuary, England; Eric Peake, North Wales, U.K.; Lee Horton, Vista, CA.; Joe McLaughlin, Dundee, OR.; Mary Jean Hessler, Costa Mesa, CA.; Dale R. Thompson, Canyon Country, CA.Judging did not come easy. Points considered and debated were: 1) basic good photo techniques - focus, clarity, lighting; 2) composition; 3) rarity of subject matter or difficult shot; 4) subject's position - relaxed and natural or stressed, awkward; 5) imagination, creativeness without appearing contrived.Keep these points in mind if you plan to enter next year's Watchbird photo contest. Along with the great portraits of macaws, Amazons and cockatoos, the judges keep eyes alert for photos that will enhance articles, and photos that themselves suggest articles. It is for this reason that the Watchbird staff selects certain photos (in addition to the winners) to hold for publication even though they are not specifically awarded a winning position. It is our intent to publish all winning photos, and others selected for special reasons. Throughout the year starting with this issue these photos will be reprinted for your viewing, a great many becoming our beautiful covers.Since the Watchbird photo contest was conceived and first displayed at AFA's 1st convention in 1975, many fine photos and photographers have come forward. These people create the backbone of Watchbird's original and outstanding photo library. The primary purpose of this contest is to locate and display the talent of our members. It works! Thanks to all who take the time and make the effort to enter our photo contests. Please keep up your fine work. We'll be eager to...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2271</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 11 No. 5 (1984): OCT-NOV 1984; 32-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2271/2245</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
