<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1636</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:50:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Reproduction of the White-necked Mynah Streptocitta albicollis at the Audubon Park Zoo</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McDowell, Bill</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en"> IntroductionThe White-necked Mynah Streptociua a. albicollis is a monomorphic starling measuring approximately 18 inches ( 48 centimeters) in length including a long graduated tail. The overall plumage as well as soft body parts are glossy black. Contrasting this is a large unbroken collar of white feathers enci.rcli.ng the nape, just overlapping the scapulars extending midway down the breast and a dull yellow on the distal third of the beak.The subspecies Streptociua a. torquata differs from the nominate form by possessing an entirely black beak. The area where the two populations converge is unknown.One of four species of starlings endemic to the Indonesian island of Sulawesi, the White-necked Mynah has a wide ecological amplitude. Feeding on fruits in small groups and mixed flocks, they have been observed in a variety of forest types and cultivated areas from sea level to 4000 feet (1000 meters) in elevation. Typical. of most Sturnids, the vocalizations of this species are complex and varied, including a three note nasal song, rasping ascending rumbles, and a piercing alarm call.Husbandry ParametersThe Audubon Park Zoo acquired an adult pair of wild-caught Whitenecked mynahs in March 1998. The female laid a total of 23 infertile eggs in seven nesting attempts over a threeyear period at the previous institution. Following quarantine, the birds were moved to the zoo's Tropical Bird House. The pair are housed. on exhibit in a woven mesh, metal framed enclosure 10 feet (3 meters) high with a curvilinear piano wire front measuring eight feet (2.4 meters) wide. The depth varies from nine feet (2.7 meters) to five feet (1.5 meters). The entire rear wall and one side of the enclosure, excluding a metal access door, is concrete. The exhibit is planted with ornamental fig Ficus benjamina, Scbefflera arboricola, and palm Rbapis exce/sa in a soil, mulch substrate. Vines and branches provide perching. A translucent fiberglass roof and two glass walls provide natural light in the exhibit area.The diet is composed of mixed fruit (diced apples, banana, corn, peas, grapes, pear, cooked yam, and lettuce) in a 3: 1 ratio with a commercial softbill pellet. In addition, a teaspoon of mixed grain (commercial finch mix, sunflower seeds and cracked corn) and insects (mealworms, waxworms and crickets) is provided. Bone meal and a vitamin/mineral mixture are added as supplements.Initially, the birds were fed once per day. Although they were eating and alert, when keepers serviced the enclosure the birds appeared somewhat stressed by producing alarm calls and flying to the front corners of the exhibit. In an effort to provide more security and due to the small exhibit space, a branch with Spanish moss Tillandsia usneoides draped over the ends was placed on the top of the enclosure. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1636</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 2 (2001): MAR-APR 2001; 29-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1636/1613</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
