<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/194</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:16:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">the Vets Corner: PACHECO'S PARROT DISEASE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cooper, Ralph</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In late August of 1975, we were presentedwith a dead Black Mask Lovebird.According to the owner, it was notnoticed to be ill prior to its death. Apreliminary gross examination revealednothing out of the ordinary. When theliver was examined microscopically, itwas discovered that the nucleii of theliver cells contained inclusion bodies.Inclusion bodies are readily identifiablestructures which are produced by someviruses when they act within a cell. Wewere familiar with similar inclusion bodiesin poultry , but it required a search ofthe literature to reveal the true nature ofthe disease in the Lovebird. It becameclear that this bird had died of Pacheco'sParrot Disease. It had been first describedby a trio of Brazilian veterinarians workingin Sao Paulo, Brazil , in 1930. On thatoccasion it caused losses among threekinds of Brazilian parrots including theorange wing parrot , the blue frontedparrot, and the mealy parrot. Subsequentexperiments showed that the virus wouldinfect and kill the Tui paroquets and theBudgerigars. Nothing more was reporteduntil 1974 when it was diagnosed inFlorida. During a single outbreak there,it killed three macaws (one Ara araraunaand two Ara militaris) which had broughtthe disease from California, and fourscarlet macaws andeight cockatoos, whichhad become infected by contact. Twohornbills and a mynah bird which sharedthe same room were not affected. Inthe early 1970's, the disease was reportedin an African Grey parrot in Kenya. Subsequentto our discovery of the disease inthe Black Mask Lovebird, we have seen itin a Mustache, a Hooded , and a Blackheaded parakeet.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/194</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 3 No. 4 (1976): AUG-SEPT 1976; 26-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/194/185</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
