<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/993</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:19:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ... NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Amazona Society ofGreat BritainThere is an Amazona Society of Great Britain. 1umerouspeople inquired about this during the 1995 AFA convention.Those wishing to join this society should make out a bankdraft of£ 13 03 pounds Sterling) to:Terry Stielman, c;o Amazona Society of Great BritainSouthfield HouseSouthfield RoadBroughtonWR Brigg, Sines DW 200 DZUnited Kingdom •AFA State CoordinatorsNeeded in North East Region"Legislation hits New York, MassachusetTs and NewHampshire preventing the ownership of bird~ ... "This could become a reality if legislation remainsunwatched in these states. The American Federation ofAviculture is seeking members residing in these states whoare interested in becoming State Coordinators. o experienceis necessaiy. only a willingness to monitor state legislationand promote the AFA at some state event&amp;lt;;. Training will beprovided. AFA State Coordinators automatically becomemembers of the AFA House of Delegates, receive quarterlyreports and are listed in the AF A Watchbird journal.If you are interested in protecting and promoting aviculturein your state, become a volunteer with the AFA, the leadingaviculru ral organization in the U.S.A. Please contactRegional Vice President Linda S. Rubin, 93 Woodcliff Road,Chestnut Hill, MA 02167. Phone: 617-469-0557, fax: 617-469-036R eHalmahera Project GetsUnderWaya Frmdutiull Loru Parque neuJS ReleaseAmongst the most recent project&amp;lt;; that the Loro ParqueFoundation has become involved with is the two-year longfield project that has been initiated by Bird life International onthe Isl::ind of Halmahera in the Maluku Island group inIndonesia.Thts is widely regarded as one of the most important conserv:J.tion project~ being undertaken at the present rime asHalmahera ~&amp;gt;upports no fewer than 26 endemic birds and isthe home for nine spedes of parrots. Perhaps the most importantpsittacine from Halmahera is the globally threatenedUmbrella Cockatoo Cacatua alba. But all of the species fromthis Island mcluclmg the Eclectus Eclectus roratus uosmaen,Blue-wmged King Parrot Alisten/.S a. hypopboniLIS, VioletneckedLory Eos s. ncinrata, Chattenng Lory Lon'z/.S p,an·u!us,Red-flanked Lorikeet Cbmmosyna place1llis, Great-hilledParrot 7'al lJ~nathus megalorhyncbus, Muluku hanging ParrotLon:ezth/.S mrwhilis, and the Red-cheeked Parrot Geoffroyusf.!,f:!Q[/royi, will he studied during the course of the project.The project budget amounts to about U.S. $ 205,000 whichincludes the employment of Indonesian personnel. travel.equipment and materials. report&amp;lt;&amp;gt; and publications and projectadministration. In September 1994 the Lora ParqueFoundation agreed to contribute approximately U .. $ 89,000over the course of the two-year project which amounts toalmost 50% of the total funding.It is hoped that this field project will lead to a detailedunderstanding of the avifauna of Halmahera and tl1at at leastone new area of natural reserve can be created once the finalrecommendations of the research team have been studied. •In Memorium: Ray H. RudisillA tragic accident recently claimed the life of Ray Rudisill.noted Canary breeder, show judge and past Second VicePresident of the AFA. An explosion at his work place, wherehe was employed as a chemist, left him with third degreeburns. Taken to the hospital, he didn't survive the night.Ray's aviculturaJ passion was Canaries, which he began tobreed in 1977, specializing in Northern Dutch Frills. He turnedto the exhibition circuit in 1978, and in later years added bothBorders and Glosters to his breeding and showing regimen.Ray became active with the AFA in 1980, when he servedas Missouri Stare Coordinator for three years. He then held theposition of Central Regional Vice President and. in 1985 waselected to tl1e office of Second Vice President which he heldfor two years.Ir was in 1985 after numerous show wins tl1at Ray becamea certified Panel judge for both the Old Varieties CanaryAssociation and 1 orth American Border Club judges panels.His judging expertise was in demand throughout the Unitedtates and he presided over the Old Valieties Division at boththe 1990 National Cage Bird , how in Atlanta, Georgia and the1994 National Show in Manchester, New Hampshire.A staunch supporter of both local and national organizations,Ray served as president or hoard member for nlllnerousassociations and org:mizations.Our heartfelt sympathy to his family and his many friendsin the fancy who shall miss his valued input and his presence. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/993</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 1 (1996): JAN-FEB 1996; 52-54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/993/973</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
