<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/808</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THE NATURAL CHOICE: Creative Caging in Home and Backyard</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cravens, Eb</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"\VA ether you own one bird orWn~:merous pairs of birds, valuabletime and money can be saved bydesigning and creating your owncages.Obviously, the least expensiveoption is to build your own cages.Materials needed include a good qualityflush wire cutters, a power grinderfor sharp edges, a supply of flatJ-clips,a clip rolling tool and cage wire whichcan often be purchased from a qualityhardware store. We find the 1/2" x 1"and 1" x 1" welded wire (galvanizedafter welding), and the 1/2" x 1/2" galvanizedhardware cloth are all easilycut and ]-clipped and suffice fornearly all our needs.These wires, however, are safe touse only with species whose beakstrength is limited. Psittacines strongerthan medium sized Amazons, Derbyansor Goffin's Cockatoos requirethicker gauge wire mesh and hardierclips. As all our breeders are secondgeneration, domestic, handfed stock,somewhat larger parrots may be keptin lighter gauge wire enclosuresbecause they do not try to escape. Inaddition, if a cage is amply filled withnatu ral chewing materials, rocks, toys,etc., a hookbill will rarely develop ahabit of attacking the wire itself.It is a good idea before you begin, toput on a long sleeved shirt and jeansas working with wire normally produceslots of scratches!A logical alternative to building athome is to purchase ready-madeflights or cages from one of the excellentcage companies listed in nationalbird magazines. They not only offerseveral wire choices, but also fabricatealmost a ny custom design you canenvision.So here are our favorite cage stylesfor home and garden based upon easeof construction and specific function:• The Cylinder CageIt is a simple matter to fabricate around parrot cage by bending a 5' to8' length of wire into a tube just as itcomes off the roll, and clipping theends together. A wire top and bottomcan be attached with patience andperhaps some galvanized wire twistsat the spots where the round piecesdo not match up well enough to be]-clipped. We also utilize 3/4" plywoodcut round as a top to protectbirds in the rain. This cage design isquite useful when hung by a chain ina backyard tree or under the houseeaves. We use it for doves kept outyear round and as temporary playcages for inside parrot pets who enjoybeing under the tree in naturalweather. Stuff branches and greeneryinto the cage to create an organicplayground for chewing hookbills.• The Window CageOne of our favorite concepts, especiallyin warmer climes, is a wire cageconstructed to hang on the outside ofthe house in front of a window whichcan be opened to access the cage. Atypical 4' x 4' metal sliding windowwill require a wire cage approximately5' x 5' built about 24" out from thehouse and attached by means of a 2" x4" frame screwed to the house. A tightfit will prevent escape. Food andwater is introduced through the windowfrom inside. These cages are perfectfor kitchen windows or in roomswhere a lot of time is spent since theparrot is both a part of indoor activityand in an outside environment at thesame time. An added advantage is thatspilled food and droppings fallthrough the wire cage bottom onto theground outside. We cultivate a gardenbed below all our window cages togrow both flowers and the sproutingseeds from wasted bird mix. In colderweather, such outside cages may bekept warmer by introducing a six inchlayer of straw or hay to the bottom ofthe cage. Change st raw every fewweeks as it becomes soiled. Thesewire cages are popular with pet parrotswho love to sleep outside, butwant to keep an eye on family activities.A closed window will dampenthe sound of a screaming bird. Thevisual delight of a clean window cagefull of new cut foliage and perhaps abreeding pair of cockatiels or a singleconure is akin to an avian aquarium!Remember that chewing psittacinesand house construction materials donot mix. Metal flashing or non-toxicboards must be used to keep adestructive bird away from paint, plaster,insulation, etc. If in doubt, build afull cage with a small door and hangthe entire cage.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/808</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 41-42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/808/790</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
