<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/788</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:02:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ...   NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">World Watch Reports Birdthe world showing all endemic regions classified as "critical" or "urgent" by Birdlife International. World Watch is published bimonthly by Worldwatch Institute, a Washington, D.C.-based environmental research organization that studies the interdependencies of human economies and the natural environment. Worldwatch publishes the annual "State of the World" and "Vital Signs" reports. For more information contact Director of Communication, or author Howard Youth, (202) 452-1999.•  Populations Declining on Every Continent Bird populations are declining or collapsing faster than generally realized, according to a global survey published in the January/February issue of World Watch. The story, based on data from Birdlife International, Defenders of Wildlife, and other research groups around the world, finds that of the 9,600 known species of birds, more than 6,000 are declining and about 1,000 appear headed for extinction. World Watch, a magazine that focuses on the relationship between human well-being and the health of the environment, notes that the decline of birds has broad ramifications for humans, as well as for birds. The editor, Edward Ayres, notes that environmental scientists regard birds as particularly good indicators of the health of whole ecosystems. "When an endemic bird population suddenly begins to die out, it usually means the whole ecosystem is in trouble - and other species will soon follow," he notes. "Ultimately, human life itself depends on the vitality of the ecosystems inhabited by birds." As an example of this interdependence of avian and human well-being, author Howard Youth points to the welldocumented decline of neotropical migrants in North America. Neotropicals consume large quantities of insects, including such destructive invaders as gypsy moths and tent caterpillars. The continuing disappearance of the birds that eat them "could result in more frequent epidemics of these pests," suggests Youth. The article also notes: • A well-documented cause of the decline in North America is the loss of forest habitat in Central America and the Caribbean, where the neotropical migrants go in the winter - often to find that the forest they left the previous spring has been burned or bulldozed for development. • But other kinds of habitat loss are also taking a toll. As a result of overgrazing and plowing of grasslands, for example, once-abundant species such as the bustards of Eurasia and prairie chickens of North America have all but disappeared. • Other species are being wiped out by the draining of wetlands. North Am · •1994 U.S. First Breeding Avy Award Nominations To AFA members, aviculturists and all exotic bird enthusiasts: the following avian species or subspecies have been nominated for a possible U.S. First Breeding Avy Award. Any knowledge of prior breedings should be submitted to Dale R. Thompson, Chairperson, Avy Awards Committee, in care of the AFA Horne Office in Phoenix, Arizona. 1. Rueppel's Parrot Poicephalus rueppellii, hatch date: November 27, 1973. 2. Bar-breasted Firefinch Lagonosticta rufopicta, hatch date: June 15, 1993. 3. Purple-bellied Parrot Triclaria malachitacea, hatch date: April 17, 1992.• Ron Reid Joins L/M Animal Farms December 14, 1993 - Larry Mohrfield, president of L/M Animal Farms, announced the appointment of Ron Reid as Director of Research and Education. Reid was an employee of Mardel Laboratories as Director of Technical Services and Product Development. Reid has written over 40 publications consisting of "Sexing Small Animals," "Nutrition of Small Animals," "Handling Small Animals," "The Management of the Guinea Pig," "Diseases of Reptiles" and "How to Care for Your Bird," just to name a few. In addition, he has been the recipient of the Pet Industry Unity Award for Joint Industry Retail Merchandising Program and the D.C. Academy of Veterinary Medicine and the Technicians Program for writing. Reid is bringing to L/M's growing company an extensive research and product development background.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/788</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 3 (1994): MAY-JUN 1994; 46-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/788/771</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
