<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/698</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Beginning Breeding Budgerigars (PART1)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">IntroductionThe Shell Parakeet (Melopsittacusundulatus), more popularly known asthe Budgerigar, or Budgie for short, isone of the most popular, colorful, andeasy breeders of the entire parrot family.This fascinating little Aussie bird ofsome six to eight inches, has not onlyendeared the hearts of millions, butcontinues to provide valuable lessonsto aviculturists at all levels.Not to be underestimated, many ofus who started out breeding Budgieslearned such valuable lessons as basicbreeding and husbandry techniques,colony breeding vs. selective breedingmethods, species specific nutrition,fostering and handfeeding techniques,not to mention a wealth of knowledgeto be gained in the areas of linebreeding,outcrossing, color breedingand genetics. Indeed, a valuable educationmay be gained by anyonechoosing to work with a number ofthese delightful, dependable birds.The first record of living Budgerigarsimported from their native Australiainto Great Britain, occurred in 1840,by world famous naturalist and artistJohn Gould. Mr. Gould's brother-inlaw,Mr. Charles Coxen, was creditedwith rearing the first Budgerigars incaptivity. 1 It was no wonder that theBudgerigar grew swiftly in popularityfrom Britain to Europe, and eventuallyother countries around the globe, withtheir relative ease and willingness tobreed, plus the many color mutationswhich erupted to fascinate fanciers.Eventually, the U.S. impotted Budgeri- gars during the early 1900's and theirpopularity continues to prevail eventoday.According to C.H. Rogers, thereexists two subspecies, M.u . intermediusfrom the north , carrying apaler neck and back color; and M.u .pallidiceps, from the west, which isprimarily paler on the head. Rogersfurther comments that all three racesare represented today and are probablythe mixed result of the tens ofthousands of wild Budgerigarsimported into England. This is apparentby the depth of color and variableshades (e.g. dark factors) which existin the many color varieties currentlyseen all over the world.2Today, the Budgerigar maintains itspopularity as an excellent aviary bird,frequently providing the financial support(or "seed money") to maintainless reliable breeders in the aviary; it isa superb family pet with its naturalcuriosity, sociability, and propensityto talk; and it offers perhaps the widestselection of color mutations of anymember of the parrot family. Its followingin exhibition circles is asstrong as ever, with societies formed all over the world, including specialtiesin many varieties and colors. Inthe U.S., many Budgie clubs can befound at the state level, in addition tothe national group to which theybelong, the American BudgerigarSociety, Inc.Selecting StockBeginning Budgie breeders shoulddecide before selecting their foundationstock, which area(s) of the fancythey wish to pursue. Fanciers refer tothe larger show birds as "English," orexhibition size Budgies, versus thesmaller "American" or pet stock variety.In the U.S., the term "English" hasstuck for show birds, perhaps becauseit was England from which we hadimported the first specimens. In anyevent, the size difference does existand fanciers do have a choice.When choosing foundation stock,top priority should go to the selectionof healthy birds. Individuals whichappear "puffy", with fluffed outfeathers, may be masking an illnessand eating less, while they expendtheir remaining energy to keep warm.Likewise, birds with soiled, stained, or dirty feathers, discharge fromnares (i.e. nostrils), eyes, or beak,straining or continuous pumping ofthe tail (e.g. possibly indicating arespiratory condition), dirty or stainedvents, or those huddled together in agroup, should be avoided. Select onlyhealthy, vigorous, active, sleek, andfully feathered individuals. Remember,these birds will be your foundationstock, and there is no room for illnessif you wish to be successful inbreeding.In general, Budgies have the advantageof being sexually dimorphicwhich will enable the fancier to tellcocks and hens apart at a glance.Usually, hens of most varieties willretain a tannish colored cere (i.e. thefleshy area above the beak surroundingthe nostrils) which will turn brownwhen in full breeding condition.Depending upon the color variety,males sport a blue to purple coloredcere which may somewhat deepen inintensity when in condition.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/698</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 7-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/698/681</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
