<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3927</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-09T03:48:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ask the Vet: To Trim or Not To Trim</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fronefield, Stephen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 3 (July 2024). The text below contains excerpts from the original article. For photographs, figures, advertisements, and the complete formatted version as originally published, please use the PDF link associated with this article. Question: Should I trim my bird's wing feathers? Answer: This is a great question, and it opens up a discussion that is the topic of considerable debate. In some countries in Europe it is illegal to trim a pet bird's wing feathers. In the United States it has not been regulated. As our parrot population grows older we are discovering many benefits of flight. These include similar medical benefits as are seen in humans that routinely exercise, including a healthier heart, joints, muscle strength, and improved bone density. Another parallel with their human counterparts is the enrichment gained through regular activity and exercise. In an ideal world our birds would not have their wing feathers trimmed and would be fully flighted; however, there are times when this activity has some inherent risks. One of the more common reasons to request wing feather trimming is for the safety of a beloved companion. Safety from flying into windows, mirrors, and ceiling fans probably tops the list. Birds have been known to fly into items cooking on the stove, toilets, and open containers with liquids in them. I also have birds that are aggressive toward a family member and a trim is requested to help modify the behavior and protect the targeted family member. In aviculture, wing feather trims have been applied to help with aggressive mate behavior. Each feather has a life cycle of approximately one year. This means that those feathers that are trimmed may take as long as one year to be molted and replaced; they do not grow out like hair. There are a number of different wing trimming techniques. If trimming is elected it is critical not to trim blood feathers, which are new feathers identified by their purple shafts, and not to over trim, which can result in the bird injuring itself from a fall. Consult with your avian veterinarian or experienced aviculturist. My preference, for its overall health benefits, is to allow birds to have their full complement of feathers. This requires a commitment to provide a safe environment and time to interact and train your bird. Birds are athletes and allowing them to perform normal activity is beneficial. My discussion with pet bird owners that are considering a wing feather trim include determining what goals they are seeking to achieve and what they can expect from a trim. A wing feather trim is not a guarantee that a bird will not fly, it is aimed at modifying their flight pattern. I hope this helps. Click the PDF link associated with this article to view the complete article as originally published in AFA Watchbird.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3927</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 3 (2024): AFA Watchbird July 2024</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3927/3892</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
