<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2651</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-19T21:07:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Product Review of" Land of Parrots" Video Tapes</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">For those aviculturists who have enjoyed keeping and breeding Australian parakeets, cockatoos, lorikeets and other parrots in captivity, we can really appreciate the beauty and grace of these popular parrots. But visualizing these birds within aviaries cannot begin to compare to the same species flying and living in their natural habitat. Viewing "Land of Parrots;' a seven-part videotape series of Australian parrots flying free in the wild is, indeed, an extraordinary way of enjoying these parrots as never before.When the early explorers first observed the wildlife in Australia, they were amazed at the quantity, variety, and beauty of the parrots found there. This is why this videotape series is called "Land of Parrots:' These parrots are found in almost every habitat in Australia, ranging from the tropical rain forests to the harsh desert scrublands. This film not only shows the beauty of this diverse group of parrots, but also their behavior, diets, camouflage, and nesting habits. Through the efforts of professional ornithologists, researchers and an excellent film crew, all of us, whether aviculrurists, bird enthusiasts or photographers, can enjoy and better understand this group of parrots.This film series separates the Australian parrots into seven groups. Each group is found on a different videotape. Many of the common names may not be familiar to us in America, but they do follow the names found in Joseph Forshaw/ William Cooper's Parrots of the World. I have included the familiar names along with the Australian version. Part 1 - Lorikeets: Rainbows (blue-mountain, redcollared, scaly-breasted, purple-crowned, musk, little and varied lorikeets). This film includes the nesting habits and the specializied diets of these beautiful parrots. Part 2 - Black Cockatoos: palms, red-tailed, white-tailed, yellow-tailed, glossy and gang gang cockatoos. This film includes a most impressive sequence of the palm cockatoo's nesting behavior. Part 3 - White Cockatoos: sulphurcrested, little and slender-billed corellas (bare-eyed and slender-billed cockatoos), Major Mitchell's (Leadbeater's), galah (rose-breasted) cockatoos and the wonderful cockatiel. Part 4 - New Arrivals: eclectus parrot, king parrot, red-winged (crimson-winged) parrot, red-cheeked parrot, Princess (of Wales) parrot, regent (rock pebblar) parrot, and the superb (baraband) parrot. The theory is that these parrots originally arrived in Australia from Asia. They all have red or coral colored bills. Part 5 - Specialists: budgerigars, ground parrots, night parrots, swift parrots, and fig parrots. An excellent film on both a common species familiar to all of us and also some uncommon species. Part 6 - Rosellas: eastern (golden-mantled), western (Stanley's), crimson (pennants), pale-headed (blue), Adelaide, green, yellow and northern (brown) rosellas. This film also includes the Port Lincoln, twenty-eight, Mallee ringneck (Baraband's), Cloncurry, and red-capped (Australian pileated) parrots. This is a great film for aviculturists interested in rosellas and the other large Australian parrots found in our aviaries. Part 7 - Grass Parrots: includes the Neophema group - Bourke's, scarletchested, turquoise, blue-winged, elegant, orange-bellied, and rock parakeets. This film also discusses the red-rumped, mulga (many-colored), bluebonnets, hooded, golden-shouldered, and paradise parakeets. This is another excellent film of popular Australian parakeets found in American aviaries.The beginning format of each videotape gives a basic discussion of Australia and its bird life and uses small parts of the other tapes so one gets an overall picture of what to expect from this film series. This is certainly not a travel log type of film, but endeavors to explain not only the basics but also the finer points in their different behaviors and needs. This film explains the difference in habitat, the need for camouflage, sexual dimorphism, mating and nesting habits, development of young, social behavior and their dietary habits and needs. It also explains some of the conservation efforts done on behalf of the Australian government on certain rare species. The agricultural problems with some of the large parrots is also addressed. Though very much a natural history program, it does show how several species have adapted to aviary life including mutations found both in captivity and in the wild. Joseph Forshaw, the noted ornithologist, is seen periodically in this film discussing some of the more technical aspects of several species.From the eyes of a photographer and an avid parrot lover, I was very happy to see plenty of close-ups of most species and plenty of footage on behavior and nesting. I personally enjoyed some remarkable footage in this film that I know was not easy to film. Each tape has its own highlights and all are well worth watching. Each tape runs approximately 45 to 60 minutes.• </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2651</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 1 (1990): FEB-MAR 1990; 36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2651/2632</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
