<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1498</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-06-30T11:51:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Captive Breeding of the Sparkling Violet-ear Hummingbird</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stoppelmoor, Greg</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There are over 300 species ofhummingbirds that occurthroughout the Americas, butmost species inhabit tropical SouthAmerica. Belonging to the familyTrochilidae of the order Apodifolmes,hummingbirds fascinate us with theirjewel-like beauty and their amazingflight ability. Not only can they suspendtheir bodies in midair and hover, theycan fly backward, upward, left, right,and even upside down. Their uniquedesign allows the wings to move inaltnost any direction from the shoulder.Soaring is the only flight capability thatthey do not possess.The humming sound that gave thesetiny birds their name is made by rapidwing beats which can nUlnber from 50-200 beats per second. Hummingbirdfeet are deSigned only for perching.They must fly even if they want tomove a few inches across a branch.They lift off and rise straight upward byflapping their wings at high speed.They fly swiftly and can stop suddenlyfor a precision landing. Hummingbirdshave an average life span of three to sixyears but the record age is 12 years.Housing the SparklingViolet-ear HummingbirdSparkling Violet -ear HummingbirdsColibri coruscans were released into theTropical Rain Forest Aviary at ButterflyWorld in 1997. Foliage is plentiful withnUInerous plants shrubs and treesobtained fron1 the birds' native SouthAmerican region. At one end of theaviary, misters are positioned around awaterfall with dense foliage, simulatingthe tropical rain forest hOlTIc of humn1ingbirds.The waterfall feeds into asn1all pond and hrook that runs throughthe aviary. The circular aviary is 100feet across with a height starting at 12feet and rising to 27 feet at the top ofthe circular dome.FeedingFor their size, humminghirds havean10ng the largest appetites in the birdworld, feeding every 10 or 15 minutesfrom dawn until dusk. Since theaviary at Butterfly World wa ' originallybuilt for the survival of butterflies,there is an -abundance of nectar-producingplants available for the hummingbirdsto feed upon. Some of theirfavorite plants for sipping nectar areFirebush Hamelia patens, PentasPentas lanceolata, PorterweedStachyta rph eta spp., BubbleiaBuddleia davidii, and FirespikeOdontonema strictum.Also provided for the over 20 individualbirds (within four species) are43 feeders placed throughout the area.These are changed twice a day andfilled with "Nektar-Plus," a special nectarmanufactured by Nekton. Althoughthe nectar is a complete diet with allthe required proteins, carbohydratesand minerals, the hummers also areprovided an ample supply of fruit flies(Drosophilia) .Hummingbirds use their long needle-like bills and special tongues toreach nectar in deep tubular flowers.The last half-inch of the long tongue isdivided into equal halves, eachgrooved on the outer edge to form twotube-like structures. Nectar is drawninto the tongue like liquid is drawn upa straw. Hummingbirds can lick up to13 times per second, and their stomachholds about five grams of mostly nectarand a few insects.NestingGenerally speaking, the hummingbirdnest is a walnut-size structure ofplant down, lichens, and moss, boundwith spider webs or fine plant fiber '.The female lays two eggs that each areless than one-half inch long. After 14-16 days of incubation and four weeksof growing, young hummingbirdsleave the nest.The Sparkling Violet-ears have builtmany nests since their introduction intothe aviary at Butterfly World. They hadtheir first successful fledging in April,1999. Nesting takes place fron1 midNovemberthrough April. The fen1ale ismore aggressive during this periodthan at any other time. She will defendher teITitory more forcefully than usualand without fear of intruders.The nesting sight is chosen verycarefully. The female hummingbirdwill fly from branch to branch lookingfor a spot that suits her. Obviouslythere are a lot of things for her to considerwhen choosing her nest site. Thenest is usually constructed 10 to 15 feethigh in a tree that overhangs a body ofwater. She looks for a site with two orthree perching places within closerange of the nest to keep a close watchwhile she is off the nest. It can take upto three days for her to choose a nestsite that she likes.Nest building takes from eight to 14days. Sometimes the female will beclose to completing the constructionwhen she decides that she does notlike the location. She will then searchfor another spot and reconstruct thenest very rapidly. The constructionmaterial is made up of string, hair, cotton,moss, and any other small fibersshe can find. Spider webbing is also akey material in the nest building. Shewill use this sticky substance to holdthe materials of the nest together.Small spiders are constantly placed inthe aviary to ensure that webbing isalways available.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-06-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1498</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 27 No. 1 (2000): Jan-Feb 2000; 52-54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1498/1475</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
