<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/509</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">West Indian Treeduck Management at White Oak Plantation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rider, Pat</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The treeducks or whistling ducks(genus Dendrocygna) form a uniquegroup of waterfowl. Superficiallythey resemble ducks, but with longernecks and longer legs. Behaviorally,however, they are most closely relatedto geese and swans. They are noisy,nocturnal birds. There is little sexualdimorphism and pairs bond for life,with males helping with incubation.The Wes t indian treeducks ,Dendrocygna arborea, are the largestof the eight species of treeducks .They inhabit the brackish water mangroveand fresh water swamps of theGreater Antilles . The majority arefound on Cuba , Hispaniola andPuerto Rico ; although small groupsmay be found in the Bahamas andLesser Antilles. They are threatenedwith extinction due to a combinationof hunting pressure, the taking ofeggs, pesticide use, habitat destruc-tion and predation from the introducedmongoose.At White Oak Plantation we havebeen fortunate to have a large colonyof West Indian treeducks for severalyears . We maintain a group ofbetween 20 and 30 birds, with five orsix pairs nesting annually. The flock iskept in a one acre enclosure with alarge, free-flowing fresh waterlagoon . Numerous cypress and tupelotrees lend a swamp-like appearance tothe enclosure.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/509</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 4 (1989): AUG-SEPT 1989; 27-29</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/509/493</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
