<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/738</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:32:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Beginning Breeding Budgerigars</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rubin, Linda S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">TYPESEITER ERROR-page fourwas inadvertently omitted from theoriginal text when the followingarticle was typeset. 1be following texthas been corrected and includes theomitted page which should have beeninserted on page 10 of the Oct/ Nov '93issue of "Watch bird."PART1Since it is unlikely that all Budgiehens will be in breeding conditionwhen the majority of cocks are, it is agood rule of thumb to have extrafemales on hand. The likelihood thatonly a few hens will be suitable forbreeding at any given time can delayyour breeding plans unless you overcomethe contingency by obtainingmore hens than cocks in your foundationstock. This plan can be usedadvantageously if you have an exceptionalmale which you wish to usewith several quality hens, either fosteringout the offspring to foster pairsset up for that purpose, or allowingthe cock to remain with his last mateof the season to rear his own chicks.Although many beginners prefer tostart with the less expensive "American"pet stock variety from which tolearn from their mistakes, it can be anadvantage to retain a few of the larger"English" or exhibition size birds.Such birds when crossed together can produce a wonderful, larger-sizepet bird, informally known as the"English-American cross."Nor should one mistake suchcrosses as hybrids since they areall (e.g. "English;' "American;' or"crosses") of the same species, Melopsittacusundulatus. The size difference,or color and feather mutationsin Budgerigars for that matter, are nothybrids but simply different varietiesof the same species. Nor should suchbirds be labelled as "splits:' The latterterm "split;' or heterozygous, refers togenes in a hidden, recessive state, anddoes not apply when referring to across between a large exhibition bird(e.g. "English") and a smaller petstock bird (e.g. "American").If choosing to eventually breed forexhibition, it is wise to contact thespecialty societies for breeders whocan supply you with their culls, or"non-keepers;' which they sell. Suchbirds may be quite suitable for beginnersto breed and are often from goodquality stock. For example, the cullsfrom a Champion or Intermediate ABS(American Budgerigar Society) exhibitormay be superior quality to anystock you may find elsewhere.Purchasers may check the birds' legbandsas registered with ABS, whichcontain the following information: theSociety initials "ABS;' the year (e.g.1993), the number bird bred that year(e.g. "105"), and the breeder's individualregistered code (usually one ortwo numbers plus a letter, e.g. mycode was "33R"). Usually the seriousbreeder of exhibition or line-bredbirds will purchase traceable, seamless,closed legbands from thenational society and such breedersmay be traced back by their bandcode. Beginners now also have theoption of purchasing bands eitherthrough the Society of Parrot Breedersand Exhibitors, or the American Federationof Aviculture, which may begood options when first trying one's hand at producing babies, or beforebanding for more serious competitionat future Budgie specialty shows.PART2Colony vs. Cage BreedingWhichever method one chooses tobreed Budgies, whether colony breedingor individual cage breeding onepair to a pen, it must be realized thatBudgies, in their natural habitat, areby nature colony breeders. That is,they will generally not go to nestunless they are stimulated to breedthrough the sight and sound of otherBudgies around them. Therefore, it isgenerally recommended that onestarts out with at least a minimum ofsix birds, or three pairs, placed in sucha manner so that they may all see andhear one another, or else additionalbirds may be required.Colony breeding may be suitable ifone is only interested in producing aquantity of Budgies, as opposed toconcentrating on the quality of offspringproduced. Special attentionmust be given to providing enoughspace for the flock so as to prevent frequentoutbursts of aggression or fighting,and may, in fact, require closemonitoring of behavior to catch troublebefore a tragedy occurs.It is best to set up an even numberof pairs and remove any unmatedbirds by the start of egg laying, so thatharmony in the colony can be maintained.Approximately one third extranestboxes, to the number of pairshoused, should be provided to offer achoice to the occupants, and cutdown on the number of arguments orterritorial fighting by pairs who opt forthe same nesting site. Otherwise, hensmay fight to the death over specificnestboxes. In the colony breeding system,a careful monitoring of breedingactivities is necessary and boxes mustbe taken down before pairs begin a third clutch, otherwise breeding willgo on endlessly, with chicks hatchingapproximately every 12 weeks, andpairs becoming quickly ill andexhausted.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/738</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 6 (1993): DECEMBER 1993; 50-52</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/738/721</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
