<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4133</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T23:43:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Lorikeet Love</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gwaltney, Ashley</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 48 Number 1 (October 2021).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Lorikeet Love Keeping a Natural Breeding Flock at the Nashville ZooBy Ashley Gwaltney, Lorikeet Area Supervisor Nashville ZooKeeping lorikeet aviaries has become popular in zoos across the country, and Nashville Zoo is no exception. Their clown-like behavior and beautiful colors make them fun to look at, while their natural curiosity and boldness make them more likely to interact with people. We added our lorikeet flock in 2005 as young birds, and as they grew and some of them paired up they were more interested in natural bird behaviors and less interested in people. Once the birds reached sexual maturity they became moreeach other. We looked for the natural territory lines the birds had already established between breeding pairs and tried to place the boxes within these territories. Initially there was lots of fighting and scrambling for nest boxes but eventually the dominant pairs took over a box and the other birds learned not to mess with their territory. The keepers were constantly watching the fighting to make sure no birds were seriously injured, and to break up any badfighting, but the birds needed to discover for themselves who was more aggressive before they would stop fighting. Most of the fighting was superficial, there were some bites and mostly bruises and swollen wings/eyelids. As pairs settled into nest boxes, most of the fighting stopped and even the pairs weren’t acting as aggressive as they once did. We also found that feeding them on their nest box or in their territory once itClick the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4133</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 48 No. 1 (2021): Watchbird October 2021; 18-20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4133/4093</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
