<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2540</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-15T14:01:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Utah Pheasant Society</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roundy, Carol</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en"> The Utah Pheasant Society was first started about 1946 with 12 members. The current roster shows 127 regular members and four honorary members.The Club's main purpose is the propagation and preservation of pheasants.Meetings are held at the Valley Jr. High School in Granger, Utah, on the third Wednesday of each month with the exceptions of July and August when most folks are occuped with summer activities. In June, they have a picnic and in September, an annual bird auction. In November, the club sponsors a show where members exhibit their birds and are judged by Federation judges. This event is held at the Murray Fairgrounds in Murray, Utah. After the judging, they have a show banquet. Each December they have a festive Christmas banquet.The members are mainly from Utah but they do have them from California, Nevada, Idaho, Wyoming, Colorado, Oregon, Kansas, Nebraska and Washington as well.Anyone interested in the Utah Pheasant Society should contact: Editor Bob Wellington, 5039 W 3500 So., West Valley City, UT 84120, telephone (801) 969-3784, or President Parley Roundy, 10895 So. 1300 W, So. Jordan, UT 84065, telephone (801)254-4313.The dues are $15.00 annually and include the Utah Pheasant Society Annual Breeder's Guide, membership roster, and a monthly newsletter that keeps the members informed of all the upcoming events and happenings.The governing structure of the Society consists of a president, vice president, secretary, treasurer, six directors, editor and show chairman. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2540</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 3 (1990): JUNE-JULY 1990; 56</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2540/2510</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
