<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/638</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Barbary Doves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Seldom does an individual remainactive in aviculture without having atleast one pair of what is frequentlyincorrectly called '' Ringnecked''Doves. While the Barbary Dove isactually a domesticated form of theAfrican Collared Dove (Streptopeliaroseogrisea), lack of agreementexists regarding whether the speciesshould be treated as S. risoria or arace of S. roseogrisea.The African Collared Dove inhabitsarid thorn scrub of north Africa.Feeding upon grass seeds , it consumeslarge quantities of berries ifwater is not present. Nesting, voiceand display is similar to that of thedomesticated form.About half the size of the commonferal pigeon, the Barbary Dove hasbeen propagated, through selectivebreeding, in numerous mutations. Acreamy buff color originated fromselectively breeding the recessivemutation from the wild form . Awhite variety is also commonlyencountered as are a variety of othercolors including what is referred to as" rosy" and " peach ~' Back-crossingthe domesticated form with the wildform has allowed the wild color toalso become available.In the wild, the African CollaredDove nests in trees and bushes oftenquite low to the ground. In captivity,Barbary Doves will lay in any tray,bowl, open box or even the floor oftheir cage! Two white eggs, the firstusually laid in the evening and thesecond in the morning, completesthe clutch . The incubation period is14 days . In the Sudan , breedingoccurs from January to June. In captivity,breeding continues throughoutthe year. Barbary Doves are frequentlyused to cross-foster even thelarger pigeons such as Pink Pigeonsand Fruit Doves.John Pire, a noted Texas dovebreeder, recommends maintainingthem in at least a 2' x 2' cage and providea diet including a good pigeonmix, fresh vegetables, black-eyedpeas and dog food. John mentionedrecently that some inbreeding hasoccurred and has resulted in some"birds having misformed toes.Individuals with an interest indoves or wanting to add a soothingcooing to their aviary " ambiance"should consider purchasing a pair ofBarbary Doves. Often considered agood beginner's bird, after over 20years of maintaining birds, it is onewith which I have not yet been ableto part.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/638</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 58-59</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/638/621</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
