<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/809</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Basics for Budgies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hazell, Richard &amp; Pati</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hopefully you have purchased ayoung Budgie that has beenhandfed or handled on a daily basis.This will enable you to quickly have ahand-tamed pet. Continue to handlethe Budgie on a regular basis if youintend for it to remain tame. Allow theBudgie to become accustomed to itsnew home and surroundings for twoor three days before you actually try tohandle it. Talk to it whenever you passits cage and as you feed and changethe water. Move slowly around it andwhile you are feeding and changingpaper as sudden, fast movementsfrighten it. Set a routine for you andyour new pet and keep to it - feedingtimes, play time outside the cage,bedtime , etc . Have patience andalways treat your Budgie with loveand tenderness.Watch your new bird closely the firsttwo or three days to ensure that itbegins to eat. This will be the first signthat it is accepting its new surroundings.As a temptation, we recommendusing spray millet available at mostreputable feed and seed specialtycompanies. They can supply you withfresh seed mix that they mix themselves,not the prepackaged brands. Itis usually a combination of many milletseeds with thistle ·added and givesthe young bird a good start with eatingseed. It is best to add to this seed mix:sprouts, veggies (thawed frozen andfresh), fruits, millet spray and variousother goodies. We have had goodresults with Super Preen vitaminsadded to the "soft food" such assprouts, etc. Super Preen is not theonly good vitamin supplement, butwe have had good results with it and itseems to be the best value for themoney (see section on "Food"). Seedalone is not enough to keep your Budgiehappy and healthy and to ensuretl1at it lives a long, happy life. We liketo leave the radio or TV on when weare gone for any length of time - itgives the Budgie some companywhile you are not at home.Cage SizeAt least 27" x 14" x 19" for a singleBudgie; this allows plenty of room toexercise and play. The bars should be1/2" apart; any wider and the Budgiecould get stuck in them or escape.Cages are never too big- only toosmall- the bigger the cage the better!If your huge cage has wide bar spacing,use 1/ 2" x 1/ 2" wire mesh to linethe inside of the cage to prevent thebird from escaping or breaking itsneck. The ideal cages for Budgieshave bars that are horizontal, as theylove to climb around on the sides ofthe cage.PerchesWood is best. Use different diametersand shapes if possible, to helpprevent foot problems. Toenailsshould not touch front to back whensitting on a perch. Natural treebranches from unsprayed safe treesmake ideal perches to perch on and tonibble. Place one perch close to thefeeders and one up high in the cagefor security and sleeping; the perch forsecurity and sleeping should be to theback of the cage, but be sure to leaveenough head room and tail room. Youmay have room for more than twoperches but do not overcrowd orplace perches where they are overfood and water dishes. This will help· prevent contamination from the bircl'sfeces. We also like to use ComfortPerches as these can be used twoways, either horizontal or vertical.Cage LocationSelect a permanent place away fromdirect sun, drafts, heater and air conditioningvents. A bright corner in aroom where there is activity worksbest as Budgies. are social birds. Butwe recommend against using a kitchen,as cooking fumes may be harmfulto the bird. Budgies like protectionfrom behind and above, so corners orup against a wall is ideal for protectinghis back and up on a table or standwhere little activity goes on above hisbead is best. It has been our experiencethat keeping the bird about youreye level works best. The danger to abird will always come from above ;that is "built into" them. If you placethe cage above your eye level, the birdwill feel that it is "boss," likewise ifyou put it at knee level you will be athreat to it. Do not place the cage on aTV or the stereo speakers; the vibrationsare nerve wracking to Budgiesand cause them undue stress whichcould cause illness. We also prefer tocover the top part of the cage at night;we leave the lower half of the cageuncovered to let in some light, andalways provide a night light in theevent the bird becomes startled in theda rk . Budgies have poor eyesight inthe dark and, if startled, can injurethemselves flapping around in a clarkcage. Budgies need 8 to 12 hours ofdarkness for ample sleep.Cage TrayLine the tray with white paper or oldnewspapers. If you use newspapers,use only the pages that are black andwhite, as the colored inks can betoxic. Pine shavings are fine but tendto be a bit messy as they scatter allover. Cedar shavings have too strongan aroma.ToysFor exercise and amusement,choose toys suited for Budgies; thebetter pet stores that specialize inbirds will have employees to assistyou in your selection . Some suggestedtoys; ladder, swing, mirror, latticeballs, wooden toys (to play with andchew o n), hoops (big enough for theBudgie to fit in without getting stuck),cow-bell type bells (do not use the"jingle bell" type as toes and beakscan become caught in them), ropetoys (3/ 8" diameter rope or larger). Ifyou make your own rope toys, useonly untreated rope; hemp or 100%cotton are good. Do not use twine,yarn or string as the Budgie canbecome caught and tangled in this.Whatever your choice of rope toys,always check them often to make surethat the bird has not gnawed itself anoose and hung itselfExerciseAllow play time outside the cagedaily if possible; this includes someflying time if your Budgie isn'tclipped. Time outside the cage isimportant, especially if your Budgie'scage is not large enough to allow a lotof exercise and wing flapping. Supervisethe time your Budgie spendsoutside of the cage at all times. Neverleave him unattended when he is outof the cage for play; accidents happenquickly and our homes are full ofdangers to an unsupervised, curiousBudgie.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/809</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 5 (1994): SEPT-OCT 1994; 43-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/809/791</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
