<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2564</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-16T21:48:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Avy Award Winners - 1990</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Jerry JenningsforChoco Toucan (Rampbastos brevis) HatchedJuly 31, 1989Woodland Park Zoological GardensEric Kowalczykfor Gold-whiskered Barbet (Megalaima chrysopogon) HatchedJune 15, 1989Jan R. van Oostenfor Musschenbroek's Lorikeet (Neopsittacus m. musscbenbroehit Hatched February 18, 1988Jan R. van OostenforSalvadori's Fig Parrot (Psittaculirostris salvadorii) Hatched August 22, 1989Houston Zoological Gardens Larry C. Shelton Curator of BirdsforLong-tailed Cissa(Cissa chinensis)Hatched April 17, 1988Dick SchroederforFairy Lorikeet (Charmosyna p. pulchella) Hatched October 10, 1989 Bill LasarzigforDesmerest's Fig Parrot (Psittaculirostris desmarestii intermedia) Hatched April 15, 1989Michael AtkinsonforEdward's Fig Parrot (Psittaculirostris edwardii) HatchedJune 19, 1988Last Chance FarmDr. Bern M. Levine KevinJ. ClubbAlicia F. Phillips John RealSusan L. Clubb, D. V.M. for Fiery-shouldered Conure (Pyrrhura egregia) Hatched May 29, 1989Jerry JenningsforCollared Aracari (Pteroglossus t. torquatus) HatchedJuly 15, 1989Joan DavisforGreat-billed Parrot (Tanygnathus megalorynchos) Hatched May 25, 1989 1989 Avy Appreciation AwardsNancy Vigranfor outstanding service given to West Valley Bird SocietySusan Benderfor outstanding service given to The Society of Parrot Breeders and ExhibitorsDr. Al Decoteaufor outstanding service given to New Hampshire Avicultural Society1989 Zoo Avy Awards Fort Worth Zoological Park forBlack-necked Swan Establishment of an individual species of birdFort Worth Zoological Park forRoseate Spoonbill Establishment of an individual species of bird 1989 Silver Avy Awards Brian and Dorothy Maslinger for1989 Show standards for CockatielsGerald Oldbergfor1989 Show standards in CockatielsMartin Von Raesfeldfor1989 Show standards in Finches/SoftbillsLinda Oldbergfor1988 Show standards in Cockatiels1989 Watchbird Avy Awards Carol SchmitzforIncubation and Troubleshooting the "Problem" EggJoanne AbramsonforMacaw Handfeeding and Pediatrics </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2564</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 17 No. 5 (1990): OCT- NOV 1990; 14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2564/2534</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
