<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2486</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-13T19:58:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Clipping - A Different Perspective</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Andreoli, Liz</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Would you break your two-year-old child's legs just to keep him from getting lost in a park, or falling into a swimming pool? Of course not. He needs to use those legs for total body health; to grow and learn about his world. Those legs pump vital oxygen to all parts of his body and without their use he could experience a multitude of health problems such as poor circulation, weakened muscles (including the heart), obesity, etc.Yet we preach constantly about clipping the wings of our bird friends simply because it's easy. Yeah, it's easy. We don't have to use our heads to remember the bird is out. We don't have ro keep the screens on the doors and windows, we don't have to hold the bird while someone else goes out the door. We can leave the sink full of water, we can cook while he is out, and on and on.There are a million-and-one things to remember for our bird's safety. How come we manage to do it with our twoyear-olds' We put locks on the household poison cupboards; we use barriers to block the stairs and pool area; we hold onto our child in the park; and so forth.I have a hard time understanding. We claim to love our birds and couldn't bear their loss. If that love is so strong why doesn't it put a paternal instinct in US'My first little pet bird brought an instinct in me so strong I thought I would go bananas. I had these horrible nightmares that my little friend some way or somehow escaped into the wildblue yonder. I would wake up sweating, shaking, and sick to my stomach. I got so protective I hassled my poor husband with, "Don't leave the door open;' "Remember to drain the sink:' "Get that poison out of here.' and mentioned every other way I might possibly lose my little darling. I decided to list these possibilities, paste the list on the refrigerator door. and go over and over them until they became second nature to me. I drilled my husband; found a good home for our beautiful cat; and guess what? It worked'Today I only clip wings to tame and train my birds, usually until the first moult, but sometimes it takes a second clipping for a bird to learn his boundaries. I find that birds are very intelligent, and with a little patience and time we can work wonders with them.While my pet birds are young and their wings are clipped I teach them windows (and mirrors) number-one priority. Take the bird to the window sill, set him down, and talk to him: "This is the window" (tap on it), "You cannot get through it" (tap again). The bird usually tries to get out, but if this simple procedure is done a couple of times a week until his flight feathers regrow I find the task is accomplished. After he begins to experience his new-found mobility any startling noise may cause a crash into a window, but the lack of strength and coordination at this time will do no more than stun, and triumphantly store a learning experience. I must add that it is very important he get access to windows while he is gaining his strength, and not after his flight is perfected. Please be aware that a crash into a window at full speed can kill a bird. I was given a plurnhead parakeet a while back that had suffered a concussion from such a crash. As a result she became so neurotic she decided to pluck herself clean (except for her head and a few odd feathers) until the clay she died.On the other hand, once windows and mirrors are mastered I have found that even if a window or glass door is left accidentally open the bird still thinks he wilJ hit a barrier and avoids it. Please don't chance this purposely though. This is also a time of "great" testing for a young bird. Not only is he testing a new-found ability, but also what this extraordinary ability means in relationship to you. Many times I'm sure I've heard my little adolescent reason, "If you tell me 'no' (on this thing I want to do) can I get far and high enough away from you (if I do it anyway) so I don't have to face being confined for my disobedience? In some cases you will be tested over and over and over. Be patient and consistent on how you respond, that little fluff of feathers has large eyes that watch your subtle body language intently. If you move to a new home some birds have to be retaught where windows are rather than what they are. This could be due to the fact that they become disoriented and confused in unfamiliar surroundings.Next teach him about the water left accidentally in the sink. Fill the sink with warm water about the height your bird would need, standing on his tiptoes, to keep his head out of the water. Float some of his favorite greens on top of the water, stand back and watch. Maybe your bird already has an instinct for this one. Ifhe jumps in give him several seconds to realize he's gotten himself into big trouble. Take him out, and in a stern voice tell him it definitely wasn't a good idea to do that; wipe him and keep him warm until he dries. Repeat this one until he ignores those delicious greens floating around in the water.In this article I can't go into all the ways we can teach our birds to protect themselves from danger. I would not, however, try any lessons to do with fire: it's too dangerous! Simply put him back in the safety of his cage when you are cooking. There are also other times when it becomes too dangerous for a bird to be loose. When we have a house full of company, for example, and we can't keep track of who has "Tweety.' or when that outside door is going to swing open again. Loud noises, fast movement, and strangers make most birds a nervous wreck. The protection of their cage will keep their anxiety and yours to a minimum. For a bird that talks, just in case, it wouldn't hurt to teach him his address, phone number, or your full name.We all learn by experience. By controlled experience we can do wonders with our cherished feathered friends without hindering and compromising the beauty of what attracted us to them in the first place: FLIGHT!Maybe it's me. I have to deal with a physical handicap every day of my life. It's not something to be taken lightly, and I can't imagine purposely debilitating any creature indefinitely and without just cause.I'm sure there are others like me out there. Let's hear your ideas on the subject. Do we want birds or do we want rodents? To clip or not; it's your choice.    </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2486</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 6 (1986): DEC 1986- JAN 1987; 12-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2486/2458</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
