<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/572</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Kori Bustard (Ardeotis kori) observations, description, status, care, behavior and captive environment</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schneider, Kevin</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Kori Bustards were in Africa whenprimative man finally decided that itmight be a good idea to stand up forthe first time. They were also therelong before the Super Continent splitinto Africa, Australia, Saudia Arabiaand India.This fact is readily apparent withthe four species of Ardeotis beingrepresented by Ardeotis kori inAfrica, Ardeotis australis in Australia,Ardeotis arabis in Saudia ArabiaandArdeotis nigriceps in India.Excerpts taken from ' 'Birds of theWorld" by Oliver L. Austin, Jr., state''The Bustards (Spp.) are a wellmarked family of large cursorialupland ground birds that live onopen, grassy plains and brushy savannas.... The Bustards are greatwanderers and some of the northernspecies perform extensive migrations.They fly in typical crane fashionwith the head and neck straightout in front. Their wings beatstrongly and steadily. In flight theystrongly resemble geese; the noticeabledifference being their long legstrailing behind the tail and curiousaerial posture of the rear of the bodysagging low. Unlike cranes and geese,they are not high fliers, and even onlong migrations Bustards seldom risemore than 200 or 300 feet above theground.As a rule, Bustards travel in smallflocks of a dozen or so birds. Highlypopular as game birds, they run sorapidly they are difficult for a hunterto approach on foot. However, theyoften crouch and hide, depending oncamouflage to protect them. Unfortunately,they show so little fear of aman on horseback or camelback or ina car that they have little chanceagainst modern weapons. Like allbirds of savory flesh, they have now become quite rare near centers ofhuman population. They survive inparts of their former range onlybecause of strict protection."</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/572</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 53-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/572/555</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
