<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1698</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:15:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Legjslative Issues</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Desborough, Laurella</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">We will briefly review the Animal Welfare Act, local regulations, and the effects of animal rights activities.USDA Regulations on AvicultureThe U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) was sued by animal rights organizations to force them to include rats, mice and birds as regulated and inspected animals under the Animal Welfare Act (AWA). In settling the lawsuit, the USDA agreed to establish regulations on rats, mice and birds. Last year, the Congress refused to fund the USDA to establish those regulations, at the urging of the medical research community. This year the USDA, with the expectation of Congress providing funds, has initiated steps to establish those regulations, which would require the inspection of bird breeders' facilities, as well as birds used in research.Helms Amemdment.Both the House and Senate have passed a massive Farm Bill to which many amendments were attached. One of those amendments proposed by Senator Helms, would remove rats, mice, and birds from the Animal Welfare Act. At present, the House and Senate Farm bills and their amendments are being reviewed by a Conference Committee composed of members from the House Agriculture Committee and the Senate Agriculture Committee. It will be up to these conferees to decide what stays in the Farm Bill and what is removed.AFAActionThe AFA State Coordinators and members will make their recommendations known to the Committee members. After the Committee decides on a final draft of the Farm Bill, it will be returned to the House and Senate for approval. If the final version of the Farm Bill continues to carry the Helms Amendment in its basic form, rats, mice and birds will not be included under the regulations of the Animal Welfare Act. This means bird breeders would NOT be inspected by official USDA veterinarians or Animal Care Specialists. Individual AFA members can keep informed on these legislative matters by signing up with their local bird club and receiving the club bulletin, as the AFA will provide basic legislative information via the AFA In Brief. Information can also be obtained from the AFA State Coordinators listed in the afa Watchbird Journal.How do we Protect Ourselves from Local Regulation?First, we have to be watchful for the appearance of restrictive regulations. We need to monitor local city and county proposals. One or two individuals from a local club can be appointed to routinely read the agenda of the meetings of the city and county zoning departments, and of the city council and county commission meetings. Monitor the newspapers for articles about problems or regulations related to dogs, cats, wild animals, exotic animals, breeding animals, or animal control regulations. Any of those items may eventually result in regulations on your bird keeping and breeding activities.Second, when we identify proposed regulations that may present problems to bird owners, we need to take immediate action and notify others interested in birds and animals. Most successful opposition to restrictive proposals comes when you present a large group of people who are working together to inform the governing officials of the serious problems posed by the proposed regulations and provide brief yet detailed remarks. The manner of presentation is as important as what is presented. Politeness carries more weight than belligerence or extreme emotionalism. In many cases the issues which provided the basis for the proposed regulations have been addressed by regulations already in place. It is extremely helpful to anyone dealing with regulation and legislation to have on hand the AFA Bird Keepers Legislative Handbook, available from the Business Office at a modest fee. This handbook provides basic information on local regulatory matters as well as guidance on dealing with local and state regulations. All bird owners need a copy of the handbook, which they should review frequently.Third, the AFA StateCoordinators and Club Delegates will be receiving some basic instruction on issues relating to proposed local regulations and proposed state and national laws. However, it is important that all members respond to local and national proposals regarding regulation of aviculturists.Future Regulatory ProposalsWe can expect to have proposals put forward regarding the following: 1) numbers of pet birds that may be legally possessed by a pet owner within a town or city, 2) restrictions on bird breeding within cities and counties, 3) regulations on the air transport of birds, 4) requirements for inspection of bird breeding facilities, 5) elimination or control of bird sales through pet stores, and 6) other restrictions that are outside the immediate area of bird breeding or bird keeping, but which, in the long run, will have a negative effect on aviculture."Animal rights" is not "animal welfare." Often animal rights folks use our passion for our birds to implement their goals. They use our concern for the welfare of animals and confuse the public into thinking that animal rights means animal welfare. Not so. The agenda of the animal rights organizations is to eliminate all animal use - including pet'&amp;gt;. The rights of U.S. citizens regarding animal ownership and use are under assauU by a mass movement orchestrated through the collaboration of many different animal rights organizations. Unless each and every bird owner realizes the seriousness of this mass movement and takes action against restrictive regulations, we will lose our right to keep birds in the U.S. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1698</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 29 No. 1 (2002): Fourth Quarter 2001; 73-74</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1698/1675</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
