<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2890</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-09T18:14:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA's New Home Office</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AFA is proud to announce the opening of its home office. The long awaited event materialized on December l st of 1978. It's staffed with a full-time "girl Friday," Kathy Young. Kathy has found herself in the middle of sorting and filing five year's accumulation of materials kept by every committee and officer we ever had. She also handles AFA's new phone, (714) 442-8276.All AF A materials that used to hide out with various committee members and staff people can now be found neatly catalogued at the office. Even the reasonably tidy supply of back issues of Watchbird are accessable. It's getting so we can find something when we want it.The home office also introduces another luxury we have not been accustomed to; full clerical, printing, typing, addressing and mailing services. These are available to all staff people, state coordinators, and delegates who are engaged in AFA projeccs.Home office manager and AFA Financial officer, Janice Pritchard, can be contacted right next door if you are unable to get through to Kathy.HOME OFFICE Kathy - (714) 442-8276 orJanice - (714) 442-1164 443 West Douglas Street,El Cajon, CA 92020.AFA materials will reach us there, or at P.O. Box 327, El Cajon, CA 92022, which we will continue to use.Office Hours: Open Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, Friday - 7:00 a.m. to 4:30 p.m. Closed Wednesday, Saturday, Sunday. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2890</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 6 No. 4 (1979): AUG-SEPT 1979; 36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2890/2874</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
