<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2275</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-13T15:48:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA 10th Annual Convention Report</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, Phyllis K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">AFA's 10th annual convention was held at the Hyatt Hotel just outside of the Magic Kingdom of Disney World in Kissimmee, Florida, August 2-5, 1984. Over 900 persons from the United States, South Africa, Trinidad, Sweden, Canada, and Spain congregated for a full three days of avicultural lectures given by some of the world's leading aviculturists.The convention started with the annual board meeting which was held on Thursday, August 2nd at which time the board voted into effect an updated and revised set of by-laws. It was also voted to award grants to the following avian research projects:1. Protein and Energy Utilization of Amazon Parrots - C.R. Grau and TE. Roudybush.2. Breeding Biology of the Monk Parrot - Prof. Stephen]. Emlen, Section of Neurobiology and Behavior, Cornell University.3. Development and Validation of Egg Waste Estrogen Analysis in Rare and Endangered Psittacine Species; Applications in Neonates for Sex Identification and Non-invasive Assessment - Arden Bryan Bercovitz, Ph.D., San Diego Zoo.4. Nutritional Requirements of Budgerigars Through Their Life Cycle - Dr. Donald Polin, Dept. of Animal Science, Michigan State University.5. Cryogenic Preservation of Psittacine Semen - Timothy L. Hargrove, Florida Atlantic University.At the Friday luncheon Dr. Val Clear honored AFA's presidents - Jerry Jennings, Lee Horton, Richard Baer, Tom Ireland, and Mrs. Lee Phillips, the current president.This year AFA encouraged affiliated clubs to set up an educational booth in the commercial exhibit area of the convention. All the participating clubs did an outstanding job and I am sure the judges had a difficult time making a decision. The first place cash award of $100.00 went to the Sunshine State Cage Bird Society, Orlando, Florida, for their very beautiful and educational display of a...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-02-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2275</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 11 No. 5 (1984): OCT-NOV 1984; 40-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2275/2249</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
