<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/413</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:20:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Canary Culture Concepts in Genetics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bucci, Tony</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Warning! After reading this article,and the knowledge you gain fromreading it, you will not be able to splicegenes, or modify chromosomes tocreate a black canary. Instead, this articleand subsequent articles on the samesubject will give you rudimentary conceptsof the subject genetics dealingwith canaries. Canaries are mostly bredfor show purposes, and breeders arestriving to improve their conformationor color so it is important to be familiarwith some concepts of genetics.Genetics is a comparatively youngscience. It has been developed mostlyduring the present century, but it isinteresting to go back to earlier studiesto see how the background for moderngenetics has evolved. Application ofgenetic principles in breeding andselection of cultivated plants anddomestic animals date back to ancientrecords. For example, early Chineseaccounts show that superior varietiesof rice had been developed almost6,000 years ago. Ancient Egyptianpaintings depict pictures of man crosspollinatingthe date palm. The greatnumber of dogs and cats that existtoday show that our distant ancestorswere using genetic breeding techniquesto produce animals best suitedto their needs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/413</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 15 No. 4 (1988): AUG-SEPT 1988; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/413/400</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
