<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3652</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-26T04:33:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Neville Connors: A Celebration of Life</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Steele-Boyce, Sheryll</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the early afternoon of 6 January 2014, Neville Connors passed away after a short battle with melanoma cancer.Neville was born in Atherton, Queensland, the youngest of four children. At the age of 10 his family moved to Grafton, where he enjoyed his schooling at St Joseph's and a variety of sports including surfing and hockey. From an early age Neville kept a variety of animals including Budgerigars and finches.As a teenager and younger man, he spent time in New Zealand, surfing-in which he showed particular talent, however he chose not to follow that path as a career. When he returned to Australia, he joined the Navy for a few years before returning to Grafton to work as a clerk with the railways. It was around this time that he purchased a property so he could further develop his interest in animals.A keen sportsman, Neville was highly regarded in Grafton for his expertise in hockey and played until just a few years ago. He coached many junior and adult teams over the years including taking the men's and women's A-grade teams to premiership victories. He was presented life membership of the Grafton Hockey Association-at his funeral service the senior members formed a guard of honour in respect of his contribution to the sport.When he met his wife Enid (Noddy), they discovered a mutual bond of devotion to family and birds. They married on the property known as Casuarina Parrot Gardens at Ramornie, near Grafton.Neville and Noddy were deservedly proud of the establishment of this picturesque property which started from humble beginnings, with them living in a caravan with their first children and a couple of Glossy Black Cockatoos!A true family man, Neville was very proud of his sons Sonny and Haley and daughters Ellanie, Shalanne and Tullara. Just prior to Christmas, Neville escorted his eldest daughter Ellanie to her marriage to Gavin-a very special family occasion indeed.Over the years Neville and Noddy bred and handreared thousands of quality birds, including a wide variety of Australian and exotic parrot species. Their greatest success was with breeding Glossy Black Cockatoos.They authored a world-first title on black cockatoos-A Guide to Black Cockatoos as Pet and Aviary Birds-which was translated into Czech. Neville presented at numerous bird conventions and clubs around the world, including the International Loro Parque Bird Conventions of which he was the Australian convenor and representative.The passing of a great man brings deep sadness and emotion. However, we are left with memories of Neville's good humour, gentleness, smiling face, enthusiasm and courteous manner.Neville showed incredible courage during his last days and periodically communicated his progress via phone and email and received visitors in good spirits on this difficult journey. He even attended the Northern Rivers Aviculture Society (NRAS) Christmas gathering after being hospitalised a few hours earlier, and caught up with close friends for meals, enjoying a special family dinner the evening before passing.In one of his emails to his concerned friends he stated-I have had a good life, don't owe any money and have always done my best to be totally fair in any and all dealings ... Would I love to be able to live longer? ... Absolutely, there have never been enough hours in a day, let alone days in our lives. Living in the bush I am constantly reminded of how beautiful nature is and try to take time to look, listen and smell such joys.Enjoying wonderful friendships, travel, our work, and most of all a beautiful family, has made my journey a pleasure trip. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3652</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 1&amp;2 (2014): Number 1&amp;2  2014; 8-10</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3652/3635</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
