<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/494</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">American Pied Indian Ringnecked Parakeet ... a developmental journey</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Salan, Jaynee</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Genetics have come a long wayfrom the days of Gregor Mendel,when a gene was considered an information-containing element ofunknown chemical nature that gaverise to an observable trait such asMendel's experiments with round orwrinkled peas. Working with peaplants, Mendel discovered the fundamentalprinciples of heredity in the1860s. Clearly, regulation of geneexpression is a major key to development.Discovering the genetic underpinningsfor this dramatic transformationis a major challenge ofbiology today.We are now in an era of biologicaldiscovery of unprecedented excitementand achievement. Genetic informationis expressed by its translationinto proteins of specific structure andfunction which , in turn , brings aboutan organism 's phenotype (the expressedtraits).Mutagenesis, the creation of mutations,can occur in a number of waysas the cells res pirate, repair, andrecombine. This can lead to base-pairsof subst itutio ns, insertions or deletions.Si nce determining how genesare translated into proteins in the1960s, scienti ts can give a descriptionof inheritable changes that arise.The DNA (deoxyribo nucleic acid)inh erited by an organism, controlsthe activity of each cell by specifyingthe sy nth esis of enzymes and otherproteins. A gene does not build a proteindirectly but, instead, dispatchesinstructions in the form of R A(ribonucleic acid) which , in turn , programsprotein synthesis. Cells are governedby a chain of command: D A -RNA - protein. The scheme is knownas the " Central Dogma of MolecularBiology;· a term coined by FrancisCrick .</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/494</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 40-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/494/479</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
