<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3252</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-08-02T17:36:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">When Disaster Strikes, We Can All Help</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">LePage, Mary Ellen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Recent months have brought what seems like an outbreak of natural disasters. Hurricanes Irene and Lee pummeled the east coast and Gulf states with torrential rains and winds, causing damage and flooding that devastated entire states. While the East coast was drowning, Texas and surrounding areas have suffered from extreme heat, drought, crop loss and numerous devastating fires destroying tracts of land the size of Connecticut. And as if that was not enough, earthquakes have shaken buildings in areas where they are not common. These disasters have caused disruptions of electrical power, road closures and have forced many from their homes in the affected areas.What happens to our birds when disaster strikes? How can we help? The American Federation of Aviculture's Disaster Relief team stands ready to help with resources donated by our members and associates. AFA board member and Northeastern Regional Director Concetta Ferragamo had her bird store demolished by the raging floods. She saved her birds by evacuating them the day before the water rose. When asked about her store, she said that "it was horrific." Her store, Parrot Safari Toy Factory, in Binghamton NY, "looks like a bomb went off in there." Despite her own massive losses, Ferragamo is helping other flood victims by being the distribution center for food purchased by AF A.The Puerto Rican Parrot Recovery Project was also hit. The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Rio Grande Field Office, Puerto Rican Parrot Recovery Project, has a successful program that has increased the species from a total of 13 wild birds, to 70-80, because of release programs. Additionally, they hold another 320 in captivity. Jafet Velez-Valentin, aviary team leader, reported that, aside from the damage from fallen trees and a blockage on their access road, they needed thousands of dollars in propane to run their generator during the extended power outage. During these catastrophic events, communication is often knocked out and it is difficult to locate bird owners in need of help. After past disasters AFA moved into the affected areas and helped our bird owners with distribution of food (generously donated by AFA and bird food manufacturing companies), temporary relocation of birds, and cage and facility repair, as well as tree removal. We remain prepared to help today. AFA is a federation of affiliated bird dubs and individual members throughout the country. The members of these local dubs (if they are not affected as well) are ideally suited to identify needs and to locate resources that are needed in their areas. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-08-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3252</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 38 No. 3 (2011): Number 3 2011; 7-8</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3252/3236</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
