<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2473</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-13T17:20:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Jacobin - Flower of Pigeondom</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Parrott-Holden, Jan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There's something fascinating about old books. So much so that if it weren't for tending my pigeons, I'd probably while away hours thumbing through vintage bookshops. Of course, I'd probably purchase many more volumes on poultry than poetry. That's the way it is with bird lovers.A lot of early poultry books are real treasures, containing a wealth of knowledge (though sometimes dated) and lots of attractive prints. One small volume penned by Alice Macleod in 1913, and titled "Pigeon Raising" is among my collection. Though it primarily explores squab production, there are a few chapters concerning the aesthetic side of the hobby. No, this is not intended to be a book review, but Macleod hits upon something in the first pages of her text that piques my curiosity. She states, "Princes, poets, prelates, judges and ladies of high degree have been in the ranks of the pigeon fancier during ages past'.' It's this statement that prompts me to ask: Was Queen Victoria's favorite hobby really breedingJacobins?There is incomplete data concerning the origin of the Jacobin, one of the oldest pigeon breeds in the world. However, some sources suggest that the variety was introduced to Europe from India, with earlier records reporting that the breed had its beginnings on the island of Cyprus. There appears to be little disagreement that the Jacobin obtained its name due to the striking similarity between its profusely feathered hood and that of the Dominican friar's cowl. This bouffant feathering earned the breed much popularity in Germany, where it was nicknamed the "wig pigeon'.'The Jacobin, a ruffed variety, is one of those breeds that has undergone quite an evolution throughout the years. Pictures from Levi's The Pigeon indicate remarkable changes in feather, body size, and carriage. In fact, it has taken well over two hundred years for the bird to have gone from a creature with tight feathers and minimum hood to become th~ full-blown flower of pigeondom.without question, the contemporary "Jac" is an incredible work of art.The standard for Jacobin beauty requires that the colored birds have a white head, rump, tail, and possess between seven and ten white flights. All colors are to be rich with the standard hues being black, red, yellow, blue, silver and tigered. The eyes are to be pearl or white and the hood must be full and round so as to inhibit the bird's peripheral vision.That old proverb, "birds of a feather flock together;' is certainly true of the Jacobin, for generally speaking they are shy, rather anti-social and prosper when housed by themselves. Due to their obstructed vision, they are floor birds and don't take readily to high perches or nest boxes.Reports vary as to the capabilities of this breed in rearing their own young. Quite honestly, it is easy to see how a jac hen or cock could be "blind" to parental responsibilities. Yet many breeders testify that jacs, when properly trimmed in the hood and vent areas, perform admirably in their biological functions. None the less, it is always a good idea to maintain foster feeders for help in the brooding and feeding regimen.Jacobins make wonderful show birds, especially when given extra attention by their keeper. This priming enables the breed to maintain calm and poise during exhibition. It also displays to the utmost their elaborate feathering.Some of the finest Jacobins in the country are bred in California. I don't know why so many fine birds come out of this area, but I'd say it has more to do with skill and tenacity of the breeder than in the healthful qualities of the sunshine.Dennis Soares of Chino is one of those outstanding breeders, dedicating 31 of his 40 years of life to a hobby that intrigues and challenges him daily. Perhaps it is the challenge that keeps Dennis' enthusiasm at its fever pitch. Says Soares, "The key word for the novice and the experienced breeder is patience, as it is easy to get discouraged'.' Soares added that jacs often are poor parents, leaving their young to die. Infertility can also be a menace. In addition, Soares says that the survivors go through a lengthy moult, trying the breeder again to wait out the ordeal before knowing exactly what kind of specimen he'll have for the showroom. A great deal of work. A great deal of applying that old adage, "try, try again'.' So why does this unique breed maintain such a following? Some say it centers around the array of beautiful colors. Others the grace and carriage. Many sum it up by calling the jac an aristocratic beauty. They are all correct.And that, I suppose, brings me right back to square one. Did Queen Victoria really raise Jacobins? Dennis Soares claims he believes the stories he's heard. And, he's in excellent company, since authors of note, including Levi, Naether and Hess make mention of this fact. But I wonder if it really matters? For every breeder who knows his pigeons seems quick to admit that the Jacobin comes closest to being the flower of pigeondom. • </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2473</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 5 (1986): OCT- NOV 1986; 26-30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2473/2445</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
