<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2120</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-07T18:34:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Hand Raising Green Imperial Fruit Pigeons</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heinrich, George</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Memphis Zoo and Aquarium has maintained green imperial fruit pigeons (Ducula aenea) since May of 1974. At present, the zoo has three adults consisting of a pair and an additional male. These are on display in the back open flight of the tropical bird house. On November 17th of 1981, we had our third successful hatching. It was named Marty Feldman because of the bulging eyes it had while a youngster. The previous two hatched out in February and May of 1980 and were raised by the parents. This third hatching is notable because it is being hand raised at the zoo's reserve bird house. The parents abandoned the nest while the youngster was pipping. The egg was removed from the nest on November 14th and placed in an incubator set at 98.5 YsF. On the morning of November 17th the squab hatched. Outside the reserve bird house was a pair of nesting common pigeons. It was decided at this time to trade the youngster with a hatchling of approximately the same age from this nest. After periodically observing the birds during the day, we noted the younster was being brooded but not fed. Not wanting to take any chances, we pulled the baby to hand raise.At first Marty was fed a very liquid formula of cooked Heinz baby cereal, KMR and small amounts of Osteoform and K-zyme. The baby cereal was cooked to aid in digestion. The bird was fed this mixture lukewarm from a spoon approximately five times daily starting at 8 A.M. Feedings were scheduled for every two hours. For the first week, an evening meal was provided. Careful observation was taken to be sure the formula was not impacting in the crop. This happened once, but gentle massage cured the problem. After approximately two weeks, Heinz blended baby fruits were added. Within another two weeks, 50% of Marty's formula consisted of these blended fruits. The blended fruits were slowly substituted with chopped fruits such as apple, banana and raisins. After a few more weeks larger pieces of fruit, as in canned fruit cocktail, were given. The fruit cocktail was thoroughly rinsed to remove the sweetened syrup. At 74days, old Marty was eating canned fruit cocktail, morning mix (a mixture of dog food, carrots,graham crackers and Heinz baby cereal), K-zyme and parrot grit. On November 19th, at two days old, the youngster weighed 17 .25 grams. At the time of this writing, Marty is 83 days old and weighs 422.00 grams. (See Table I for schedule of weight gains.)Ducu/a aenea, their scientific name, are found in India, Ceylon, Burma, the Adamans, Thailand, Inda China, Malay Peninsula, the Phillipines and Indonesian Islands. They are light, grayish-green above and pale gray below. The sexes arealike and are approximately 18 inches in length. In the wild these fruit pigeons frequent low-lying forest regions and are rarely found at elevations above 1,500 feet. They are shy birds and usually keep to the tops of high trees. Feeding in the cool of early morning and evening, they sometimes gather in small flocks in trees heavy with fruit. Strong feet with broad, flattened toes make it easier for them to move about the branches. They are seldom seen on the ground, except to drink. Flexible mandibles enable them to gape wide enough to swallow large fruits whole. The flesh of the fruit is digested and the hard seeds are later regurgitated. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2120</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 9 No. 4 (1982): AUG-SEPT 1982; 40-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2120/2091</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
