<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/566</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Crowned Pigeons</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wetzel, Dave</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Found on the island of New Guinea(in both Papua New Guinea and Irian .Jaya) and a few small adjoiningislands, the three species of CrownedPigeons of the genus Goura are thelargest members of the pigeonfamily. These magnificent birds arepopular both as zoo exhibits and inprivate breeding facilities.Taxonomists have long debated thestatus of these birds. Currently, threedistinct species are recognized.Recent DNA mapping (Bohmke &amp;amp;Patton 1987) seems to support this.The apparently extinct Microgourameeki of the Solomon Island chainmay have been their closest relative.Trugon terrestris may be their closestliving relative with M. meekihaving been the link between thetwo living genera.Crowned Pigeons are currently onAppendix II of the CITES convention.Individuals in Rotterdam are developinga petition to have these birdsplaced on Appendix I, furtherrestricting trade in wild-caught birds(Nijboer, 1991). The reasoning forthis is clear. Little data currentlyexists on their status in the wild.What little is known is that they havebeen locally extirpated whereverman has established settlements(Collar &amp;amp; Andrew 1988; Coates 1985;Beehler 1985; Bell, 1982, 1970,1969; Pearson 1974). Despite lawsprohibiting the taking of these birdsby shotgun or nets, shooting and collectingcontinue. While there is littletrade in wild-caught birds within theU.S., there appears to be a significanttrade in eastern Europe and southeastAsia. Reportedly one dealer based inSingapore took some 900 G. cristatafrom waterholes in IrianJaya in 1987(Nijboer 1991). This same dealer washolding approximately 300 individualsat two locations in southeast Asiain 1990 (King 1991).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/566</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 30-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/566/549</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
