<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/603</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Australian King Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rattray, Bill</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the age of specialization, Idecided on a group of very colorfulparrots called king parrots. Startingin 1982, I have worked with threespecies of the king parrots. Theseinclude the Australian King (Alisterusscapularis) from eastern Australia,the moszkowskii subspeciesof the Green-winged King (A. chloroperus)from New Guinea and theAmboina King Parrot (A. amboinensis)from several Indonesian islandsincluding Amboina in the southernMoluccas.King parrots are naturally tame andconfiding, hardy, non-destructive andthe quietest of the mid-sized parrots.These endearing qualities make thisparrot highly prized by parrot enthusiastswho are ready for a beautifulbird which will not cause complaintsfrom the neighbors.The Australian King Parrot is not ashy bird and is commonly seen innearby fields, parks and gardens inAustralia. It is the largest of thebroad-tailed Australian "parakeets,''measuring 17 inches in total length.The adult males have a brilliant redhead in comparison to the adultfemales. A bright, pale green scapularbar above the wings can be seen inthe adult males.I have been a bird hobbyist for 25years, ten of which I have bred kingparrots. Most of the flimsy literaturewhich is available on breeding kingparrots would discourage even themost avid aviculturists. But the truthis that the Australian King and theother kings are as easy to breed asany of the other Australian parrots,once you allow them to settle downwith the correct conditions. I place one pair of king parrots peraviary. The aviaries are eight feetlong, three feet wide and four feet inheight. I have bred king parrots in cages six to 16 feet long without anynoticeable change in productivity.The cages are suspended three and ahalf feet above the ground. This isdone to eliminate bacteria, fungi andworms. Three gang perches areplaced at each end of the aviary. Themale seems to think that any perchthe female is on is his! This gives thefemale an opportunity to give way to"his majesty", thus avoiding stress.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/603</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/603/586</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
