<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1918</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-10-31T00:59:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">From The Editor's Desk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dingle, Sheldon</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Ah, gentle readers, how quickly your passions flare, how volatile your emotions. This column isaforumforexchange between reader and reader and between reader and editor. Exchange is healthy, I think, but I should like to see it done quietly, amicable, logically, and based on issues rather than on personalities. Nothing printed in this column has been intentionally directed toward the denigration of any individual.Individuals, by name, do pop up now and again in various letters, but individuals are often intimately involved in one issue or another. The Alba Ballard controversy is a prime recent example. Alba Ballard is the individual and draping human clothes on an animal is the issue. In my mind, I separate the two instantly.As an individual, as a human being, Alba Ballard has all of the qualities and ingredients that entitles her to the same honor and respect that one should afford any other human being. Never for an instant have I meant to take anything away from Alba. I don't know her personally, but from all I can learn she is a gifted and remarkable woman.Now to the issue. Just as some people like jazz and others like classical music, some people like animals in human garb and some people like animals in their natural form. Theissueoftogarbornotto garb is one of personal taste. It has no bearing on the virtue or worth of an individual. For example, my wife would dearly love to see Alba's dressed up birds. I, on the other hand, would be made distinctly uncomfortable by such a display. Do I love my wife lessf or her taste in this matter? Certainly not. My very good buddy H. Richard Mattice loves good scotch whiskey while I prefer a good wine. ls he less afriendfor the difference? You already know the answer to that.As a final installment on this particular issue I have included excerpts from several letters on the subject. Dear Mr. Dingle,When I read the letter that Catherine C.Tyler wrote in the Oct. I Nov. issue of the A.F.A. Wathcbird, I felt it warranted a reply. Either she knows Alba Ballard personally or she speaks with forked tongue.I went to the 1979 AF.A. Convention in Florida and I came back with a notebook loaded with information. While I was there, I had, quite by chance, a little chat with Alba and I found her to be a lovely and very charming lady. I also observed and petted "Galaxy" her pet Moluccan Cockatoo. I found that "Galaxy" was in beautiful plumage. If "Galaxy" was "clipped", then she had a really great way of hiding it. By the way, Alba's show was very fascinating. Some of the costumes were adorable. Since "Galaxy" does a jiffy little two-step on her perch, she would be A-1 in any disco ...In all seriousness now, those who missed the convention really missed a wonderful gathering. I learned an awful lot down there and I met a lot of very interesting people. The speakers were all very informative and it gave me quite an insight to aviculture. I must say it was a valued experience.Sincerely, Beth Greenberg </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-10-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1918</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 7 No. 1 (1980): FEB-MAR 1980; 42-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1918/1889</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
