<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2298</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-05T20:48:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Basement Breeding Moluccan Cockatoos - Condo Style</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kotz, Dona</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">We who are unfortunate enough to live in a climate that prohibits yearround outdoor breeding accommodations for our birds are often confronted with a limited amount of space in which to house our birds. Such was the case in our aviary, a disadvantage that may have contributed to successful breeding of two pairs of newly introduced Moluccan cockatoos two successive years in a row.The basement space available was long and narrow. After much discussion and discouragement from other aviculturists, two 14 x 8 x 6 flights were constructed in extreme close proximity. Two metal drums were installed as nest boxes in the rear of each enclosure, one barrel placed vertically on top of the other, "condominium style'.' One pair's access to the box was high, the other entry low.To provide security, a visional screen covered two thirds of each cage. To simulate communal feeding, dishes were placed in full view, cage to cage. Perches were placed to encourage flight, with additional 2 x 4s offered to fulfill instinctive destruction. The light cycle provides twelve hours of daylight, with one hour of dawn and one hour of dusk. A night light supplies continual moonlight. Humidity control during the two year time period fluctuated greatly during the cockatoo breeding season.Our much disputed diet consists of Lafeber's Special Needs Diet in pelleted form and water. We add a few sunflower seeds each day as we change water, mostly for our own psychological satisfaction. If you are interested in learning more about Lafeber's pelletized food, contact Dorothy Products, 7278 Milwaukee Avenue, Niles, Illinois 60648. ln this short paper we are focusing on the housing of the birds rather than the diet. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-05</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2298</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 12 No. 1 (1985): FEB-MAR 1985; 49-50</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2298/2272</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
