<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/65</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-09-22T16:38:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Influence of Early Experience Upon the Development of Social Behavior in Estrildine Finches</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Immelmann, Klauss</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Besides the mother-infant-relationshipsdiscussed in a previous paper, experienceduring the first days or weeks of lifehas also proved to exert an important influenceon adult behavior, mainly uponthe determination of sexual preferences,but also on several other aspects of socialbehavior. The establishment of sexualattachments through early experience isgenerally referred to as sexual imprinting.Its characteristics have first been compiledby Lorenz (I 935) although thephenomenon of early sexual fixation hadbeen mentioned long before (cf. Gray1963). Since 1935, numerous experimentalinvestigations have been carried outabout sexual imprinting. Most of themhave been concerned with precocial birds(for review, see Moltz 1963, Hess 1964,Schutz 1965, 1968, Sluckin 1965, Bateson1966, o.a.). For altricial birds, materialis still very scanty and consists mainlyof numerous occasional observations ofhand-raised individuals which became imprintedon humans (for review, see Klinghammer1967). The only experimentalinvestigations with altricial birds are thoseby Nicolai (1956, 1959, 1964)with BullfinchesPyrrhula pyrrhula and the parasiticwidow birds Viduinae, by Warriner,et a/. {1963) with pigeons and by Klinghammer(I.e.) with Ring Doves Streptopeliarisoria and Mourning Doves Zenaiduramacroura (Klinghammer I.e.).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/65</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 2 No. 3 (1975): June 1975; 8-10 &amp;30</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/65/56</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
