<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1279</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">IN SEARCH OF CANARIES ... Frills</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mitchell, Glenn A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">FrillsT here are three main varieties of frills - Parisian, Dutch, and Italian. The first two we will deal with in this article. The Italian is practically non-existent in our area, thus our lack of information on it.Dutch FrillThe Dutch Frill undoubtedly originated from the old Dutch canary bred in Holland, France, and Belgium which was very much in evidence in the 1700s. At that time a good specimen measured eight inches in length. Currently, though, they are breaking this type down into so many names and variations that it is becoming almost impossible to know what they are talking about. Now the Dutch Frill, as a rule, is smaller than the Parisian Frill and is much less densely feathered. Its feathering is lightly frilled, is regular and symmetrical. It has a small head and clearly visible neck without any curled feathers. In the rear there is an absence of heavy feathering and the rump and the vent are smoothly covered. It has long stilty legs, normally feathered. Parisian FrillOn the other hand, the Parisian Frill is robust in appearance and is vigorous in action with plenty of bounce and vitality. It is a slim bird, with a profusion of feathering all over its body. The bird stands upright on long supple legs. The feathering can be irregular, either tightly frilled or in long plumes. However, in a good show specimen, the mantle extends well down the back towards the rump and the jobot must be double-sided - the frills must come from each side of the breast to form a feathery ruffle. On the head, the feathers may curl or roll upwards. The neck carries a general collar of frilled feathers. A final interesting characteristic are the toenails - they grow with a pronounced twist sort of like a corkscrew.Small FrillsAlso, there has come into focus a variety of small Frills. The normal standard for a Frill is that the bird should be as large as possible, (73/4 to 81/4 inches for a Parisian Frill and 6 1/2 to 6 3 /4 for a Dutch). People are bastardizing the breed by cross breeding in a willynilly manner and have created a bird with many strange examples of the breeders supposed art. However, we are speaking of the Frill as it should be and this means a large bird.The neck is straight and the head held high - but the same shape as the Belgian Fancy. The body has a somewhat curved appearance as the tail is usually hanging down instead of out and this gives the appearance of a half round bird. Parisian Frill, Dutch Frill, Northern Frill, Southern Frill - all mean the same bird and it takes a judge of quality to determine the difference. Curly FeathersObviously there must be a feather difference because of the name and this is true. The feathers of the long breast curl in and the feathers of the mantle curl also. Many of the wing feathers are curled and this gives the appearance of the old fashioned wind blown bob that women used to wear.SwnmaryThese birds are again Old World Varieties and as such command our respect. They are beautiful singers and are real personality birds. They talk a lot during the day and sing a great deal and are very active in spite of their peculiar appearance. Once again, we are speaking of a bird that is almost endangered. For many years we did not see any of them, but a few faithful breeders kept the breed going and now more of us are into breeding this delightful bird. The judging is changing on these birds and now it is assumed that the wings should not cross. Before they were to cross slightly, but now they say "no" so watch for this in your birds. The head should be in proportion and without a crest - though the back of the head can be slightly hooded. The legs should be long and supple without the stiff appearance.These birds should not be color fed but you will find in some a bit of orange. This comes from the Italians who have introduced this into the birds. Too many of the judges are not aware of this quality in the Italian birds and it makes quite a problem at a show when one of these judges is presiding. We are hopeful of making it well enough known that all of the judges will be aware of this quality. This is common in Canada as they seem to be doing more in breeding Frills than the Americans.Those of you who read this I hope will discuss this in your clubs and see what can be done to instill the adventure of exciting birds in people who are stuck with the hum drum variety of the ordinary canary. Live excitingly and raise some of these delightful canaries and let us strive to bring these varieties - Rollers, Frills, and Belgians - back from the brink of extinction.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1279</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 2 (1998): MAR-APR 1998; 37</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1279/1258</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
