<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4121</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:18:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Behind the Headlines: Parrot Chicks Rescued from Traffickers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Low, Rosemary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 49 Number 4 (October/November 2022).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Behind the Headlines: Parrot Chicks Rescued from TraffickersPhotos Courtesy of Maria Fernanda GondimThroughout the tropics, an increasing number of dedicated people are doing amazing things to help the survival of parrot species and individual birds. The number of projects and people involved has increased enormously during the past decade in many countries, from Indonesia and Africa to South America and the Caribbean islands. On the one hand it demonstrates awareness of the problems faced by these charismatic birds; on the other the resources, human and financial that are needed. Never enough… I would like to focus on several remarkable people and their colleagues who, especially during the past few months (and for years previously), have demonstrated their passion to saving some of the most threatened parrots in Brazil. This story mainly concerns the rare Red-browed Parrot (Amazona rhodocorytha). At 36cm, the Redbrowed is the second largest of the mainland Brazilian Amazons, after...Fernando and Beto with chicks on arrival at Beto’s premises.Combined pressures: habitat loss and illegal trade Its IUCN status is Vulnerable but more logically under Brazilian law it is recognised as Endangered. Once abundant, this parrot has suffered a significant decline, due to habitat loss and illegal capture. This trade in live birds for pets was primarily local, especially in the states of Rio de Janeiro, Espírito Santo and Bahia. This parrot has always been rare in aviculture outside Brazil. During the 1980s some illegally exported birds reached Europe and the USA. Thefts from nests are difficult to control. Even eggs have been taken. For example, in May 2013 a Portuguese man was caught at an airport in northern Brazil with 36 eggs which he planned to smuggle into Portugal. In the 1998-1999 breeding season, 174 nestlings were poached, mostly from reserves, for the national and international bird trade (Brown and Brown, 1992). In recent...Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-11-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4121</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 49 No. 4 (2022): Watchbird October/November 2022; 20-24</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4121/4081</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
