<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/560</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Indigo Macaw Re-appraised A smaller bird or a mystery solved?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pickering, Robin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cuddy, Joe</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As close friends of world renownedaviculturists Harry and Pat Sissen, Joeand I often visit them to discuss variousavicultural and ornithologicalmatters.For some time now we have alltaken a keen interest in Harry'sefforts to bring together the lastremaining captive Lear's Macaws in aserious attempt to establish a successfulbreeding program.At the present time, Harry and Pat'sefforts represent the only positiveattempt in Europe to save this macawfrom oblivion. It was therefore amidgreat excitement that the two''Lear's" Macaws arrived from MulhousZoo in France to join the programin February this year. RolandWirth of ICBP had initiated theirmove by suggesting to Dr.]. Lernouldof Mulhouse Zoo that results mightbe achieved if the pair was placedinto Harry's care in England. Furtherdialogue between Dr. Lernould andHarry led to the decision to organizetheir transfer to England. It is regrettablethat others holding Lear'sMacaws do not have the same insightas Roland and John, if perhaps allowners cooperated and sent nonbreedingstock into the one programthen positive results might beachieved more quickly.Prior to their arrival, Joe had calledme and indicated that he had seen anold photograph of this pair of Lear'sand was suspicious that one, indeed,may be a Glaucous Macaw. However,he believed that the suspect bird wasthe male and that it had originated inBelgium. I knew that this bird hadbeen sent some time previously backto Brazil and had since died. In thelight of this information, Joe abortedhis plan to view the birds in France.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/560</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 14-16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/560/543</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
