<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1791</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-04T01:27:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pet Bird Rescue</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ewell, Stacey Y.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The summer of 2001 was a wonderful time in the Tidewater area where I live. There were two local bird clubs flourishing on both sides of the river. Both held monthly meetings attended by regular members as well as new recruits. Memberships were growing, nationally recognized speakers were taken for granted, and fund raising was a success. Education was the goal and with the finances to reach out to the public, that goal was well on its way to being met.Speakers introduced at both clubs were the owners of a new rescue facility in the local area. A young couple, well educated and motivated to contribute to the well being of the lives of birds were now in the area. They presented a short introduction relating to their education, background, and desire to work with the local clubs and breeders alike. They stated that PIJAC was already consulting with them regarding the requirements of such a facility and they were working towards meeting the requirements set forth by this nationally recognized organization.Soon the rescue facility was setting up booths at the local marts. Educational materials filled the booth explaining the facilities purpose, contacts, and goals. Adoption applications, business cards, and beautiful pictures quickly drew attendees to the booth. Their booth was located right up front at the mart's entrance for everyone to notice.Board members of the local bird clubs, breeders, and pet owners also were excited to finally have a facility willing to work with the clubs. Donations to the facility from both clubs were approved unanimously by the board members. All contributions to such a good cause were important because both would have an interest in education. The club could provide an endless list of volunteers to the facility and donations would help the rescue get off to a good start.At a following meeting, another donation was discussed with the board. It appeared that a cockatoo at the facility had a broken leg and had presented quite a hefty bill for the rescue facility. One of the owners had apparently flung the bird to the floor in his surprise when the bird had latched firmly onto his hand. Advice was given to the general membership about this incident and everyone laughed with an uneasy feeling about what had happened. None the less, a donation went forward to aid in payment of the medical expenses incurred.After a year or so, it was announced the facility was moving to the country. Here the family and the birds could both enjoy the space. Everyone was excited to hear the good news. Obviously, the number of birds in the facility was growing and the ability to house them ever increasing. A country setting, more room, and experience could now set the facility on the path to growth.Several months after the facility moved I received a phone call from a friend living in the county where the rescue had relocated. They wanted to know who these new bird people were that had moved into the community. The neighbors were upset because the grass was growing up over the property. There were birdcages everywhere in the yard. I explained they were the new rescue facility. They were just getting moved in and I was sure things would improve.At the next club meeting, I felt I should mention the phone call to the board. Several members appeared to be offended. One member stated that she had been to the facility. She could assure the board that on every occasion things were up to standard. A recommendation was made to have several members visit the facility prior to making another donation. A recommendation was also made to assist the facility in other ways. We could keep an eye on the situation, still provide support through free space at the marts, volunteers from the club, and watch the progression of the facility. Finally, it was decided any request for several board members to visit the facility prior to donation would be an intrusion. The donation went forward.Sadly, after approximately two or so years of operation, it was announced in the club newsletter that the facility had been closed. No further information was provided. The fate of the birds in the facility was not disclosed. What would be the disposition of these birds? Without the clubs financial support how would they receive proper care, food, and vet work? Were they still there? Even though at this writing it has been several months since the closing, no further information about their fate has been published.As a bird breeder or bird club board member, it is likely you will receive calls from your veterinarian, referrals from previous clients, and general questions about re-homing of relinquished birds. It is my hope that through reading this article, all will become more aware of the word rescue and its implications. Pet bird rescue...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1791</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 31 No. 1 (2004): First Quarter 2004; 4-7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1791/1766</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
