<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2695</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-23T13:50:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ex Libris: "Life of the Pigeon" by Alexander Skutch</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clinton-Eitniear, Jack</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Once again, the prolific Costa Rican naturalist Alexander Skutch has produced a popular reading account on the life of a popular avian family. Having observed Central American pigeons/ doves for several decades, he could certainly have written this book entirely from a New World perspective. His decision to include information on species throughout the world, however, increases the breadth and, therefore, usefulness of the book. '' Life of a Piegon" has a rather straight forward organization starting with a bit of history on the pigeon family, then progressing to '' Eating and Drinking," "Daily Cycle", "Voice and Courtship", etc. The chapters on "Nests and Eggs", "Incubation" and "The Young and their Care" should interest the aviculturist. One should not, however, neglect to read the chapter on "Rate of Reproduction'.' A viculturists often set their goals at 100% when it comes to pairs nesting, eggs hatching and young fledging. Information assimilated by Skutch into a table indicates that for nine species (Feral, Wood, Whitecrowned, Mourning, Eared, Gala pagos, White-winged, Croaking Ground, and Ruddy Quail), only 54% of over 5,000 nests constructed were used for egg laying. Even more astounding is his data on the percentage of eggs that hatched. Of over 11,000 eggs laid, only 48% actually hatched!The center of the book contains 24 color plates, including the rather well known Blue Ground Dove of the Fiji Islands. Throughout the book, the author placed 30 figures and four tables including '' Incubation Schedules of Pigeons", '' Schedule of Feeding for two Mourning Doves" and' 'Nesting Success of Pigeons."For the pigeon and dove owner/ breeder, this book makes an excellent companion to Derek Goodwin's '' Pigeons and Doves of the World/ Third Edition." The chapters on "Homing Pigeons" and "Pigeons and Man" should appeal to those with domesticated breeds. Finally, to the connoisseur/ collector of fine books on birds, this book deserves a rightful place alongside Skutchs previous contributions, "Life of a Tanager;' "Life of a Woodpecker;· and "The Life of a Hummingbird'.' •  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2695</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 4 (1991): AUG-SEPT 1991; 47-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2695/2676</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
