<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4131</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T23:43:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">47th Annual AFA Conference Recap</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferragamo, Concetta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 48 Number 1 (October 2021).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Minneapolis, Minnesota welcomed AFAThe AFA 47th annual educational conference was absolutely fantastic! It’s always wonderful to mingle with like-minded people who all share an interest of having birds in our lives. Meeting with people in-person was deeply appreciated by all, especially since we are finally post pandemic. AFA held the first hybrid conference so that those who could not attend in person were still able to participate. There were some minor glitches, but the feedback has been positive, and the conference was well received by both in-person and virtual attendees. AFA plans to continue with the hybrid conference and will continue to fine tune the virtual experience. Both groups benefitted from the hybrid efforts sincebirds being cared for by us humans. AFA is the hub where bird clubs, pet owners, conservationists, bird keepers, breeders, sanctuaries, rescues, educators, manufacturers, pet stores, behavioral consultants, veterinarians, vet techs, students, artists, exhibitionists, free flyers and bird enthusiasts all come together. This is where everyone can exchange ideas and research - all in support of keeping birds in our lives to the best of our abilities. There is always something new to learn in aviculture and AFA is the networking plethora for all things bird related.When you attend an AFA conference you get together with friends, meet new people, put a face to the name you may have been following over thethe zoom meeting presentations were recorded. But more about that a little later. In-person first time attendee, Beverly Lynch, describes being in “awe” the entire time. Virtual attendee and AFA in-person conference veteran, Ginny Heptig, reported that the virtual experience needs some work but holds a promising future.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4131</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 48 No. 1 (2021): Watchbird October 2021; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4131/4091</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
