<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1073</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-18T17:21:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Red-tailed Amazon (Amazona brasihensis)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martins, Bob</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Amazona brasiliensis, found only in Brazil, is also called the Red-tailedAmazon, Purple-faced Amazon or Chua. Among this magnificent parrot's striking features are its purple head and colorful tail feathers which fan into a bright yellow and red display. With the combination of brilliant coloration and outspread feathers, this Amazon presents a picture of unequaled beauty and has its own particular personality. It has the habit of erecting nape and hindneck feathers, just like the Hawk-headed and the Amazona vinacea. It does not have any similarity with the Amazona festiva bodini or any other Amazon as described by some writers.In the wild, they are fast, agile highf1yers whose range is below 300m (900 ft). They live in pairs or small f1ocks and mate for life. Despite the fact that if one of the pair dies or is captured the other will find another mate, their propagation rate in the wild is very poor. The average female weighs 519 grams; the average male weighs 486 grams. They measure 35cm in length with no difference between the male and female. During breeding season both parents become extremely aggressive and noisy to protect their nest site.The average summer temperature in their natural habitat, which encompasses a wide area in three Brazilian states, is 30 degrees Centigrade (84 degrees Fahrenheit) while the lowest winter temperature is around 14 degrees Centigrade (20 degrees Fahrenheit). Annual rainfall ranges from 1500mm to 2000mm (60 to 80 inches).They line their nests with tree bark in either live or dead trees. For nesting they prefer the Guanandi tree Callophyllum brasilienses. They also like the Figueira Ficus enormis trees as well as several other types of palm trees. The diameter of their nestingtrees is between lm and l.Sm (3 ft. - 5 ft.). Thirty-three percent of the nest sites are located in the Guanandi trees. They begin searching for appropriate nest sites in August and will usually lay eggs in September or October although they are capable of breeding from September through February.Normally only two chicks will hatch from the three to four white eggs measuring 40mm x 22mm and usually only one chick will survive to fledge. The baby chick will reach adult size in 53 days and can be seen flying with both parents shortly thereafter, although its feathers are still rather dull compared to the adult's bright colors.The nest entrance is always against the wind and is situated from lm to lOm (3.3 - 33 ft.) above the ground with the average height being 6.4m (21 ft.). In live trees the entrance is of irregular shape; in dead trees the entrance is usually round measuring from lScm to 20cm (6 - 8 in.) in diameter. The nests range from 0.20m to l. lOm (1 in. - 3'h ft.) in depth. In one particular island community, the six existing nests were situated an average of 79m (260 ft.) apart. Artificial nesting in the wild has been attempted with no success; usually wild bees have taken over the artificial nests.These parrots are not easy to spot in the forest, making natural observation ve1y difficult. However, it is known that, depending on the time of year, they leave their resting area between 5:45 A.M. and 7:00 A.M. to feed and return between 5:00 P.M. and 6:30 P.M. During feeding, one of the flock "stands watch" for predators or strange circumstances and sounds an alarm call to signal the rest of the flock to fly away.Although they will eat flowers and leaves, the A. brasiliensis feeds primarily on fruits and prefers the fruit of the Guanandi tree. Since this tree is one of its main nesting sites and also provides the birds' main food source, the Guanandi is an important element in the survival of this species.Like most rare Amazons, this bird makes a wonderful pet; however, because of its rarity, any A. brasiliensis kept as pets should be placed in a qualified, avicultural breeding program immediately. In captivity, it can become a very good talker and likes a varied diet of seed mix, fruits and vegetables and, like most parrots, loves peanuts. In the excitement of feeding time it sounds much like a chicken.   </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1073</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 5 (1996): SEPT-OCT 1996; 24-25</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1073/1053</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
