<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1277</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">the Great Indian Hornbill a breeding attempt (Buceros bicomis)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">de Ruiter, Maarten</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he Great Indian Hornbill is one of the most impressive members of the hornbill family. There are two sub-species found in South and South-east Asia. The nominate form Buceros bicomis bicornis is found in West India, from the Himalayas to Indochina and Malaysia. The sub-species, Buceros bicornis cavastus is distributed in South-west India. This latter sub-species differs from the nominate race by its larger size. There are several differences between male and female. The iris of the male is red, while that of the female is white. Males are usually larger than females, particularly as to bill size.Although a number of breeding reports have been published (Bohmke, 1987, Choy, 1980, Golding and Williams, 1986, Healy, Preuss and Preuss, 1973, Robiller and Trochisch, 1989, Seisun and de Ruiter, 1989 and van der Sluis, 1983) breeding this species in captivity is still a rare event. Threats in the wild urge that a healthy captive population be established. There are already several established regional breeding programs in Europe and an international studbook exists for the species. This record system is maintained by Bruce Bohmke. The pair of birds maintained at Gettorf is registered in both the European and the International studbooks.ThreatsIn earlier days, catching Great Indian Hornbills for the animal trade was the greatest threat to the species. When the females were sealed in their cavity nests, they were victims for the local bird catchers. One may conclude that may also be one reason females outnumber males in captivity.Since 1992 the Great Indian Hornbill has been on the CITES Appendix I list. Although some birds are still taken from the wild illegally, the animal trade is no longer seen tobe a serious threat to the maintenance of the species. Far more alarming is the rapid destruction of tropical rain forests by logging. Destruction of the bird's natural environment will make it impossible for these birds (as well as many thousands of other animals and plant-species) to survive.Hornbills at GettorfLocated in the northernmost part of Germany is the Animals Park of Gettorf. This park has a large collection ofhornbills. It contains 11 species, four of which have made several breeding attempts. Only two of the breeding attempts were successful. The Trumpeter Hornbills Bycanistes bucinator have raised six young successfully, over a three year period.The Red-billed Hornbills Tockus erythrorhynchus raised two young in 1992 (de Ruiter 1993). The Wreathed Hornbills Aceros undulatus have made four breeding attempts. In each instance only one infertile egg was found (de Ruiter). The fourth species, the Great Indian Hornbill laid twice. One egg each time. The rest of the article will deal with this species.FeedingAs written in a previous article, things essential to successful breeding are: a harmonious pair, optimal housing, and the right nest box. The right food (diet) is also very important for successful breeding of hornbills. At Gettorf, most hornbill species (except the Ground Hornbills and the Redbilled Hornbills) are fed the same food (diet). Half of the food is made up of fruit. When possible the birds are fed at least five varieties of fruit each day. Seasonal availability of fruit is a major factor. Among fruits provided are: apples, bananas, pineapple, kiwis, melons (three different kinds), mangos, papayas, a variety of berries, cherries, tomatoes, cooked rice, cooked potatoes and soaked raisins. About a quarter of the diet is soaked dog-pellets (Peca Bello). The dog pellets are placed in water in the afternoon and are fed the following morning. The last quarter of the diet contains our own insectivorous mixture. Live food such as meal worms and crickets are fed occasionally, particularly when young are in the next. A vitamin powder (Vitazon) and a calcium powder (Vitakalk) are given on the food twice a week.HistoryWhen I arrived at Gettorf in 1989, one female was kept in the collection. It is a wild caught bird, which was brought to Germany in 1972. We know she is at least 21 years old. In 1989 we succeeded in obtaining a wild-caught male from another zoo. This bird was quarantined for six weeks and when we determined the bird was healthy he was placed in an aviary directly next to the female.The birds were separated from each other by wire-mesh. The male was quite arrogant, but the female immediately made some contact attempts. Within two days the female was observed trying to feed the male through the wire. After the birds had been next to each other for 10 days, we decided to open the door between the two enclosures and it was the female tried to make contact. The birds were under observation during the time together.At night the birds were returned to their own aviary space and the connecting door was closed. After 10 days, since there was no aggression demonstrated by the male, the door was left open day and night.In December 1989, four new breeding enclosures were built for the hornbills and the pair was moved to one of these. We installed a small pool, some living plants (which were destroyed by the birds within two months) and an enormous nest-hole. A small fence was placed at the rear. This blended with the heating pipes, which were provided for visitors comfort.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1277</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 2 (1998): MAR-APR 1998; 34-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1277/1256</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
