<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4025</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T18:21:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Ask the Vet - Feather Plucking</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">DVM, Stephen Fronefield,</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 2 (April/May 2024).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Question: Why does my bird pluck or damage his feathers? What can I do? Answer: When birds pluck and damage their feathers we lump this issue into what is called “feather damaging behavior ” (FDB). This is one of the most challenging conditions we see in veterinary medicine.The list of causes include degenerative changes (arthritis, atherosclerosis, etc), metabolic disease (kidney, liver, etc), neoplasia (tumors or cancer), infectious diseases (bacterial, fungal, parasitic, viral), nutritional issues (deficiencies, excesses, imbalances), inflammatory disease (allergy, irritant, etc), traumatic causes, toxic exposure, and behavioral issues (hormonal, non - hormonal, environmentally-driven)……to name a few possibilities. I give this list not to discourage you from seeking the cause and solution, but to set the expectation that often a definitive diagnosis is not readily forthcoming. Many birds have more than one of the elements listed above thatdrive them to damage their own feathers. Looking for medical causes involves veterinary assistance. Your avian veterinarian will ask you an array of questions to characterize the problem. This history taking exercise is critical to help in working toward a tentative diagnosis and creating a treatment plan. The veterinarian will also recommend that a series of test be performed. These commonly include fecal evaluation, blood work, x-rays and sometimes other special test are considered pending initial findings.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4025</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 2 (2024): Watchbird April/May 2024; 16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/4025/3985</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
