<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2439</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-12T14:48:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Hand-feeding Pigeons and Doves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Parrott-Holden, Jan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dave's note was emphatic. "I will not hand-feed a bird. That's uiby there are big birds - to feed the little birds, durnbiell!"I've saved that note for quite awhile, laughing over it each time I mix up a fresh supply of mash to hand-feed a nestling or two. True, Dave's words hold a grain of truth. I'm sure nature intended the big birds raise the little ones. And yet, you don't have to be in this hobby very long before you realize this is just another rule with many, many exceptions.Dave tells me his pigeons number in the hundreds. (Who keeps an exact count when your loft reaches that size?) Me, I keep anywhere from 30-60 birds, depending upon the time of year. A lot of my birds are practically pets, riding upon my shoulder as I clean out nest boxes and replenish feed and water. We share a close association, leaving few surprises. Indeed, only upon one occasion did J find a bird whose lineage had me baffled. In short, if the big ones muffed their parental duties J always seemed to know about it.Now some breeders won't pinch-hit under any circumstances. I don't condemn their view, just prefer mine. An unattended squab elicits more sympathy from me than a dozen squalling infants in a hospital. And I've found the display of gratitude from a rescued bird to be far more satisfying than that of a human child. Eccentric? I suppose. But those of you who've reared one bird or another will certainly corroborate my testimony. Won't you?Let's say you haven't hand-raised anything. If you have an urge to try, there's really no better place to begin than with a pigeon or dove. Though there is no monetary advantage to possessing a hand-raised pigeon like there is with exotic caged-birds, you 'II find that there are some rewards worth noting. First, you 'll not have to chase your bird after it has been reared. (There's nothing more aggravating than having a wild bird in your loft.) In addition, you'll probably find that your hand-fed bird will turn into a calm and attentive parent. Since it trusts you, you won't be denied the privilege of handling and checking progress in the nest box. Finally, as a learning experience, hand-feeding pigeons and doves is far easier than attempting the same task with young finches, parakeets or canaries. By the time you 've taken a four-day-old squab to the "squeaker" stage you will feel so good about your wet-nurse skills that you'll be ready for greater avian challenges.Let's suppose you have a baby pigeon to feed. You may have found it in your own loft or, like the good Samaritan, discovered a stranded feral tossed from its nest.What's the first thing you do? Well, if it happens to be very young (no pin feathers) you will have to get it indoors immediately. l have kept four and five day old squabs in a brooder at about 90° until they sprouted pinfeathers. After that time period a room temperature of 70° should suffice. Warmth is not the biggest problem. Nourishment is really the stickler. You musn't throw in the towel because you haven't a beak. A trip to your local pharmacy or a good department store should take care of locating the necessary tools for feeding a young bird. A pigeon or dove from about four days of age can be fed easily through a medicine syringe, like the type used in dispensing medications to children and invalids. You will want to locate some Yi'' rubber tubing (the type used by fishermen to secure weights to their line). Purchase several inches, it's inexpensive and fits snugly on the tip of the syringe. While some recommend aquarium hose as a substitute, I don't advocate its use. Not only is it stiff, but inserted improperly, it could seriously injure the bird. As an added precaution, I suggest a tiny drop of magic glue to reinforce the bond between the tube and syringe tip. Nothing is more frustrating than having the hose fly off into the bird's crop along with the mash. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2439</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 13 No. 3 (1986): JUNE-JULY 1986; 58-64</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2439/2412</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
