<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/700</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Zebra Finches</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reynolds, Jean</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Native to Australia, the Zebra Finchis one of the most commonly heldcage birds among exotic finchesbecause it is one of the easiest birds tohouse and feed and is ideal for thebeginning bird keeper.Once you have decided to keepZebra Finches, you need to select perfectspecimens. Choose birds from areliable breeder and observe if yourbirds are alert, lively, sleek featheredand plump.Whether you choose one ZebraFinch, or a pair, you will want todetermine the sex of your birds. ZebraFinches are sexually dimorphic; that is,males and females look differentlyfrom one another in all the color varietiesexcept the white mutation. Evenwhites can usually be sexed by themale's redder beak.Male zebras are easily distinguishedfrom females by their distinctiveorange-red ear spots, while thefemale's head is plain gray. Both maleand female are silver gray with blackand white crossbarring on the tail,hence their name "zebra". In raisingZebra Finches many mutations willoccur - black and white mixtures, even gray or fawn colors.Zebra Finches will breed inside thehouse in flight cages that are at leastthree feet long. They like to bLJild theirnests in wooden finch boxes or rattanbaskets and need soft, dry grass, mossand bits of yarn or string for nestbuilding. They find lint from theclothes dryer very acceptable nestingmaterial. Your cages should not havewire flooring because finches like toeat off the floor. Do not place cages indrafts or direct sunshine.If you decide on an outside aviary,you may want to build your own.Modular welded wire with a squaresteel post framework can be used foryour bird house. These modular unitscan be easily and quickly constructed.You may want to consider buildingyour bird house using plywood andwire. We have two such avaries in ourback patio, each is four feet square byeight feet high. They are constructedof four by eight sheets of quarter-inchplywood for sides and sloping roofand half-inch plywood for the floor.Before construction began, all woodenmaterials were given two coats ofwhite paint.We used non-toxic half-inch weldedwire, a few two by fours split to twoby twos, a little roofing paper, clearplastic sheeting for a fold-down windowcover, and with a handful of nailsand hinges we made a suitable outsidehome for our Zebras. Leaveplenty of window openings coveredwith wire with fold-down frames coveredwith plastic sheeting. This plasticpanel can be hinged and raised atnight for protection from cold, windsand cats. Perches were made of varioussized branches from our mockmulberry tree.The bird house should face south orsoutheast if at all possible, and someshade should be provided: Our birdhouse can be easily moved; simplynail a two by four on each side atabout hand height and four men caneasily pick it up and move it to a newlocation. This is particularly advantageousif you live on rented propertyand wish to move.Should you want a second four-footsquare bird house, reverse your floorplan, set the houses side by side leavinga small safety area between thehouses with the food and "people"door inside the safety area. Add a roofand a few shelves for food storage andyou will have a very practical and usefulbird house.My Zebras feed on finch seed, spraymillet, boiled egg, cuttle bone, andcooked grains. I cook cracked corn (3parts), milo (1 part) and reel wheat (1part) in my crock pot overnight. Nextclay the food is rinsed, put in plasticcontainers and refrigerated. I feedone-fourth cup of cooked food perclay, or only as much as they clean up.Each clay they are feel a sprig of celery,chopped apple, orange or any otherfruit they will eat. In aclclition, they areoffered a small bowl of Petamine.During breeding season they are feelsmall mealworms.Zebras lay four to six white eggs atdaily intervals. The incubation periodis about 14 clays with the female sittingon the eggs at night. After hatching,both parents feed the young. Thebabies leave the nest at about three tofour weeks of age.A vail yourself of the many finebooks and periodicals regardingfinches. Join a bird club, listen to lectureson birds and talk with experiencedfinch breeders.Finches can be ideal pets. Enjoythem.•</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/700</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 14</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/700/683</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
