<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/849</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Prepared for the 1994 CITES CONVENTION</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">C onservation and aviculture: do thesetwo words even belong together in asentence? For most of its history, avicultureconnoted, at best, the breeding ofbirds for profit. At its worst, avi.culture isassociated with poor breeding practices(such as inbreeding), instances of poorhusbandry and abusive conditions, andthe capture of wild birds, either forbreeding or for sale. In orne instances,bird collectors have even hindered conervationefforts. When pleas went outfor the 26 collectors who are believed toown Spix's Macaws to donate or lendtheir birds for breeding, many refusedto admit they owned the birds. Otherssimply refused.1 As none are held byzoos and they are probably extinct in thewild, it may be impos ible to begin acaptive breeding program (Frank, 1992) .o wonder conservationi ts had littlegood to say about the pet bird industry.Today, pet bird ownership is on therise. With this increase has come anincreasing awareness of conservation onthe part of bird breeders, sellers andowners. Through publications reachingover 200,000 readers, organizations suchas the American Federation of Aviculture(AFA) have steadily focused attention onconservation is ue such as the status ofvarious wild populations, habitat loss,and the need to prevent the trade of wildcaughtbirds (Clubb, S. 1992). One popularmagazine, Bird Talk, carried no articlesabout conservation during its firstthree years of publication (88-90). Sincethen, partially in response to reader demand,the magazine regularly featuresarticles about endangered species.2 TheAFA al o assists conservation efforts directlyby di tributing surveys to memberat conferences (Allen and Johnson1992) and in its Watchbird magazine.For example, the October/November1993 issue carried a survey from theAmerican Zoological and Aquarium AssoCiatton(AZA) Passerine Taxon AdvioryGroup about the owner hip andbreeding of passerines. The AFA conventionsfeature leading conservationistssuch as Don Merton. He gave twotalks at the 1993 meeting the first onthe application of avicultural techniquesto save the Black Robin, the other onefforts to save the Kakapo. Ulysses Sealspoke at this year 's InternationalAviculturalist~ ociety meeting, as didRosemary Low and Dr. Carlos Yamashita,of the Brazilian Ornithological Society.The AFA has al o made direct financialcontributions to conservation of the BaliMynah, Bahama Parrot and other birdspecies through its Conservation SmallGrants Fund.Concern is developing into action. Thispaper examines two formal programfor bird conservation involving privateaviculturalists, along with orne of theinfgrmal and indirect contributions ofprivate aviculture to conservation breedingefforts.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/849</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 6 (1994): NOV-DEC 1994; between 32 &amp; 33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/849/831</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
