<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/827</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T17:48:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA in action ...   NEWS and VIEWS</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">n/a, n/a</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Orange County Bird Breeders Strong AFA Supporter On Saturday, 11, '94,' Aletta M. Long, southern California regional vice president, was asked to attend the Orange County Bird Breeders' annual fund raiser and picnic. OCBB President Donna Reynolds had a special donation of $1,000 to present to Aletta for AFA Small Grants programs. The OCBB had worked all year selling raffle tickets for a much desired bird. The winner was delighted, and so are much appreciated AFA Small Grant programs. This is not the first time this club has rallied to AFA support. This is the kind of dedication that enables AFA to continue its very important work.e AIM Established to Improve A viculture Avian Information Management (AIM) was established to provide a stable system for improving aviculture. There are many volunteer organizations that have done much for aviculture but, because of burn-out and other problems associated with volunteer organizations, their service to the avian community can be inefficient and inconsistent. AIM supports these organizations by performing services that are often duplicated by others and giving them the best possible access to publicity opportunities. AIM has three major goals: Education (only through education can we solve many of aviculture.'s problems), Responsibility (only through responsible avian management will these birds be available for future generations to enjoy) and Service (AIM must provide good service to its customers and clients just like any other business to survive). AIM's vehicle for providing its many services to manufacturers, distributors, pet and feed stores, breeders, clubs, exhibitors, pet owners, researchers, veterinarians and other aviculturists is through the Bird Bank News (BBN), the only newspaper devoted exclusively to captive birds. BBN keeps subscribers informed about AIM services, prints timely news items, lists events and has a classified ad section for breeders organized by species. Subscriptions are $16 for 12 monthly issues and BBN has some fund-raising opportunities for you, your club or bird program of your choice. For more information write or call Ron McMurtry, manager, AIM, 1115 Fern Ave., Felton, CA 95018-9515, phone (800) 246-5577.• The ultimate fate of animals and plants on our planet rests with the attitudes and values of those humans who share their environments. The old saying, "we will save what we know, we know what we are taught" should not be taken lightly when designing comprehensive conservation strategies. · It should not be surprising that most successful field-based conservation efforts involving birds have a strong educational component. Unfortunately, scientists often feel ill equipped to deal with these aspects due to their lack of training in elementary and secondary education. Recall, however, that all is often lost if the people do not value the resource. Incorporating an educational element into the parrot conservation strategy called PROYECTO LORO has not been easy. Funds are difficult to locate for educational purposes. Additionally, educational materials have to be developed specifically for the region and topic. With some limited financial support from the World Nature Association, British Council and the World Wildlife Fund, a pilot program has been developed targeting 10 villages (ejidoes) in northeastern Mexico. The villages are all within the known range of the Yellow-headed Amazon Amazona oratrix and the Green-cheeked Amazon Amazona viridigenalis, both IUCN/ICBP Red Data Book listed species. Due to the popularity of these birds as pets and their close proximity to the U.S. border, smuggling is a major factor in the species' decline. To address th.is issue, a coloring book was produced titled, •'Los Loros y Su Mundo" translated as parrots and their world. The book is based on an ecosystem approach depicting "the various kinds of parrots," "Animals that also nest in tree cavities," ''animals with the same diet as parrots," "predators of parrots" and the "habitats of parrots." Included also is a "connect the dots," "follow the parrot to its nest" and parrot crossword puzzle. In addition to the coloring book, which includes a short text with each drawing, is a giant 3' x 4' coloring poster drafted from the coloring book's drawings. Augmented with a video on Proyecto Loro, the materials will be presented this summer. While we are certain the effort will be a big hit, a great need exists to take it to additional villages. Bird clubs wishing to "adopt" a village and provide the materials are encouraged to do so and contact Proyecto Loro by writing 218 Conway Drive, San Antonio, Texas 78209. For your tax deductible donation, a slide set, taken at "your" village, and a short commentary will be provided so your club members can see first hand the difference their involvement has made in conserving parrots in the wild.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/827</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 21 No. 4 (1994): JUL-AUG 1994; 48-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/827/809</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
