<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/486</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Feathers and Bones</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hobbs, Bobbi</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Death is an issue that all aviculturistsencounter, particularly duringbreeding season. We agonize overchicks who die in the egg or shortlyafter hatching, and death among adolescentor adult birds. At times , anecropsy is performed to determinethe exact cause of death , other timesnot.For the atural HistOry Museum ,their work begins with death .Recently I had the privilege of meetingwith Steve Gustafson, curatorialassistant of San Diego's atural HistoryMuseum , Department of Birdsand Mammals. According tO Stevenatural history museums are alwaysinterested in obtaining donations ofall types of birds. For the ornithologist,vast amounts of knowledge maybe gained through the examination ofa bird 's corpse. It is through the donationof birds that they can Learn anddocument characteristic of a species,what role they played in survival andhow the e species currently relate toother species.External examination providesinformation on plumage, color patterns,body measurements, moltingpattern , and other specific detailsunique to that pecies. However, thecrux of the study is that which cannotbe seen in life ; the skeletalmakeup of the species. To the cientist, the skeletOn provides some of themost valuable information . Eachbone is measured and examined toextract the most minute details possible.With this knowledge, a scientistcan identify and classify a speciesand , if needed , reconstruct thespecies. In addition, the scienti t cannow determine the similarities ordifferences between various speciesof birds.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/486</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 20-21</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/486/471</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
