<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3776</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-20T02:49:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bird Illustration In The 19th Century</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abbott, Susan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The 19th century was an exciting time for bird illustration. The vast number of expeditions within the United States and around the world enabled ornithologists, naturalists and artists to identify, study, draw and research species across Continents. This article will provide a brief overview of artists who spearheaded bird illustration in the United States and those who contributed to making London the center of the finely illustrated bird book publishing industry in the 19th century. Scottish born poet and naturalist, Alexander Wilson (1766- 1833) became a teacher in Pennsylvania in 1794 and met famous naturalist William Bartram who encouraged Wilson’s interest in ornithology and painting. Bartram’s encouragement assisted Wilson from 1803 through 1813 to create a nine- volume series entitled American Ornithology. This series was not only the first major scientific publication focusing on American birds in the United States but also the first to provide hand-colored engravings. As a result, Alexander Wilson is widely known as the Father of American Ornithology. To observe birds and also obtain subscriptions for his planned work, Publisher Samuel Bradford of Philadelphia provided Wilson with the first printed volume to show prospective buyers with a goal of 200 subscribers at $120 for the series. Wilson returned with 250 subscribers among them were Thomas Jefferson and James Madison. He also returned with specimens to be used in later volumes. By 1811 Wilson had nearly doubled the number of subscribers. As another way to reduce cost, Wilson frequently included multiple species on one plate. For 10 years Wilson traveled more than 12,000 miles in 15 of the 18 states as well as the Tennessee, Mississippi and Louisiana territories. He described 264 species and added 48 species using the Linnaean species classification system. During that time he also hired and supervised colorists, familiarized himself with the scientific literature of each species, produced pictures of each bird and composed descriptions. He died of dysentery at the age of 47 and his final volume was completed after his death and published by George Ord, an American naturalist, ornithologist and writer. Wilson later had several species of birds...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-04-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3776</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 43 No. 3 &amp; 4 (2016): Special Double Issue; 17-23</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3776/3751</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
