<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2128</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-01-07T19:10:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Practical Suggestions For Beginners: Preparations For The Show</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bucci, Toni</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">My last article ended with the suggestion to place your choice and potential exhibition canaries in individual cages. Individual cages offer protection from plucking that sometimes causes unrepairable damage. For example, when a plucked tail feather grows back, it is longer than the original feathers. A Norwich or Gloster canary is more desirable with a short tail. The difference in length between the original and the new feathers is very small; but this small dif-ference may offset the delicate balance of aesthetic value. These canaries are judged for their conformation.Yorkshires or frilled canaries, on the other hand, could benefit from a longer tail. However, other unrepairable damage could result, such that the new tail may be open or flared ("fish tail"). This feature is not desirable in any breed.Now that we have established the definite advantage of a single cage, let's move on to other show prerequisites.The next show prerequisite is training.Training canaries priot to the show is not the same as that of training tigers and lions. We don't crack a whip and shout! To train canaries is to get them used to the show cage and people handling them during the show.The first step was already accomplished by getting them used to isolation and a small cage. The second step is to have them accept the show cage. The canaries that require this training the most are Borders, Yorkshires, and Frills. For these breeds, an all-wire show cage is used.Until this time, my choice canaries are housed in single, box-type breeding cages. To train Borders, Yorks, and frills, their respective show cage is hung in front of their housing cage (Fig. lA and lB). The doors on the housing cage and the show cage must be open to allow the canary to enter freely in and out at his own will. Once the canary gains confidence and finds the show cage to be another comfortable place, it will spend more and more time enjoying the view offered from the show cage.When the canary is totally familiar with the show cage, we can close the doors and move the cage to another location. This move will offer a new experience and should be repeated by placing the cage in alternate locations. Always return the show cage to the housing cage, leaving the doors open to give the canary a chance to go back to more comfortable quarters. The above procedure should be repeated as often as. .your nrne permits.The show cage used to train canaries may become soiled. Another clean show cage should be used for the final show.For canaries other than Borders, Yorks, and frills, a wooden show cage is used (Fig. 2). The internal environment of the wooden show cage is very similar to that of the box-type breeding cage. The size is the major difference. The similarity of the cages makes training almost unnecessary.One very important point I wish to stress concerns the water drinker. Most show cages require the outboard drinker. Birds that are not trained to this type of drinker will not find the water when placed in the show cage. Some training is also required for the bird to find the water. A small piece of lettuce or other greens placed in the drinker will entice the bird to reach for it, and at the same time, it will find water. I personally place a great deal of attention on this part of training. I have seen dead birds in show cages, obviously dead because of dehydration.Food is not a problem because seeds are placed on the floor of the show cage. Place at least 1/i inch deep of seeds on the bottom of the cage. Traditionally, a canary I rape mixture was mandatory. In the last few years, seed mixtures with colored seeds have been used progressively more and more, and are accepted at the shows.If your birds are used to a certain seed mixture, it should be continued during the show. A change in its diet may stress the bird and prevent it from showing at its best.For several reasons, a show canary should be closed-banded. However, an unbanded canary can be entered in a show. An unbanded canary must be entered as an old bird. In most cases, the band is the only evidence of its age. Also, a traceable closed band which was purchased from a legitimate club gives evidence of who the breeder of that particular canary is. To receive top awards, many clubs require definite proof that· the person receiving the award has bred the bird himself.One thing that I have neglected to suggest is that during the training period, birds should be sprayed with a fine mist of water at least once a day. Spraying the birds encourages preening. Preening is basically the birds' way of grooming themselves, resulting in a tightening up of the feathers and a clean-look.Two or three days before the show, clip the birds' toenails, and trim the beak, if necessary.You are now ready to exhibit your canary' I hope you win the largest trophy offered at the show' •  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-01-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2128</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 9 No. 5 (1982): OCT-NOV 1982; 30-33</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2128/2099</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
