<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/637</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-01-19T21:20:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Genus Barnardius</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schulenburg, Wayne A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Taxonomists have argued for yearsover the proper placement of thisAustralian group of birds. Some havepreferred to place them with theRosella (Platycercus) and some havedecided to isolate them into a separategenus (Barnardius). So, for thepresent, we will refer to them as theBarnardius group.There are two species in the Barnardiusgroup, the Barnard Parakeetor, as the Australians refer to them,the Mallee Ringneck Parakeet (Barnardiusb. barnardi). This specieshas three subspecies, but only one ofthem has become focused on as anavicuitural subject in the past fewyears, the Cloncurry Parakeet (Barnardiusb. macgillivrayi).The second species is the Port LincolnParakeet (Barnardius z. zonarius)which has two subspecies ofwhich only one is being kept as anavicultural subject, the Twenty-eightParakeet (Barnardius z. semitorguatus).This particular subspecies isthe largest of the group, has the widestrange and occurs in the mostdiverse of habitats.As a group, Barnardius are excellentavicultural sllt&amp;gt;jects, much likethe Rosellas in dietary requirements,space requirements and nestingbehaviors. In captivity, the group hasa great tendency for becoming overweight.As a precaution, sunflowerseed should be limited or eliminatedaltogether. A good cockatiel mixworks very well, given with largequantities of green food such as spinach,New Zealand spinach, kale orromaine lettuce. Fruits and vegetablessuch as apple, pear, cherries,carrot, sweet potatoes, celery, cornon the cob and berries such as Pyracanthaare relished.Like the Rosellas, the Barnardiusgroup can be readily appreciated ingood size enclosures, somewhere inthe neighborhood of four feet by 12feet by eight feet. With flights shelteredon one end and protected fromthe wind, this group tolerates thecold very well and can handle downto 25°F for short periods with no illeffects.Generally, the breeding seasonbegins in June and lasts throughDecember, which is the Australianspring and beginning of summer.While this is winter in the U.S., theclimate reverse does not seem todeter the group at all. Nest boxesprovided should be 14" x 24" x 14".Clutch sizes vary from three to fiveeggs and if a pair has started earlyenough they will often doubleclutch.The Barnard Parakeet occurs inNorthern Queensland and across theinterior of New South Wales throughto the interior of South Australia. Theadult males' crown and nape are abright green bordered by a red frontalband and bluish cheek patches.There is a brownish V-shaped bandextending from the eyes through theback of the head which meets a narrowyellow collar encircling the backof the neck. The underparts are a turquoisegreen with an orange-yellowabdominal band, which is often irregular.The back and mantel are deepbluish-black and the shoulders areyellow. The secondaries are green asare the rump and upper-tail coverts.Hens are slightly duller than themales and are slightly smaller. Averagesize for this species is around13-1/2 inches.The Cloncurry Parakeet is perhapsthe most beautiful of the group. Thegeneral coloring is a pale turquoisegreen.There is no red frontal band.The lower parts of the ear coverts area bright pale blue merging into a pastelbluish-green on the sides of thehead, with a very wide uniform bandof pale yellow. Again the hens areslightly smaller, but look identical tothe males in coloration. This subspeciesoccurs in Queensland only.As with many of the species of parrotsthat come from Australia, maleswill often come into breeding conditionprior to females. It is wise to trimthe adult males' first three primarieson each wing, if they begin to showaggressive behavior towards thehens, such as driving them to thenest box or not allowing them toleave the nest box to feed. Oftenbehaviors such as this will accumulateto the point, if left unchecked, ofthe hen losing her upper mandible.The head, nape and upper earcoverts of the Port Lincoln Parakeetare dull black. There is a red frontalband in most, but it is not alwayspresent. There is a yellow collar onthe neck and the back and the wingsare a brilliant green. The yellowchanges to a yellowish-green on theunderside of the tail coverts and thevent as well as the under wingcoverts are a bright blue. Again thehen is identical in coloring to themale, however, she is slightlysmaller.The Ports, as they are affectionatelycalled, have the largest range of thegenus. They are found throughoutsouthern, central and western Australia,as well as ranging into the northernterritory. This is probably themost adaptable species occurring in avariety of habitats throughout morethan one-third of the coastal Eucalyptusforest of the southwest and in thewheat-belt or western Australia.The Twenty-eight Parakeet isentirely green, with a pronouncedcrimson frontal band. While thefemale is similar, her coloration isslightly duller. This is the largest ofthe group, being 15-1/2 to 16 inches.It is best not to house pairs adjacentto each other since they can beargumentative to the point of that isall they will do.One caution with Ports andTwenty-eights is that they easilyhybridize. While it is difficult to spota hybrid, you will see a hefty birdwith a broken yellow abdominalpatch where as in true Ports theyellow should remain solid. In trueTwenty-eights there should be noyellow at all.The Europeans are now reportingmutations in Port Lincolns andTwenty-eights which are showing upwith blue, yellow and cinnamon. Sofar there have been no reports ofmutations of Barnards or Cloncurrys.As the limitations of our ability toprocure birds seems to be imminent,it is essential for aviculturists toensure the safety and well-being ofthe species we have been able toestablish. The Barnardius group isnot there yet and it is imperative thatwe make it so!</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/637</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 1 (1993): FEB-MARCH 1993; 56-57</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/637/620</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
