<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3670</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-26T05:20:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Remembering Elke Hanna</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">fuAmember and supporter, Elke Hanna, (6/29/57-5/23/14) passed away unexpectedly from a major cardiac infection. Elke was a loving wife, treasured mother, adored grandmother, true friend and dedicated bird pet owner, breeder and adoption/ re-homer. Elke was born in Germany and moved to the United States in 1997. As with most breeders, Elke's passion for birds started by her love of her own pets, Bingo (Timneh grey), Rocky (Congo African grey), Mr. Suzie (White-bellied caique) and Sunny (Sun conure). Elke started breeding birds in 2004 with a pair of parrodets. Eventually she was successful breeding over 16 different species of parrots. She probably was most wellknown for breeding Queen of Bavaria conures and for creating enchanting video clips of her pet Queens that she adored with all her heart.Birds were Elke's passion. She was a Fundamentals of Aviculture I aviculturist and loyal member of the American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. She was also involved with the Central New York Bird Breeders, the Golden Conure Association and World Parrot Trust.Elke was a passionate writer as well (with the help of a translator). Her work was accepted and set to be published in the U.K. in the book, The Secret Life of the Golden Conures. The proceeds of the book will go to the World Parrot Trust and be placed in the Golden Conure Survival Fund for conservation, preservation and further research of the species. There will be a special tribute to Elke shown on the back of the book.Elke is survived by her husband, children and grandchildren. Elke's husband, Tony, expressed thanks and gratitude for the outpouring of support from friends and family. Tony also shared that he is happy that he has their beloved pet parrots with him and that through their mimicry and comedic antics, a part of Elke is with him every day. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3670</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 3 (2014): Number 3 2014; 7</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3670/3653</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
