<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1344</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-28T18:24:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Sick House Syndrome: Is Your Home Safe for Parrots?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Swicegood, Carolyn</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Do you and your parrots live in a safe environment? Indoor air, according to the Environmental Protection Agency, is our worst pollution problem. Research tells us that whatever the quality of outside air, it nearly always is worse indoors, where we spend ninety percent of our time and where many of our parrots spend all of their time. A Massachusetts Special Legislative Commission has concluded that indoor air pollution accounts for fifty percent of all human illness in the United States. In one study, twentyfour percent of the people complaining of the Au actually were suffering from carbon monoxide poisoning.Some homes, usually those 20 years or older, were constructed of materials now known to be dangerous. Most homes have a problem with toxins emanating from carpets, cabinets, draperies, and many other sources. Outgassing refers to the fumes that a substance gives off, as it ages or degrades. Outgassing is responsible for the "new home" smell that sometimes causes stinging, watery eyes. Signs of a sick house include a musty, stuffy smell and other unusual and noticeable odors. Feeling noticeably better outside the home also can indicate an indoor pollution problem.Airtight buildings block out nature's ability to clean the air. Before the energy crisis of the 1970s most houses were not especially energy efficient. Small openings in their structure were left unsealed, so fresh air passed freely through them, diluting and carrying away toxins. The oil crisis spawned the development of airtight houses in an effort to make them more energy efficient.Parrots are exquisitely sensitive to toxins, especially those in the air that they breathe. We all remember the stories of canaries being taken into coal mines as sentinels to warn of the accumulation of deadly gases.just as the death of the canaries inthe coal mines warned of dangerous toxins in the air, the respiratory system of birds is so much more sensitive than ours that they are harmed by unsafe indoor air long before we become aware of the danger.Parrots have been described as "magnificent athletes." They are capable of flying long distances, so their respiratory systems are extremely efficient. While humans breathe at the rate of 12 to 16 breaths per minute, large parrots take 25 to 40 breaths per minute. Therefore it is not surprising that polluted air rapidly takes its toll on their health. Respiratory problems are one of the most common ailments in pet birds and any problem that interferes with breathing must be regarded as potentially life threatening.Humans breathe in about 50 pounds of air every day. We are as much what we breathe as what we eat. People who live in "sick homes" often suffer from a variety of health problems including allergies, asthma, sinus conditions, respiratory problems, chemical sensitivity, pneurnonitis, cancer, chronic fatigue, and aspergillosis. Could sick house syndrome account for the many mysterious cases of aspergillosis in parrots today?AspergillosisOwners of birds kept indoors often are shocked when they hear the aspergillosis diagnosis because they considered it a disease of parrots living in outdoor aviaries or in crowded warehouse conditions. This deadly and all too prevalent infection frequently is found in birds living in clean, air-conditioned homes where damp conditions have allowed the growth and dispersal of invisible fungal spores. Aspergillus mold can be found growing on the surfaces and walls of bathrooms and on the ceilings of homes with roof leaks. Many parrots that self-mutilate and destroy their feathers 1~1ay silently be fighting off subtle but health-damaging fungal infections caused by contaminated indoor air. Aspergillosis is a most dif- ficult disease to treat. Even with antifungal medicines, months of therapy are required, with no guarantee of survival, so prevention is of paramount importance.Sinus ProblemsNot surprisingly, sinus problems in parrots have become increasingly common, just as they have in humans.Dust from air conditioning and heat ducts, as well as from moldy basements, often is circulated throughout the house. Until recently, ducts in most buildings were never cleaned. Most homeowners never have their duct system cleaned.In warm, humid climates where many parrots are kept, sick house problems also can worsen during summer months when the outside air is humid. Most air conditioning units contain mold-contaminated components such as insulation and blowers. Ventilation which brings in humid outside air may increase mildew and other moisturerelated problems when the air-conditioner does not sufficiently dehumidify the air. In most cases, the ideal relativehumidity range is between 37 and 55 percent. New homes are insulated and sealed so well that moisture builds up and cannot escape, creating a much higher than ideal humidity level and perfect breeding conditions for the growth of a variety of molds.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1344</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 4 (1999): JULY-AUG 1999; 23-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1344/1322</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
