<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/705</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:31:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding of the Blue-rumped Parrot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harris, Robbie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Psittinus cyanurus, is commonlyknown here in the U.S. as theBlue-rumped Parrot or MalaysianBlue-rumped Parrot. They are alsoreferred to in some books by thenames of Little or Rainbow Parrot. TheBlue-rumped is a small type of parrot,similar in size to the Peach-facedLovebird. The adult plumage of thesebirds is very striking, especially in themales. Like the Eclectus Parrots, malesand female are colored quite differentlyfrom each other. The male has ablue head, with a dark blue color onthe lower back and rump. The wingsare green with each feather edged in alight yellowish color. A small maroonpatch is on the upper wing coverts.The flanks and under the wings arered, The upper mandible is bright red,with tl1e lower brownish. The iris is ayellowish-white. Feet and legs aregrayish. The males have more of ablue wash over their body, where thefemales' color is slightly yellowishgreen.The female has some of the samecharacteristics in color as the male,such as the yellow feather edging, redunder the wings, feet color and iriscolor. My hen has a solid dark brownhead. As young birds feather intoadult plumage, they will either start to"blue up" in the head feathers or gobrown. As my domestically raisedbirds approached a year old they losttheir baby coloring and have a soliddark brown head, just like theirmother. The Blue-rumped Parrots are distributedfrom south-western Thailandand southern Burma, through Malaysiato Borneo and Sumatra, Indonesia.They inhabit forested areas feeding onfruits, seeds and blossoms. I've beentold that where these birds nest is ve1ywarm. The temperature stays at about95° with the humidity about 90% dayand night.Many years back, I purchased someBlue-rumped parrots from an imp01terwho brought a small number of thesebirds into the U.S. They were youngbirds, not yet in their full adult plumage.Visual sexing did not work wellon these birds. I had some surgicallysexed to find that one of the "hens"with somewhat of a brown head was ayoung male. It took almost a year forthe Blue-rumpeds to color into theirfull splendor. After years of intensework and study of these birds, beautifulhealthy chicks were finally produced.I successfully reared twoyoungsters to weaning. When I saythe word "work" with these birds, I domean it.Lots of close work and observationwent into breeding these birds. Hereis how it all went ... Success and truepairing just was not happening. I triedto observe them close up and fromafar. But the birds would just usuallysit motionless, not doing much. Avideo camera is what told the realstory on these birds. After muchobservation, studying tapes of theBlue-rumpeds and changing mates around, a true pair did finally form. Inow had a pair that was truly compatible.Now it was just a matter ofpatience and time, along with makingsure this pair was completely happyand at ease with their surroundings.The pair was set up outdoors in awire cage, no added heat or cooling (Ilive in Southern California in an areawhere the weather usually does notdrop below 40°F). The cage measured36" wide, 33" tall and 23" deep. Awooden nest box measuring 9" x 10"by 14" deep having a 3" in diameterhole was offered to the pair. The nestbox was lined in a dark cork, whichwas adhered to the inside with nontoxicglue. To the bottom of the nestbox three inches of pine shavings wasadded to use as a base. I now use thecork lining for many types of birdswith great success.As a safety precaution their cage isinside a large wire enclosure. Thiswire building has many pairs of birdsset up in individual cages for breeding.They do not seem to be botheredby their close neighbors of differentspecies, and the neighbors do notmind the Blue-rum peds either. Next tothe Blue-rumped Parrot's cage arePhilippine Blue-naped Parrots. SpectacledAmazons, Timneh Gray Parrotsand Plum-crowned and WhitecrownedPionus (all of which arebreeding).The diet I provide for the Bluerumpedsis very similar to the diet Ioffer to most of my other parrots. Theyhave available to them at all times avariety of dry seeds consisting ofmedium size gray sunflower seed, safflowerseed and a parakeet mix containing42% canary seed. Along withthe chy seeds the pair is given daily abowl of fresh cut up fruits, vegetablesand greens. Corn on the cob and cranberriesare their favorite foods whichare always the first to be eaten. I find itamazing that two little birds canquickly devour an entire ear of cornand seem to be waiting for more.In early spring, the male courts thehen into breeding with his melodioussinging.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/705</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 5 (1993): OCT-NOV 1993; 23-26</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/705/688</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
