<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2974</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-14T09:52:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AFA Visits a Member; .Iola Bays</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jennings, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Long a popular bird and the most domesticated of Psittacines, the Budgerigar is a perennial favorite among pet lovers and bird breeders alike.One of the more successful Budgie fanciers and a favorite personality at local bird clubs is this month's A.F.A. member under the spotlight, Iola Bays. Iola is a native of Washington state, where she grew up in a family of four brothers and a sister on a farm near Grandview.In her late teens Iola forsook the rigors of farm life for a husband and family in Seattle. Her family moved south to sunny southern California in 1955. It was about that time Iola received her first Budgie. Not long after she was smitten by the avicultural bug.In 1960 her collection of Budgies had grown to an extent necessitating the purchase of her present home in Temple City. There would now be sufficient room for a few aviaries and it is there that Iola has steadily built her reputation as a fine breeder of English Budgies (her exclusive interest) and a winner on the show bench.Iola has specialized in the Violet Budgie and is nationally recognized for her contributions in improving their size. In fact, national show judge Crawford Maddox once commented that Iola's Violets were an example of the great strides being made with that variety.Iola competes annually in a number of bird shows, winning a considerable assortment of trophies. The glint of gold and silver in her trophy room is impressive.Success on the show bench, Tola feels, depends on careful observation and hard work in the breeding room. She is an avid student of genetics and a sound nutritionist - factors that have produced quality birds.Cafeteria style is the method of feeding at Iola's, The diet consists of Parrakeet Mix, oat groats, and during breeding season a mix of "four grain cereal", alfalfa, sea kelp, and Petamine. The birds are also routinely fed greens including Spinach and Swiss Chard. Grit, Mineral Block, and Avitron Vitamins round out the program. Young birds are offered small sunflower seeds, which they delight in chewing up.Breeding season begins with nestboxes in place around Thanksgiving. Shortly after Christmas the first birds hatch. The birds are control bred in individual breeding cages and later flighted in spacious aviaties. All the young are banded before the age of ten days (a California legal requirement).lo!a maintains membership in a number of Budgie clubs including the American Budgerigar Society. Great Western Budgerigar Society, San Gabriel Valley Parrakeet Association, Washington Budgerigar Society, and Chapter No. 4 of the Bird Association of California, of which she is currently Treasurer. Iola has been generous enough to have had a room added on to her garage in order that B.A.C. Chapter 4 may have a regular place to meet. Now, that is dedicated service!Iola joined the American Federation of Aviculture during the organization's infancy in early 1974. She has been a stead fast supporter of A .F .A. goals and a loyal friend of a vi culture. It is her spirit and enthusiasm that make it a pleasure to be an aviculturist , </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2974</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 5 No. 4 (1978): AUG-SEPT 1978; 34-35</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2974/2958</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
