<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1767</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-25T16:00:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">News Release</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shepard, Gail</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Shawnee, Kan. ZuPreem introducesAvianBreeder™ Diets in new large-size 40 lb. bags. AvianBreeder Diets come in two formulas: FruitBlend™ Flavor and Natural with a variety of nugget sizes for different species. Also new is AvianBreeder Natural Diet in cockatiel size nuggets now available only in the new 40 lb. bag."ZuPreem breeder customers have been asking for the large-size bags, and the company has answered their requests," says Gail Shepard, senior marketing manager at ZuPreem. "The 40 lb. bags offer convenience, as well as a cost saving advantage, especially for customers with large breeding operations," she says. Both diets are still offered in the original 20 lb. quantity."ZuPreem AvianBreeder Diets are recommended and fed by leading breeders because they are nutritionally balanced especially for breeding birds," says Darlia A. Morris, DVM, ZuPreem vice president. "Breeders find the higher levels of protein, fat and calcium meet breeding birds needs before and during breeding season, helping promote a healthy breeding stock for the optimum production of offspring," she says.ZuPreem manufacturers and distributes diets and treats for companion birds and other exotic animals. For nearly 40 years, the company has been committed to nutrition research and the development of proven effective diets and treats. The company, whose parent name is Premium Nutritional Products, Inc. is located in Shawnee, Kansas, and distributes products worldwide. •!• </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1767</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 30 No. 4 (2003): Fourth Quarter 2003; 46</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1767/1742</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
