<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1037</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-11-11T03:21:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Aviculture on the Wild Side</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Joyner, Kim L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Working with avian species outside of their countries of origin is often very different from working with them in their native habitat. A single visit to a conservation site in a Third World country may highlight some of the unique experiences that can occur, but only extensive journeying on the wild side of aviculture will clear away the misconceptions that exist regarding in-country avian conservation. By not only understanding the disadvantages and advantages of such programs but also by realizing the literal amount of blood. sweat and tears (did I mention pain?) that makes up the backbone of the work abroad, perhaps we in the so called civilized world can approach the problems of avian conservation with more of a global outlook and an empathetic response. So let us now take a walk on the wild side .... Avian Conservation Maxim #1 "Parrots are not necessarily greener in countries of origin." How wonderful we envision life in tropical countries where the days are long and warm with refreshing rains. No doubt the parrots themselves experience benefits from living so close to nature (get your minds off the beaches and snorkeling now, and concentrate on avian conservation), hut, alas, paradise does have its disadvantages. The parrots suffer much like the people do in tropical lands where the climate, the abundance of naturally occurring dis- ease vectors, and harsh living conditions dispel anyone's dreams of perfect living The more common problems occurring in captive avians include parasitism, predation, trauma, malnutrition and stress due to climatic conditions. In established in-country captive breeding aviaries, however, the overall incidence of illness and disease can be quite low, despite the plethora of risks. The manifestation of these diseases, though, can he unique to each facility and each country. Parasitic diseases include protozoan species such as Sarcocystis, Plasmodium (malaria), Leucocytozoon. Cryptosporidia, and Coccidia. Tape worm and round worm infestations can be quite dramatic and finally make checking feces for parasites on any bird worth the effort. Often these parasitic diseases occur in new species or manifest disease differently. Traditional avian viral diseases do exist and, again, their manifestations can he quite different than that seen in traditional aviculture. been definitely identified. Fungal diseases occur with frequency but mostly in debilitated or stressed birds. Given the high humidity and level of fungal spores in the food and air, it is not surprising to see frequent Aspergillus and yeast infections. Chlamydia is also seen sporadically, but, as in the U.S., it almost disappears from any well maintained aviary that observes careful introductions of new pairs. Enteritis seems to occur with greater frequency but, again, the diagnosis is often elusive. The causes probably range from contaminated or spoiled food to contaminated water, amoebas (Montezuma's revenge): and a mixture of bacterial and viral diseases. Then, of course, there are the "icks" that occur. A bird can have an "ick" anywhere on its body but they seem to occur mostly in the extremities such as the toes. By "ick'' one means an undiagnosed skin infection with varying severity and rates of...</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1037</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 23 No. 2 (1996): MARCH-APRIL 1996; 47-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1037/1017</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
