<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/280</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:17:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding, Husbandry and Management of7anager Species</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harris, Erika</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The majority of tanagers are foundfrom Costa Rica in Central Americathrough the northern half of SouthAmerica into Paraguay. Some speciesoccur through Argentina (Skutch, 1954;Dunning, 1982). They inhabit the loweredge of coastal foothills and 4,000-7,000 feet elevations into the mountains.These mainly frugivorous birdsroam through tropical forest tree topsand edges of forest clearings foragingfor fruits, berries, small insects, andvegetation (Skutch, 1954). Many tanagerspecies are brilliantly colored and theirsongs are generally short, sharp monosyllablechirpings. This chirping is especiallyevident when they are agitated,alarmed, or excited. The majority oftanagers are basically monomorphic,with the males a shade or more brighterthan the females, making the sexesindistinguishable in some species.However, several species display astriking sexual dimorphism, with themales brilliantly colored and thefemales a drab, subtle-colored plumage.Tanager species vary in sizes from assmall as 9 em to 26 em in the largerspecies (Dunning, 1982). The tanagersdisplayed at Woodland Park ZoologicalGardens have been mostly medium tolarge species ranging from 12-17 em inlength.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/280</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 14 No. 3 (1987): JUNE-JULY 1987; 20-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/280/269</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
