<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3659</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-26T04:33:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">COVER STORY The Cape Parrot Group</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lewis, Scott</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Cape Parrot group, as referred to herein, is comprised of the African parrots Poicephalus robustus, P. fuscicollis fuscicollis, and Pf suahelicus. The common names of these birds are the Cape Parrot, the Brown-necked Parrot, and the Grey-headed Parrot, respectively. Prior to 2005, these birds were all subspecies of the single species P. robustus. Based on DNA studies along with morphology, behavior, and ecology, in 2005 P. robustus was recognized as an independent species.'Descriptions, taxonomy, natural history, and conservation Members of the Cape Parrot group are stocky, mediumsized parrots with large heads and beaks. (Poicephalus, from the Greek, literally means made of head.) They are about 11 to 12 inches long. Weights, depending on sex and species or subspecies, vary from about 225g for a small hen to about 425g for a large male. Adult birds are clearly dimorphic; juveniles prior to the first molt only to the trained eye, if at all. In mature birds, females have orange coloration above the cere and often more broadly on the head; males do not. In juveniles, the orange coloration on the head is present in both sexes.Of the studied species within the genus, the group is most closely related to the jardine's Parrot, P. guliemi, with which they form a "superspecies cluster." Hybridization is possible and has been demonstrated in aviculture. Based strictly on appearance and size, the group also may be closely related to the Yellow-faced Parrot, P. fiavifrons. However, little is known about this parrot, and no scientific studies have been performed on its relationship to other members of the genus. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3659</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 1&amp;2 (2014): Number 1&amp;2  2014; 36-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3659/3642</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
