<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3059</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-05-17T17:41:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">American Vet. Wins British Award.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T.J. Lafeber, DVM. returned recently from a trip to London where he was honored by the British Small Animal Veterinary Association. Dr. Lafebar is the first American to be presented the Melton Award, which is given for meritorious work in the field of Avian Science with particular reference to caged birds.Dr. Lafeber opened the Niles Animal Hospital and began practice for small animals after graduating from Iowa State University in 1949.Awards are not new to Dr. Lafeber. He received a Special Award in 1970 from the American Animal Hospi ta! Association in recognition of scientific contributions in the field of Avian Medicine and Clinical Laboratory Medicine. In 1975, he was named the Outstanding Practitioner of the Year from Region III, which includes 13 states and 2 provinces, by the American Animal Hospital Association.The Stange Award was presented to him in 1976 as an outstanding alumnus by Iowa State University Veterinary School. Dr. Lafeber is Past Chairman of the Committee on Clinical Pathology for theAmerican Animal Hospital Association and Chairman of their Committee on Avian Medicine and Surgery.He is a member of the American Veterinary Medical Association, the American Animal Hospital Association, Illinois Veterinary Medical Association, Chicago Veterinary Medical Association, the Radiology Society, and the Clinical Pathology Society.Dr. Lafeber is a well known speaker and writer. For the past sixteen years, he has spoken at American Animal Hospital Association meetings, at several American Veterinary Medical Association meetings, and at the World Veterinary Medical Association and the Society of Laboratory Animal Medicine, plus many state and local meetings. The Department of Agriculture regional seminars were given by Dr. Lafeber to train USDA veterinarians for Avian Medicine concerned with their quarantine program. He has regularly given intensified instruction programs to help veterinary colleges set up courses in pet bird medicine.Writings of Dr. Lafeber have been published in the Journal of the American Animal Hospital, Pet Shop Management and Current Veterinary Therapy. He has written a pamphlet on Avian Medicine for the AAl--IA and handouts on Bird Care for Veterinarians to give to their clients. Hundreds of slides, hundreds of colored pictures each with case reports. and '27 colored I 6mm films, some with sound tracks, have been made by him and are used for research and teaching aids.Some of the Avian Projects Dr. Lafeber has worked on to merit the Melton Award include: 1. Introduction and use of the microliter syringe. From this breakthrough, accurate dosages of drugs can be given to small birds.a. It is now safe to give injections.b. Results of treatment are more accurately predicted.2. Development of formulas for force feeding sick birds. Sick birds that had stopped eating are now maintained nutritionally, while their disease condition is being corrected, and they are eating again. 3. Revision of surgical techniques which control blood loss and increase the survival rate.4. Drug dosage schedules were expanded. Because of the inherent reaction of birds to any slight toxicity, safe doses of drugs and their amounts were developed and scheduled.5. Introduction of X-ray procedures - radiographs of even the smallest birds can be valuable aids in diagnosis.6. Investigations are being carried out on avian hematology and blood chemistries. Conditions such as diabetes, renal failure, and hepatitis have been discovered.7. Present bird cage design is being questioned and new approaches are being taken to allow for the emotional and psychological needs of the bird.Dr. Lafeber is Past President of the Niles Lions Club, and a Boy Scout Counselor, and has lots of hobbies. He enjoys camping, backpacking, skiing, tennis, photography and bike riding to work, and collects antique wood carvings. Dr. Lafeber. his wife and seven children live in Park Ridge, Illinois. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-05-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3059</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 4 No. 3 (1977): JUNE-JULY 1977; 36</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3059/3043</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
