<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/670</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">In Memory of</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, Phyllis K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">M. SchubotRichard M. Schubot, 66, an internationallyknown aviculturist, owner of Avicultural Breeding &amp;amp; Research Cen- ter and co-owner of Parrot Jungle and Gardens, died Saturday, May 15, 1993 at his home in Loxahatchee, Florida after a long illness. He is survived by his son, Scott rfSchubot and daughter, Shari Schubot.Richard was a late comer to the fieldof aviculture but during the past 12years he was able to take giant stridestoward the advancement of avianresearch and conservation. In 1981 ,Richard created the Avicultural Breedingand Research Center (ABRC) inLoxahatchee, Florida where he andhis staff did a tremendous job of captivebreeding management of manyexotic birds including some highlythreatened and endangered species.Under the direction of Richard, ABRCactively participated in the captivemanagement and release of the ThickbilledParrots here in the U.S. and tookpart in the reintroduction program ofthe Military Macaw Release Project, Santa Maria-Zunil, Volcanos NationalPark, Quezaltenango, Guatemala.Through his tireless work, manytimes under adverse conditions,Richard continued to lead the waytoward the betterment of avian life incaptivity. He devoted endless hourslecturing to bird clubs across thecountry, sharing his experiences andknowledge about his one love, birds.In 1986, Richard funded the SchubotExotic Bird Health Center atTexas A&amp;amp;M University to benefit avianresearch. He was an active member ofmany bird organizations includingAAZPA, a life member of the AmericanFederation of Aviculture (AFA), afounder and board member of theInterna tiona! A vicultu rists Society(lAS).Richard's dream was to continue tomake life better for exotic birds and hehas shown through his actions thatthis is possible, especially if all aviculturistsjoin together through commongoals- education, captive breeding,research and conservation.Scott Schubot will continue with thegreat work started by his father atABRC. In memory of Richard, contributionsmay be made to the InternationalA viculturists Society or the A viculturalBreeding &amp;amp; Research Center.For address information, please call(407) 793-5135. Marcia L. BernardThrough the course of our lives wecultivate different friendships. Somestay aquaintances, some become "anice person" but rarely are we blessedwith a friend with whom we can trulybe what we are, and still feel loved.That was the kind of friend MarciaBernard was. Honest, sincere, andcaring.In every circle of aviculture, thosewho knew her held her in the highestregard. They knew her gifts, her talents.Her masters degree in animalhusbandry gave her the scientificbackground she needed to manageand maintain her flock but her truesuccesses were brought to life fromwithin her somewhere. Marcia wasable to combine these two sources toreach that level of perfection experiencedby very few in her field. Shepored over every journal, every symposiumtranscript, every bird-relatedpiece of material possible. She spenthours on the phone with people fromevery corner of the world, she sharedher knowledge freely to most anyonewho asked. Marcia developed thehandfeeding formula for Hyacinthsthat many breeders are using today,although they may not know its origin. Very few knew of her accomplishmentsand contributions to aviculturebecause Marcia wanted it thatway. She was happy with what shehad accomplished and that wasenough for her.Marcia's birds, husband and personallife were just that. She didn'twant people to intrude and she didn'twant to be taken advantage of.Although each and every baby sheraised was specia l to her, her heartand soul were with those that werethe most difficult to breed and raise.The most endangered species captivatedher attention and brought herher greatest successes.Marcia was a very unique personnot only with her gifts but with herstandards. She set them high for herselfand expected no less than the bestfrom any person. She lived her life with purpose, tenderness, love andrespect for herself, her family and forthose who were her friends.We can all continue to learn fromMarcia and what she believed in andloved. Those of us who knew her willmiss her so much, but when we see ortouch a Hyacinth, a Major Mitchell, orjust our pet birds we'll know she stilllives in our hea1ts and souls. As morerare and endangered species are propagated,we will know that her spiritlives on and that the world will be abetter place because she was here.Our deepest sympathies to Marcia'shusband Frank, her family, and theworld of aviculture. We will alwaysremember and love you , Marcia.Your Friends , Jacquie , Charlie ,Keith , Nancye, Karl , Tina, Joe, Tim,John, Greg, John, Mitzie, Tim, Joe,Janet and your friends from aroundthe world.Donations can be made in Marcia'smemory to: The World Parrot TrustPBFD. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/670</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/670/653</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
