<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/664</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:30:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Poicephalus Parrots: Senegals and Their Relatives</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Taylor, Isabel</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This marvelous group of parrotsconsists of nine species. Six are availablein the U.S. today, the best knownbeing the Senegal Parrot. Threespecies (Rueppell's, Niam-Niam andYellow-fronted) are quite rare andintensive cooperative breeding isurgently needed to keep them alivefor future generations. One couple isnow sharing their experience andknowledge of breeding Rueppell'sParrots. Their experience containsimportant clues about how to managethese birds successfully and is perhapsa clue about why these birds arestill so rare after being in this countryfor many years. Only by sharing generouslythe information about commonand rare species will we be ableto preserve them in captivity and liveup to our calling to be responsiblestewards of the world's wildlife. This is a quiet group of birds whichmakes it possible to raise them inapartments without disturbing yourneighbors. I have found, however,that Capes can make a lot of cheerfulnoise, especially if you have morethan one pair. Like Grays, Poicephalusparrots can all growl; but tend not tovery often. Poicephalus vary fromabout 100 to 400 grams in bodyweight and are a very colorful group.They sport every color of the rainbowexcept purple. The name Poicephalusmost probably comes from two Greekwords, kephalos meaning head andpoios meaning what kind of. Thisrefers to the puzzling head colors seenin this group of birds. These headcolors and frontal bands are influencedby sex, age, location or subspeciesand individual differences.Three species are sexually dimorphic:Capes, Rueppell's and Red-bellieds.One of the lesser known facts aboutthis group is what wonderful petshandraised babies make. The wildcaughtbirds can be extremely shy andare best suited for breeding as a generalmle. However, a handraised baby can seem like a different species fromits parents. They are affectionate,devoted, comical, not demanding,have strong personalities and are lovinglittle birds. They all can talk, butsome species are more adept thanothers. The talking ability and intelligence of the Red-bellied Parrot has beena delight to many owners and an unusual characteristic for a small bird.This group has many advantages forthe breeder. Low noise is a clearadvantage for city dwellers andsmaller species can live in smallspaces. They will breed year-round,which can be an advantage or a disadvantageif you need a break from"baby birdie burnout". Wild-caughtbirds are seldom aggressive, but I amfinding handraised parents can bequite aggressive when breeding. Theyare not very destructive to perchesand nestboxes and many make excellentfoster parents.The young of sexually dimorphicspecies will resemble the mostbrightly colored parent. For Capes andRueppell's the most brightly coloredparent is the female. Red-belliedbabies can be very confusing tobreeders as they all resemble thebrightly colored male. You will findthat almost every book you pick upwill tell you incorrectly that youngresemble the adult female.Subspecies can also be very confusingin this group of birds. Forashaw isthe most widely used reference onsubspecies, but it is virtually impossibleto tell a "more or less washed withorange" from an "orange" tummy in asingle Senegal. Most people do not tryto tell the difference in a Meyer's witha "bluish-green rump" from one witha "rump green washed with blue". Icannot tell the difference in "broadmargins" on a Jardine's feathers fromthe "broader margins" of another subspecies.I have found Jardine's themost confusing of all. Most of us havealimited number of birds of a speciesto observe and we should be cautiousin declaring a subspecies withoutextensive comparison of birds frommany sources. Many of us have hadthe experience of matching breedingpairs colorwise, only to have themproduce young that are colored likeanother subspecies. Some of theanswers may be found in studying theskin collections of the world'smuseums. Other answers lie in fieldstudies in Africa which have beenpractically non-existent.These birds like privacy for breedingin captivity and as little interferencefrom keepers as possible. Wild-caughtpairs seem to settle down and breedbest in smaller cages (2' x 2'). </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/664</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 20 No. 3 (1993): JUNE-JULY 1993; 27-31</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/664/647</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
