<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/493</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">breeders' notes ... Abyssinian Lovebirds (Agapornis taranta)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baer, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Abyssinian lovebird (Agapornistaranta) is described by Forshawin Parrots of the World as the blackwingedlovebird. A more completedescription of this species of lovebirdis found in Rosemary Low's Parrots- Their Care and Breeding. Anattractive feature of the Abyssinian isits radiant-like green coloration.E.N.T. Vane in the book, Guide toLovebirds and Parrotlets, claims thatthere are two sub-species of A.taranta, but the differences he listsare so slight they appear to be insignificant.William C. Dilger in his TheComparative Ethnology of theAfrican Parrot Genus Agapornis,(from the Laboratory of Ornithology,Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 1960)produced a most informative study ofthe behavioral patterns of all lovebirdsincluding the Abyssinian.Rosemary Low reported she has seentwo cases of abnormally coloredAbyssinian lovebirds.A native of Ethiopia, Abyssinianlovebirds inhabit the dry, highlandforests where freezing temperaturesat night are common. They do, however,descend to the lower altitudes.In the wild they roost in the hollowsof trees and feed on seeds, berries andfruits. They are not nest builders.Considering that this species oflovebird is native to high altitudeswhere it can drop to below freezing atnight, it would be interesting to try toacclimate and keep these birds out ofdoors the year around in our moretemperate climates.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/493</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 3 (1989): JUNE-JULY 1989; 37-39</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/493/478</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
