<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/574</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-11-03T19:29:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Breeding the White--eyed Conure</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harris, Robbie</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Many years ago, (almost too far toremember, about 15 years or so) Ipurchased a beautiful, slightly unusuallycolored White-eyed Comu·e.When I first examined this bird Iknew it was far different from the''normal" species of White-eyed ConuresI was so used to seeing. Theones that are imported here tothe U.S. are usually all green with justbits of scattered red feathers on theirhead and neck. Red is found on thecarpal edge of the wings, with yellowon the greater under-wing coverts(which can only be seen if the wing isextended). The beak is a horn color,feet greyish and eye ring white. Thelength of this bird is about 14 inches.What made this particular conure sodifferent was the facial cheek areawas solid red, as well as the overallbird seemed to be slightly larger thanother White-eyed Conures. Going bythe pelvic bones and personalappraisal, I guessed that this prettybird was a hen. But, I thought it stillbest to have her surgically sexed tohave my suspicions confirmed. As itturned out, the bird was a hen. I soonpurchased another White-eyed Conure,a male, as a mate for my prettyhen. Upon putting the two togetherit became even more obvious thatthey were two very different birds.She was a little larger in comparisonin body and head. Her color was alsovery different as her green was a bitdarker, along with her red cheekmarkings which made her even moredifferent. I decided this was not aproper match, so I started to doresearch for information on this species.Back then, not much literaturecould be found on these birds. I diddiscover that she was a White-eyedConure, but of a different sub-speciesthan is normally imported. I foundthat she was an Aratinga leucopthalmuscallogenys. This information atthe time was found in Parrots of theWorld by Joseph Forshaw. In lateryears, a photo and more informationwas published on this sub-species inThomas Arndt's book Encyclopediaof Conures- 171e Aratingas.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-11-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/574</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 19 No. 4 (1992): AUG-SEPT 1992; 61-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/574/557</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
