<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3923</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-09T03:48:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Message from the President</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buddy Waskey, Lewis</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 51 Number 3 (July 2024). The text below contains excerpts from the original article. For photographs, figures, advertisements, and the complete formatted version as originally published, please use the PDF link associated with this article. Dear Members and Associates, As we commemorate the 50th anniversary of the American Federation of Aviculture, we reflect on half a century of invaluable support for aviculturists dedicated to bird keeping. This milestone represents a collaborative effort among our individual and commercial members, as well as affiliated organizations, all united in their commitment to face and surmount challenges. Together, we have influenced legislation at both state and federal levels and addressed various regulations and ordinances throughout the United States. Our collective success is rooted in ongoing education, shared amongst ourselves and with the public, enhancing our care and conservation efforts for birds. The advent of modern technology has vastly simplified the ways in which we communicate and educate. Our esteemed journal, Watchbird, continues to be a cornerstone of our educational efforts, available quarterly in print and archived digitally for wider accessibility, with resources readily accessible on the AFA website. A highlight of our educational endeavors is the annual Education Conference, which offers a unique platform for aviculturists, conservationists, and bird enthusiasts to connect, learn, and network. I personally find it the most enriching experience for fostering growth and collaboration within our community. We are excited to announce that our 50th Anniversary Educational Conference will take place September 5-7, 2024, in Costa Mesa, California, and we eagerly anticipate your participation. With warm regards, Lewis "Buddy" Waskey President, The American Federation of Aviculture Click the PDF link associated with this article to view the complete article as originally published in AFA Watchbird.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3923</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 51 No. 3 (2024): AFA Watchbird July 2024</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3923/3888</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
