<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1644</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-07-03T15:50:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Legislative Issues</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oesborough, Laurella</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I n this new column I am going to focus on proposed legislation and regulations which will have an impact on aviculture in the United States. Presently there are at least three such matters ahead of us, the USDA settlement under the Animal Welfare Act, the proposed regulations under the Invasive Species Act, and the proposed uplistings of species presently being written under the U.S. Endangered Species Act CESA). The present column will deal specifically with the ESA, wherein new regulations may affect the sale and transportation within the U.S. of many species of cockatoos, macaws and amazons.The U.S. Endangered Species Act directs the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (U.S.F.W.S.), to administer regulations regarding native species of wildlife and imported exotic or nonnative species as well. Last year, the U.S.F.W.S. announced in the Federal Register a review of regulations, (as a part of their policy for a formal review every five years). The review of the uplisting and delisting of avian species and its meaning for us is of concern to aviculture.When species are uplisted to Endangered under the ESA regulations, the USFWS requires for birds sold across state lines, that the sellers obtain a Captive Bred Wildlife Permit and that buyers also obtain such a permit. Obtaining the CBW permits from the USFWS is not a simple matter. Following is a personal report by an individual who has had extensive experience with the CBW permit system and how it has affected his avicultural activities. This report is reprinted with his permission. Thank you Dave Followill for providing us with this important information. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-07-03</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1644</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 28 No. 2 (2001): MAR-APR 2001; 47-48</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1644/1621</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
