<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3697</identifier>
				<datestamp>2017-02-26T17:29:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Twenty New Nest Boxes in the Barba Azul Nature Reserve</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In December 2013, Asociadon Armonfa extended the Barba Azul Nature Reserve with the addition of 15,000 acres (red border-Figure 2) creating a protected area of 27,000 acres. This acquisition was made possible through the combined support of many organizations and individuals: American Bird Conservancy, Patricia and David Davidson, International Conservation Fund of Canada, IUCN National Committee of the Netherlands (supported by the Dutch Postcode Lottery), Loro Parque Fundaci6n, Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Act of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Rainforest Trust, Robert Wilson Charitable Trust, and World Land Trust.An important part of the extension of Barba Azul is the Tiniji River found in the centre of the area. This area holds 15 isolated forest islands that appear ideal for nesting habitat for the Bluethroated Macaw. The macaws avoid nesting in large forest areas because of the high number of potential forest predators adapted to climbing trees. These isolated forest islands are far away from the majority of climbing predators, and in this area, are surrounded by water much of the breeding season (figure 3). The Blue-throated and Blue-and-yellow Macaws know the sanctuary of these islands, as at dusk each day over 200 individuals fly to these remote areas after foraging throughout Barba Azul to take advantage of these safe islands for roosting. But through 150 years of intensive ranching, these forest islands have not been able to offer a safe breeding area. The Bluethroated Macaw requires a nesting cavity in a tree to breed, and ideally a large nesting cavity. Such cavities were abundant in the past when trees were allowed to grow very old, and even die while standing. But ranching activities in the area over time has logged all the old growth deciduous trees, and cut out most of the larger trees. During Armonia's research in July on these forest islands, we found no potential natural nesting cavities and a sad high decrease in natural MotacuPalm Tree regeneration- the favorite fruit of the Blue- throated Macaw. But seeing the importance of these palm forest islands as roosting sites, secured the idea that the macaws know these sites as safe, and if we were able to offer large nesting cavities, it is very possible the Blue- throated Macaws will nest on the reserve. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-02-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3697</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 41 No. 4 (2014): Volume 41, Number 4, 2014, Volume 42, Number 1, 2015; 44-47</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3697/3680</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
