<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/475</identifier>
				<datestamp>2014-10-06T17:21:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">THICK-BILLED PARROTS released &amp; raised in the wilds of Arizona</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Snyder, Noel F.R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Snyder, Helen A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, Terry B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One of only two species of psittacinesnative to the continental UnitedStates, thick-billed parrots (Rhynchopsittapachyrhyncha) effectivelydisappeared from here early in the1900s. They still persist, though indwindling numbers, in the SierraMadre of western Mexico. The causesof their disappearance from thenortherly parts of their range are notsurely known. They were never intensivelystudied while occurring northof the border.Recently we interviewed elderlyArizonans who were personally familiarwith thick-billed parrots in thoseby-gone decades. Our conversationsindicate a primary cause of their disappearancemay have been shootingby subsistence-hunting miners andwoodsmen. They may also have sufferedfrom extensive cutting of themountain forests to support the miningindustry. Subsistence-hunting isnot widely practiced in southeasternArizona at the present time (and notat all for parrots), and timbering is nolonger a major activity there.There are no historical breedingrecords for thick-billed parrots northof Mexico. However, such records arealso virtually nonex istent for Mexicoitself for the period when thick-billsoccurred in the United States. Thus itseems quite likely the absence ofbreeding records is merely an observationalartifact. None of the earlynaturalists visiting Arizona-NewMexico is known either to have seenthick-bills or to have made efforts tolocate their nests. In fact, most informationon thick-bills in the wild hascome from incidental observations ofranchers, lumbermen and casual naturalists.This is hardly adequate to prove what this species' breedingstatus may have been anywhere.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-10-06</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/475</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 16 No. 2 (1989): APR-MAY 1989; 40-45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/475/460</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
