<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3986</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-11T20:18:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Message from the President</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Waskey, Lewis “Buddy”</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This item originally appeared in AFA Watchbird Volume 50 Number 1 (October/November 2023).The following is an excerpt from the full PDF link.Lewis “Buddy” Waskey President, the American Federation of Aviculture I am humbled by the support I have received since being elected as the president of the American Federation of Aviculture. Our Past President Mary Ellen LePage has been valuable member to AFA over the years and her continued involvement will be much needed and appreciated. The Board of Directors, the Committees, the State Coordinators and the membership will be crucial to promote AFA by educating fellow Aviculturists, bird owners and the public about Aviculture.The annual conference this year was held in Dallas, Texas with the combined efforts of the Avicultural Society of America and the Organization of Professional Aviculturist. The theme of the conference was “Aviculture United”, which was surely felt and clearly present. We should applaud all three organizations for a great conference!The American Federation of Aviculture will need to focus on sharing information about the best practices of Aviculture, conservation and the legislative challenges of keeping birds through a focused presents on social media. We should continue to provide communications to the public and our membership through our website, emails and the WatchBird.Click the PDF link associated with this item to view the complete item as originally published.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3986</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 50 No. 4 (2023): Watchbird October/November 2023; 3</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/3986/3946</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 AFA Watchbird</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
