<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1283</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-03-30T17:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">ROSELLAS; A U.S. VIEWPOINT: The Eastern Rosella in the US.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">T he parrots known as rosellas have been favorite avicultural subjects for many years. They are noted for their beautiful colors, conspicuous cheek patches, and the scalloping on their back feathers. There are eight species of rosellas, all inhabiting Australia; the Green (Yellow-bellied), the Crimson (Pennant's), Yellow, Adelaide, Eastern (Golden-mantled), Pale-headed (Blue or Mealy), Northern (Brown's), and the Stanley.The Eastern is probably the best known of the rosellas. It is one of the most beautiful parrots in captivity. From its scarlet head and breast to blues, greens, and golden yellows on other parts of its body, it is vividly col- orful. The adult male has more intense coloration than the female. Its upper mandible is usually larger and wider than that of the female and his white cheek patch is more distinctive and wider. Immature birds look much like the females but their colors are duller and where the adults are red, the immatures are often green.Because of its great beauty, it has been collected for over a century and has been a free breeder for many generations. This is an excellent rosella to begin with as it will delight the new aviculturist with its beauty and graceful flight.The Eastern Rosella is very hardy and, when acclimatized, can withstand rather cold winters. It originates in southwestern Australia which can get very cold.Housing and AggressionAll rosellas, including the Eastern, should be placed in individual pairs for breeding. It is best to scatter rosellas throughout your aviary complex so they cannot see one another. Rosella males are very aggressive and will fight bitterly with any male next door. Toes or beaks are sometimes bitten off through the wire and, worse yet, a male may take out his rage and frustration on his own mate. Often infertile eggs result because the males are preoccupied with each other through the wire and do not attend to their mates.To resolve this problem, pairs of other species should be placed between pairs of rosellas. Of course, it is wise to double wire aviaries to prevent toe chewing of newly fledged birds.Rosellas are extremely good flyers and it is best to give them space to exercise. The housing for rosellas varies greatly with breeders but I prefer long narrow flights. I have bred them in flights that measured only three feet wide but in lengths of six, eight, and twelve feet. A small portion of their flight should provide shelter from direct sun and the elements.If rosellas are kept in flights where they can reach the floor, it is advisable to check with a good avian vet for methods to control round worms.FeedingRosellas should be fed a variety of small seeds (parakeet, straight canary, and small millets) along with soft foods such as soaked rolled corn, vegetables, and whole wheat bread. They sometimes enjoy seeded broccoli, New Zealand spinach, and Swiss chard.They should be give fresh water daily and a larger bowl for bathing. They often submerge themselves in water up to the neck. During incubation, the females bathe at need to keep humidity high in the nest.BreedingThe Eastern Rosella usually breeds in the spring months of March, April, and May but a few may double clutch or nest in the early summer months.I prefer to use a vertical nest box 12 in. x 12 in. square and from 24 to 36 in. deep. I use half inch plywood as the birds will chew up anything flimsier. If two nest boxes are place in the aviary at opposite sides of the sheltered area, the pair has a choice. They often use the additional box when starting a second clutch.Eggs are laid every other day and a clutch usually consists of 4-8 eggs. The female usually begins an 18 day incubation by the second or third egg which means the babies do not hatch all at the same time. There will usually be babies of differing ages in the nest. The hatchlings have a fuzzy white down.Rosellas are generally very good feeders with the male feeding the female who, in turn, feeds the babies. This lasts about two weeks at which time the male will begin to enter the box to help feed the babies.The young fledge at around five tosix weeks of age and the parents continue to feed them on the perch until they are weaned.Foster ParentsOf all the rosellas, I have used the Eastern most as foster parents. They will rear not only other rosellas but other species such as Barraband's, Rock Pebblars, and Australian King Parrots.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-03-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1283</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 25 No. 2 (1998): MAR-APR 1998; 47-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1283/1262</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
