<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2663</identifier>
				<datestamp>2016-04-20T07:32:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Editorial Comment on 1990 Macaw Census Information</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thompson, Dale R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">by Dale R. Thompson Canyon Country, CaliforniaThe first time any sufficient data was done on the captive breeding of macaws and other psittacine species in the U.S. was in the 1990 Psittacine Captive Breeding Survey and Census by TRAFFIC (USA). There are 183 species and subspecies of parrots recorded in this census. The figures on the macaw group appears below.Blue &amp;amp; Gold MacawThe most notable figure in this census is the total number of Blue and Gold Macaws hatched (630) and weaned (581 ). This is the fourth highest hatched total in this census behind Peachfaced Lovebirds (4,049), African Grey Parrots (799), and Monk Parakeets (634). Of greater interest to me is the ratio of the number hatched vs. the number of pairs of Blue and Gold Macaws set up for breeding (397). This figure is 1.46 babies hatched per pair set up. A remarkable figure indeed. Even though this census does not come close to the total numbers of Blue and Gold Macaws kept and bred in the U.S., it does, however, give an indication of how readily and successfully this species of macaw can be reproduced by the American aviculturist. Of all the large macaws, the Blue and Gold is generally rated number one in pet quality. With the number of Blue and Gold Macaws bred and hand reared in captivity, the need by the pet trade for this species should be filled. The price of handfed Blue and Gold Macaws has dropped significantly over the past two years due to the increased numbers bred and this should hopefully replace the need long-term for any wild-caught birds being used by the pet trade.Scarlet MacawI feel the Scarlet Macaw will quickly follow the example of the Blue and Gold Macaw in its ability to reproduce in captivity. Since the Scarlet Macaw has been listed on the Appendix I list (CITES), wild-caught birds will not be imported into the U.S. for commercial purposes. The Scarlet Macaw should hold its own in the breeder market as babies of this species are often retained by aviculturists for future breeding stock. Many babies are also sold into the pet trade. This species has wrongly received a reputation as not being a desirable pet. When ignored during and/or after being handfed, this species can be nippy, but so can other avian species when not attended to or played with. Many scarlet macaw breeders put out excellent hand-fed pets. I feel the American aviculturist will maintain this species for both the breeder and the pet market as is now being done with the Blue and Gold Macaw.Green-winged MacawThis species of macaw over the past two decades has not been reproduced in the numbers as the Blue and Gold and Scarlet Macaws. Only recently in the past few years has this changed. Likewise, the number of babies reared vs. the number of Green-winged Macaws set up for breeding has been very low in the past. This also is changing. As a preliminary indication, this census shows great improvement occurring in this area .This large macaw is highly rated as a handfed pet. Green-winged Macaws are in considerable numbers in the U.S. and, with more reproduction, this species should also begin to fill the needs of the breeder and pet owner.  </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-04-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2663</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 18 No. 3 (1991): JUNE-JULY 1991; 11-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/2663/2644</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
