<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1361</identifier>
				<datestamp>2015-02-04T17:35:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>watchbird:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">What is CITES?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">N/A, N/A</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">[tiditots Note: because I am often asked about CITES and actually iuaiued to learn more myself I presented some questions to Rick [ordan. Chairman of the AFA OTt'S Committee. Tbe follounng is a s11m111my of our Q &amp;amp; A session SLD/Question: Just what is CITES? Answer: CITES stands for The Convention on the International Trade in Endangered Species. It is an International Treaty.Q: Does CITES deal only with endangered species in International Trade?A: No. Actually CITES deals with the trade in any Appendix listed species. Basically there are three appendices under CITES. The most endangered species are found on CITES Appendix I, threatened species, or species that may become threatened by over harvesting from the wild can be found on Appendix II, and Appendix III is a list of species protected by a country of origin, designed to limit trade of that species from that particular country.Q: I hear about CITES "Conference of the Parties" (COP)? What is that?A: The actual "COP" is the meeting where all the member countries come together to vote on resolutions or changes to the Convention Treaty. This is the meeting where Patties (government representatives to CITES) may vote to add or remove species from the appendices, or to change or update definitions found within the Convention Treaty. Only government Parties have a vote.Q: What, then, is the role of the AF A in CITES?A: The American Federation of Aviculture, Inc. (AFA) is an approved Non-Governmental Observer, or NGO. The role of an NGO is to monitor the proposed resolutions to the treaty or appendices and provide comment or scientific data to support or oppose these changes. In other words, the AF A's role is to educate the governmental Parties to CITES about the decisions they are ahout to make concerning aviculture and the breeding of birds in captivity.Q: Are there other NGO participants?If so, who are the other US NGOs'A: There are many NGO status organizations from the United States. Some of them include the North American Falconer's Association, Pet Industry joint Advisory Council, Born Free Foundation, Ringling Brothers Circus, Environmental Investigation Agency, The Humane Society of the United States, and many more. Q: When did AF A become an NGO?How' What does it cost to be an NGO?A: The AF A was granted NGO status to CITES back in 1984. An organization can apply for NGO status to the United States Fish and Wildlife Service in Washington, DC. In order to qualify, the organization must serve as a scientific advisor, conservation organization, or trade organization. Actual NGO status does not cost anything. However, the attendance to a committee meeting is $100 and to attend the Conference of the Parties costs $600. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1361</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AFA Watchbird; Vol. 26 No. 5 (1999): SEPT-OCT 1999; 17-19</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://watchbird-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/watchbird/article/view/1361/1339</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
