<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/104</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-03-29T00:16:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Conceptual Framework for Positive Black Female Identity Formation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kala Burrell Craft</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Robinson, Petra</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Allen-Handy, Ayana</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">critical media literacy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">identity development</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black feminist theory</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Educating Black females about critical media literacy is a fundamental responsibility that should be shared by all who are concerned with the ways in which Black females navigate the world, especially because of the media’s pervasiveness. We proposed a conceptual framework for equipping Black females with the necessary critical media literacy (CML) skills to successfully recognize, decode, and deconstruct negative media messaging to develop a positive Black female identity. Utilizing the Critical Literacies Advancement Model (CLAM) as a foundation, we argued that critical theory can help in terms of developing a variety of critical, nontraditional literacies and to advance and promote positive Black female identity. Supported by the CLAM, we built our conceptual framework using Black Feminist Theory, critical media literacy, and critical consciousness, to outline a clear argument for the development of CML skills and critical consciousness to disrupt the perpetual cycle of subjugation of Black female identity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-07-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/104</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v2i3a104</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 3 No. 1 (2023): Spring/Summer 2023; 34-49</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v2i3</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/104/39</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
