<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/70</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-12-29T02:37:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Dads Matter, Too: Fathers’ Impact on Physical Activity in Black Women</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Blackshear, Tara B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">father involvement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">African American Families</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">African American Females</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black Fathers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">African American Fathers</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The purpose of this study was to explore the impact of father involvement on physical activity behaviors among Black women in college. Data were collected at a large, predominantly White university. Forty-two (Mage= 19.79, SD=1.52) Black women wore Fitbit ZipTM activity trackers, completed father involvement scales, and demographic questionnaires. Height and weight status were taken to compute BMI. Seventy-one percent of participants reported high levels of father involvement, and most (86%) were moderately active, despite 62% having &amp;gt; 25 BMI. Fifty-seven percent did not meet minimal weekly step count recommendations for good health (&amp;gt;52,500); however, only 17% were sedentary (&amp;lt;35,000). Although all father involvement and physical activity relationships were weak, sixty-four percent of participants reported that fathers were directly involved in their physical activities, with 43% reporting that fathers were actively engaged. Fathers are involved in Black daughters’ lives, but their impact on physical activity needs further exploration. Findings can aid in the development of culturally appropriate physical education pedagogy, and encourage the inclusion of fathers/men in public health promotion, as they are excluded in the schooling of Black female and health and physical activity research.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-12-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/70</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v1i3a70</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 1 No. 3 (2021): Fall 2021; 10-27</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v1i3</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/70/15</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
