<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/129</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-31T15:02:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Towards an Understanding of Black Girls’ Digital Activism: What the Black Girls’ Literacy Framework Reveals About the Digital Literacy Practices of Adolescent Black Girls</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Odlum, Lakisha</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">African American girls</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">critical media literacy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">black girl literacies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">social justice</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This qualitative study explored the digital literacy practices of adolescent Black girls who actively engaged on social media in the aftermath of the murders of Breonna Taylor and George Floyd. I employ intersectionality and the Black Girls’ Literacies (BGL) framework (Haddix &amp;amp; Muhammad, 2016) to analyze six qualitative interviews I conducted with adolescent Black girls who avidly used video sharing social media during that time. The data analysis aligned with the following components of the BGL Framework: Black girls’ literacies are intellectual, political, and critical. Moreover, the data analysis also revealed that Black girls espoused two different identities while using social media to address anti-Black violence. These themes were: Crafting Digital Narratives of the Self as Educators and Crafting Digital Narratives of the Self as Digital Activists. The study concludes with national, district-wide, and schoolwide recommendations for policy to improve the teaching and learning of adolescent Black girls.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-10-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/129</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v4i2a129</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 4 No. 2 (2024): Volume 4 Number 2; 159-177</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v4i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/129/69</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
