<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/73</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-18T07:09:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Determining our Destination: The Future of Professional Counterspaces for African American Women in Student Affairs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">West, Nicole M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Michele D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">African American women</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black women</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Student affairs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Professional counterspaces</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Professional development</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This basic qualitative study catalogued the collective insight of Black women student affairs professionals regarding the development and evolution of professional counterspaces in the future. Focus group discussions were facilitated with 50 women participating in a professional counterspace (PC) in the U.S., known as the African American Women’s Summit. Participants were asked to explore the following topics: 1) the purposes of PCs for Black women, 2) how PCs can be enhanced with regard to curriculum content and delivery, and 3) how PCs can be enhanced with regard to opportunities for leadership. Findings indicated that Black women in student affairs still need professional development opportunities that allow them to share their collective wisdom, and that are focused on helping them combat isolation and succeed in the profession. In addition, these types of PCs should include a high degree of interactivity among participants, feature a structured curriculum focused on concrete skill and professional competency development, and provide opportunities for prolonged engagement, perhaps even virtually. Finally, the leadership of PCs for Black women in student affairs can be enhanced by engaging in clear and regular communication with participants, maximizing opportunities for leadership among participants, and using technology to facilitate participants’ leadership development.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-03-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/73</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v1i1a73</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 1 No. 1 (2021): Spring 2021 | Inaugural Issue</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v1i1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/73/4</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
