<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/172</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-12-31T21:15:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">    Prestige or Peril: The Experiences of Three Black Women Doctoral Students at Predominately White Institutions  </dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Garrett, Ramarra</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Taylor, Michelle</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brown, Anglesia</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black Feminist thought</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">care work</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sister circles</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black Women</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This collaborative autoethnographic research aimed to explore the experiences of three Black women higher education practitioners who were full-time doctoral students at a predominantly white institution (PWI) in the Midwest. The women chose Sister Circles Methodology (SCM) as their methodological approach, which focuses on centering Black women's lived experiences and voices. The participants engaged in six sister circle sessions in various modes and settings, discussing a range of topics that included family dynamics, the meaning of Black womanhood, navigating doctoral studies, and workplace dynamics. Black Feminist Thought (BFT) was utilized to provide the theoretical foundation for this research endeavor. BFT emphasizes the ethic of caring and personal responsibility and provides a strong foundation for guiding and grounding discussions. Overall, the research provides valuable insights into the nuanced challenges and experiences of Black women pursuing doctoral degrees, highlighted the importance of centering their voices in research, and provided implications for doctoral programs.&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/172</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v5i2a172</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 5 No. 2 (2025): Winter 2025; 39-64</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v5i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/172/82</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
