<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/187</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-04-23T03:00:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Margins and Political Messaging: A Mixed Methods Exploration of Black Female Students' Mobilization at HBCUs Using Ambitions on the Margin</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wilkerson, Amanda</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Entress , Rebecca </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Walker, Larry </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Samuels , Shalander "Shelly" </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Political Socialization</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Historically Black Colleges and Universities </dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black women and girls</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This mixed-methods study, grounded in the "ambition on the margins" framework, examines the political socialization and mobilization of Black female college students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities in the Southeastern United States. Surveys and focus groups with 80 self-identified Black female undergraduates explored two research questions: How do these students engage politically? and What motivates their participation? Findings reveal that voting, primarily driven by family encouragement and ancestral obligation, is their principal political activity. HBCUs play a crucial role in fostering political awareness. While a reliable voting bloc, participants critiqued political messaging employing racial stereotypes and cultural tropes (e.g., rap music, HBCU bands), favoring authentic messaging focused on actionable change. Although representation matters, impactful policies were prioritized over symbolic representation. This study underscores the need for political communication that resonates with the lived experiences of young Black women, addressing systemic issues like economic inequality and student debt. It highlights HBCUs as vital spaces for cultivating political engagement and advocacy. By amplifying their voices, this research positions Black women as agents of systemic change, offering insights for effective engagement with this influential demographic.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-04-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/187</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v5i1a187</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 5 No. 1 (2025): I AM! Discovering/Centering Black Women at Historically Black Colleges and Universities; 42-63</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v5i1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/187/74</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
