<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/206</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-12-31T21:15:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Peer Review as Collective Care: Building a Caring and Critical Editorial Culture at JAAWGE</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Young, Jemimah</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bango, Eboni</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Peer review</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">collective care</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black feminist</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The present editorial advances a Black feminist vision of peer review as collective care within the Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education (JAAWGE). Rejecting gatekeeping models that reproduce anti-Blackness and sexism, I conceptualize reviewing as an ethic of love, rigor, and solidarity that safeguards the intellectual and emotional labor of scholars writing about Black women and girls. I describe the structural conditions that overburden Black women with invisible service and argue that equitable review cultures must be intentionally built, not assumed. The editorial outlines care-centered, equity-focused practices for reviewers attending to tone, justice-oriented rigor, race and power, timeliness, and mentoring, as well as issues parallel calls to authors and institutions. I invite authors to receive critique as a protected space for growth and to “pay it forward” through their own reviewing. Finally, I urge institutions to recognize and resource reviewing as essential labor in sustaining liberatory scholarship. Collectively, they sustain a just home.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/206</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v5i2a206</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 5 No. 2 (2025): Winter 2025; 1-15</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v5i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/206/84</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
