<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/30</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-18T07:09:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Commitment, Community and Consciousness: A Collaborative Autoethnography of a Doctoral Sister Circle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Teasdell, Annette</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lee, Shanique Joan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Calloway, Alexis Monique</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Adams, Tempestt Richardson</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Collaborative autoethnography</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">African American doctoral women</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mentoring</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Although multiple studies acknowledge the significance of mentoring for African American women doctoral students, the literature lacks empirical support for the formation, sustainability and outcomes of mentoring relationships. In academia, African American women are an understudied subject which leads to a paucity of educational programming and policies that address their specific learning needs. Without targeted research, educators are limited in their ability to understand African American women doctoral students’ educational needs. The purpose of this collaborative autoethnography was to examine the reflections of four women participating in a doctoral sister circle called UUSC. This study explored their lived experiences and ways UUSC nurtured, supported, and empowered both the students and their mentor. Data analysis showcased themes of commitment, community and consciousness which can be instructive for other African American women doctoral students and mentors.  Findings indicated that in safe spaces, such as this sister circle, where African American women are authentically concerned about each other’s well being and success, their level of commitment and consciousness increases. This work has implications for educators and students because it provides a roadmap for addressing the unique learning needs of African American women through mentoring.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-03-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/30</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v1i1a30</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 1 No. 1 (2021): Spring 2021 | Inaugural Issue</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v1i1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/30/2</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
