<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/148</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-06-04T15:01:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jaawge:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en"> Diary Study on Microaggressions, Identity Shifting, and Mental Health among Black Women in STEM Graduate Programs During COVID-19: The Mediating Role of Perceived Supervisor Support : Microaggressions, Identity Shifting, and Mental Health among Black Women in STEM Graduate Programs During COVID-19</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Danielle Dickens</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hall, Naiomi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Farmer, Makyra</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, Nailah</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black women</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">identity shifting</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">microaggressions</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mental health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">STEM</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Black women in STEM graduate programs may develop coping strategies, such as identity shifting, to minimize gendered racial stressors, especially in the context of COVID-19. Identity shifting is the process of altering one’s speech, behavior, perspective, and appearance. Past studies found a positive association between identity shifting and mental health outcomes among young Black women; however, research on the mental&amp;nbsp;health of Black women in STEM graduate&amp;nbsp;programs is limited. The present study utilized a Black feminist standpoint theoretical framework to examine daily experiences of gendered racial microaggressions (GRM), identity shifting, perceived supervisor support (PSS), and mental health outcomes among 102 Black women in STEM graduate programs. Participants completed online daily questionnaires for 10 workdays using Qualtrics. We hypothesized that identity shifting and GRM would positively predict anxiety and depressive symptoms. Additionally, we hypothesized that PSS would significantly mediate the relationship between GRMs and mental&amp;nbsp;health outcomes. Results showed that women with higher experiences of GRM and shifting reported more depressive and anxiety symptoms. PSS did not mediate the relationship between GRM and mental health outcomes. The results of this study can be used to develop culturally tailored support programs to create inclusive environments for Black women in academia.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Open Journal Systems 3.0</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-12-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/148</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jaawge-v3i1a148</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education; Vol. 3 No. 2 (2023): You’re Not Burnt Out: They are Setting You on Fire: Addressing Institutional Responses to the Duel American Pandemics ; 10-30</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2992-9504</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jaawge-v3i1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jaawge-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jaawge/article/view/148/61</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Journal of African American Women and Girls in Education</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
