<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:epbj-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/16</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-02-22T02:32:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>epbj:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Opportunity outside the City: Understanding and Promoting Equity in Rural Schools</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gagnon, Douglas</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Recent times have not always been kind to rural places. A persistent decline inmanufacturing and agricultural sectors has hallowed out the economic base of many rural towns,leaving diminished prospects and casting a cloud of poverty over large swaths of the rurallandscape. A divergent recovery from the Great Recession, during which gains were made butnot evenly so across place or economic strata, has in some ways obscured this fact. The reality isthat politics, power, and populations increasingly reside in metropolitan centers, and many ruraldwellers are at risk of being left behind in tomorrow’s society. Few things could underscore thispoint more than our nation’s recent election, an unprecedented event in which working classvoters made clear that concerns about limited opportunity outside the city must be takenseriously.But in many ways, these voters have been sold a bill of goods. Those who yearn for areturn to the good old days, where 20th Century jobs will allow 21st Century rural communities toprosper, are likely to remain yearning: returns to education are now higher than ever, while theindustries that used to support rural areas are forecasted to decline over the next decade. Thetrue chance for rural places to thrive once again lies more in innovation and adaptation than itdoes in a revisiting old stomping grounds. Standing at the nexus of rural children and theiropportunities for future success lies public education.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-02-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://epbj-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/epbj/article/view/16</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Education Law and Policy Briefs Journal; Vol. 2 No. 1 (2018): Vol. 2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2473-6570</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://epbj-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/epbj/article/view/16/3</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Education Law and Policy Briefs Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
