<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/690</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-10-15T05:01:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:RART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Empowering Preservice Teachers in Teaching Mathematics through Family Math Night</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zhou, Lili</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Community engagement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Family Math Night</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Teacher preparation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study investigates the impact of a Family Math Night event on preservice teachers' perceptions of mathematics within a mathematics methodology course at a Hispanic Serving University on the West Coast. Sixteen preservice teachers participated in designing and implementing activities for the Family Math Night event, aimed at fostering community-based field experiences in teaching mathematics. Through a qualitative analysis of preservice teachers’ reflections and discussions, the findings reveal a transformative impact of the Family Math Night event on preservice teachers’ perceptions of mathematics and its teaching and learning. Moreover, preservice teachers emphasized the opportunity of teaching mathematics at Family Math Night in relevant ways to accommodate individual students’ mathematical levels and enhance student engagement. Additionally, they recognized the significance of parental involvement in mathematics education and indicated their intention to involve parents in future careers. Overall, the findings highlight the potential of informal community-based learning initiatives like Family Math Night to expand preservice teachers’ perception of mathematics education and bridge the gap between methodology course and field teaching practices. This study contributes to the understanding of informal learning environments and community-based learning opportunities in mathematics teacher education, emphasizing their potential to enrich professional development of preservice teachers.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-09-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Double-Blind Peer-Reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/690</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v18i1a690</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 18 No. 1 (2025): Journal of Urban Mathematics Education ; 12-33</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v18i1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/690/354</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Lili Zhou</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
