<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/519</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-01-22T23:10:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:FDC</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Integration of ethnomathematics in teaching geometry: a systematic review and bibliometric report</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kyeremeh, Patrick</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kwadwo Awuah, Francis</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dorwu, Esenam</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Integration of ethnomathematics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Geometry teaching</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Systematic review</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bibliometric analysis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Due to the growing interest in the integration of ethnomathematics in mathematics education, we undertook a systematic literature review and bibliometric analysis of research on incorporation of ethnomathematics in geometry teaching from 2011 to 2021. Specifically, we addressed the trends on the study topic, such as the distribution of the publication over the past 10 years, journals, countries, and the main topics/themes receiving the most attention as well as its main findings. The search for 37 relevant research articles were done on Google Scholar, Scopus and also, by handsearch of some key journals. Data retrieved were analysed descriptively by using Excel and NVivo. The findings show that literature on the use of ethnomathematics in teaching geometry is mostly produced and consumed in Indonesia, Zimbabwe, Nigeria, and Israel. Also, the findings showed that the research topics/themes addressed by literature on ethnomathematics integration in teaching geometry can be grouped into 5 themes: views, practices, effects, challenges, and development of competence. Most of the studies conducted in this area employed ethnography. From the study, it was observed that the number of research article publications relevant to the study has increased exponentially especially from 2018 to 2021. Therefore, it is our believe that this review will aid in the creation of systematic review procedures and reviews that are specifically concerned with the incorporation of ethnomathematics into geometry instruction.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-01-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Blind Peer-Reviewed Public Story</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/519</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v16i2a519</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 16 No. 2 (2023):  Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; 68-89</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v16i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/519/343</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Patrick Kyeremeh, Dr., Esenam Dorwu</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
