<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/851</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-01-01T01:51:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:EDT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">AI in Manuscript Development, Review, and Publication: Ethical Use,  Accountability, and Justice-Centered  Scholarship </dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Young, Jamaal Rashad</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Young, Jemimah </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Artificial Intelligence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">AI publication Ethics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en"> Socially Just AI Scholarship</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Generative artificial intelligence (AI) is rapidly reshaping scholarly writing and publication workflows, raising urgent ethical questions for urban mathematics education. This editorial articulates guidance for the responsible use of AI in manuscript development and peer review, grounded in commitments to rigor, justice, and community accountability. We argue that AI can support accessibility and efficiency (e.g., language refinement, organization, and clarity) but also introduces significant risks, including fabricated or misaligned citations, methodological misrepresentation, confidentiality breaches, deficit framings, and erosion of scholarly voice. To move from principle to practice, we propose a clear framework that distinguishes permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses of AI for authors, reviewers, and editors, emphasizing non-transferable human accountability and transparency through meaningful disclosure. We further outline review practices that prioritize evidence-based critique over speculative “AI detection,” and editorial stewardship that ensures consistent, fair enforcement aligned with publication ethics. We conclude with a call to action: integrate AI tools in ways that strengthen, rather than undermine, trustworthy, justice-centered urban mathematics education scholarship.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Editiorial; Open Peer-reviewed Editorial</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/851</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v18i2a851</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 18 No. 2 (2025): Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; 1-18</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v18i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/851/357</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Jamaal Rashad Young, Jemimah  Young</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
