<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/730</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-21T08:11:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:EDT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Intersection of Race, Data, and Learning: Applying QuantCrit to Mathematics Education Research</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Young, Jamaal </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Young, Jemimah </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Edosomwan, Kristian</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">QuantCrit </dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Equity and Justice </dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Critical Methodologies </dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Systemic Inequities</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Mathematics education research has long relied on traditional quantitative methodologies that often obscure systemic inequities. This editorial advocates for the integration of Quantitative Critical Race Theory (QuantCrit) to critically examine the racialized dimensions of mathematical learning, assessment, and policy. QuantCrit challenges the assumed neutrality of data interrogates deficit-based narratives and calls for the use of quantitative methods that advance social justice. By applying QuantCrit, researchers can uncover how structural barriers shape student outcomes and reframe assessment practices to better support historically marginalized learners. This editorial highlights key tenets of QuantCrit, explores its implications for mathematics education, and provides actionable strategies for scholars and educators to incorporate this framework into research and practice. A shift toward justice-oriented quantitative methodologies is necessary to ensure mathematics education fosters equity and inclusion. This work urges researchers and policymakers to engage with QuantCrit as a transformative tool for reimagining mathematics education.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Editiorial; Open Peer-reviewed Editorial</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/730</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v17i2a730</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 17 No. 2 (2025): Journal of Urban Mathematics Education ; 1-10</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v17i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/730/352</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Jamaal  Young, Jemimah  Young, Kristian Edosomwan</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
