<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/213</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-13T03:45:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:RART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Urban Latina/o Undergraduate Students'  Negotiations of Identities and Participation in an Emerging Scholars Calculus I Workshop</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oppland-Cordell, Sarah</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">collaborative learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">identity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Latina/o students</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mathematics education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">race</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In this article, the author presents a qualitative multiple case study that explored how two urban Latina/o undergraduate students' emerging mathematical and racial identity constructions influenced their participation in a culturally diverse, Emerging Scholars Program, Calculus I workshop at a predominately White urban university. Drawing on critical race theory and Latina/o critical theory, cross-case analysis illustrates that participants' emerging mathematical and racial identities--co-constructed with their other salient identities--contributed to positively shifting their participation by: (a) changing their perceptions of their and peers' mathematics abilities, (b) allowing them to challenge racialized mathematical experiences, and (c) strengthening their comfort levels in the workshop environment. The Latina/o participants' counter-stories support that the sociopolitical nature of identity development and participation in mathematical learning contexts should be embraced because it provides additional knowledge regarding how and why Latina/o students attain mathematical success.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-07-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Double-Blind Peer-Reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/213</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v7i1a213</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 7 No. 1 (2014)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v7i1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/213/151</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
