<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/414</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-06-25T20:40:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:ITAA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">"We Made Math!": Black Parents as a Guide for Supporting Black Children's Mathematical Identities</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cunningham, Jahneille</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Black parents</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">elementary mathematics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">informal mathematics learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mathematics identity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parent engagement</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Black parents are often presumed to be uninvolved in their children’s education, especially in mathematics. These stereotypes are arguably sustained by White, middle-class expectations for parent engagement. This qualitative study challenges the dominant narrative by exploring the ways eight Black parents support their elementary-aged children’s mathematical identities. Although many scholars have examined the relationship between mathematics identity and academic outcomes, few have explored the role parents play in this identity development. Drawing on Martin’s (2000) mathematics identity framework and McCarthy Foubert’s (2019) Racial Realist Parent Engagement framework, the author argues that Black parents’ experiential knowledge of race and racism in mathematical spaces positions them to teach their children about the everyday importance and usefulness of mathematics. Using parent interviews and family observations, the author’s findings suggest the parents supported their children’s mathematics identities using four approaches: 1) pragmatic (emphasizing financial literacy and basic life skills), 2) aspirational (promoting math-intensive careers), 3) affirmational (sharing words of encouragement), and 4) race-conscious (applying mathematical concepts to lessons in Black history, culture, and anti-Blackness). Implications for educators are discussed, as parent identity support strategies may be useful for reform-oriented teachers seeking to foster positive mathematical identities in Black children.
 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-05-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/414</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v14i1a414</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 14 No. 1 (2021): May 2021, Special Issue – I, Too, Am America! Teaching Mathematics for Empowerment; 24–44</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v14i1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/414/314</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Jahneille Cunningham</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
