<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/589</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-01-22T22:58:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:EDT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Role of Technology in Enhancing Urban Mathematics Education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Young, Jamaal Rashad</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Urban Mathematics Education </dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Technology Integration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">  Inclusivity in Learning Equitable Access</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">AI</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Game-based Learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The integration of technology in urban mathematics education has emerged as a promising approach to address educational disparities and foster engaging learning environments. With the widespread availability of technology infrastructure in urban schools, there is a growing focus on leveraging digital tools and resources to enhance mathematics learning outcomes. This editorial examines the impact of technology on urban mathematics education, exploring its potential to bridge opportunity gaps and promote inclusivity. Drawing on current research and best practices, we highlight the benefits and challenges of technology integration, emphasizing the importance of equitable access, teacher professional development, and tailored instructional approaches. The editorial underscores the need for collaborative efforts among stakeholders to advocate for increased funding and support for technology initiatives in urban schools. By embracing innovative practices such as educational apps, virtual reality, and online collaborative projects, educators can create dynamic learning environments that empower students to excel in mathematics. The ongoing dialogue and efforts surrounding the role of technology in urban mathematics education are critical for achieving educational equity and excellence for all students. As technology continues to evolve, it remains imperative for educators and policymakers to prioritize effective technology integration strategies that cater to the diverse needs of urban learners.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-01-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Editiorial; Open Peer-reviewed Editorial</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/589</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v16i2a589</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 16 No. 2 (2023):  Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; 1-13</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v16i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/589/340</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Jamaal Rashad Young</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
