<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/563</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-21T08:11:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:RART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Influence of Language on Multilingual Middle Grades Learners’ Mathematical Problem-Solving Outcomes</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cahill, Jodie</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bostic, Jonathan</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">English Language Learners</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Mathematical Problem solving</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">middle school</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Multilingual learners (MLs) encounter key language features that influence their mathematical word problem solving processes. Much of the readily available literature surrounding MLs’ experiences in the mathematics classroom explores either their content knowledge or how language affects their mathematics achievement. Far less literature has examined problem-solving outcomes among MLs. The present study attempts to fill a gap in the literature by examining seventh-grade MLs’ engagement with grade-level word problems that align to mathematics standards and are realistic, complex, and open (Verschaffel et. al., 1999). &amp;nbsp;An explanatory mixed-methods approach (Creswell, 2012) was utilized to explain the features underlying ML’s problem-solving outcomes. MLs were interviewed via a Retrospective Think Aloud protocol following their engagement with each word problem. Findings indicate that MLs are extremely successful at engaging in sensemaking, a vital aspect of problem solving, based on their abilities to describe the problem context presented in their own words. Further, words having both mathematical and nonmathematical connotations were utilized by MLs in terms of their nonmathematical connotations, which influenced their mathematical word problem solving processes. These two findings add to past studies (Gándara &amp;amp; Hopkins, 2010) and highlight a need to integrate English Language Proficiency skills throughout mathematics instruction.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Double-Blind Peer-Reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/563</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v17i2a563</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 17 No. 2 (2025): Journal of Urban Mathematics Education ; 11-42</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v17i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/563/349</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Jodie Cahill, Jonathan Bostic</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
