<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/423</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-05-28T15:01:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:FDC</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Disrupting Research, Theory, and Pedagogy With Critical Race Theory in Mathematics Education for Black Populations</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Davis, Julius</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">critical legal studies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">critical race theory</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mathematics education</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Mathematics education consists of dominant research, theoretical, and pedagogical perspectives that frame Black students and adults from a deficit perspective. Critical race theory in mathematics education (CRT(ME)) provides a framework that can disrupt the field to support Black students and adults. CRT(ME) is essential because it offers a lens to examine the permanence of race, racism, classism, sexism, and other forms of oppression. CRT(ME) provides mathematics educators with the tools to achieve racial justice and liberation for Black populations both within and outside of the discipline. Scholars have called for increased CRT(ME) use for doctoral candidates and faculty to usher in a new paradigm. However, researchers interested in using CRT(ME) must first develop knowledge and understanding of critical legal studies, as well as CRT in law, education, and mathematics education. In this commentary article, I provide a brief overview of my CRT(ME) journey; examine CRT in law, education, and mathematics education; and elaborate on how to continue to move the framework forward in the field.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-05-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Blind Peer-Reviewed Public Story</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/423</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 15 No. 1 (2022): May 2022 Issue; 9–30</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v15i1</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/423/328</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 Julius Davis</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
