<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/511</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-06-25T20:41:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>jume:EDT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Revisiting Urban Mathematics Education: Towards Robust Theoretical, Conceptual, and Analytical Methods</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Young, Jamaal</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Candace Raygoza, Mary</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Madkins, Tia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lawler, Brian</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roberts, Thomas</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There are unique, enduring challenges related to mathematics instruction in urban schools, and the most common concerns are related to issues of equitable access to mathematics learning opportunities. In this editorial, we argue that the complexity of teaching mathematics in urban schools requires the attention of mathematics scholars with unique training, expertise, and experiences. Developing mathematics instruction for urban spaces often involves refined research techniques, multi-disciplinary perspectives, and collaboration between diverse stakeholders. Specificity is the key to addressing these challenges. However, to date, the Journal of Urban Mathematics Education (JUME)—out of 69 mathematics education-focused journals (Nivens &amp;amp; Otten, 2017)—is the only journal venue devoted to mathematics teaching and learning in urban environments. Although other mathematics education journals and conferences accept scholarship related to urban schools, due to the vast nature of mathematics education research and limitations in journal space, the nuances of specific issues in urban mathematics education (e.g., preparing mathematics teachers well for high-needs urban schools) are underexamined and poorly understood.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Aggie STEM</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Editiorial; Open Peer-reviewed Editorial</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/511</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/jume-v15i2a511</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Journal of Urban Mathematics Education; Vol. 15 No. 2 (2022): December 2022 Issue; 1–7</dc:source>
	<dc:source>2151-2612</dc:source>
	<dc:source>10.21423/jume-v15i2</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://jume-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/jume/article/view/511/334</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 Jamaal Young, Mary Candace Raygoza, Tia Madkins, Brian Lawler, Thomas Roberts</dc:rights>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
