<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/93</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-03-04T01:32:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Career Paths of Women Working in Leadership Positions within Intercollegiate Athletic Administration</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bower, Glenna G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hums, Mary A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Scholars have focused their attention on the careers of women working in management positions in several sport industry segments, however, limited research has focused on careers of women working in intercollegiate athletic administration. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to examine career information of women working in the administration of intercollegiate athletics. The study addressed the following amongst women working in intercollegiate athletic administration: (a) demographics, (b) career paths, (c) most/least enjoyable aspects of their jobs, (d) greatest challenges, (e) career advice, and (f) short-term and long-term career aspirations. This descriptive study provided insight for women wanting to explore a career within intercollegiate athletic administration. The information is useful for both women and men working in intercollegiate athletic administration and to the NCAA organization in support of its ongoing work to promote diversity in leadership positions. In addition, women wishing to pursue a career in intercollegiate athletics face a number of challenges, but acknowledging the voices of the women within this study can begin to explain some of the steps needed to maximize women's contributions to this field. Finally, this study contributes to the body of knowledge in the sport management literature in intercollegiate athletics.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/93</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v33.a93</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 33 (2013); 1-14</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>en</dc:language>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
