<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/487</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-20T23:43:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:FrM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Call for Manuscripts/Publication Guidelines</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Editors</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Manuscript Submissions Manuscripts should meet the following requirements:1. All articles should follow The Publication Manual of the American Psychological Association (APA) Fourth Edition format. If an individual is from a country other than the United States and is unfamiliar with this publication style, the editors will assist the author in formatting the manuscript in APA style if the manuscript is accepted for publication. Because html formatting is slightly different from that of regular paper publishing, the APA style will be followed as closely as possible. Indentions, spacing, and footnoting may vary in this journal.2. Manuscripts should be typed, double-spaced, titled, and should be approximately 1200 to 3000 words in length. Pertinent photographs, charts, or graphs should accompany the manuscript.3. Manuscripts submitted should be previously unpublished and not under consideration by another publication.4. Include a brief biography of each author of the paper and an address, telephone number, fax number, and e-mail address.5. Manuscripts may be e-mailed to the Editors at edu_bid@shsu.edu or snail mailed to: (If mailed by regular mail, the author should submit the manuscript on MacMSWord5.0 or 6.0 or if saved in DOS, the document must be saved as a Word or as an RTF file)

Dr. Genevieve Brown/Dr. Beverly J. Irby, EditorsSam Houston State UniversityP.O. Box 2119Huntsville, Texas 77341Telephone: 409-294-1147; FAX: 409-294-3886Manuscript Deadlines: For the Spring Issue, January 1For the Summer Issue, June 1For the Fall/Winter Issue, September 1
</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1997-04-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/487</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 1, No. 1 = No.1 (1997 Spring)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/487/358</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1997 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
