<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/106</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-21T20:43:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Role Performance of Female Headteachers in Primary Schools: A Case of Bondo District, Kenya</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Atieno, Omondi E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The purpose of the study was to determine the role performance of female head teachers in primary schools in Bondo district of the republic of Kenya. Descriptive survey design was used in the study. As the population of female headteachers is not so big, 16 out of 17 schools were used for the research. Questionnaire and interview guide were used to gather information from the respondents. Data were analysed using tally marks and total frequencies to generate frequency accounts out of which percentages were calculated. Information collected through interview schedules and discussions were thematically described.The findings revealed that in all six administrative tasks, the female head teachers' performance was generally good. It is expected that the results of this study may help to shed light on how female head teachers perform their roles as administrators and to provide some indication of direction that could change the perception of the role of female head teachers from negative to positive. Results may also provide an indication of what additional steps may need to be taken to address the elevations of more female teachers to leadership roles. Based on the findings of the study, it was recommended that the government should come up with mentors among the female head teachers, thoroughly train some of them who will in turn be in a positions to offer assistance and more guidance to their counter parts. This will help motivate female teachers to pursue leadership roles.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/106</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v33.a106</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 33 (2013); 96-105</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/106/92</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
