<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/468</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-15T21:37:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Gender Equity Models in Science Teaching and Learning Mirrored Structures, and Designs for Chang</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ash, Doris</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In this paper I develop a 'mirrored structures' model that applies to three NSF-funded gender and science projects aimed at improving girls understanding, attitudes, and abilities in science, mathematics, and technology. All are concerned with the under-representation of women in science, math, and technology. All three facilitate girls' success at critical educational junctures particularly the middle/ junior high transition where girls are lost to science. The three projects have developed rich and varied programs aimed at increasing understanding, confidence, and ability in the science, math, and technology for girls, and for their teachers, their parents, and administrators. The projects are different but share some common underlying elements and in many ways are typical of the multi-tiered gender equity programs across the country. Together the three programs offer powerful evidence for understanding systemic change within diverse geographies. All three programs share similar philosophies3 there are many different ways to achieve equity goals but it is essential that participants at all levels capitalize on existing strengths, their particular "ways of knowing". I argue that the 'mirrored structures' model cuts across all levels of participation within all three projects. 
The projects, are: FIRST (Female Involvement in Real Science and Technology) in Oakland, California; The Voices project: Rural and Urban Images: Voices of Girls in Science Mathematics and Technology in rural Appalachia, West Virginia; and Girls Inc. of Lynn, Massachusetts's Operation SMART (Science Math and Relevant Technology). While the model offered in this paper was based originally on the FIRST project, it is applied to the Voices and Operation SMART programs. 
Together they provide exemplars for examining systemic change because the programs emphasize not only the changes within the target audience, elementary and middle school girls, but also an expanded group of teachers, parents, and administrators within school districts that serve diverse student populations. By systemic change, I mean change at multiple levels of participation which can interact in both positive and negative ways. Change can be better understood by analysis of these relationships and by maximizing the positive interactions as leverage points. </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-05-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/468</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 9, No. 1 = No. 9 (2001 Summer)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/468/331</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2001 Advancing Women</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
