<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/213</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-02-08T01:08:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Role of Forgiveness in the Leadership Practices of Women Leaders in Higher Education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Grace-Odeleye, Beverlyn E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Osula, Bramwell</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study examined the use of interpersonal forgiveness in the leadership practices of women leaders inhigher education. Six women, with senior level administrative positions in a large public university, wereinterviewed and asked a range of questions regarding their use of forgiveness in leadership practices.Responses from participants were grouped together using cross-case analysis to discover meaning andinterpreting themes. The interview guide sought to elicit a common definition of forgiveness, examined theuse of forgiveness, and identified steps in the process of forgiveness in leadership practices. The evidence isthat the participants in the study defined forgiveness as choosing and making a decision to reduce negativethoughts, such as blame and anger. Recognizing the problem, identifying the nature of the problem, andaddressing the problem were identified as key steps in the process of forgiveness. Growth producingexperiences and improved relationships are cited as additional benefits. Working through conflict in apositive manner is a primary reason that the women studied utilized forgiveness in their leadership practices.Modeling the behavior and mentoring others are additional approaches used to demonstrate the purpose andmeaning of forgiveness. All participants identified mentoring as an important relationship and described amentor as one who exhibited and used some aspect of the principles of forgiveness in their leadershippractices. Additionally, females were said to utilize forgiveness more often than males. The reason given forthis was that females are seen as being more interested in maintaining relationships than are men. The studyalso provides some general insights into actions and behaviors associated with the exercise of forgiveness inleadership practices within the workplace.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-04-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/213</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v23.a213</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 24 (2007 Spring)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/213/191</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
