<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/356</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-12-02T00:43:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Would You Send Your Daughter to Howard? Historically Black Colleges and Universities Advancing Black Women in Leadership</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Yeboah, Amy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In this article, we address the influence of Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) on Black women’s participation in American politics. Focusing on the rise and record number of Black women running and winning political office in 2018, a remarkable list of over 400 Black women candidates were collected. Focusing on lives of three Black women whose dedication, determination, leadership, and activism are shifting the American political; Kamala Harris, Stacey Abrams, Lucy McBath, its evident that HBCUs have empowered Black women to continue to lead, make a change and break barriers in American politics. These results highlight some of the long-term impacts supporting HBCU environments has created for Black women in politics and America.
 
Keywords: black women, politics, underpresented, gender, leadership, historically black colleges and universitites</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/356</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v40.a356</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 40 No. 1 (2021): Advancing Women in Leadership; 56-64</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/356/301</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
