<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/508</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-09-16T16:36:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Let the Silenced Speak: Digital Platform Usage by Feminist and Gender Equity Nongovernmental Organizations in Ghana</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dogbatse, Felicity Sena</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The freedom and acceptance of feminists’ activities in Ghana hit several rocks after the first African Feminist Congress in Ghana in 2004. In Ghana, research on gender advocacy and feminist organizations has increased, but little emphasis has been paid to the contribution of self-identified feminists to women’s empowerment. I explored how self-identified feminists and gender equity-focused NGOs in Ghana leverage social media to educate and advocate for women’s and children’s welfare. I also examined how these feminists and NGOs engage women in rural areas in seminars, discussion sessions, and training workshops to create spaces for women to voice their concerns and gain empowerment. Given this, 17 in-depth interviews were conducted with self-identified Ghanaian feminists and NGO leaders. I employed muted group theory and African feminist theory to guide the data analysis. I argued that Ghanaian self-identified feminists and NGOs have put in a lot of work to empower Ghanaian women to enable them to express themselves and share their experiences. The findings contribute to the discussion on Ghanaian feminism and how they enact empowerment and advance how the growing acceptance of feminism in Ghana allows Ghanaian women to speak for themselves and have their voices heard in national and global digital spaces.
Keywords: Freedom, Feminism, Digital platforms, Muted Groups, NGOs
 </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-09-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/508</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v43.a508</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 43 (2024): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 66-76</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/508/378</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
