<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/256</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-14T02:19:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Linking Literacy and Community Development: A Case Study of Women in New Orleans</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Subban, Jennifer E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper examines the impact of a family literacy program in New Orleans , developed in response to low literacy levels, high drop-out rates, and a corresponding lack of resident participation in community development efforts in the area. The program, Toyota Families for Learning (TFFL), worked to transcend disciplinary barriers by linking adult literacy education and community development through a community-based approach to adult literacy. TFFL continuously evolved to serve as a catalyst for transformation in the lives of the women it served, their families, and their communities. The experiences of the women in this study were explored in relation to the following indicators of community building: (1) developing the ability to express personal experiences and observed phenomena, (2) constructing one's own knowledge, (3) setting and following through on goals, (4) building a positive community environment, and (5) developing a vision of the community. Qualitative data in the form of literacy narratives informed this inquiry. The narratives were triangulated with field notes and focus group data collected over a six-year period commencing in 1992. The findings of this research indicate that literacy programs can be structured to successfully build the capacity of participants to engage in community development processes.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/256</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v21.a256</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 22 (2006 Fall)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/256/231</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
