<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/123</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-21T23:11:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">An Examination of Indo-Trinidadian Females' Identity Beliefs: Implications for their Centered Leadership</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bissessar, Charmaine</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Discussions around the development of Caribbean women have, to a great extent, marginalized Indo-Trinidadian with scant anecdotal evidence of their leadership potential and identity beliefs. I sought to examine Indo-Trinidadian women's identity beliefs and how this is linked to the concept of leadership. The underlying theoretical framework of this qualitative methodology study was Centered Leadership (Brash &amp;amp; Cranston, 2011). The questions posed were, what are the beliefs as regards Indo-Trinidadian females' identity and how do such beliefs reflect the subscales of Centered Leadership? Most of the 50 participants belonged to the 18 to 36 age range with 20 of them possessing high school certificates, 19 Indo-Trinidadian females lived in North-East Trinidad, and 12 were salesclerks. All participants displayed high levels of self-efficacy, 80% indicated that they used positive methods of eliminating stress and they felt empowered emotionally, physically, and mentally. In responding to questions about their belief in freewill, 84% of respondents indicated that they favored free-will over destiny. Four participants who lived in other countries indicated that they did not have any major issues assimilating a new culture. Moreover, 10 of the participants verified the findings. Indo-Trinidadian women's identity and belief systems closely matched the five stages of Centered Leadership: (a) meaning; (b) framing; (c) connecting; (d) engaging; and (e) energizing.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/123</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v35.a123</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 35 (2015); 134-143</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/123/108</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
