<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/502</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-11-14T20:44:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Examining and Overcoming Barriers to Leadership for Black Women in HBCU Spaces</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Williams, Dr. Tameka</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Clark , Dr. Tyler S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mcgill-Youngblood , Dr. Larrisha</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Henderson , Lauren</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The researchers in this study aimed to explore the barriers Black women face when ascending to leadership roles at Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) and the coping strategies they employ to overcome them. Guided by two research questions, we gathered data from 93 Black women who currently work or have worked at HBCUs and aspire to leadership roles. Our findings, integrated with existing literature, reveal several significant barriers: microaggressions and gender oppression, limited access to professional networks and mentors, and work-life imbalances. Gender Oppression and Workplace Microaggressions emerged as prominent barriers, aligning with previous research on gender discrimination in academic settings. Most respondents reported not having access to formal mentorship programs, significantly impacting career progression. Additionally, balancing work and personal responsibilities, coupled with discrimination, adversely affects well-being and career advancement. The stereotypes and perceptions of Black women also emerged as a significant issue, placing undue emotional and psychological burdens on Black women. Respondents highlighted the importance of personal support networks, professional networks, and mentorship in coping strategies. Support from family and friends, professional networks, and seeking additional education were commonly cited strategies, with mentorship being particularly valued.
Keywords: Black, women, Historically Black College and University, HBCU, ascension, leadership, barriers</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-11-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/502</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v43.a502</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 43 (2024): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 77-90</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/502/379</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
