<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/108</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-21T20:43:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Perceived Self-Efficacy, Domestic Violence and Women's Ability to Break Industrial Glass Ceiling</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ottu, Iboro F.A</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Inwang, Winifred Chris</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The purpose of this study was to examine perceived influence of self-efficacy and domestic violence on women's ability to break industrial glass ceiling and become leaders in their chosen careers. A total of 150 women working in 3 government departments in Akwa Ibom State, Nigeria comprised our study group. Participation was voluntary. Participants filled out questionnaires anonymously. Women's ability to break glass ceiling was measured using industrial glass ceiling questionnaire constructed by the researchers. The self-efficacy questionnaire and the domestic violence scales, also developed by the researchers, measured self-efficacy and practices of domestic violence by women. Results showed that self-efficacy [F(1,146) = 4.85, P &amp;lt; .05] and the interaction of domestic violence and self-efficacy [F(1,146) = 5.95 P &amp;lt; .05] significantly influenced women's ability to break industrial glass ceiling. We found that the nature of domestic violence — whether it was emotional or physical — differentially impacts women's career aspiration depending on their levels of self-efficacy. Women who reported high self-efficacy in the midst of exposure to emotional violence made the greatest effort to break industrial barriers towards career success. In the same way, women who reported low self-efficacy in an atmosphere of emotional violence were found to perform least in ability to achieve career goals. Physical violence however showed a near-inelastic effect irrespective of whether the women were high or low in self-efficacy. We therefore suggest that partners in dual career families should denounce violence and be supportive of each other in order to boost each other's (especially the wife's) self-efficacy, not only to achieve career success but also to meet the labyrinth of demands that marriage has placed on each partner.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/108</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v33.a108</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 33 (2013); 177-187</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/108/94</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
