<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/244</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-13T21:11:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Helping Non-tenured Education Faculty Get Published in Peer-reviewed Journals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sanacore, Joseph</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">If university trustees and administrators in the United States require junior faculty to publish or perish, then they should provide extensive support for this requirement. Such support is evident in the School of Education at the C.W. Post Campus of Long Island University, where administrators and faculty became team members and held cooperatively planned informal get-togethers with non-tenured faculty. These informal sessions focused on pertinent topics aimed at getting published in peer-reviewed journals. The topics included: (a) synthesizing a dissertation and condensing it into a manuscript format; (b) increasing an awareness of the format, content, editorial policy, and audience of journals for which authors intend to submit a manuscript; (c) realizing creative potential and being aware of methods that kill creativity; (d) becoming a serious critic and editor of one's own work; (e) weighing the benefits of submitting manuscripts to themed issues or regular issues of journals; (f) selecting journals that represent one's current developmental level of research and writing and that the university considers acceptable; (g) considering electronic journals as viable options for publishing; (h) thinking about presenting a paper at a convention but realizing its pros and cons; and (i) managing a busy academic year while being productive and visible, but not exhausted.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/244</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v20.a244</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 20 (2006 Spring)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/244/220</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
