<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/177</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-07-03T17:57:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Study of the Correlation Between the Motives of Female High Self Monitors and Emergent Leadership: A Literature Review</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Slater, Charles</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In 1972, researchers reported that only 4% of the Master of Business Administration graduates were women. This figure now exceeds 33%. Similarly, in 1972, women occupied about 20% of non-clerical, white-collar jobs. This figure has now grown to more than 46% (Sharpe, 1994). Sharpe also contended that in 1972, only 17% of all managerial positions were held by women, but by 1994 that number had increased by 43%. Although women have flooded managerial positions in recent years, concern still remains about what some refer to as a "glass ceiling" that prohibits women from reaching the topmost levels of corporate leadership. Ragins, Townsend, and Mattis (1998) stated that, of the most highly compensated corporate executives in Fortune 500 companies only 2% are currently women and only .4% of the Fortune 1000 Chief Executive Officer, (CEO), positions are held by women. Maruca (1997) promulgated that male CEOs blamed the "glass ceiling" on women's lack of experience and time in organizations. In the same study, however, female executives disagreed citing exclusionary corporate cultures as the reason for their lack of advancement to top management positions. This paper looks at one of the human behaviors known to be compatible with emergent leadership, self-monitoring behavior, and its possible relationship to the "glass ceiling" prohibiting women's advancement within corporations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/177</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v14.a177</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 14 (2003 Fall); 55-58</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/177/156</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
