<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/537</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-11-24T20:45:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Navigating the Nexus: Exploring the Intersections of Race and Gender in the Experiences of Black Women Higher Education Administrators at Predominantly White Institutions</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tanja Bibbs</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Although Black women have established themselves as leaders within colleges and universities, few have advanced to the most senior levels of postsecondary administration, leaving them underrepresented in these roles (Williams et al., 2024). Existing research on Black women at this level has largely focused on the presidency, often overlooking the experiences of those serving in other executive positions (Johnson, 2025). In this phenomenological study, I examined how four Black women in executive positions perceived the influence of their racial and gendered identities on their leadership experiences at predominantly White institutions (PWIs). Guided by Black Feminist Thought, in-depth interviews explored how participants navigated their institutions. The analysis revealed participants described instances of stereotyping, exclusion, and challenges to their authority which they addressed through identity management, coalition-building, and active resistance. The findings draw attention to the persistent structural barriers Black women encounter within executive administration and their strength to adapt to institutional environments.  
Keywords: Black women; higher education; executive-level administration; predominantly white institutions; phenomenology; Black Feminist Thought</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-11-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/537</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v44.a537</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 44 No. 1 (2025): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 122-137</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/537/394</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
