<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/469</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-15T21:37:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Career Path and Profile of Women Chief Academic Officers in Public Community Colleges </dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McKenney, Cynthia B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cejda, Brent D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"...it would appear that for women a variety of credentials and experiences have become the medium of exchange." 
The position of chief academic officer (CAO) is complex and demanding. The holders of this office are generally recognized as the highest-ranking academic administrator of their institution and are charged with directing its academic mission. They are looked to for leadership, vision, and wisdom. This position is also the one most commonly held prior to assuming a presidency of an institution of higher education (Plotts, 1998; Ross &amp;amp; Green, 1998; Twombly, 1986). Vaughan (1989) reported that 50% of the presidents in community colleges held the CAO position immediately prior to the presidency. Twombly (1988) also confirms the importance of the CAO position in the career path leading to the community college presidency. Given their impact on the academic programs of their institutions and the likelihood that they will advance to the presidency, investigations into the career paths of these academic professionals are warranted.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-05-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/469</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 9, No. 1 = No. 9 (2001 Summer)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/469/332</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2001 Advancing Women</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
