<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/331</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-02-08T02:03:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Women and Multi-tasking: Strategy or pitfall for Career Advancement?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Guramatunhu-Mudiwa, Precious</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cherry, Jewel B</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Despite its ubiquitous adoption in the workplace and home, research suggests that multitasking is not an effective strategy forproductivity (Cabrera, 2016; Crews &amp;amp; Russ, 2020). Workplace demands and the disproportionate division of labor in the homemake multitasking unavoidable, indispensable and a necessary coping tool, especially for women with professional and domesticresponsibilities (Holdsworth, 2020; Kirchberg et al., 2015). Women multitask more than men do and are also perceived to bebetter multitaskers than men but sadly multitasking decreases productivity and increases error rates (Cabrera, 2016; Crews &amp;amp;Russ, 2020). The purpose of this concept paper is to share research on multitasking and its effects on productivity and to assistwomen in making informed decisions about whether multitasking is a strategy or a pitfall for career advancement. We offerperspectives on why women multi-task, the challenges associated with multitasking and cultural differences to be considered. Weconducted a literature review and concluded that multitasking is the de facto coping strategy for most women in the modern-dayera given the competing demands on their time. We also suggested strategies for career advancement in professional andpersonal spaces.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-08-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/331</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v42.a331</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 42 (2023): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 80-87</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/331/365</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
