<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/586</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-01-05T18:28:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">"The Challenge is to Come to Work with a Smile": The Mentorship, Salary, and Relationships of Administrative Assistants in Higher Education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Listermann, Kelli</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Salinas, Cristobal</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Penna, Tamara</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Administrative assistants play a vital role in higher education institutions in the United States by supporting faculty, staff, and students in a variety of ways. Despite providing critical day-to-day duties, administrative assistants employed in higher education lack mentorship and are underpaid and overworked, contributing to job dissatisfaction. Counter to these demotivators, administrative assistants build and sustain rewarding relationships with students and peers. To better increase job satisfaction and retention of administrative assistants, higher education leaders should consider the following findings of this qualitative study using Herzberg’s Two-Factory Theory: lack of training and mentorship, being overworked and underpaid, and building relationships, all contribute to job satisfaction for administrative assistants in higher education in the United States.
Keywords: administrative staff experiences, higher education administrative assistants, job satisfaction </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/586</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v44.a586</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 44 No. 1 (2025): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 84-93</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/586/391</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
