<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/526</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-08-13T19:33:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Female Executives in the Sport Industry: An Interpretive Phenomenological Study</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hofferberth, Lindsay</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Babyak, Andrew</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The purpose of this qualitative, interpretative phenomenological study was to explore how executive women working in the sport industry described their lived experiences navigating challenges to attaining executive positions. The theoretical framework for this study was the Leadership Labyrinth, which is used to identify the unique and specific challenges women may face throughout their professional careers and personal lives. The study was guided by two research questions which asked how do executive women describe their lived experiences pertaining to gender bias while working in the sport industry and how do executive women in the sport industry described their lived experiences of overcoming challenges of gender bias in attaining executive positions? The sample consisted of 12 female executives in the sport industry in the United States. The primary method of data collection was a 60–90-minute open-ended interview, and the analysis method for this research study was Heidegger’s method of Interpretive Phenomenological Analysis. The results of this study identify the role gender bias plays in women’s careers. Other career inhibiting factors like work-life balance, double standards, societal gender roles, stereotypes, the need for male sponsors, men as decision makers, and the Queen Bee Syndrome were identified as unique challenges. The findings of this study also outline factors and techniques used to navigate and overcome the challenges associated with gender bias including personality type, a need for confidence, building relationships, and using gender as an advantage. This study provides a unique perspective and contributes to the overall body of work pertaining to the female experience in the sport industry.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-08-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/526</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v44.a526</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 44 No. 1 (2025): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 1-15</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/526/385</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
