<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/532</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-11-21T17:35:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Benefits and Challenges of Inhabiting the Dual Role of Mother/Leader</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hasson, Julie</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Money, Kimberly</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sikes, Olivia </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">What does it mean to be a good mother? What does it mean to be an effective school leader? These questions elicit a myriad of answers, illustrating the complex roles of mother and leader. The complexities are magnified for those who inhabit both roles. The purpose of this study was to understand the intersectionality of motherhood and educational leadership through the experiences of women who are mothers and leaders in a public school district in North Carolina. In this qualitative study using a phenomenological approach, a focus group was formed to explore participants’ experiences and perceptions of the benefits and conflicts inherent in maintaining the roles of mother and school leader as well as their perceptions of the non-dichotomous relationship of the two roles. Feminist standpoint theory and work/family border theory were utilized as frameworks to inform study design, data collection, and data analysis. Ideas around gendered roles as well as work/family balance were central in our efforts to  understand the lived experiences of each participant. Through  analysis of each focus group session, followed by an analysis across group sessions, three themes emerged: 1) emotional challenges 2) mother’s ways of leading, and 3) work-life balance.
 
Keywords: Mother/Leader, Women in School Leadership, Feminist Standpoint Theory, Intersection of Motherhood and Leadership</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-11-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/532</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v43.a532</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 43 (2024): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 107-116</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/532/381</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
