<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/534</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-08-13T19:33:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Emotional Labor and the Helper Identity: Student Affairs Mothers of Children with Disabilities</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McKinney, Kellie</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gischlar, Karen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Through a narrative portraiture lens, this qualitative study examines how women who work in student affairs, and have at least one child with at least one identified disability, describe emotional labor and strategies they utilize to navigate emotional labor. The findings of this study suggest that these women assume a “helper identity” across settings, which requires them to use emotional labor frequently in both their personal and professional lives. For many women, demands within the family system and the organizational culture of the workplace drive their need to “mask,” which ultimately influences overall satisfaction with home life and work performance. We provide higher educational leaders with practical and sustainable recommendations to transform organizational culture, policies, and practice. Findings indicate that these suggestions could reduce emotional labor for student affairs mothers with children with disabilities.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-08-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/534</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v44.a534</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 44 No. 1 (2025): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 30-43</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/534/387</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
