<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/80</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-28T01:05:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Using Classroom Community to Achieve Gender Equity in Online and Face-to-Face Graduate Classes</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Polnick, Barbara</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ritter, Carol</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fink, Raymond</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The purpose of this study was to determine the degree to which graduate students' perceptions of classroom community in their online and face-to-face classes differed based on gender. Students participating in the study were generally from urban, suburban, and rural school districts in Southwest Texas. All students (144) who were pursuing a master's degree in educational leadership using either face-to-face or online format in the fall semester, 2008 were emailed a survey. Of the 126 surveys returned (88%), 102 participants were selected for this study based on completion of data. Perceptions were measured using the Classroom Community Scale (CCS), which included three measures: Total classroom community, connectedness, and learning. Classroom community in both online and face-to-face classes was evaluated by students who were enrolled during the fall semester, 2008. It was found that after implementing classroom community elements, there were no statistically significant differences in the perceived total classroom community, connectedness, and learning of male and female students attending both face-to-face and online classes. The study also found that there were no statistically significant differences in the perceived total classroom community, connectedness, and learning of male and female students attending only online classes and for those attending only face-to-face classes. Findings suggest that by providing elements of a positive classroom community, university instructors can better meet the needs of male and female graduate students, thus eliminating any potential gender inequities in both face-to-face and online classes.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/80</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v31.a80</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 31 (2011); 213-222</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/80/68</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
