<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/172</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-07-03T17:57:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Women Faculty in Higher Education: Impeded by Academe</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Christman, Dana E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper attempts to synthesize literature available regarding the status of women faculty in the academy and barriers that hinder their success. First, a short treatise of the historical and sociological perspectives of women in higher education is provided. The institutional structure, culture and climate in postsecondary institutions will be examined. Particular attention will be paid to such structural issues as hiring practices, salary, tenure, research, service, and teaching and advising loads, while intradepartmental relations, socialization and mentoring patterns, isolation, research support, and financial resources and child care will be covered under climate and cultural issues. Both the experiences of the collectivity of women as well as individual women will also be portrayed. Findings from the literature suggest that gender inequity is still a practice of the present, rather than a part of the academy's past. Finally, suggestions for improving the chances for women's success in the academy will be provided.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/172</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v14.a172</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 14 (2003 Fall); 5-12</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/172/152</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
