<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/411</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-01-11T23:57:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Organization Development and Effectiveness: Essential Female Leadership Competencies for Industry 4.0 Transformation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chuang, Szufang</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Eversole, Barbara</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper summarizes and synthesizes research evidence on different women leadership characteristics and behaviors from men and identifies essential female leadership competencies that are necessary to address the new challenges of today’s workplace and the paradigm shifts for female leaders to remain competitive in Industry 4.0. Recent neuroscience and social science research findings regarding women’s leadership characteristics and behaviors were reviewed and discussed. Critical leadership traits, abilities, and skills for (international) business success were studied. Six essential female leadership skill sets for Industry 4.0 were then proposed to provide human resource development practitioners a strategic framework that will be necessary for women leadership development and to promote gender equality in the workplace. Some feminine traits can be women’s leadership strengths such as sensing, listening, accepting, approaching, collaborating, supporting, and encouraging skills. Finally, implications for human resource development and recommendations for future research were provided.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/411</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v41.a411</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 41 No. 1 (2022): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 37-49</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/411/306</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
