<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/377</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-12-02T00:43:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">WOMEN IN THE WORK PLACE – AN EMPIRICAL ANALYSIS OF THE CHALLENGE OF WORK LOAD</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wani, Ambreen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ahmad, Mufeed</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Female employment has witnessed a drastic paradigm shift. Several factors like improving literacy, change is the socio-economic scenario, zest for financial independence and ambition; are responsible for this changing trend. Being the largest employer of women in India, education sector is witnessing drastic changes. The present study examines Work-Life Balance of women working in various universities of J&amp;amp;K with emphasis on work pressure the females face in the course of trying to balance their professional life with their personal life.
Investigation shows that most working women are upset with the amount of work-load in the universities. Women who work for longer hours tend to be more dissatisfied with their Work-Life Balance. The study strongly suggests that academic expectations must be attuned with the demands of a woman’s personal life or else a woman can never give her best.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-05-04</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/377</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v40.a377</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 40 No. 1 (2021): Advancing Women in Leadership; 49-55</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/377/295</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
