<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/276</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-14T00:59:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Women, Organizational Development, and the New Science of Happiness</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Milhouse, Virginia H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Do people need a lot of money or wealth to be happy?  Some social scientists say no.   Once people get beyond having their basic needs met, making more money does little to raise the sense of satisfaction (Diener &amp;amp; Seligman, 2002).  What, then, makes people happy?  According to a new science of happiness, authentic happiness centers on conditions that enable people to flourish in their lives (Seligman, 2003).  When asked what conditions brought them the greatest source of happiness, more than 900 women said their greatest sense of happiness came from their children, religious or spiritual life, family connections and friendships, contributing to the lives of others, and leisure and holiday time (Diener &amp;amp; Seligman, 2002).   Further, research reported in the Miller, Caldwell, and Lawson (2000), the Sloane Business Review (1991), and by the Business Women's Network (2002) reveals that many professional working women, if given the option, would choose flextime, spending time with family, and helping others over making more money.  Other studies show women want friendly and supportive work environments and are, therefore, working with organizational leaders to achieve them.  In fact, a recent article, The Opt-Out Revolution, reports that because the corporate world has not enabled conditions that help women flourish, many are unhappy and many others are leaving the traditional corporate world altogether (Belkin, 2003).  Thus, while some studies suggest that women are leaving the workplace only for reasons such as maternity leaves or day care problems, this paper suggests that although “motherhood” is very important to women, it is not just about this.  Social scientists such as Gallos (1989), Ehrenreich (1995), and Hall (1986) say this trend is more about conditions that impede women’s satisfaction with the workplace.  Therefore, this study seeks to know more about the conditions which can impede or enhance women’s happiness in the workplace.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/276</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v21.a276</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 21 (2006 Summer)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/276/349</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
