<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/296</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-03-03T02:32:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Leadership Discourse Amongst Female Police Leaders in Sweden</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Österlind, Malin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Haake, Dr. Ulrika</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Female leaders within the police force in Sweden are in a minority. Although their numbers are increasing, little is known about their experiences. By using interviews and discourse analysis, this article aims to analyse and construct the leadership discourse articulated by female leaders within the Swedish Police. It is argued here, as in previous research, that female leaders experience a range of different aspects in their roles as leaders. The female leadership discourse within the police is constructed around five themes of discussion: (a) the leadership style of good leaders is generally a transformational one; (b) a transactional approach to leadership is visible in relation to crisis situations; (c) extensive experience as a police officer is of importance; (d) leaders need support in different ways, and (e) experiences of being a "˜token' female in a male-dominated organisation is common. Above all, this article challenges the notion that a "˜feminine leadership style' exists. It is also argued that an intersectional perspective on police leadership is preferable, and that co-workers have an impact on leadership processes.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-02</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/296</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v30.a296</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 30 (2010)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/296/265</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
