<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/227</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-15T21:35:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">WOMEN AS LEADERS: PIECING TOGETHER THEIR REFLECTIONS ON LIFE AND THE PRINCIPALSHIP</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Colflesh, Nancy Anne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Just as the women who, for generations, worked alone and together to piece together the scraps and remains of former clothing to provide warm coverings for their family members, were not acknowledged as legitimate artists until the women's movement, women leaders have not, until more recently, been acknowledged as legitimate leaders in organizations. Some writers have noted that there is a new paradigm of leadership developing in contemporary organizations, due partly to the strengths that women are realizing they bring to the workplace. The paradigm has been there for some time, but there is now enough of a critical mass of women in formal organizations and unique entrepreneurial efforts that the effects of that paradigm are being felt (Bancroft, 1995; Lee, 1994). Called "the subtle revolution," the increase in numbers of executive and management women has changed, and will continue to change, the attitudes and actions of organizations (Helgesen, 1990; Leavitt, 1988; Towery, 1998). This need reinforces Harding's (1987) position that, until the less powerful raise their voices to articulate their experiences, all leaders and their organizations will not benefit or gain perspective from those experiences. Undoubtedly, attention must be paid to the need for leadership theory that acknowledges and incorporates women's experiences and perspectives (Helgesen, 1990; Regan &amp;amp; Brooks, 1995; Shakeshaft, 1989; Waggoner, 1998).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/227</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v6.a227</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 3, No. 1 = No. 6 (2000 Winter)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/227/204</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
