<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/599</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-29T15:30:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Tentacles of Trauma: Gender Bias-Induced Trauma and Its Contribution to Women Attorneys Leaving Their Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Alexander, Stacy</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rogers, Gimel</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The purpose of this study was to explore whether gender bias induces trauma and whether it is a factor in women attorneys leaving their legal practice. The American Psychological Association (n.d.) defines trauma as a deeply distressing or disturbing experience that overwhelms a person’s ability to cope and leaves lasting emotional, psychological, or physical effects. Traumatic events include those caused by human behavior (e.g., rape, war, industrial accidents) as well as by nature (e.g., earthquakes) and often challenge an individual’s view of the world as a just, safe, and predictable place. This may be one of the first quantitative studies to establish a correlation between trauma and workplace gender bias with inferential statistics regarding its impact on job turnover in the legal profession, as there is limited research in this specific area. Based on previous research that links identity trauma with gender bias by Cherry and Wilcox (2020) and research showing gender bias in the workplace can lead to job dissatisfaction and turnover by Diehl et al. (2020), the authors tailored research questions to determine whether gender bias experiences would positively correlate to trauma, and whether the resulting gender bias-induced trauma would positively correlate to attrition from legal practice. The participants were 275 attorneys who identified as female and practiced law within the United States (n = 275). Expanding on the Gender Bias Scale by Diehl et al. (2021), this study employed a cross-sectional survey design using a self-administered online questionnaire to collect quantitative data for exploratory correlational analyses of gender bias and trauma, and their impact on turnover. There was partial support for both research questions. Almost 90% (n = 247) of the participants responded affirmatively to trauma symptoms due to gender-bias incidents in their workplaces. Of those who endorsed trauma symptoms, most attributed the trauma as a reason for leaving (43.80%) or contemplating leaving a position (34.90%), their practice, a position, or the field of law. Specific gender-based barriers have been identified from this data that human resource personnel and bias training programs can target to minimize trauma symptoms and enhance the retention of women attorneys.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/599</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v45.a599</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 45 No. 1 (2026): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal ; 1-15</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/599/404</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
