<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/249</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-15T00:27:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Educating for Social Justice: The Life and Times of Septima Clark in Review</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hines III, Mack T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reed, Dianne</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One of the most important goals of teacher education programs is to train preservice teachers on how to teach for social justice (Atweh, Kemmis, &amp;amp; Weeks, 1998). Educating for social justice is teaching people how to make just and democratic contributions to their communities and society. Many teacher education programs use Jean Piaget's (1963), Lev Vygotsky's (1978), and other male theorists' learning theories to convey this idea to students. Scant research shows how these programs provide minority groups' perspectives on social justice education. This paper fills these voids by highlighting Septima Clark's (1898- 1987) endeavors of teaching for social justice. Septima Clark (1962) was a famous South Carolina educator and Civil Rights leader who used reading and writing to enhance African-American leaders. A lifelong learner, she combined her daily life experiences with the fundamentals of reading and writing to teach African-Americans how to become informed citizens of their communities. During this process, she continuously evolved and elevated her personal and professional philosophy of how to empower other people to change society. As such, her life and legacy bears significant implications for preparing preservice teachers to become lifelong leaders of graduating value-added, needs-satisfying citizens of society.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/249</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v22.a249</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 23 (2007 Winter)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/249/225</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
