<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/343</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-10-27T01:33:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Journey of Women Entrepreneurs for Two decades: A Meta-analytical review</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aggarwal, Ansita</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study meta-analytically consolidates results from two decades of women entrepreneurship research. The objective of this study is to make an index of challenges, factors affecting challenges and moderators from the past studies. Tables are also drawn which would briefly disclose all of them in a meticulous manner. The Principal Component Analysis (PCA) test is run on all those tables to determine the factors which are the consequential or principal one of all. Findings are relevant for practitioners (educators, policy makers) and for future research. The findings of this research would be of utmost use for the researchers who would like to carry their research forward on the same line. It will support them in recognizing a concise number of challenges and factors affecting those challenges which needs to be taken as the foundation for any future research. This research also helps in identifying all the significant moderating variables from past studies.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-07-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/343</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v39.a343</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 39: Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 13-20</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/343/293</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
