<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/160</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-06-15T21:40:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Mentoring Females and Minorities into Higher Education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Patterson, Janice</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dahle, Karen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nix, Mary</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Collins, Loucrecia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abbott, Gypsy</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Whether we see through the lens of gender or ethnicity, the perception of self defines our work. The loss of women and people of color from tenure earning positions in higher education argues for more productive initiatives if we are to attract, retain, and promote female and minority faculty (Howard-Vital &amp;amp; Morgan, 1993). The literature overwhelmingly supports the benefits of mentoring in easing the loneliness and confusion that can derail women and people of color in higher education (Howard-Vital &amp;amp; Morgan).
Descriptions of mentoring in professional literature suggest that the relationships between individuals that perpetuate traditional academic culture. Professional guidance includes assistance with research and writing, teaching, service, and grant writing. Social support includes shared outings and recreational activities. Few empirical studies exist on mentoring among faculty in academic settings. Qualitative research offers thick descriptions of some programs, e.g., the work in Colorado that investigated faculty mentoring in schools, colleges, and departments of education (Goodwin, Stevens, &amp;amp; Bellamy, 1998) and the faculty-mentoring program at Montclair State University (Pierce, 1998).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/160</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v12.a160</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 12, No. 1 = No. 12 (2002 Fall)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/160/140</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 Advancing Women in Leadership</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
