<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/385</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-04-07T19:11:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Factors Impacting Female Senior Enlisted Leaders’ Representation in the U.S. Army’s Basic Combat Training Units</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Dr. Allison </dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fyock, Dr. James</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Godette-Baker, Dr. Carole</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Idleman, Dr. Lynda</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This qualitative study explored the lived experiences of 10 retired female senior enlisted leaders assigned as first sergeant (1SG) and command sergeant major (CSM) in initial entry training (IET) to ascertain if their experiences shed light on the underrepresentation of female leaders in the basic combat training (BCT) environment. Data collection emphasized factors that led to success in the IET environment, as well as challenges and barriers they faced. The theoretical framework underpinning this study included the social role theory, which holds that the expectations for men and women are based on sex differences that regulate behaviour in an adult’s work and family life, and the role congruity theory of prejudice toward female leaders, which suggests women do not reach top-level positions because they are less capable than men and because women are judged more harshly when they are in leadership roles. Having to prove oneself, reaction to female leadership, family obligations, and fighting stereotypes emerged as barriers and challenges. Attributes needed for success in the IET BCT environment included Army values and toughness and tenacity. Coding of positions and male perception of female leaders emerged as barriers that preventfemales from attaining 1SG and CSM in the BCT environment. The findings support the social role theory and role congruity theory of prejudice toward female leaders. The results extend research on the representation of women in senior leadership positions because they illuminate female leaders in a nontraditional educational environment in the largest branch of the U.S. military.
Keywords: women, leaders, U.S. Army, basic combat training, glass ceiling, women in leadership; leadership theories</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/385</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v44.a385</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 44 No. 1 (2025): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 15-29</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/385/386</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
