<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/561</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-01-01T07:25:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Editorial Overview: Exploring Leadership, Mentorship, and Gender in Academia: Insights from Recent Research</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Irby, Beverly</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Abdelrahman, Nahed</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ballenger, Julia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rodriguez, Sonia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hall, Kristina</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">De Witt, Melissa</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The 2024 Volume of Advancing Women in Leadership Journal (AWLJ) includes researchers from around the world. They are from Canada (Ontario and British Columbia), the Philippines, Australia, and the United States, including California, Maryland, New York, North Carolina, and Ohio, and the work that is published here also highlights women from these locations and Trinidad and Ghana. These researchers dealt with structural impediments to women’s opportunities, highlighting the transformative power of mentorship, resilience, and targeted strategies against professional obstacles. This is a valuable collection because it underlines how gendered expectations, cultural biases, and organizational structures continue to be essential factors in the construction of women's leadership experiences. Yet it also points out some novel approaches, such as informal and peer mentoring, narrative inquiry, and digital advocacy, reflecting the potent role of collective action and relational support in promoting better levels of empowerment and equity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-01-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/561</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v43.a561</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 43 No. 2 (2024): Mentoring Women Girls in Leadership in East Africa; i-ii</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/561/384</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
