<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/555</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-12-22T20:43:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>awl:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Exploring the Source of Leadership Self-Efficacy among Japanese Female High School Student-Athletes through Sport Experiences</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mikura, Akane</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Takezawa, Mika</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ogasawara, Etsuko</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To apply self-efficacy theory to identify the sport-related themes and the processes through which they influence leadership self-efficacy (LSE) among Japanese female high school student-athletes. Method: Focus group and one -on-one interviews were conducted with 30 female high school student-athletes aged 16-17. A grounded theory approach (GTA), which allows the generation of theory from participants’ narratives, was employed to extend self-efficacy theory within the sport context. Result: We identified four categories that impact LSE: (a) leadership experience, (b) feedback on leadership behavior, (c) observation of leaders, and (d) sport performance level. Implication: These findings of this study contribute to the development of leadership education programs for girls through sport, helping to address the underrepresentation of female leaders in Japan.
Keywords: leadership development; female student-athletes; leadership self-efficacy; sport leadership</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Education Leadership Research Center, Texas A&amp;M University</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/awlj-v44.a555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; Vol. 44 No. 1 (2025): Advancing Women in Leadership Journal; 72-83</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1093-7099</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://awl-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/awl/article/view/555/390</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Advancing Women in Leadership Journal</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
