<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/196</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:15:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pharmacodynamics of Ca⁺⁺ Channel Blocking Drugs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Allert, J. Allen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Adams, Richard H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calcium channel blocking drugs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cardiovascular disorders</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cardiomyopathy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tachyarrhythmia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calcium overload</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Pharmacologic agents that selectively inhibit the influx of Ca⁺⁺ through voltage-regulated cell membrane channels in excitable tissues represent a new pharmacodynamic approach to the therapy of cardiovascular disorders. These drugs, the Ca⁺⁺ channel blocking agents, have established important therapeutic niches in human medicine in the management of angina pectoris and certain types of cardiac arrhythmias. A rapidly expanding body of evidence indicates that these compounds may also exert beneficial actions in various cardiovascular-related disorders important in veterinary medicine including some forms of shock, trauma, cardiomyopathy, and supraventricular tachyarrhythmias. Hypothetically, beneficial responses of ischemic tissue to Ca⁺⁺ channel blockade can be explained by either a direct reduction of pathologic Ca⁺⁺ overload in injured cells or, indirectly, by vasodilatation and hemodynamic improvement in tissue perfusion-oxygen demand relationships. Many issues remain unresolved, however, and recent studies have questioned the routine use of these drugs in certain clinical situations. The propensity for cardiodepressant and hypotensive actions of Ca⁺⁺ channel blockade may be particularly enhanced in patients with preexisting or occult loss of myocardial contractile reserves, and appropriate caveats should now be established. Although interest in the Ca⁺⁺ channel blocking drugs is high, their pharmacodynamic complexities must be carefully assessed to ensure their appropriate incorporation into veterinary therapeutics.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/196</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fifth Biennial Symposium; 79-88</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/196/186</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
