<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/20</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-25T02:45:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Drug Testing in Livestock Show Animals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mays, Travis</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fajt, Virginia</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug testing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">analytical chemistry</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug residues</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Livestock shows and county fairs utilize drug testing programs to ensure animal welfare and fairness among exhibitors. TVMDL has served as a drug testing laboratory for many programs since 1999. Summarizing test data could provide trends about the evolution of drug testing over the last seventeen years. The authors are not aware of any similar published data on drug testing in livestock show animals.Drug analysis was performed by various methods over the years, including thin layer chromatography (TLC), enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), gas chromatography – mass spectrometry (GC-MS) and liquid chromatography – mass spectrometry (LC-MS). Sample matrices tested included urine, serum, feces, retina, liver, kidney, and muscle tissue. Animal species included cattle, sheep, goats, pigs, horses, chickens, turkeys and rabbits. More than 30,800 drug tests have been performed on show animals at TVMDL since 1999. The total number of tests performed annually ranged from 154 to 3,507. The mean annual number of tests performed by species was 452 bovine tests, 301 caprine tests, 294 ovine, 468 porcine, 99 chickens and turkeys, 14 equine, and 12 rabbits. The annual percent positive (% POS) rate ranged from approximately one to 16%. The mean % POS from 1999 – 2014 was approximately 3%. In 2015, drug screening was transitioned from TLC and ELISA to LC-MS which significantly increased detection sensitivity. As a result, the mean % POS from 2015 – 2016 was approximately 15%. The most frequently confirmed drugs since 1999 were ractopamine, flunixin, dexamethasone, zilpaterol, sulfamethazine, and caffeine.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/20</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/20/20</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
