<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/184</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S8</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Therapeutic Management of Cardiovascular Disorders in Small Animals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Knauer, Kenneth W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mitral insufficiency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dogs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cardiovascular disorders</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">digitalis glycosides</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the dog the incidence of cardiovascular disorders is ten percent. Of these, 90% have acquired heart disease and 10% have congenital heart defects. The most common acquired lesion of the heart in dogs is mitral valve insufficiency. This is an aging change during which mucopolysaccharide is deposited in the valve leaflets and they become fibrotic with rolled-back free borders. The chordae tendinae supporting the valve also are involved and undergo shortening, thickening and fibrosis. In addition, the papillary muscles attached to the chordae tendinae undergo a microscopic intramural myocardial infarction process which may alter their function. Therefore, the whole "mitral valve apparatus" is affected progressively with aging in the dog to produce increasing mitral regurgitation into the left atrium. The consequence of this is the production of left atrial enlargement, increased pulmonary venous pressure and eventually pulmonary edema. Left ventricular dilatation due to volume overload and left atrial endocardial splitting may also be present late in the syndrome. &amp;nbsp;
The medical management of mitral insufficiency is an area that has taken a dramatic turnabout in recent years. In the past, these dogs were medicated with digitalis glycosides, some as soon as a murmur was detected, others when they went into left heart failure. With the advent of diagnostic ultrasound we have learned that almost all dogs in early mitral insufficiency have no inotropic deficits. Most of those in the moderate, and some in the early severe category, do not either. We now feel that it is contraindicated to use digitalis glycosides in the early and moderate mitral insufficiency case. By potentially increasing the positive inotropy (this doesn't happen in all cases), we are increasing the regurgitant fraction through the mitral valve. The left atrium is further enlarged causing increased pressure on the left mainstem bronchus and potentially producing more left atrial endocardial splitting. The possibility of rupture of a primary chordae tendinae is increased and if this happens, acute fulminating pulmonary edema is the consequence, often with fatal results. It has been shown that dogs with mitral insufficiency but normal heart rates, when treated with digitalis glycosides, lived a shorter time than similar dogs who were treated with rest and diuretics alone.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/184</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 231-244</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/184/176</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
