<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/64</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T19:15:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pharmacokinetics and Impact of Nonsteroidal Anti-Inflammatory Drugs on Biomarkers of Pain and Inflammation at Piglet Castration</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nixon, Emma</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Routh, Patricia A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hernandez, Liliana</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baynes, Ronald E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Messenger, Kristen</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Piglet</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Castration/Processing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Pain</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">NSAID</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Pharmacokinetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Piglet processing (including castration/tail-docking) is routinely performed in the US without analgesia. Pain medications, predominately NSAIDs, are used in the EU/Canada to decrease pain associated with processing and improve piglet welfare. The efficacy and required dose are unknown. This study assessed efficacy and pharmacokinetics of three NSAIDs (meloxicam, flunixin and ketoprofen) in piglets undergoing routine processing. Five-day-old male piglets (8/group) received one of 5 randomized treatments; intramuscular saline (SAL CAST), meloxicam (MLX; 0.4mg/kg), flunixin (FLU; 2.2mg/kg), ketoprofen (KETO; 3mg/kg) or sham (SAL SHAM; saline injection, no processing). Two hours post-dose, piglets underwent processing. Drug concentrations were quantified in plasma and interstitial fluid (ISF). Cortisol/prostaglandin E2 (PGE2) were quantified in plasma/ISF, respectively. Plasma Tmax and T1/2 of meloxicam, flunixin and (S-)-ketoprofen were 1.21, 0.85 and 0.59h and 4.39, 7.69 and 3.50h, respectively. ISF Tmax were 2.81 and 3.64h for meloxicam and flunixin. SAL CAST cortisol was significantly (p=0.0031) higher than SAL SHAM at processing (2h post-dose), suggesting that the procedure, rather than handling, greatly increased cortisol and is indicative of pain/stress. Cortisol was significantly (p=0.0488) lower in FLU piglets compared to SAL CAST at processing. While no significant differences were shown between treatments for PGE2 in ISF, all NSAIDs decreased PGE2 compared to SAL CAST, and only flunixin maintained inhibition beyond 24h post-dose. Results confirm processing is painful and NSAIDs reduce cortisol/PGE2 post-processing. Flunixin better controls pain in piglets compared to other NSAIDs, and administration prior to processing would improve piglet health and welfare in the US.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/64</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 21st Biennial Symposium; 45</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/64/59</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
