<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/110</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:33:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S5</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Hormonal Induction of Lactation in Nonpregnant Dairy Cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bauman, D. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Collier, R. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lactation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk production</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hormonal induction</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk synthesis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Scientists have been attempting to induce lactation in dairy cows for over 40 years. In general, the studies involved long periods of hormone administration and low rates of success. Recently Ors. E. L. Smith and F. L. Schanbacher made the dramatic observation that a 7-day treatment with an estrogen and progesterone caused the mammary glands of nonpregnant nonlactating cows to fill with secretion. Since this original observation, our knowledge has progressed rapidly to where a relatively simple treatment allows the induction of copious milk production in nonpregnant dairy cows.
The hormonal induction of lactation in dairy cows is not approved for commercial dairy herd operations. If approved for commercial application it could be selectively utilized for cows with reproductive problems. National dairy records indicate that dairymen cull approximately 25-35% of their cows each year because of reproductive problems. Since reproductive problems tend to increase as individual cows achieve higher levels of milk production and as herd size becomes larger one would anticipate that this will continue to be a very significant problem in the future. As will be discussed subsequently, approximately 60% of these "problem breeders” successfully conceive and complete a normal pregnancy when bred during the induced lactation. Although it would not be an alternative to a sound management program, the hormonal induction of lactation in nonpregnant cows could be selectively used as a management tool with problem breeders of superior genetic potential for milk production.
A second ramification of studies to hormonally induce lactation in dairy cows is that these investigations yield insight into the factors involved in regulation of nutrient utilization for milk synthesis. As this process becomes understood many exciting possibilities exist for future application. These may include identification of new and more accurate selection devices to use in assessing an animal’s genetic potential for milk production and/or identifying means to alter the mammary tissue environment to allow maximum milk production. Perhaps this knowledge could even be utilized for inducing lactation in other animal species in which various maladies leading to agalactia is of catistrophic importance to survival of the nursing young.
In the following sections we will characterize the Estradiol-Progesterone treatment to induce lactation and the subsequent modifications which have markedly improved the lactational performance of induced cows.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/110</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 427-441</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/110/104</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
