<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/163</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Current Approaches to Internal Parasite Control in Small Animals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roberson, Edward L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Parasite Control</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dog</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">transmission</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hookworms</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ascarids</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">treatment</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Treatment of young dogs for parasites routinely has been done following weaning, i.e. when the pup is 7 to 8 weeks of age. The typical pattern is for a litter of pups to be disbursed to new owners after weaning and the pup is taken to a veterinary clinic for the first time at 7 to 8 weeks of age for its vaccinations and deworming. Flotation of feces at this time almost invariably reveals eggs of the common ascarid, Toxocara canis, and usually shows eggs of the common hookworm, Ancylostoma caninum.
How have pups acquired these infections? Environmental contamination? Prenatally via the uterus of the mother? Lactationally via the milk of the mother? Earlier studies concerning prenatal and lactational transmission of hookworms and ascarids to pups have been reviewed by Burke and Roberson. In spite of the investigative attention to bitch-to-pup transmission of these parasites, the relative importance of each of these two routes remained in question. We were able to quantitate the importance of prenatal and lactational transmission of these parasites to pups in a recent study in which we found that ascarids (T. canis) were transmitted to pups both prenatally (98.5%) and lactationally (1.5%) and that hookworms (A. caninum) were transmitted to pups only through the bitch's milk.
What does this mean concerning the necessity for treatment of young pups? It means they need to be treated early while still nursing. Ascarid larvae (L₂ stage) which have prenatally invaded the fetus will be located in the liver of the pup at birth. From the liver, they will pass via the circulatory system to the lungs, break into the respiratory passage and ascend the respiratory tree from which they get into the pharynx and are swallowed. They can grow in the digestive tract to egg-laying adults by the time the pup is 4 weeks of age. A pup with a heavy ascarid burden at this age will show the typical pot-bellied appearance. The earlier lung phase of migration may be fatal to heavily infected pups when they are but 2 days of age. Hookworms acquired as 3rd stage larvae in the first milk a pup takes from its infected mother will develop to patency by the time the pup is 2 weeks of age. Heavy hookworm infections may be fatal to pups before they reach 3 weeks of age.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/163</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 63-69</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/163/155</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
