<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/93</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:33:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Problem of Adverse Drug Reactions in Veterinary Therapeutics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Teske, Richard H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harvey, Terence</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Animal drugs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">toxicity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">therapeutic value</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug reaction</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"All things are poisons, for there is nothing without poisonous qualities. It is only the dose which makes a thing a poison” - Paracelus.
Animal drugs may be divided into 2 major categories: (1) those intended to have a pharmacological effect on the animal body such as hormones, anesthetics, tranqulizers, etc; and (2) those compounds used to kill or suppress growth of bacteria, protozoa, and internal or external parasites.
Toxicity in the first group is a function of their pharmacological (either primary or secondary) activity. It should be noted that what is an adverse response under one set of circumstances may under other conditions represent the desired pharmacological effect. Toxicity may result from an enhancement of effect caused by increased dosage (overdosage) or from increased sensitivity (hypersensitivity), to the drug's action. The “toxic” effect may also be a manifestation of pharmacological effects of the drug other than that for which the drug is being administered. Again, the adverse effect may result from enhancement of a side effect by overdosage, either actual (as in an error in dosage) or relative (as a result of increased sensitivity to the drug's side effects).
With respect to the second group, the therapeutic value of such drugs is based upon their selective toxicity for the pathogenic invader. As a result of the specificity of effect such drugs (antibiotics for example) often enjoy a wide margin of safety. Those adverse reactions which do occur following administration of these drugs have often been ascribed to allergic reactions or cytotoxic changes occurring as a result of repeated treatment. There is considerable evidence, however, to show, that under certain circumstances, such drugs can elicit acute pharmacological effects unrelated to immune phenomena or to cytotoxic lesions.
It should be noted that only a small percentage of drug-induced changes are beneficial in that they normalize pathological functions, alleviate disease symptoms or combat infection. All other drug effects are either meaningless, undesirable or harmful.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/93</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 113-123</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/93/87</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
