<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/175</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S5</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Current Chemotherapeutic Management of Small Animal Neoplasia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Barton, Claudia L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">chemotherapeutic treatment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">canine testing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">palliation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">chemotherapeutic agents</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There are two major objectives of the chemotherapeutic treatment of cancer: palliation and cure. In some human malignancies, a cure is now possible solely with the use of chemotherapy; these tumors include seminoma, choriocarcinoma, Wilm's tumor and acute lymphocytic leukemia of childhood. In other tumors, cure can be achieved with the use of chemotherapy as an adjuvant measure to surgery, radiation or hormonal treatment. Tumors in this category include osteosarcoma and mammary adenocarcinoma. Many tumors are less sensitive to the effects of currently available drugs; palliation of disease is achieved for a variable period of time, with cure being rare. Examples of tumors in this category would be the gastrointestinal malignancies and most adult-onset lymphoid and hematologic tumors. In some forms of cancer, no cure or prolongation of life has yet been achieved with chemotherapy. Drug therapy is of little value, for example, in the treatment of bronchogenic carcinoma and pancreatic adenocarcinoma; both tumors progress relentlessly despite aggressively applied drug regimens. It is apparent that, in working to achieve a chemotherapeutic cure for cancer, one must first learn to palliate before one can learn to cure. Drugs must be discovered which are effective against a particular tumor cell type.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/175</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 163-168</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/175/168</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
