<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/32</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T18:18:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Preliminary Population Pharmacokinetics of Meloxicam in Lion (Panthera leo), Cheetah (Acinonyx jubatus), and Tiger (Panthera tigris)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Visser, Marike</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bronson, Ellen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boothe, Dawn M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">meloxicam</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">population pharmacokinetic</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cheetah</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tiger</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatories (NSAIDS) are a group of drugs commonly used in the treatment of both acute and chronic inflammation and pain in human and veterinary medicine. The most common meloxicam indications in non-domestic felids include control of both acute pain, such as post-operative, as well as chronic pain from degenerative osteoarthritis. Very limited information is available regarding efficacy, safety and adverse events in non-domestic felids. The purpose of this study was to compare and contrast the population pharmacokinetics (PPK) between lion (Panthera leo; n=22), cheetah (Acinonyx jubatus; n=9) and tiger (Panthera tigris; n=6). At their respective zoological institute, each subject received a dose of oral meloxicam (0.1-0.2mg/kg), and up to three blood samples collected at 2-4hrs, 8-12hrs, and 20-24 hours. An appropriate PPK model established based on the AIC and 2-LLC score. In lions, the maximum concentration (Cmax) was 817.9ng/ml at a time (Tmax) of 2.1hr, and a half-life (t1/2) of 5.92hr. In cheetah, Cmax was 1412.14ng/ml at a Tmax of 10.03 hrs, and t1/2 was 8.11hrs. Tiger Cmax was 613.7ng/ml at Tmax of 2hr, and t1/2 was 6.31hr. The absorption in cheetahs appears slower compared to lion and tiger, but they can reach higher therapeutic concentrations. All three species were able to achieve therapeutic concentrations based on the domestic felid pain model. However, cheetahs may take longer to reach therapeutic efficacy due to the prolonged absorption time. This is the first use of PPK and sparse data collection to report pharmacokinetics in non-domestic felids.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/32</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/32/31</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
