<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/237</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SII</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Biochemical Assays for Residue Analysis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">O'Rangers, John J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">rapid screening tests</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug residues</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">test performance</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The growth in applications of biochemical methods of analysis began in 1959 with the introduction of radioimmunoassay by Berson and Yalow in the United States and Roger Ekins in England. Since its introduction in 1959, radioimmunoassay has evolved from an esoteric research technique to a widely used tool in laboratory medicine. Although radioimmunoassay will continue to be extensively used, the rate of growth of the RIA market appears to be slowing with the so-called "non-isotopic" or more accurately, "non-nuclidic" immunoassays coming into wide use. The commercial outlook for these "non-nuclidic" procedures is quite rosy. It is expected that the immunoassay and microbiology portions of the total clinical products market will grow to 15%-23% of the total market by 1990.
In the veterinary diagnostic area, it is estimated that the market for antibody based veterinary diagnostic tests will rise from the current 1.5 million per year to over 60 million by 1990. It is particularly interesting that of 105 new biotechnology companies that have been formed, 40% are in the hybridoma, monoclonal area, with the biggest commitment being in the pharmaceutical area. It is quite likely that not only will new pharmaceutical products be forthcoming but the associated immunochemical methods of analysis will also be available.
I think it is evident that biochemical methods of analysis, especially ligand assay techniques, offer many potential advantages for the screening and monitoring of veterinary drugs and residues. However, the reliable application of rapid biochemical tests can be compromised if the test methods exhibit inconsistent performance. For example, a residue screening test that has an excessive false positive rate would result in unnecessary withdrawal or retention of marketable product. Typically, samples testing positive would be submitted to further laboratory analysis for confirmation of screening test results and a false positive rate would result in the unnecessary expenditure of analytical resources. In many cases, residue screening methods will be used in field environment by persons not specifically trained in chemical analysis and associated quality assurance procedures. It is essential that tests used in this milieu be analytically rugged and not exhibit reagent instability.
These are two examples that indicate that rapid screening tests for residues should meet rigorous performance criteria. Indeed, given the intended use of screening tests, I believe it can be argued that screening test performance criteria be among the most rigorous applied to analytical methods.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/237</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 51-54</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/237/220</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
