<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/87</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:34:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Factors Influencing Drug Disposition in the Body: Biopharmaceutics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bourne, David W. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">absorption</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">distribution</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">metabolism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">excretion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug concentration</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Once a drug is introduced into a living animal it is subjected to a number of processes which act together to alter the disposition of the drug. These processes can be classified into four fundamental directions. These are the ADME processes of absorption, distribution, metabolism, and excretion, Figure 1. The drug must first be absorbed into the body. It is during the absorption process that drug product inequivalence may markedly influence the amount of drug which is absorbed and the rate at which the drug is absorbed. There are also a number of physiologic factors which can influence the absorption of a drug. The drug will be distributed within body fluids and tissues entering receptor sites to elicit pharmacologic effects or storage sites thereby affecting the duration of action. Many drugs are metabolized in the body, chiefly in the liver, and thereby inactivated and made ready for the final step, excretion. Other drugs are excreted intact and finally removed from the body. These four processes occur simultaneously and thereby cause the concentration of a drug in the various body fluids and tissues to vary constantly. Factors which influence even one process can have a dramatic effect on the overall disposition of a drug.
The aim of drug therapy is to maintain an effective drug concentration at the site of action. However, the body is continually trying to remove the drug and thereby reduce its effect. A thorough knowledge of the factors effecting drug disposition will allow the optimization of drug therapy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/87</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 14-28</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/87/81</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
