<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/29</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T18:13:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Investigation of Phylogenetics, Multilocus Sequence Typing, Virulence Genotype and Antimicrobial Resistance of Canine Uropathogenic Escherichia coli Isolates</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thungrat, Kamoltip</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boothe, Dawn M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">E. coli</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">infection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dogs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">virulence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">MLST</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">E. coli associated urinary tract infections (UTI) that cause varying severities of clinical signs, ranging from absent to severe, are based on the presence of selected virulence factors. In humans, asymptomatic bacteriuria (ABU) is indicated not to use antimicrobial therapy since treatment may lead to multidrug resistant (MDR) infection. The purpose of this study was to characterize E. coli from canine UTIs (n=96) based on the relationships between virulence and resistance in terms of phylogenetics, multi-locus sequence typing (MLST), virulence genotype, antimicrobial resistance, and clinical signs. Of the 96 canine E. coli UTIs, symptoms were classified as ABU in 19 patients (20%) and symptomatic UTIs in 77 patients (80%). The most common phylogenetic group was B2 (n=75), followed by A (n=16), D (n=4), and E (n=1). Thirty-five MLSTs were identified with 15 being unknown. The most frequent MLST was a community based strain ST372 (n=25) followed by ST961 (n=7), ST12 (n=5), a global UTI epidemic strain ST131 (n=4). ST372 was represented by 19 non-multidrug resistant (SDR) isolates and 6 MDR isolates. ST131 included 1 SDR and 3 MDR isolates, all carrying the highest number of virulence genes. pap genes were most commonly identified among 32 virulence adhesin genes in symptomatic UTIs and afa/draBC for ABU. Twenty-three MLSTs (66%; 23/35) in this study have previously been reported in human infections, implying that these MLSTs may be shared with human owners. These results suggest that the complexity of the relationship between virulence and resistance should be taken into consideration before antimicrobial therapy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/29</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/29/29</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
