<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/213</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:15:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S6</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Advances in Pharmacologic Applications at the Center for Veterinary Medicine</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weissinger, Judi</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug approval</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacokinetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">new animal drug applications</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacologic evidence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">efficacy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">safety</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The overall requirement for approval of a new animal drug is demonstration of drug efficacy and safety to the target animal and safety to the consumer. The law has not changed with time, but our guidelines for demonstrating efficacy and safety, especially in the case of dose determination, minor species, bioequivalence and supplemental applications, are somewhat more flexible to allow for the dynamic and ever-changing pharmacologic knowledge and scientific discovery. The Pharmacokinetics Committee of the Center for Veterinary Medicine, has been in existence for 1 1/2 years and is charged with 1) promoting interaction and dissemination of pharmacokinetic information in the Center, 2) recommendation of policies and assurance of consistancy regarding applications and usefulness of pharmacokinetics in the Center and 3) continual update and revision of policies involving pharmacokinetics as the state of the art dictates. Many of the issues presented to the committee are direct results of industry's advances in using pharmacologic principles in new animal drug applications.
Recommendations of the committee have been used to judge the appropriateness and validity of pharmacologic evidence submitted in lieu of the standard criteria. In cases where the pharmacologic principles were applicable, the Center has succeeded in alleviating some of the encumbering studies without sacrificing confidence in the effectiveness of the drug, the safety of the animal or the safety of the human food supply.
At this time, I will not go into all of the requirements of the approval process as they have been presented here before, but will instead discuss the outcome of the third task force's recommendations as regards the use of pharmacologic principles in the approval process. At this time, two guidelines, involving bioequivalence and supplemental (human food safety) applications have been reviewed by the Pharmacokinetics Committee for consistency with current knowledge.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/213</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fifth Biennial Symposium; 255-263</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/213/201</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
