<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/16</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-25T02:39:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Aspects in controlled-release dosage forms in veterinary medicine</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lavy, Eran</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Friedman, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hoffman, Amnon</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Segev, Gilad</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Steinberg, Doron</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Veterinary Medicine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Controlled-Release</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Drugs</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Early development of controlled-release drug delivery systems was aimed at serving the challenges of human medicine. Around the mid-1970s, the technology of controlled-release dosage form (CRDF) began to be applied for veterinary medicine purposes.The development of CRDF is highly desirable, from both a convenience and a compliance perspective. One of the biggest advantages of such formulations over the conventional ones is their ability to release a drug at a pre-prescribed rate, leading to relatively constant and stable serum concentrations. Another benefit is their ability to administer medications in infrequent mode. The use of CRDFs reduces adverse affects and thereby assists in optimizing therapy.During recent years, our team developed and evaluated several kinds of CRDFs based on a drug-delivery system producing a polymeric matrix for various indications in animals. These include parenteral controlled-release antibiotic formulation models in goats, pigs, calves, dogs, pigeons, and parrots; a topical sustained release varnish for treatment of dental disorders in dogs and kangaroos; a topical sustained release formulation for udder health in dairy cows; a gastro-retentive dosage form (GRDF) in dogs, and coated catheters with a sustained release varnish for prevention of urinary tract infections in dogs. In many of these trials, by using a single administration, we achieved the ability to provide a constant serum drug level for several days that is higher than the MIC.To summarize, there appears to be enormous potential for controlled-release drugs for many animal species as well as for human beings.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/16</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/16/14</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
