<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/59</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T19:09:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pharmakokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of oral oxycodone administration in horses</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Haughan, J. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Missanelli, Jaclyn</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">You, Youwen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McDonnel, Sue</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Slack, JoAnn</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Robinson, Mary A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Opioid</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Equine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Drug Testing</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Oxycodone, a µ-agonist commonly prescribed to alleviate pain in humans, has been detected in plasma and urine samples collected for equine post-race drug testing.&amp;nbsp; The pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of oxycodone (5 mg) administered orally to 12 healthy horses (6TB, 6 SB, 8.6 ±2.7 years) was investigated.&amp;nbsp; Plasma and urine samples were collected for up to 96 hours.&amp;nbsp; Oxycodone concentrations were measured using a validated LC-MS/MS method (lower limit of quantification (LLOQ) = 2.5 pg/mL for both matrices). Video monitoring and ECG recording was performed before and after oxycodone administration to 6 horses, and videos and data were evaluated by equine behavioral and cardiac specialists.&amp;nbsp; Oxycodone plasma concentration versus time data best fit a two compartmental model with a weighting factor of 1/Y2 and a lag time based on visual inspection of the residual plots, the Akaike information criterion (AIC), the Schwartz information criterion (SIC) and minimizing the coefficients of variation for the estimated parameters.&amp;nbsp; The absorption and distribution phases were very rapid (K01 T ½ = 0.1 (0-0.3) h; α T½ = 0.4 (0.1-1.4) h, respectively), and were followed by a slower but still fast elimination phase (β T½ = 3.3 (0.9-35.1) h).&amp;nbsp; The oxycodone concentration was below the LLOQ in plasma by 10 (8-20) hours and in urine by 72 (12 to &amp;gt;96) hours. No behavioral or ECG abnormalities were observed.&amp;nbsp; Ongoing studies are in progress to determine if exposure to oxycodone in the environment could result in its detection in equine blood and/or urine.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/59</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 21st Biennial Symposium; 40</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/59/54</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
