<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/230</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SII</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Analytical Detection Systems: Present and Future</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ellis, Richard L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug residue</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">analytical methods</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">regulatory analysis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It is a pleasure to address this Symposium sponsored by the American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics on analytical detection systems-past, present, and future. We rely heavily on residue analytical methods within USDA, Food Safety and Inspection Service to support the Meat and Poultry Inspection program. In 1986, we analyzed over 330,000 samples. These analyses included a broad spectrum of topic areas including antibiotic residues, food chemistry, chemical residues, food microbiology, species identification, non-residue pathology samples, and serological tests.
I believe it is particularly appropriate to review this topic with you because, in genealogical terms, our National Residue Program (NRP) is approaching adulthood. We have raised it through its infancy and adolescent growing pains, albeit not without close oversight by PSIS, the regulated industry, consumer groups, Congress, congressional oversight, and our peers. We are pleased in its growth and direction. There is, in many respects, a parallelism between the NRP development and the growth and development of our analytical detection systems over the past 20-25 years. Chromatography systems to separate individual components of a mixture were entering a period of rapid development that is still going on. It has been aided by integrating attributes of computer science, electronics, materials sciences, and the physical sciences.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/230</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 39-43</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/230/217</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
