<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/27</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-25T02:55:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Exenatide as a Safe and Efficacious Treatment for Laminitis in Horse</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stefanovski, Darko</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boston, Raymond C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Robinson, Mary</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Insulin Resistance (IR)</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Equine Metabolic Syndrome</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Hyperinsulinemia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Laminitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Today the general veterinary public recognizes that “equine metabolic syndrome (EMS)” is a similar disease to the metabolic syndrome in humans. While the onset of the metabolic syndrome in humans is associated with abnormalities in the coronary vessels, horses suffer from increased risk of laminitis, inflammatory condition in tissues of the horses hoof. However, while the manifestation may be different, there is a growing consensus that the underlying causes of metabolic syndrome in humans and horses are similar. Metabolic syndrome is associated with the inability of the organism to effectively use insulin, termed insulin resistance (IR). The aim of this study is to assess safety and efficacy of Exenatide in healthy horses. We hypothesize that Exenatide will decrease IR and as such lead to a decrease in hyperinsulinemia, major risk factor for laminitis. In 6 normal horses (3 mares, three geldings) the current high human dose of Byetta subcutaneous injection of 10 mcg/per dose can be safely used with no adverse effects observed. While this dose translates into much smaller concentration normalized per kg of body weight, it nevertheless showed to be efficacious and resulted in statistically significantly reduction of postprandial insulin secretion by 20% (P=0.034). This study is the first evidence that Exenatide, GLP-1 mimetic, can be safely used in horses. Furthermore, we provide evidence that this dose resulted in decreased postprandial insulin secretion. The observed effect is likely extra-pancreatic related to decreased hepatic IR.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/27</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/27/27</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
