<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/34</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T18:22:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Updated guidance for registration of Veterinary Medicinal Products (VMPs) under MUMS (minor use - minor species) in the European Union</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hellmann, Klaus</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wolf, Regina</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Veterinary Medicines Regulation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">MUMS</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Minor Use</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Minor Species</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">With effect of 01JUL2017, several revised guidelines for Minor Indication – Minor Species (MUMS) come into force in the European Union (EU). There is a list of species generally classified as major species (cattle, sheep, pig, chicken, salmon, dog, cat). All other animal species are by default, classed as minor species. Respective classification guidance is provided for minor or limited markets in a separate document (EMA/CVMP/388694/2014).The guideline on quality data requirements for VMP intended for MUMS reflects that where an EU authorised veterinary medicine already exists a full part II dossier (CMC, chemistry, manufacturing and controls) in support of an application to add a minor species to the authorisation is not required.The guideline for the establishment of residue limits of pharmacologically active substances in foodstuffs of animal origin are based on regulation (EC) No 470/2009 permitting only very limited scope for reduction of data requirements under MUMS Nevertheless, there may be scope for data reductions, e.g by use of extrapolation.The guideline on efficacy and target animal safety (TAS) data requirements for VMPs for MUMS allows for data reduction where this can be justified. Tolerance may be demonstrated in the field and/or based on literature data.Overall some further clarifications are given with a focus on known substances and products for extension to minor species. However there are no major improvements for new VMPs for MUMS compared to previous guidance. Therefore the impact on availability of VMPs for these categories in the EU is questionable.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/34</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/34/33</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
