<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/168</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S4</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Phenylbutazone Levels in Post-Race Samples from Horses Racing in Kentucky: A Review</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Houston, Teresa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chay, Sylvia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Woods, W. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Blake, Jerry W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tobin, Thomas</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">phenylbutazone</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">horseracing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Kentucky Equine Drug Research Program</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">masking ability</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">horses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Thoroughbred</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">When I came to Kentucky in about 1975 to start the Kentucky Equine Drug Research Program, I was told that I could work on any drug that I wished except phenylbutazone (PB). According to my authority, phenylbutazone was a drug whose characteristics were well known and was of little interest to regulators. Since then, however, phenylbutazone has become the drug of greatest interest in racing and a major part of our work is devoted to this problem. Among the more recently perceived problems with phenylbutazone is the thought that it may "mask" the detection of other drugs and the Kentucky Equine Drug Research Program is currently working on a project to deter mine the impact, if any, of the supposed masking ability of this drug on the efficacy of equine drug testing (Tobin, 1981, Takade, 1982, Woods, 1984a, 1984b).
Masking is thought to occur when the presence of one drug in a sample interferes with the detection of another (Woods, 1984a, 1984b). Usually this is thought of as occurring in thin layer chromatographic systems and the masking is considered to be due to simple physical obstruction of the visualization of the "masked" drug by either phenylbutazone or one of its metabolites (Woods, 1984b). For this problem to be studied in the laboratory, however, one needs to know the levels of both phenylbutazone and its metabolites actually found in the blood and urine of horses post-race. This report represents the results of such a survey done on Thoroughbred horses racing in Kentucky in the spring of 1983. In addition, we have presented data on the levels of phenylbutazone found in horses after dosing with standard schedules of phenylbutazone in order that these levels may be compared with those found in actual post race urine samples.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/168</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 96-115</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/168/159</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
