<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/74</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T19:32:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S4</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Training Veterinary Pharmacologists – Updating the Blueprint for Graduate Education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fajt, Virginia</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">graduate students</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">professional skills</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">At the 15th AAVPT Biennial (Asilomar Conference Center, California) in 2007, a workshop was held to identify and prioritize skills and knowledge necessary for success of veterinary pharmacologists working in industry, academia, or regulatory agencies. The results were published in 2008 (V.R. Fajt, Skills and competencies required by veterinary pharmacologists: a blueprint for graduate education in veterinary pharmacology in North America, Journal of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics, 2008, 31:22-30), and the identified items are included in the appendices below.
&amp;nbsp;
A search of the literature since initial publication of the blueprint in JVPT in 2008 suggests that these have not been re-reviewed for graduate veterinary pharmacology. This is not surprising, since veterinary pharmacology continues to be a relatively small discipline, with few graduate training programs, whether clinical pharmacology training programs are included or not. The question then is: Is it still valid?&amp;nbsp; Additional questions or items for discussion might include:
&amp;nbsp;

Would a comprehensive review of currently available graduate programs in veterinary pharmacology yield any useful data for current or potential programs?

&amp;nbsp;

Recent discussions with JVPT have clarified the scope of the journal, and they highlight the breadth of veterinary pharmacology, i.e., it may include translational work (with humans being the ultimate target) and veterinary-specific work (with animals being the ultimate target). This is part of what complicates any discussion of graduate training and skills.

&amp;nbsp;

In addition to providing students and training program leaders with a blueprint for skills, how else could AAVPT support graduate training? For example, how could industry internships be identified or supported, how could student training grants or travel grants be supported and awarded, how could emerging leaders be identified and mentored?
</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/74</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 21st Biennial Symposium; 64-66</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/74/69</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
