<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/61</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T19:11:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Practical and affordable tick prevention in horses in Grenada, West Indies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Karasek, Inga</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Butler, Catherine</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baynes, Ronald</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Werners, Arno</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Tick parasitism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Grenada</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Theileria equi</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Babesia caballi</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">piperonyl butoxide</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">abamectin</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Tick parasitism can cause serious equine welfare and health issues through transmission of pathogens. A previous study revealed that 75% and 7% of Grenadian horses and donkeys were seropositive for Theileria equi, and Babesia caballi respectively. We hypothesize that commercial cattle ear tags impregnated with abamectin applied around the neck of horses by means of a collar, will result in the distribution of the drug over the body of the horse at levels sufficient to kill and repel ticks.
Seven clinically healthy horses were fitted an EquestriSafe® Multipurpose Collar with two XP 820™Ear Tags (Y-Tex, Cody, WY, USA) of 20 % piperonyl butoxide and 8 % abamectin attached and assessed at three time points over 20 days. Tick burden was assessed using photographs of each animal to quantify tick numbers.&amp;nbsp; One pinna (left) and the perineum were imaged at day 0, 6 and 20. Five independent individuals assigned percentage coverage of the ticks in those regions.
The results of the pooled median tick percentages show a significant difference (p &amp;lt; 0.05) in tick numbers over time from 80 % at time 0, to 5 % at 20 days of the treated horses. The control horses tick counts did not show this trend (27 % at time 0, 20 % at 20 days). Further research to assess the concentration of the abamectin in the hair and stratum corneum over the same time period, and to extend the time of the study to ascertain time of efficacy is warranted.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/61</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 21st Biennial Symposium; 42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/61/56</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
