<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/100</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:33:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S4</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Newer Concepts of Therapy in Dermatology</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Allbritton, A. R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dermatology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunopathological process</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">My object is to define some of the more recent advances in dermatological therapy and to relate refinements in existing accepted therapeutic practices used in skin diseases. In pursuing a practice in dermatology one quickly realizes that the language of dermatology is immunology and to a lesser extent bacteriology and endocrinology. Most of the more recent advances made in the rapidly expanding field of immunology have been quickly incorporated into the practice of clinical dermatology. The skin is often thought of as the first line of defense from invasion by pathogenic organisms from the exterior and frequently reflects disruptive changes which originate internally. Since the immune process is often intimately involved in external invasions as well as internal derangements, advances in understanding this system is of vital importance to the dermatologist. Less it be forgotten it should also be stated that in the field of dermatology the immunopathological process frequently is of equal or greater concern to the clinician than the protective function of the immune system.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/100</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 182-226</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/100/94</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
