<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/92</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:33:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Drug Residue Safety</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perez, Marilyn K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug residue</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">USDA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">FDA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food supply</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food safety</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In the United States today the public probably enjoys better protection from potential adverse health effects that might result from the use of drugs in food-producing animals than anywhere else in the world. This opinion is based on a comparison of the pre-clearance standards currently in use for approving the safety of animal drugs and the residue surveillance programs used to control drug use in the manner prescribed by regulation. The current USDA drug residue monitoring program in conjunction with the FDA enforcement program provides one of the most advanced and comprehensive programs in the world. Similarly, FDA's current pre-clearance requirements for drug approval compare favorably with, and in most cases, exceed the safety requirements of other countries. These programs not only prevent the exposure of the American consuming public to potentially unsafe drugs, but also act as a deterrent to the misuse of the drugs in a manner which violates the safety provisions included in the approval process.
We are extremely furtunate in the United States to have an abundant supply of animal-derived foods. There is no question that the use of animal drugs plays a major role both in maintaining the supply, and also in increasing it to the point that our food supply can be exported to benefit consumers in less fortunate countries. In order to protect this supply and also maintain the standards of safety which have become associated with confidence in the animal-derived food industry, several issues need to be realistically considered.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/92</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 102-112</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/92/86</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
