<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/243</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SIV</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Role of Computers in Managing Information for Pharmacology Teaching and Research: Medical Informatics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Talbot, Richard B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biomedical science</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hematology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">medical curricula</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Rapid advances in the biomedical sciences, including veterinary pharmacology, have led to an explosion in the volume of medical knowledge. The rate of growth far outstrips the rate in any previous period of time. The first volume of Index Medicus contained about 17,000 citations from 700 periodicals. Today, each month's issue averages about 21,000 citations from over 3,000 publications. The textbook on veterinary hematology by Schalm that I used in the '60s contained 664 pages. The current edition has 1241 pages to cover the same discipline. It is predicted that medical knowledge will continue to grow at a faster pace than either the population or the economy (1).
Information growth is not simply addition to previous knowledge. Veterinarians are also faced with the responsibility of identifying and replacing knowledge that has become outdated or obsolete. This process of keeping current is increasingly difficult. Veterinary medical curricula are particularly affected by this proliferation of knowledge. Each year the amount of knowledge within each discipline increases, and the pressure increases to include more information in that discipline's courses. This has resulted in the students being submerged in details and memorization of facts with little opportunity and little encouragement from faculty to do other than rote learning during the basic science years. In most schools this has precluded the teaching of problem-solving skills, even though many of us give lip service to the concept.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/243</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 77-82</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/243/226</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
