<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/227</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SI</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Opportunities in Veterinary Education for Improving Food Safety and Quality</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Osburn, B. I.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food safety</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">public health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animals</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Veterinary medicine has had long standing involvement in food safety. This stems back to the tum of the century when the meat inspection service was established to help control the ravages of tuberculosis. In fact, most human tuberculosis in those days was thought to be of animal origin and the most appropriate way to control it was by establishing a meat inspection program. The basis for the program was organoleptic examination of carcasses where those carcasses with observable lesions of any cause were condemned. Even in 1986, there were 55 million poultry and 375,000 red meat carcasses condemned as unsuitable for human consumption (1). Although this system is in place, it is estimated that there are over 33 million cases of food-borne illness and nine thousand human deaths occurring annually in the United States (2, 3). In the last 8 to 10 years, increasing pressure has been brought to bear by consumers and the Public Health Service to provide a safe, wholesome food supply. This led to two National Academy of Science studies on the Poultry Meat Inspection Service and the Red Meat Inspection Service. Additionally, consumers are insisting through Congress and by other means that they be presented with food free of potential human health hazards.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/227</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 24-27</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/227/214</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
