<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/161</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Current Approaches to Internal Parasite Control in Horses</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">DiPietro, J. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">internal parasites</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parasite control program</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">horses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">equine anthelmintics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The most fundamental aspect of a herd health program for horses is the control of internal parasites. Parasite infections are the most costly, insidious and permanently damaging disease entities of the horse. They may cause serious sequellae such as impaction, pneumonia, rupture of the gastrointestinal tract and colic. Verminous arteritis has been reported as the cause of death in 10 to 33% of all abdominal crises in the horse.7-3 In fact, it has been suggested that up to 90% of all colic cases result from damage done by Strongylus vulgar is. The seriousness of controlling equine parasites was emphasized by W. R. McGee who in 1972 wrote, "…no single function of the veterinarian on a breeding farm is more important than establishing an effective parasite control program. Such a program is essential for the success, indeed for the survival of any horse breeding operation." In a like manner the importance of adequate control of equine parasites at the race track was emphasized by G. L. Ferraro who wrote, "Parasite control is the single most important factor to be considered in the digestive system of race horses." Like veterinarians, most horsemen realize the serious consequences of uncontrolled parasitic infections. A survey on parasite control of over 1700 Illinois horse farms revealed that 72.5% of the farms felt that parasites were a problem.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/161</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 51-81</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/161/154</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
