<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/192</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:16:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Role and Control of Eisosanoid in Acute Non-Immune Inflammation in the Equine</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lees, P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sedwick, A. D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Higgins, A. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Taylor, J. B. O.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">acute inflammatory process</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">horses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">eicosanoids</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anti-inflammatory agents</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A range of in vitro and ex vivo techniques have been developed and used to study the acute inflammatory process in the horse, with particular reference to the roles of eicosanoids as putative inflammatory mediators and the actions of anti-inflammatory agents as inhibitors of eicosanoid synthesis. Two ethically acceptable models of acute non-immune inflammation based on the inflammatory actions of the galactan, carrageenin, were used to obtain serial samples of inflammatory exudate. Demonstration of the presence in acute inflammatory exudate of PGE2, PGI2, TXA2 and LTB4 suggest that cyclooxygenase and lipoxygenase products of arachidonic acid metabolism may be involved in the vascular and cellular components of inflammation. The chemoattractant properties of PGE2 and LTB4 for equine polymorphonuclear leucocytes (PMN) and mononuclear cells (MN) were investigated using two in vitro assay systems. The actions of a range of non-steroidal and steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs on eicosanoid concentrations and cell numbers in acute inflammatory exudate were. investigated and their actions were related to drug concentrations in exudate. The effectiveness of circulating concentrations of anti-inflammatory drugs as cyclo-oxygenase inhibitors was assessed by measuring TXB2 concentrations in serum harvested from blood allowed to clot under standard conditions. It is suggested that the use of these techniques, in combination, may help to further our knowledge of the inflammatory process and the actions of anti-inflammatory drugs in the horse.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/192</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fifth Biennial Symposium; 43-62</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/192/183</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
