<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/33</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T18:20:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Registration of Veterinary Medicinal Products under conditional license – differences to EU</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hellmann, Klaus</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wolf, Regina</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Veterinary Medicines Regulation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">conditional license</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Since 2004 the Minor Use and Minor Species (MUMS) Animal Health Act1 allowed conditional licenses (CNADA)2. This is a very effective way to bring products to market more quickly especially in the area of specific needs and for products that fall under the minor use – minor species (MUMS) categories. Hence further safety and efficacy data in the field can be gathered whilst initially starting to sell the product. While this pathway provides faster and easier access to novel and niche products and promotes the availability of VMPs, thorough marketing including advertising to achieve market penetration is usually not possible. In contrast to the expectations, the significant sales are mostly not reached.In the European Union (EU) the current legislation of Directive 2001/82/EC3 as amended does not foresee exceptional licenses for limited markets except for some vaccines under emergency use. However, in many countries of the EU national conditional/exceptional licenses are possible. These are not extendable to other Member States (MS) unless the data can be updated to a full dossier. The proposed new regulation4 however considers also exceptional licenses applicable for centralised and decentralised procedures for MUMS products. Unfortunately, the implementation of this regulation may be still a few years away. However, with good planning, a full marketing authorisation in the European market may be reached in a similar timeline. Thus, an applicant has to consider carefully which may be the fastest way to reach return of investment.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/33</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/33/32</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
