<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-25T02:30:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">An Overview of One Health Activities</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dunham, Bernadette</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">public health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">one health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">infectious disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">climate change</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food security</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antimicrobial resistance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">obesity</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One Health is defined as the collaborative effort of multiple disciplines – working locally, nationally, and globally – to attain optimal health for people, animals, and our environment. Basically, one health links the well-being of humans, animals and the ecosystem. Today’s presentation will highlight a number of one health activities.
Today we face a number of global challenges such as emerging and re-emerging infectious diseases; climate change; food security issues (availability of safe and nutritious food); access to safe and abundant water supplies; antimicrobial resistance; and obesity. Worldwide, nearly 75% of all emerging human infectious diseases in the past three decades have originated in animals. Climate change, increased CO2 levels, land-use changes, resource scarcity, decreased biodiversity, loss of pollinators, dams and irrigation projects, air and water pollution, and encroachment into wildlife habitat are just a few of the items impacting the ecosystem which in turn affects the health of humans and animals. Moreover, the world population is projected to grow from 7.4 billion in 2016 to 9 billion by 2050, further increasing humanity’s ecological footprint.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/5</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium; 12-15</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/5/4</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
