<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/236</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SII</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Multiresidue Methods: Chemical Assays</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Guyer, C. Greg</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug approval process</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug residue</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">multiresidue detection methods</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As an integral part of the drug approval process, the sponsor of a new animal drug for use in food-producing animals has the responsibility to develop analytical methods that are capable of quantitating the amount of residue that remains in the animal after the administration of their product. Then, a procedure must also be developed by the sponsor that can confirm the presence of that residue. These procedures have varied from mouse uterine assays to microbiological assays to chemical assays. The one common theme that these procedures have is that they are relatively cumbersome and tedious to perform. In other words, they are not very amenable to short analysis times. Under FDA's current SOM guidelines, the drug sponsor is not held accountable for developing methods with short analysis times, but rather methods with reasonable analysis times (usually no more than 48 hours).
As defined by Dr. Ellis and Dr. Norcross of FSIS in their presentations given earlier today, the challenge of monitoring for drug residues in animal tissues is a great one. With the large number of approved veterinary drugs and the billions of food-producing animals slaughtered every year in the U.S., I think you can get an idea of the monumental task that USDA has. Over the last several years, FDA and USDA have been working together both through our contracts and through our own research to develop strategies to make the task more manageable. The two primary schemes of thought in these discussions have been that we either have to develop methods that can detect the residues utilizing shorter analysis times or develop methods that can concomitantly detect more than one residue. Although both avenues are being explored in great detail, my discussion will concentrate on the development of chemical methods that can detect more than one residue at a time. These methods are referred to as multiresidue methods.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/236</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 50-51</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/236/219</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
