<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/99</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:33:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S4</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Needs for Veterinary Clinical Pharmacology by the Pharmaceutical Industry</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brander, G. C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary surgeon</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug usage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibacterial</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anthelmintic</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Our discussions in the Symposium revealed the breadth of the field of veterinary pharmacology and I wish to emphasize in my introduction the importance that industry attaches to the effective training of the modern veterinary surgeon. When he goes into practice, he has in his hands a range of sophisticated drugs which have passed through very detailed examinations both in vitro and in vivo and been tested in a series of clinical trials prior to marketing, so that his success in using these drugs will depend on a good knowledge of the literature, and on the ability to make a sound diagnosis. Nowadays, because of intensive methods of animal management, the diagnosis may depend both on a study of the farm records and the use of the many diagnostic aids which assist in deciding whether a disease is new to the unit, or whether it is really a symptom of persistent subclinical disease. &amp;nbsp;
To illustrate the relevance of effective clinical pharmacology, I would like to consider as examples of the requirement for clinical testing two different types of products which make special demands on veterinary expertise. The examples I have selected are an antibacterial and an anthelmintic. Products of this type have wide usage in the veterinary field and in the case of many antibacterials, very wide usage also in the human field.
Before discussing the products in detail, I would like to consider in general terms several parameters which have to be established at the early stages of the investigation of a new compound, and their relevance to the eventual clinical investigations:

Drug activity.
Blood level pattern of a new drug.
Areas of concentration.
Persistence.
Metabolism and identification of metabolites.
Relevance of animal models.
Relationship between pharmacokinetics and likely clinical efficacy.
Formulation
</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/99</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 170-181</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/99/93</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
