<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/170</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S4</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Biochemical Response of the Sympatho-adrenal Axis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vulliet, P. Richard</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sympatho-adrenal axis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stress responsive systems</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">acute stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">chronic stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Stress is a complex condition that frequently impacts the health and well being of both animals and man. Much of our knowledge about the response of the sympatho-adrenal axis is based on the classic work of Cannon (1) and Selye (2). Discharge of the sympatho-adrenal axis has been characterized as that which functions to prepare the body for "fight or flight". This response is generally thought to be rapid and to affect most of the organ systems in the body. However, additional research in this area has demonstrated that sympatho-adrenal discharge is regulated by mechanisms that can also produce long-term changes at the cellular level. The purpose of this communication is to review recently obtained knowledge about the response of the sympatho-adrenal axis to stress and its relationship to other stress responsive systems. For a more thorough discussion of the responses to stress situations, the reader should see references (3,4).
Activity of the sympathetic nervous system is modulated by a variety of stressors including heat, cold, immobilization, pain, psychological factors and starvation. The response generated to these stressors is dependent upon the duration, intensity and frequency of the stressor. Intense stressors that are applied for a short duration (on the order of seconds to minutes) can be functionally defined as producing a condition of acute stress and this correlates with the "fight or flight response" described by Cannon (1). These same stressors applied at a lower intensity over a period of days to weeks produces a condition termed chronic stress.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/170</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 117-123</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/170/161</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
