<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/86</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:34:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pharmacokinetic Modeling</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bourne, David W. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug absorption</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacokinetic compartmental models</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">compartmental model</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The disposition of a drug in the body is a complex process and involves many interrelated kinetically controlled steps. Fortunately from a pharmacokinetic modeling point of view many of these steps are either rapid and therefore not rate determining or so slow that they are unimportant. Also, if a number of processes have similar rates they may be lumped together and treated as one process. Consequently plasma concentration time curves will often involve only a one or two exponential decay. This would suggest that the body can be described as a single compartment or as two interconnected compartments. Less frequently a three or four compartment model may be derived from the plasma concentration time curve. This is the basis for the pharmacokinetic compartmental models which are used to describe plasma concentration time data obtained experimentally. The one, two, and three compartment open pharmacokinetic models are shown in figures 1, 2, and 3. Shown with each compartmental model is a typical plasma concentration time curve generated from the one, two, or three compartment model. When all the rate processes of a pharmacokinetic model follow first order kinetics the pharmacokinetic model is called a linear model. The equations derived for the plasma concentration as a function of time are then the sum of one, two or three exponentials for a one, two, or three compartment pharmacokinetic model respectively. These exponential equations are shown in figure 4 and are termed the integrated equations with the A, B, C, α, β, or γ terms functions of the intercompartmental rate constants. If plasma time data alone is to be modeled then the integrated equations are very useful and may be used exclusively. However if more data is available from other body fluids or tissues, such as urine, or data is collected following multiple dose administration then the differential equations may be easier to use. The differential equations for the plasma compartment derived from the one, two or three compartment pharmacokinetic model are shown in figure 5. The same differential equation can be used to describe the urine compartment for each of the pharmacokinetic models, figure 6. With ready-access to large digital computers it is relatively easy to use the differential equations since the computer will quickly and efficiently perform the necessary numerical integration for calculation of the plasma or urine data.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/86</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 1-13</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/86/80</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
