<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/165</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Therapeutic Use and Clinical Features of Novel Drug Delivery Systems</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Doluisio, James T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug delivery system</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dosing regimen</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dosage form design</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">analytical chemistry</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacokinetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biopharmaceutics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Ever since medicinal agents have been prescribed, dosage forms have existed, as they constitute the physical-chemical form for administering a medicine. It is noteworthy that most drugs today are still prescribed in dosage forms that date back to the earliest records of pharmaceutical practice: the pill, described in Eber's Papyrus 1500 BC; the coated pill, accredited to Rhazes about AD 900; the tablet, described by Al Zahrawi during the last half of the 10th century; and the capsule, invented by Mothes in France, 1833. (Felix Theeuwes, Pharmacology and Therapeutics "Drug Delivery Systems," 13, 149-191; 1981.)
With this statement Felix Theeuwes of the Alza Corporation begins his excellent 1981 review of contemporary drug delivery systems--systems that extend man's control of dosing regimens in ways that can optimize a drug's desirable therapeutic activities while minimizing undesirable activities. These new drug delivery systems often use new routes of administration (e.g., transdermal for systemic effects) and new technologies (e.g., laser beams, computerized pumps); and are designed for careful programmed release of drugs for local effects (e.g., in the eye) or for systemic effects.
Why is it that there currently is such rapid advancement in dosage form technology after so many centuries of little advancement? The reason is that before there could be advances in dosage form design there had to be advances in analytical chemistry, clinical pharmacology, pharmacokinetics and biopharmaceutics.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/165</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 79-87</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/165/157</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
