<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/239</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SIII</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Basic and Clinical Pharmacology in the Professional Curriculum: Current Trends and Future Needs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jenkins, William L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary medicine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary curriculum</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">What are the current trends and future needs of both basic and clinical pharmacology in the professional veterinary curriculum and, perhaps even more importantly, how can they best be managed and co-ordinated? These are provocative and timely questions! There are presently significant academic as well as extramural issues that impact directly on the place and role of pharmacology in today's veterinary curriculum. We, as the Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics, need to keep abreast of these developments so that we can respond appropriately and expediently and thereby continue to serve the best interests of our discipline. Hopefully, we will also then be in a position to play a pivotal role in the evolution of the sophisticated standard of veterinary medicine that will be required, if not demanded, during the years ahead.
It is simply not possible on this occasion to address every current issue confronting veterinary medicine that may either directly or indirectly influence the development and growth of various aspects of veterinary pharmacology. However, there are a number of very important trends that must at least be recognized prior to any debate on how best to respond to the challenges and needs of the future with specific reference to the teaching of pharmacology to tomorrow's veterinarians at both the basic and applied levels. I believe that the diverse speculative matters synoptically outlined below will deserve special attention in the future in this regard. &amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/239</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 59-63</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/239/222</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
