<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/90</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:34:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Practical Applications of Pharmacokinetics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mercer, H. Dwight</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacokinetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">practical application</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug withdrawal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bioavailability</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bioequivalency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animals</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Pharmacokinetics has been defined as the quantitative study of the absorption, distribution, metabolism, and excretion of drugs and their pharmacologic, therapeutic, and toxic responses in animals and man. You have heard from several authors the definitive uses of pharmacokinetics, including the applications of pharmacokinetics in the modeling of a drug. You have seen the extensive use of mathematics and computer requirements in applying the science of pharmacokinetics to the definition of a drug profile in the body. It is my intention to discuss with you the application of pharmacokinetics when there are no computer programs available. In other words, does pharmacokinetics have any everyday practical uses. There are three major practical applications for pharmacokinetics in veterinary medicine. One is the delineation and definition of specific dosage regimens; (2) the determination of drug bioavailability and bioequivalency; and (3) the estimation and projection of drug withdrawl intervals in food producing animals. The determination of a dosage regimen probably has its greatest applicability for the clinician, the practitioner, and for the veterinary student. The determination of bioavailability and bioequivalency probably has its greatest degree of application in the drug industry, where there is often a need for making determinations about the comparability of new or generic versus trade name drugs. The third area involves the application of pharmacokinetics in estimating the withdrawal time of drugs used in food animals. There are many instances where the practitioner feels a need to use an unapproved drug in the therapy of a disease in food animals, but has no way of estimating the potential withdrawal period. With a little drug kinetic data and some knowledge about pharmacokinetics he may be able to estimate or project a withdrawal time.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/90</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 47-74</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/90/84</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
