<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/177</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S6</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Impact of Federal and State Regulations on the Management of Veterinary Pharmacy</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stephen, Stephen P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">federal regulation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">state regulation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug abuse</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary medicine</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper is a review of the federal and state regulations which affect hospital pharmacies associated with colleges of veterinary medicine. Aspects of the regulations which impact the pharmacist in performing their professional responsibilities in the veterinary setting will be identified and discussed.
The pharmacy profession is one of the most regulated in this country. The reasons for the high degree of regulation are many and diverse in origin. Major origins stem from the intent to protect the general public from inappropriate use (i.e. safe and effective drugs) and to reduce the abuse of drugs.
Federal regulations which primarily affect the veterinary hospital pharmacy are the Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, the Controlled Substances Act, and the Hazardous Substance Labeling Act. The effect of these Acts in the veterinary setting are similar to the human pharmacy settings. State regulations which affect the veterinary hospital pharmacy are primarily enforced by the state Boards of Pharmacy. However, the application of these regulations varies considerably from state to state.
This paper will primarily discuss those Federal and State regulations affecting pharmacies in the United States. These regulations are different for our Canadian colleagues. For example, the Canadian pharmacies are regulated by Federal regulation only, thus providing a more consistent legal basis for their practice settings.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/177</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 180-185</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/177/170</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
