<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/172</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S4</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of Monensin on Cardiac and Erythrocyte Function</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Amend, James F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">monensin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">toxicity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cardiovascular response</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">erythrocyte response</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Effects of monensin have also been noted in studies of the bloo d. Pressman and co-workers (21), in early studies on monensin and its effects, noted that it caused disturbance in ion transport across erythrocyte membranes, leading to osmotic water fluxes and possible increases in fragility of the cell. Feinstein et al. (8) showed that monensin was capable of compromising function of blood platelets, as the presence of the compound caused a change in the rate of serotonin uptake.
Evidence exists, therefore, that both heart muscle and erythrocytes may be stressed by the presence of monensin. The purpose of this study, then, was to examine these focuses of toxicity in domestic ponies subjected to controlled doses of crystalline monensin sodium and to determine to what extent cardiovascular and erythrocyte responses to monensin may contribute to the clinical event of equine monensin toxicosis. A secondary objective of the study was to identify mechanisms of toxicity which might be focuses of rational therapy for affected animals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/172</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 133-155</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/172/163</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
