<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/182</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S8</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pharmacology and Pharmacokinetics of Antiarrhythmic Drugs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Muir, W. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ntiarrhythmic drugs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">toxicity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cardiac arrhythmia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">electrophysiologic mechanisms</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The need to develop and test new antiarrhythmic drugs is essential if morbidity and mortality rates associated with cardiac arrhythmias are to be reduced. New antiarrhythmic drugs should demonstrate negligible toxicity, excellent efficacy against a variety of arrhythmias, convenient dosing regimens and be devoid of drug toxicity and interactions. The "ideal" antiarrhythmic drug has yet to be developed, although a wide variety of chemical compounds are currently being evaluated for clinical use. Theoretically, the development and use of antiarrhythmic drugs should be based upon a complete understanding of those mechanisms responsible for the production of cardiac arrhythmias. Regrettably, the mechanisms responsible for the production of many experimentally induced cardiac arrhythmias are incompletely understood while mechanisms responsible for the spontaneous development of cardiac arrhythmias are largely speculative. Recent advances in electrophysiologic testing procedures are helping to elucidate potential causes for the development of cardiac arrhythmias. Table 1 lists basic cellular electrophysiologic mechanisms believed responsible for arrhythmia development. Among these, abnormal automatic mechanisms and reentry are believed to be responsible for the development of most spontaneously occurring arrhythmias.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/182</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 213-221</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/182/174</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
