<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/242</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SIII</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pharmacology as a Basis of Knowledge for Postgraduate (Residency) Training and Continuing Education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Powers, Thomas E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">academia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary profession</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">continuing education</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I am very pleased to be here today. When Bill Jenkins asked me to present a paper on "Pharmacology as a Basis of Knowledge for Postgraduate (Residency) Training and Continuing Education," I readily accepted for several reasons. First, it is certainly a great pleasure for me to be part of a program to honor Dr. Lloyd E. Davis, another Buckeye from Ohio State. The interactions between Lloyd and me go back 33 years and have involved student/faculty, faculty/faculty and faculty/administrator relationships. But most importantly, it has been one of a long-lasting true friendship that has permitted us not only to work together as colleagues for the betterment of veterinary medicine through our efforts in pharmacology, but also to take the time to be social friends. Yes, Lloyd, I consider it an honor to have been able to work with you during our careers. Secondly, I have spent my entire career devoting a great amount of effort to these two areas, and thirdly, it gives me an excellent opportunity to expound on my biased opinions regarding the proper role and responsibilities of the university faculty.
In spite of this background, I stand here to tell you that you in academia-as well as other members of the academy- do have a major responsibility in the training of residents and in providing a continuing education program to the veterinary profession at large. This responsibility may be accomplished through your own individual efforts or through the academic or other formal channels, such as those sponsored by the AAVPT.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/242</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 70-73</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/242/225</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
