<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/132</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:54:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SII</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Psychotropic Drugs: Antagonism by 4-aminopyridine and other antagonists</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Booth, Nicholas H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hatch, Roger C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">psychotropic agents</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">chemical restraint</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neuropharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neuropeptides</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">After the first veterinary medical use of reserpine and chlorpromazine in the early 1950's, many potent psychotropic agents soon appeared. Use of these agents in the "chemical restraint" of animals for various diagnostic and anesthetic procedures has been most valuable in the practice of veterinary medicine.
With discovery of brain peptides that bind to opiate receptors, ie, endorphins and enkephalins, during the past decade or more, giant strides in advancement of neuropharmacology have occurred. This has led to a tremendous amount of activity in neuropeptide research.
A number of neuropeptides, at least 30, have been identified in the central nervous system (CNS). Their functional relationships involving neurotransmitter activity in the CNS remains largely obscure. How these neuropeptides relate to increased or decreased release of major brain neurotransmitter chemicals such as acetylcholine, norepinephrine, gamma aminobutyric acid, dopamine, serotonin, and others is not completely clear. As more specific information is acquired regarding the functional significance of the neuropeptides, greater insight will be gained into the appropriate clinical use of CNS drugs, including the psychotropic agents. With greater knowledge about specific chemical receptor sites of CNS drug agonists within the brain, the ability to antagonize or terminate their action will be possible through the use of rather specific acting cell receptor antagonists.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1982-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/132</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Third Symposium; 153-170</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/132/126</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1982 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
