<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/97</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:33:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Development of Veterinary Clinical Pharmacology in Europe</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Yoxall, A. T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">toxicology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">European veterinary practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">"Es gibt keine Pharmakologie ohne Toxikologie und keine Toxikologie ohne Pharmakologie”.
"There is no pharmacology without toxicology, and no toxicology without pharmacology". So runs the motto of the Institute for Pharmacology, Toxicology and Pharmacy at the Hannover Veterinary School. Paradoxically, since Professor Kaemmerer, of that Department, is one of the chief proponents for veterinary clinical pharmacology in Europe, this motto underlines one of the underlying difficulties which has delayed the emergence of veterinary clinical pharmacology in Europe.
There is no doubt that the sentiment enshrined in this motto is admirable and true - although one might have been happier if it had read "There is no medicinal product which is not capable of producing unwanted side effects". The snag lies in the implicit linking of the discipline of pharmacology with that of toxicology. Almost every university department of veterinary pharmacology, on the continent of Europe at least, is also a department of toxicology.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/97</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 159-166</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/97/91</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
