<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/109</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:33:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S5</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Chemically Stimulated Feed Intake in Ruminants</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baile, Clifton A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">chemical feed intake stimulants</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">growth rate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feed efficiency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feed intake</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Rumensin</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Our work with chemical feed intake stimulants has been in five areas: 1) Feed intake stimulants have been tested under conditions comparable to those in the feed lot to develop means of improving growth rate and feed efficiency. Figs.1 and 2 illustrate the effect of increased feed intake over a range of intakes relative to maintenance requirement on growth rate and the proportion of the net energy theoretically available for growth.
2) The acceptance of some low quality feeds likely decreases the economical value of some byproducts and crop residues. Feed intake stimulants increase hunger drive and can increase the intake of those less-acceptable feeds making available more metabolizable energy for tissue synthesis.
3) A special application for a chemical feed intake stimulant is to increase the acceptance of feed containing agents which are a source of post-ingestion aversions. Specifically, Rumensin can be a cause of decreased and irregular intakes because of an apparent association between the fermentation effects of Rumensin, after ingestion, on sensory inputs during subsequent prehension.
4) Feed intake stimulants may help prevent development of hypophagia which occurs under various types of stress conditions and which often precipitates disease states and irregular feeding, e.g., shipping fever. Also the stimulant may be useful during chronic stress conditions such as the heat endured by cattle in the southwest feeding areas during summer months.
5) Many disease states have an associated anorexia which often may contribute to the debilitated condition of the animals. Chemical feed intake stimulants may be employed to override the now little-understood inhibitors of feeding which occur in various disease states, especially where the clinician would otherwise attempt force-feeding.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-03-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/109</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; First Symposium; 399-426</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/109/103</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
