<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/228</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SI</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Strategies to Increase Meat Yield and Reduce Fat/Cholesterol</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Convey, Edward M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">livestock industry</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">marketing system</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lean to fat ratio</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">meat processing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">growth hormone</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The American livestock industry is caught in a dilemma that will require drastic measures to correct. The problem, when viewed from the standpoint of the consuming public is clear. Health and weight conscious consumers are modifying their diets to reduce intake of fat, cholesterol and total calories. All three are associated with meat and meat products. Therefore, it is little wonder that consumption of meat and meat products has declined over the last ten years. If livestock producers are to reverse this trend, they must adopt new approaches to reducing the fat/cholesterol content of meat. From the standpoint of the producers, the problem is an antiquated marketing system. Currently, the vast majority of meat animals are sold on a liveweight basis and given premium grades for high finishing (fattening). Consequently, there is no incentive for producers to maximize production of lean. A recent National Research Council report (1) recommended reduction of animal fat and cholesterol in the American diet by: education of consumers; introduction of production methods to reduce fat and increase lean, and; revision of the current meat grading system to provide incentives for production of lean. Clearly this is an opportunity for change.
This paper addresses strategies to improve the lean to fat ratio of meat animals. There is an opportunity to reduce carcass fat/cholesterol by applying traditional procedures: proper nutrition, genetic selection and meat processing. The principles of each are well understood and will not be considered further in this report. Rather, the focus will be on new strategies afforded by potential new products.
These include growth hormone (GH) and peptides regulating its secretion and expression of its biological effects, β-adrenergic agonists and transgenic animals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/228</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 27-32</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/228/215</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
