<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/78</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T19:38:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S5</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Recent Trends in Patent and Trade Secret Laws and Their Impact on Our Industry</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Annis, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">patent law</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">trade secrets</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">case law</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">legislation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">industry</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The principal purpose of this presentation is to address with the audience growing trends in the intellectual property world, focusing on patent and trade secret rights, and, in particular, how those trends are impacting the animal health and biotech industries. Changes in patent law over the last decade, especially in the area of patent eligibility, along with enactment of the Defend Trade Secrets Act, has forced a rethinking of how to protect innovation and advancements in biotechnology and diagnostic methods.&amp;nbsp; The program will address the changes in law and how to better navigate the new paradigm.&amp;nbsp; We will also discuss pending federal legislation addressed to the American patent system and whether we may see some normalization on the issue of patent eligibility.&amp;nbsp; I will unpack recent case law and pending litigation to reveal industry vulnerabilities, while offering a look ahead to the likely direction future disputes will take.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/78</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 21st Biennial Symposium; 73</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/78/73</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
