<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/217</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:15:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S7</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Development of Clinical Pharmacology Over the Next Decade</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wilcke, Jeff R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary clinical pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacokinetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">therapeutic drug monitoring</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animal medicine</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Several specific areas should be addressed by veterinary clinical pharmacology. Practicing veterinarians need a grounding in practical pharmacokinetics and therapeutic drug monitoring. A knowledge of pharmacokinetics will allow for appropriate modification in therapy for the diseased animal and in the face of drug interactions. Therapeutic monitoring has the potential to assist us in food animal medicine, allowing for dose flexibility while we avoid inappropriate drug residues. We must emphasize therapeutic decision making rather than limiting options for the sake of convenience. If we wish to retain the right to formulate drug products from bulk drug supplies, emphasis must be given to formulation chemistry, bioavailability, and drug interactions which occur during the formulation process. Our graduates should become more familiar with the practice and utility of professional pharmacy. The clinical pharmacologist can help accomplish these things by participating in the core professional curriculum, in clinical rounds and seminars for students, house staff and clinical faculty, through therapeutic consultation in teaching hospitals, in the graduate program within the college of veterinary medicine, and through continuing education programs for graduate veterinarians.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/217</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fifth Biennial Symposium; 299-305</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/217/205</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
