<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/48</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T18:58:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Drug Testing in Livestock Show Animals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mays, Travis</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Three different methods for establishing decision limits for therapeutic drugs detected in animals exhibited at livestock shows were evaluated. The first method considered for establishing decision limits in therapeutic drugs detected in animals exhibited at livestock shows was the 95/95 Tolerance Interval (Products, 2000) used in the US by the Racing Medication &amp;amp; Testing Consortium (RMTC) Scientific Advisory Committee (SAC). The second method was the irrelevant plasma concentration (IPC) and irrelevant urine concentration (IUC) approach used by regulators in horse racing in Europe (Toutain &amp;amp; Lassourd, 2002). The third method was a novel method using pharmacodynamic models and incorporating variability and measurement error. . This new approach could be used to define thresholds for identifying potentially unacceptable levels of therapeutic drugs in urine from exhibition animals as it takes into consideration drug effects and multiple aspects of measurement error and population variability</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/48</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 21st Biennial Symposium; 14-16</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/48/42</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
