<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/129</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:54:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SI</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Task Force</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">therapeutics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">task force</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics (AAVPT), in accord with the organization's stated mission and purpose, has the responsibility to respond to issues of major concern in the field of veterinary pharmacology and therapeutics. Several aspects of the developmental and approval processes as well as the availability of veterinary drugs, have been the subject of a continuing dialogue between the pharmaceutical industry, Food and Drug Administration, American Veterinary Medical Association and academia in recent years. The rate of introducing new animal drug products continue to decline, particularly those intended for use in food animals. The time required to develop new animal drugs continually increases and the economics, as related to approval requirements, are certainly less than favorable. Likewise, the concerns for public health and consumer protection continue to intensify.
Recognizing the complexity of these issues, at its Third Symposium of the Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics, a special task force was appointed to explore in depth some of those potential and real problem areas that may adversely impact the veterinary profession. This report is the result of the deliberations of this special task force.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1982-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/129</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Third Symposium; 135-143</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/129/123</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1982 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
