<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/28</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-25T02:56:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Patterns of Antimicrobial Prescribing Practices for Treatment of Escherichia coli Infections in Dogs and Cats in the United States</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thungrat, Kamoltip</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boothe, Dawn M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Antimicrobials</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Prescribing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">E. coli</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Infection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Dogs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cats</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To effectively control resistance, medical communities need to monitor and limit antimicrobial use. The objective of this study was to describe patterns of veterinary antimicrobial prescribing behaviors and investigate any associations between MDR infections, antimicrobial use, and clinical outcomes of antimicrobial therapy. A retrospective study was conducted from January 2008 through January 2013 of spontaneous E. coli canine and feline infections (n=823) diagnosed in veterinary practices in the US. A questionnaire was sent to veterinarians that had submitted samples with isolates that were subjected to antimicrobial susceptibility testing. Collected information included signalment, history of infection, and antimicrobial information (drug and dosing regimens). Univariate analyses were performed to describe the patterns of antimicrobial use. Risk factors for MDR E. coli infections were polymicrobial infections and non-urinary tract infections. Antimicrobials most frequently used and the proportions of isolates resistant to that drug were amoxicillin-clavulanic acid (AMC; 25% [190/760] use, 24% [46/190] resistance), enrofloxacin (22% [170/760] use, 6% [10/170] resistance), 1st generation cephalosporins (9% [68/670] use, 99% [67/38] cephalothin-resistance), and amoxicillin (9% [66/760] use, 21% [14/66] resistance). The proportions of appropriate dosing regimens used were 0.6% of AMC, 23% of enrofloxacin, 26% of 1st generation cephalosporins, and 3.5% of amoxicillin for treatment of urinary tract infections. Proportions of success versus failure were not demonstratively different among drugs except for 1st generation cephalosporins (P=0.03). Dose and duration could be related to success only for AMC. Our study suggests that the inappropriate use of antimicrobials is not the only cause of therapeutic failure.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/28</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/28/28</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
