<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/200</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:15:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S4</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Tissue Residues of Aminoglycoside Antibiotics in Sheep</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brown, Scott Anthony</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Coppoc, Gordon L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Gentamicin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sheep</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">renal cortex</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">intramuscular injection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tissue concentration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animals</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Gentamicin was administered to sheep at several single intramuscular dosages and as multiple doses for up to seven days. Concentrations of gentamicin determined serially after the last dose were highest in the renal cortex. The exponential model used to predict the decline in renal cortical concentrations increased in complexity as the dose increased, whereas the power function model of that decline remained stable across all doses and durations of therapy. Other tissue concentrations of gentamicin in decreasing order were renal medulla, liver, spleen and lung, and muscle. Heart and skeletal muscle contained less than 0.6 μg/g one day after the last of the multiple doses. Injection site skeletal muscle contained up to 29 μg/g one day after the last dose and were dependent on the number of injections made, not on the total amount of gentamicin administered. The results presented here argue in favor of selective condemnation of the kidneys and liver of animals given aminoglycosides and against intramuscular injection of aminoglycosides in food-producing animals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/200</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fifth Biennial Symposium; 127-140</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/200/190</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
