<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/159</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:55:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Kinetic Fate of Anthelmintics and Therapeutic Implications</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Paul, John W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anthelmintics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">benzimidazoles</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">levamisole</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ivermectin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacokinetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacodynamics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parasites</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Until recent years, the pharmacology of anthelmintics had not been extensively studied. With the introduction of modern drugs, notably the benzimidazoles, levamisole and ivermectin, a new interest to investigate the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of anthelmintics has arisen. Regulatory requirements for approval of anthelmintics for use in food-producing animals have dictated the necessity of more elaborate pharmacological studies. For this reason, and in an effort to gain more scientific knowledge about the use of new drugs, the pharmaceutical industry, in cooperation with academia, has been instrumental in the development of pharmacological data with anthelmintics.
Previously, anthelmintics had been evaluated mainly for efficacy in removing adult parasites from the gastrointestinal tract and for safety to the host; pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics did not seem to be important. Now, with the application of pharmacological data, it is possible to predict how to remove adult parasites such as lungworms and kidneyworms from other sites in the body. In addition, various immature forms of parasites in histotropic stages can now be controlled. Obviously, the parasites, regard less of their location or stage of development, must be susceptible to the action of the drug.
It must be pointed out that there are certain limitations with pharmacokinetic studies with many of the currently available anthelmintics because of the difficulty in administering these drugs intravenously; benzimidazoles due to low solubility, levamisole and ivermectin due to toxicological consideration. The information presented in this paper is limited to data collected following oral administration of drugs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1984-04-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/159</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fourth Symposium; 29-</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/159/152</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1984 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
