<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/245</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SIV</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Development of an Automated Clinical Pharmacokinetic Dosing Program for Therapeutic Drug Monitoring in Veterinary Medicine</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Riviere, J. Edmond</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">serum concentration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug concentration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dosage regimen</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">computer</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It is well established that the dose of drug administered to an individual clinical patient is often poorly correlated with the serum concentrations achieved. Therapeutic Drug Monitoring (TDM) has recently been advocated for use in monitoring drug concentrations in veterinary patients in order to adjust dosage regimens to compensate for this variability. Pharmacokinetic principles have been applied to this problem in a research setting in an effort to quantitate this lack of prediction. With the advent of microcomputers and relatively inexpensive minicomputers, the full power of pharmacokinetics can be applied to veterinary TDM allowing clinicians to individualize dosages based on pharmacokinetic parameters and assayed drug concentrations.
Our laboratory has been involved in using computers to individualize drug dosage regimens in a research and clinical setting for the past five years and has developed two strategies to address this problem. The first, which is ideally suited to a research and intensive care setting, is to utilize computer driven infusion pumps to precisely achieve targeted serum drug concentration-time profiles in individual animals (1,2). The second approach was to develop a software program to calculate multiple dosage regimens based on individual pharmacokinetics and a targeted serum concentration time profile (3,4). This program, PETDR (Pharmacokinetic Estimation of Therapeutic Dosage Regimens), is an outgrowth of software development for the FARAD (Food Animal Residue Avoidance Databank) program (see preceding Sundlof contribution). The goal of developing automated software systems for veterinary clinical pharmacokinetics is to make the mathematical computations transparent to the user and provide a tool by which TDM can be easily applied in a clinical setting for drugs warranting close surveillance.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/245</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 86-89</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/245/228</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
