<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/255</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SV</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">New Frontiers in Veterinary and Comparative Pharmacology for Regulatory Agencies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Teske, Richard H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary clinical pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug distribution</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animals</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I would like to stimulate some thoughts about the future in veterinary clinical pharmacology. My perspective is that of a veterinary drug regulator, and I must begin by saying that from my perspective these are, at once, exciting, depressing, challenging, frustrating times. I believe that we are on the threshold of significant change, particularly in the area of drug distribution and use in food animals.
One of the driving forces causing change in this area is the concern being expressed by consumers for animal-derived food products that are free of drug or pesticided residues. This concern has led to a change in the attitude or philosophy of many livestock producers relative to the products they produce. More and more producers recognize that responsibility for their product does not end when their animals are shipped for slaughter or the milk tanker heads down the lane. They recognize that they are both dependent on and bear a shared responsibility for, not only the actual but also the perceived, wholesomeness of the product at the retail level.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/255</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 113-114</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/255/238</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
