<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/152</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:53:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SV</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Clinical Pharmacology of Cephalosporins in Veterinary Medicine</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sams, Richard A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cephalosporins</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cephalosporin generation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hydrolysis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The cephalosporins are beta-lactam antibiotics closely related to the penicillins. They are semisynthetic derivatives of cephalosporin C, first isolated from the fungus, Cephalosporium acremonium, which was discovered by Giuseppi Brotzu in 1945 in seawater near a sewage outlet. This organism was found to produce antibiotic material with activity against both Gram positive and Gram negative bacteria. Investigators identified three new antibiotics produced by the fungus. Among these antibiotics is cephalsporin C which was shown to be a broad-spectrum antibiotic with low specific activity. It resembles penicillin N, which is also produced by C. acremonium, in having a beta-lactam ring and the D-α-aminoadipyl side chain. However, in cephalosporin C, the beta-lactam ring is fused to a dihydrothiazine ring in contrast to the thiazolidine ring of the penicillins. Moreover, cephalosporin C is stable in dilute acids and is resistant to hydrolysis by many bacterial penicillinases.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1982-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/152</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Third Symposium; 247-275</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/152/146</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1982 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
