<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/68</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-28T19:21:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Identifying the source of arsenic residues following parenteral versus oral dosing in horses</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Whittem, Ted</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kysenius, Kai</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bailey, Simon R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Steel, Cate M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Crouch, Peter</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zahra, Paul</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">arsenic</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">racehorses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">urine testing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hair testing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">crib-biting</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Australian racing laboratories routinely screen equine urine using ICP-MS for arsenic, to enforce a urinary arsenic threshold of 300ng/mL. Trainers of horses whose samples exceed the threshold have claimed that the elevated urinary arsenic concentration results from consumption of arsenic-chromium treated fencing timbers. Previously we have shown that feeding horses 100g sawdust per 500 kg bodyweight or a single IV dose of 1mg/kg sodium arsanilate (Jurocyl; CEVA) to individual horses resulted in urinary arsenic concentrations above the threshold. Urinary chromium could be detected but differentiation between the dose’s source was not possible (AEC 1513794.2). We now report that mane-hair samples were also collected by plucking at 4 weeks post-dose and analysed using laser-ablation ICP-MS. Hair from a control horse and from one horse of each treatment group were analysed twice. First, LA-ICP-MS was directed along the cortex of the hairs and second, the hairs were split and the laser was directed along the core of the hairs. In the first analysis, a strong signal for As (m/z 75) was detected in hair from the treated horses, at points along the hair shaft corresponding to dose-timing with hair growth rate of approximately 2cm/mo. In the second analysis, a strong signal for Cr (m/z 52) was detected only in the orally treated horse’s hair at the relevant hair shaft length. We conclude that LA-ICP-MS using hair samples is a useful tool for retrospective confirmation of crib-biting of As-treated timber which can result in urinary arsenic detection.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/68</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 21st Biennial Symposium; 49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/68/63</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
