<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/22</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-06-25T02:46:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The ontogeny of hepatic cytochrome P450 enzymes in conventional pigs using enzyme activity and proteomics</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Millecam, Joske</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gasthuys, Elke</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Devreese, Mathias</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Deforce, Dieter</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Van Bocxlaer, Jan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Croubels, Siska</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pig</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ontogeny</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cytochrome P450</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">proteomics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">enzyme activity</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Development of appropriate animal models taking growth and maturation into account is pivotal for pediatric preclinical pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic (PK/PD) research. Literature reports have demonstrated a high homology between human and porcine CYP450 enzymes in adults, suggesting the pig as a suited animal model for PK/PD and safety studies [1]. However data regarding the ontogeny of porcine hepatic CYP enzymes are lacking.The in vitro CYP450 enzyme activity of the following probe substrates was measured in microsomes: midazolam, tolbutamide and chlorzoxazone. The microsomes were prepared of each time 16 pigs (8 ♂ and 8 ♀, Hybrid sow x Piétrain boar) aging 2 days, 4 weeks, 8 weeks and 6-7 months. Furthermore, the microsomal protein per gram liver (MPPGL) was determined [2]. In addition to these in vitro activity experiments, the CYP isoenzymes in the same microsomes were determined by high definition data directed analysis (HD-DDA) mass spectrometry. The data analysis was performed using Progenesis QI.The microsomal activity of the three substrates increased with age. Significant sex differences were observed at 8 weeks of age for the three substrates and at 6 months of age for chlorzoxazone. The activity per gram liver, as calculated with the MPPGL, also showed a maturation profile. The increase in microsomal activity is reflected in an increase in CYP450 proteins in the microsomes. A total of 17 CYP isoenzymes was identified from which 10 had 2 or more unique peptides. These results show similar trends with human CYP ontogeny.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/22</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; 20th Biennial Symposium</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/22/22</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
