<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/126</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:54:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SI</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Responsibilities and Obligations of the Sponsors, Monitors and Investigators to Clinical Studies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gable, Donald A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Carnevale, Richard</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">FDA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical studies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Investigational New Animal Drugs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">regulations</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) regulations pertaining to clinical investigations of test articles (including animal drugs and animal food additives) are intended to help assure the quality and integrity of the data filed with FDA and to assure adequate protection of the rights and safety of subjects (humans and animals) involved in clinical investigations.
This paper discusses the specific requirements for sponsors, monitors, and investigators to the conduct of clinical investigations and itemizes some of the existing deficiencies with primary interest in Investigational New Animal Drugs (INADs). The purpose of the paper is to address the FDA concern about the validity and reliability of scientific data on the safety and effectiveness of animal drug products and contend that the clinical investigation regulations would complement existing regulations to improve the conduct of clinical investigations.
The clinical investigation regulations and their related compliance programs establish procedures and responsibilities for the following groups: sponsors, including contract research organizations; monitors; clinical investigators; and FDA personnel involved in field inspections and the preclearance review of clinical studies.
Exemptions, as used, refer to the existing premarketing regulations providing for clinical investigational use of test articles regulated by FDA. The specific statutes are: new drug (Part 312), new animal drug (Part 511), investigational device (Part 812), and biological product (Part 601). Each of these parts enumerates requirements to the investigation which are specific to that test article.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1982-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/126</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Third Symposium; 81-103</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/126/120</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1982 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
