<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/191</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:16:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:S2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Eicosanoids: A Selective Update</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Boothe, Dawn Merton</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Friedlander, Lynn G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jenkins, William L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">eicosanoids</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pathophysiology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ion transport</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">inflammatory responses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immune responses</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The phenomenal and on-going explosion of knowledge regarding the physiological and pathological roles of the eicosanoids, as well as the pharmacological modulation of their biosynthesis and actions, precludes any comprehensive commentary on the current understanding of all aspects of the biosynthesis, pathophysiology and pharmacology of the prostaglandins, leukotrienes and the hydroperoxy fatty acids. Several recent reviews should serve as adequate sources for many of the details of eicosanoid-associated pathophysiology and pharmacology and only a few select topics of special interest will be covered in this presentation. However, a synoptic overview of the arachidonic acid cascades and the main physiological and pharmacological actions of the principle eicosanoids will be furnished to serve as a basis for the succeeding papers in this section. The subjects that will be discussed include the concept of membrane-mediated control of intra- and extracellular events by phospholipid-derived substances, the roles of eicosanoids in membrane ion transport, the renal effects of the prostaglandins and some features of the inflammatory and immune responses that are modulated by the eicosanoids. It is clearly recognized that substantial advances have also taken place with regard to our knowledge of the eicosanoids' actions in many other body systems, such as the gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, reproductive and central nervous systems, but these will not be addressed specifically in this review simply due to the extensiveness of such a task.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/191</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Fifth Biennial Symposium; 20-42</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/191/182</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
