<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/115</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T18:54:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SI</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">New Animal Drug Evaluation and Approval Process</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baldwin, Robert A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">therapeutics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">FD&amp;C Act</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">safety</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">manufacturing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">labeling</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One of the important aspects of the way veterinarians practice veterinary medicine in the United States is that they, as well as those they serve expect that the drugs they receive are safe, effective, properly labeled and manufactured with the highest standards of quality.
The therapeutic arsenal of veterinary medicine today contains an array of drugs that are more rational, better understood, and more accurately labeled than were drugs in the market place before the 1962 Drug Amendments, better known as the 1962 Kefauver-Harris Amendments to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, the FD&amp;amp;C Act.
Before 1962, only certifiable antibiotics needed data to support efficacy before marketing. Safety, manufacturing methods and controls, and labeling were all that was necessary to support the marketing of a new animal drug.
In the almost 20 years since those amendments were enacted, an extensive evolution in science, veterinary medicine, and the management of animals, especially food animals, has changed the development, testing, approval, and marketing of new animal drugs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1982-04-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/115</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Third Symposium; 2-20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/115/109</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1982 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
