<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/241</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SIII</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Integration of Pharmacology Research and Graduate Training</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Riviere, J. Edmond</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">graduate students</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmacology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">research programs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">academic institution</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">To many veterinary pharmacologists, training graduate students and conducting research are synonymous. However, recent advances in veterinary and comparative pharmacology, a myriad of possible funding sources to support research, and new types of training programs have resulted in the need to reevaluate the goals of both graduate student training and pharmacology research. Many definitions exist as to what a graduate student should be taught. Numerous tags have been placed on the various types of pharmacology research being conducted in academic institutions and industry. Since many of these labels have been created for different purposes, it is instructive to explore this lexicon before a discussion of integrating graduate studies with research programs is begun.
This paper will be written from the personal perspective of the author as a member of a traditional academic institution, as a major advisor for both "classical" graduate students and for those who have combined residency training with graduate studies, as a "consumer" of both federal and industrial grants and contracts, and most recently as the Director of a newly established hybrid academic/industrial research program, whose goals are both research and graduate training. I do not pretend to have the solutions, however I believe that what follows is a reasonable definition of the problems and presents some alternatives for integrating the wide range of graduate training and research approaches that exist in veterinary medicine today.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/241</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 66-69</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/241/224</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
