<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/231</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-10-30T19:17:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aavptbiennial:SII</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Analytical Methodologies for Establishing Residue Control</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Norcross, M. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Post, A. R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Miller, W. R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal drugs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">agricultural chemical use</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">toxicity</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">No single entity has full responsibility for monitoring and controlling the use of animal drugs and agricultural chemicals in the food production sector. The control of residues is a complex and difficult task shared by government, academia and industry and to be successful there must be continuous and complete coordination and cooperation between those responsible for residue control. Symposia such as this one greatly enhance our efforts to improve mechanisms for cooperation between residue control entities.
The past 4 decades have seen a remarkable scientific revolution in agriculture in which chemical technology has played a crucial role. Pharmaceutical and other chemicals have been used to fertilize the soil, destroy pests, enrich feed, control disease and promote the growth of livestock and poultry. Few will question the advances conferred on today's agriculture by chemical technology. The use of these chemical agents has assured an abundant wholesome food supply and in many ways contributed to the health and welfare of our nation. While these chemical entities have contributed positively to each of these goals, in some instances they have had undesirable side effects, including polluting the environment, jeopardizing human health, or, in the longer term, intensifying the productivity problem the chemical was to solve.
The exposure of food-producing animals to environmental contaminants, or the use of pesticides or animal drugs in a way that does not conform with approved uses, can leave unacceptable levels of chemical residues in edible tissues. Advances in analytical technology have made possible the detection of increasingly lower levels of these chemical residues, causing new concerns about their potential toxicological significance.
It is a fact that most agricultural chemicals have some toxic properties, and while the scope and degree of toxicity vary widely among the compounds, virtually none can be considered harmless. For most toxic effects there is a threshold dose. Agricultural chemical use is regulated so that the threshold dose of toxicity is not exceeded and that safety is assured when these chemicals are properly used. It is not surprising, therefore, that the general public is aroused when instances of careless or unnecessary use of agricultural chemicals are brought to their attention.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-06-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/231</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">AAVPT Biennial Symposia; Sixth Biennial Symposium; 44-49</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://aavptbiennial-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aavptbiennial/article/view/231/218</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Academy of Veterinary Pharmacology and Therapeutics</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
