<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4712</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-14T15:20:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:VetTech</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Understanding Bovine Behavior for Safe Handling</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wagner, Sarah</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle behavior</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">body language</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">flight zone</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">point of balance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">safe handling</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Understanding the behavior of cattle makes working with them easier, safer and more enjoyable. Reading the cow's body language helps indicate if she is relaxed or stressed, healthy or ill. A cow will remain calmer and easier to work with if she can see you approach her. Stress may be minimized by taking care not to isolate a cow away from other cattle and by minimizing startling or loud noises, including yelling. Cows are individuals; like people, some will remain relatively calm and some will become agitated under the same circumstances. Cows that are handled gently tend to be gentler cows than those that are handled roughly.
Keeping the principles of flight zone and point of balance in mind will make moving cattle as quick and calm as possible. When cattle are lined up in a chute or alley, walking through their flight zone in a nose-to-tail direction will cause each animal to step forward as their point of balance is passed.
Cattle may become aggressive when they feel threatened, anxious, or protective of a calf. If a cow shows signs such as vocalization, pacing, pawing, or head-shaking, entering her flight zone may cause her to attack. Bulls must always be handled carefully, particularly dairy breed bulls. A bull that displays a broadside threat should be removed from the herd at once.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2006-09-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4712</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20064712</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2006; 227-228</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4712/4610</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2006 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
