<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6088</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-06T00:15:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CCFS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Seven Ways You Can be Misled by Efficacy Studies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hancock, Dale</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">product efficacy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine practitioner</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">efficacy screening</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">efficacy trials</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biological products</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmaceutical products</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Arguably, evaluating and comparing the efficacies of products is the most important activity of bovine practitioners. Some practitioners may believe that any legally marketed products must be effective due either to government mandate or to free market forces which would drive an ineffective product to ruin. Yet, there seems little basis for either notion. Even a relatively non-critical review of literature related to extant licensed biologicals leads one to conclude that many of them are - at best - of questionable efficacy. And, given the ease with which, frankly, quack products (e.g., various "immunological" and "nutritional" supplements) are marketed over a period of many years, it is difficult to support a conclusion that the free market does a good job of "efficacy screening."
The purpose of this report is to provide, in a hopefully humorous and satiric format, the seven principal means - intentional and unintentional, conscious and unconscious - by which reports of efficacy trials make biological and pharmaceutical products seem more effective than they really are.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1995-09-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6088</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1995; 111-114</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6088/6865</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1995 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
