<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5186</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:21:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:AABPSFT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Teaser Bull Preparation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hull, Bruce L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Heat detection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">teaser bulls</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sterile</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">venereal disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">libido</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">production economics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Heat detection by human observation in beef cows is much more difficult and time intensive than it is in dairy cows. Consequently many producers rely on teaser bulls (a.k.a. gomer bulls). Any time one creates a teaser bull there are two main objectives. The first and most important is to be sure the bull in question is unable to impregnate the cows he is placed with. Of secondary importance in creating a teaser that is a non-entry teaser and will not spread venereal disease. In some herds the spread of venereal disease is of very little concern and as such the herd owner does not worry about this aspect. Choosing a bull from the owner's herd helps assure a healthy bull.
A third aspect that people seldom worry about is the libido of the teaser. We as veterinarians should be creating teaser bulls from young, vigorous, fertile bulls. We are occasionally presented with a cull bull (rejected because of failure to pass a breeding soundness examination) to be made into a teaser bull. This is always an uncomfortable scenario as if the bull does not have enough libido to follow and mark cows in heat we have failed in our mission. With this same thought in mind a young bull is far more sexually active than an older more lethargic bull, and therefore makes a superior teaser bull.
We are often asked how long a given teaser bull will remain sexually active, and there are certainly techniques that produce bulls that are only active (at least in the owners perception) for a year. Far too much emphasis is placed on this aspect of teaser bull preparation. From a production economics standpoint, new teaser bulls should be created each year from young sexually active bulls. These young bulls will gain weight over the summer and can be sold in the fall of the year before harvested forages and purchased feed needs to be put into them. Basically these are non-productive animals and to winter them does not produce profits.
The technique one uses to create a teaser bull is largely a matter of personal preference, although client demand may enter into the selection process.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2001-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5186</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20015186</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2001; 92-94</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5186/5058</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2001 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
