<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8532</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-12-22T03:05:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Preweaned dairy calf nutrition: Veterinarian’s role in a milk feeding program</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cox, Elizabeth A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy calf</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk feeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">preweaning nutrition</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The herd veterinarian has an important role on calf raising op­erations to promote the health and welfare of calves through having a role in the milk phase nutrition program. Optimal nutrition will benefit the calves and the herd veterinarian can help provide input and critique of a milk program using their expertise in animal health, husbandry, nutrition and behav­ior. Milk feeding of calves, traditionally around 60 days, has been shown to have long term production benefits for adult dairy cows, and yet often the milk feeding plan is delegated to a private or feed company nutritionist. This paper describes tools and best practices for herd veterinarians to ensure young calves are fed appropriately to meet their genetic potential and the dairy producer’s goals. Even if the herd veterinarian does not have overall authority of a milk program, they can use the best practices to align producer expectations with what is be­ing offered to the calves and give their impartial input of how to best apply the producer’s resources in a feeding program for the benefit of the calves.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8532</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228532</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2022 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 100-104</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8532/8324</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
