<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8510</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-12-22T03:06:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Beef nutrition 101: What a veterinarian needs to know to work with a nutritionist</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Linneen, Sara</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nutrition</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The disunion between veterinarians and nutritionists sup­porting the cattle industry is not new, albeit there are plentiful opportunities to improve. Successful operations need the per­spective and technical knowledge of both professionals to op­timize productivity. The need for improvement is magnified by the inability of the cattle industry to make strides in improving mortality rates that is most likely a reflection of management x health x nutrition interactions. Opportunity for veterinarians to support producers nutritionally is most prevalent among cattle segments not traditionally supported by trained nutri­tionists. These include cow-calf operations and confinement feeding operations with less than 500 head capacity. To facili­tate nutritional conversations with the nutritionists, a basic un­derstanding of the 6 classes of nutrients is critical. These class­es include water, carbohydrates, lipids, protein, vitamins and minerals. A base level understanding of each nutrient paired with a broad idea of applied concepts associated with feeding will make for constructive two-sided conversations about nutri­tion between technical professionals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8510</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228510</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2022 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 37-40</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8510/8302</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
