<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3727</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:41:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Disposition of ampicillin trihydrate in plasma, uterine tissue, and lochial fluid of post-partum dairy cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Credille, Brent</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Giguere, Steeve</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vickroy, Thomas W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fishman, Heidi J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jones, A. Lee</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ensley, Douglas T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Acute puerperal metritis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antimicrobials</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ceftiofur</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">FDA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cephalosporins</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dairy cattle are susceptible to numerous infectious and metabolic disorders in the immediate postparturient period. Acute puerperal metritis (APM) is one of the most common clinical conditions seen in modern dairy cattle, affecting 18-33% of all cattle that calve. Antimicrobials are a mainstay of therapy for cattle with APM. Currently, three antimicrobials are labeled for systemic therapy in cattle with APM. Of these, products containing ceftiofur as the active compound are used most frequently. The United States Food and Drug Administration recently passed an order prohibiting the extra-label use of cephalosporins in major food-producing species because of concerns over the development of resistance to similar 3rd generation cephalosporin compounds used in critically ill human patients. Thus, it is prudent to consider and investigate the use of other antimicrobials for cattle with this important clinical disease. While emerging evidence would suggest that ampicillin trihydrate would have value as a therapeutic agent in dairy cattle with APM, the disposition of the drug in plasma, uterine tissue, and lochial fluid has not been investigated.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3727</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20143727</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2014; 146</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3727/3668</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2014 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
