<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7879</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:14:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bovine Virus Diarrhea (BVD) Vaccination</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Caley, Homer D. </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine viral diarrhea (BVD)</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stressed calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">titers</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine viral diarrhea (BVD) was first reported in 1946, or approximately 30 years ago, yet there is still confusion and lack of understanding of this disease. It is difficult to find general agreement on any part of this disease entity from vaccination to titer. Despite the confusion, most people have definite opinions about the disease, including the use of vaccine. The majority of feedlot cattle in southwestern Kansas receive an intramuscular inoculation of BVD vaccine when they enter feedlots . Recently, some oral BVD vaccine has been used. This trial was to compare oral and intramuscular BVD vaccine in stressed calves. Rate of gain, feed consumption, and feed efficiency were not influenced by BVD vaccine administration (Table 1). This was an anticipated response, as initial BVD titers indicated calves had not been previously exposed to BVD. BVD vaccine administered orally did not increase titers at 42 days after inoculation. But when it was administered intramuscularly, five steers had BVD titers exceeding 1 :4. Sickness was held to a minimum and no calves died.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-12-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7879</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19787879</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1978; 152-153</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7879/7494</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
