<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9176</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-26T17:14:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Detecting Salmonella Dublin in environmental samples through endpoint multiplex PCR and culture</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Arevalo-Mayorga, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Locke, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Middleton, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kopkey, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Habing, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Salmonella Dublin (S. Dublin), a host-adapted serovar, is ca足pable of causing disease in both humans and cattle. Infected animals are prone to becoming long-term carriers, shedding the pathogen, contaminating the environment, and sustaining the disease cycle on the farm. Traditional culture methods are often less sensitive for detecting the pathogen in environmen足tal samples, limiting our ability to understand its prevalence and epidemiology. Therefore, integrating culture-independent techniques is imperative to enhance our capacity to identify affected areas, provide insights into transmission routes, and contribute to mitigating the risk of disease transmission. This study aims to ascertain the prevalence of S. Dublin in environ足mental samples from calf production systems, including calf marketing operations, veal and dairy-beef farms, using mul足tiplex endpoint polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and culture. We hypothesize that PCR will enhance the specific detection of S. Dublin in cattle environments.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9176</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20249176</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 58 (2024): 2024 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 225</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9176/8834</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
