<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5509</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-30T20:02:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:APC</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Dairy Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hicks, Jerry</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It is a pleasure to be here. We have a group practice in Edgerton. We have five veterinarians, one having a Ph.D. in nutrition. Our mornings start out like about everyone else's. We start out with a routine visit to some farm, sometimes two of us are out on routine visits. We always have one free to cover; someone has to check the small -animal clinic and see if anything died overnight. Anyway, he also covers emergencies. Every time we pregnancy check a cow we try to record everything on a clipboard. We leave the clipboard at the barn. We have less than a dollar invested there! We figure we can give that to anyone whether he is on the herd health program or not. We try to write down everything; every veterinarian does this because we do not all necessarily go to the same farms all the time. We rotate and it is very hard to remember what somebody else gave to what animal. Sometimes we get bad drug reactions when we do not keep track of what was done. Also, it is a place to leave messages. I do not know if you find it this way, but half the time I go to the farm and the farmer is gone. I do not know why he calls me if he is not going to bother to be there but at least I like to let him know that I have been there, before my bill arrives!</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5509</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1972; 18-19</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5509/5363</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1972 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
