<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3764</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:40:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:AASRPPRS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Penetrating captive-bolt euthanasia of goats: optimal shot placement and evaluation of polled and horned goats</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Plummer, P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shearer, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ramirez, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kleinhenz, K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weber, W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shearer, L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">euthanization</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">penetrating captive bolt device</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">PCB</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anatomic site</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">captive bolt placement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">frontal site</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">positioning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">brainstem disruption</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Anatomical placement of a penetrating captive bolt device (PCB) when euthanizing animals is critical to ensure vital structures are damaged, thereby rendering animals immediately unconscious and death occurring without a return to sensibility. Although PCB are an approved method for euthanizing small ruminants, the current peer-reviewed literature contains discrepancies regarding the appropriate anatomic site to be used for euthanasia procedures. Currently, 2 important documents, American Veterinary Medical Association’s 2013 Euthanasia Guidelines (AVMA) and World Organization for Animal Health’s Terrestrial Code (OIE), are in disagreement over the recommended site for captive bolt placement in small ruminants. The AVMA 2013 guideline recommends use of a frontal site high on the forehead aiming towards the foramen magnum as an alternative site in horned goats. The OIE recommends the frontal site be used for gunshot only. Exact positioning of a PCB at the poll is poorly described in the literature. The objective of this study was to determine the optimal anatomical site for PCB placement in horned and polled goats to ensure brainstem disruption consistently occurs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3764</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20143764</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2014; 177-178</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3764/3703</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2014 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
