<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9365</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PMS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Neurodiverse minds, visible solutions: Enhancing workplace inclusion</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Carey, Regina Marie</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">invisible disabilities</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neurodiversity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">inclusion</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Not all challenges are visible, but the impact of invisible chal­lenges on performance, communication and morale is very real. In veterinary practice, many brilliant professionals are quietly navigating invisible challenges including attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), anxiety, depression, autoimmune conditions, menopause, or chronic pain while striving to meet the demands of their work. This session ex­plores how invisible disabilities and neurodivergence shape daily experiences for people across their lifespan and discusses why understanding these realities matters for personnel reten­tion, workplace well-being, and staff performance in veterinary medicine. Participants will gain insight into the prevalence and comorbid nature of invisible disabilities, the overlap with neu­rodiverse conditions, and the growing prevalence and impact of chronic conditions in the workforce. Using interactive tools, participants will reflect on attitudes toward neurodiversity and uncover strategies to improve psychological safety, morale and team communication. Practical examples and universal design approaches will highlight low-cost, high-impact accommoda­tions that reduce burnout and surface hidden strengths. With curiosity, creativity and commitment, veterinary teams can move beyond awareness to action – creating inclusive cultures that value ability, foster trust and sustain well-being. Partici­pants can expect research-backed insights and practical steps to shift from accommodation to true inclusion.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9365</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259365</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 147-150</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9365/8978</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
