<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3265</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:34:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Transitioning from film to farm: A retrospective observational study</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ostrum, Peter</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Charlie</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Chocolate Factory</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Willy Wonka</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As a food animal veterinarian in a rural community, it can sometimes be difficult to appreciate the contributions that our profession provides to the local and global healthcare arena. As trusted and respected professionals, veterinarians may be the ideal messenger to help promote the "One Health” initiative of interdisciplinary collaboration and communication in all aspects of healthcare for humans, animals, and the environment.&amp;nbsp; Modern agricultural trends and demographic changes in recent decades have allowed many consumers to lose touch with their historical agrarian roots. To help bridge this gap, technically proficient veterinarians with excellent communication skills can play a key role to clarify animal agriculture practices in the US today.&amp;nbsp; Drawing on our previous life experiences, our responsibility to the veterinary profession as bovine practitioners is to embrace new challenges with imagination and grace. Recent graduates and seasoned veterans need to remain confident, yet humble, as we realize our personal and professional goals and aspirations.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-02-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3265</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20183265</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2018 Recent Graduate Proceedings; 1-5</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3265/3227</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
