<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4166</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:50:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Dynamics of Tritrichomonas foetus Infection in Bulls Used for Natural Service in a Florida Dairy Farm</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pena, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Riso, C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rae, O.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">trichomonosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">natural service</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">venereal disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Tritrichomonas foetus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">protozoa</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">infertility</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The economic impact of bovine trichomonosis has been well reported for beef and grazing livestock. However, in dairy farms the extensive use of artificial insemination (AI) has reduced its prevalence. The one exception is those herds where natural service (NS) is a part of the reproductive management and the potential for venereal disease transmission exist. In the US, a considerable number of dairies use bulls in their reproductive program. In the Southeast, de Vries et al, (2005) reported that 70% of herds used NS along with an AI program. Worldwide trichomonosis is considered a major cause of infertility in cattle bred by natural service. Tritrichomonas foetus (T. foetus) is a flagellate, obligate, anaerobic protozoa which causes venereal disease in domestic animals. The transmission of T. foetus occurs at coitus when an infected bull breeds a susceptible female or vice versa. In bulls, the infection is asymptomatic. In females, the protozoa cause embryonic death during early stages of pregnancy and temporary infertility. However, pyometra or abortions are the only clinical signs that may be observed. The objective of this study was to evaluate the prevalence of T. foetus in dairy bulls used for natural service in Florida dairy farm.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2010-08-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4166</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20104166</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2010; 243</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4166/4089</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2010 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
