<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3416</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:37:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Why is change so hard? Communication as a tool for optimizing producer adherence to veterinary recommendations</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cary, Julie A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">client adherence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary communication</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Awareness of the importance of communication in veterinary medicine has been heightened in the last 2 decades. Formal communication instruction is now a core requirement for all AVMA-accredited Colleges of Veterinary Medicine. The profession as a whole is realizing the importance of communication as it relates to business success, professional satisfaction, and patient outcomes. Clinicians, clients, and patients benefit from the use of evidence-based clinical communication skills; assuring accurate, efficient, and effective transfer of information. While the initial efforts for communication in veterinary medicine seemed to focus on companion animal practice, few would dispute that communication is critical for production animal veterinarians. The complexity of the contexts in which production animal veterinarians work to effect change requires even greater understanding of how people make decisions and how to influence those decisions effectively. Veterinarians are encouraged to be curious: Take the time to understand your clients and stakeholders; what extrinsic and intrinsic motivators are present? How does their organization run and why is it run that way? To ensure accurate understanding, consider demonstrating an understanding of the client through summarizing and empathy. Once there is clear understanding that has been communicated, only then can the veterinarian begin to make recommendations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-09-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3416</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20163416</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2016; 17-20</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3416/3370</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2016 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
