<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6667</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-11T00:33:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Misc</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Encephalopathie Hepatique, Un Nouveau Syndrome Neonatal Chez Les Veaux</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ghergariu, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Baba, A. I.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gorgan, L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rotaru, O.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Spinu, O.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">alcohols</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">corn silage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hepatic encephalopathy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neonatal diarrhea</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nervous disturbances</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">blood ammonia</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In a farm of dairy cows, during an outbreak of neonatal diarrhea, the following nervous disturbances were observed in 3 calves without diarrhea and in 1 calf with diarrhea: ataxia, recumbency, abnormal positions of the head, hyperexcitability, an unusual and persistent bellowing and finally a comatose status. No bacterial or virusological implications were confirmed.
The blood ammonia in 2 sick calves (6 hours and 3 days of age) was 134,3 and 200,6 ) μg/dl respectively; the levels obtained in 11 healthy newborn calves 6-24 hours of age in a farm free of neonatal diarrhea were comprised between 1,03 and 52,26 μg/dl. The hepatic vitamin A in the above mentioned calves was 65,72 and 49,29 i.u./g.
The necropsy performed in the 2 calves after euthanasy as well as in 2 other dead calves revealed hepatic steatosis and fibrosis and spongy transformation of the white matter in the brain, the brain stem, cerebellum and medulla oblongata.
A diagnosis of hepatic encephalopathy was made as a result of the hyperammonaemia and the spongiosis of the white maiter of the C.N.S.
The possible involvement of an intrauterine exposition to the toxic effect of the high level of alcohols (16%) detected in the corn silage fed to the cows is suspected.
Article in French, English summary on PDF</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6667</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926667</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 3; 416-420</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6667/7221</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
