<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7203</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-10-16T01:02:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A randomized clinical trial assessing the effect of 3 different commercial oral calcium supplementation bolus on calcium dynamics and urine pH after calving: Interim findings</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferro, P. P. C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Antunes, A. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Neves, R. C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Caixeta, L. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calcium homeostasis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lactation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">serum calcium</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">postpartum</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Calcium (Ca) homeostasis is one of the many metabolic challenges faced by a dairy cow during her transition from the dry period into lactation. The use of anionic salts during the dry period is an effective strategy to prevent clinical hypocalcemia, yet subclinical hypocalcemia (SCH) has been reported to affect up to 70% of multiparous cows. Although the use of oral calcium supplements immediately after calving is a commonly adopted method to prevent and treat SCH in multiparous cows, there is a shortage of information comparing different oral calcium products. Thus, the overall goal of this project is to evaluate the effect of different commercially available oral calcium products on postpartum serum calcium profiles of dairy cows. Additional objectives are: determine milk production, urine pH, and Ca concentrations during the first 5 days after oral calcium supplementation. This study is ongoing, with serum and urine samples currently being analyzed to determine Ca concentrations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-09-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7203</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20197203</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2019; 340</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7203/5971</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
