<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3264</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:36:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Nine months in with the veterinary feed directive: Experiences and what is next</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Apley, Michael D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">VFD</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Guidance #213</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Last year at this time we were preparing for the Veterinary Feed Directive (VFD) transition and now we are survivors. There have been countless conversations between veterinarians and clients related to label indications, extralabel use, durations of use, concurrent use, repeated regimens (pulses), "hand fed” vs approved free choice feeds, and what comes next. We have advanced to the point of at least clarifying the uncertainties related to these subjects, and there is an indication of the next regulatory focus related to in-feed drugs. The "Blue Bird" labels have become familiar to many veterinarians to clarify the legal inclusions of Type C feeds. Also, Compliance Policy guide 615.115 has been useful for understanding the ability to use in-feed drugs in an extralabel manner in minor species. It is now clearly understood that asecond administration of an approved in-feed drug regimen to an animal requires an additional VFD be written. For determining which drugs may be concurrently fed together in feed, the Blue Bird labels and the Feed Additive Compendium are key sources. Next in the regulatory lineup is an evaluation of medically important in-feed antibiotics for which there is not a defined duration of administration in the label regimen.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3264</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20173264</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2017; 16-19</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3264/3226</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2017 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
