<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8298</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-10-24T20:58:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The U.S. Roundtable for Sustainable Beef and application of practices in a Nebraska feedlot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McDonald, Ashley</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sustainability</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">USRBS</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feedlot</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">goals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">metrics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The U.S. Roundtable for Sustainable Beef (USRSB) was formed in 2015 by more than 90 member-companies in the U.S. beef supply chain, allied industry partners, and stakeholders in civil society. Since inception, the USRSB has accomplished developing the U.S. Beef Industry Sustainability Framework (Framework) inclusive of 6 high-priority indicators, sector-spe足cific metrics for each indicator, and sustainability assessment guides which include tools and resources for every company in the supply chain. Drinnin Feedlots is one feedlot member implementing components of the Framework in a practical and commercial setting. The USRSB also has developed a self-assessment tool for all beef supply chain sectors, and is cur足rently in the process of developing interactive educational on足line modules. The USRSB also aids programs already developed in the marketplace through a Recognition Process that allows supply chain programs that have incorporated the metrics of the Framework to apply, be evaluated by a third party, and ap足proved for Recognition by the USRSB. The USRSB is now poised to set 6 U.S. beef industry sustainability goals and supply chain sector targets in the Fall of 2021. The tactics underlying the goals and targets will direct the work of the USRSB into the future.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8298</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2021 Annual Conference Proceedings; 24-27</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8298/8178</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
