<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4997</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-18T07:12:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Rendering Farm Mortalities: How Veterinarians Can Influence the Cost?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kirstein, Dave</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle mortalities</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">byproduct value</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">environmental</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biosecure</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Service charges for the collection and rendering of farm/feedlot cattle mortalities have become common practice and have increased most notably in the past three years. The loss of cattle by-product value is primarily responsible for this trend. Further loss of byproduct value is anticipated following the implementation of rules that are currently being proposed by the USDA to restrict additional cattle by-products from the food/feed chain. However, the collection and rendering of cattle mortalities will most likely remain the most appropriate environmental, biosecure and traceable means of disposal. Therefore, it is important to handle cattle mortalities in a manner that optimizes their remaining value. A number of practices that veterinarians and their clients perform can have a substantial impact upon the cattle by-product value. Cooperation with local renderers regarding these practices can help stabilize future disposal fees.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2002-09-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4997</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20024997</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2002; 1-6</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4997/4886</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2002 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
