<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7941</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T22:34:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Exploring value-added dairy services for clients</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Willingham, Callie D. </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">new services</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">value-added services</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As the dairy industry continues to consolidate, veterinary practices must adapt the services offered to meet changing needs and challenges of their clients. One part of that can be to develop and offer value-added services to complement the technical services already provided. Examining the strengths and weaknesses of the veterinary practice team members, and the opportunities and challenges facing clients, can help to align practice strengths with opportunities for clients when deciding what value-added services to incorporate into your services. Any new service offered needs to be evaluated for the value it can bring not only to the client, but also to the veterinary practice. Determining a fee schedule for new services must also be considered, as a fee-per-service or time model may not be the most appropriate way to charge for all types of services. Incorporating new services that provide value outside of technical services can help a practice to diversify the services offered to clients.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-02-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7941</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2019 Recent Graduate Proceedings; 53-54</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7941/7524</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
