<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8695</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-07-18T01:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pilot study: Refining a culture-guided selective dry cow therapy program to enhance antimicrobial stewardship on dairy farms</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Godden, S. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Royster, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leonard, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Albrecht, D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Timmerman, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Selective dry cow therapy (SDCT) programs typically use either milk culture or algorithm methods to identify cows with a high risk of infection, and thereby warranting antimicrobial therapy (AMX) at dry off (DO). Multiple studies have demonstrated that SDCT programs can maintain future cow health while signifi­cantly reducing antimicrobial use (AMU), as compared to blan­ket DCT (BDCT). However, we may be able to further reduce AMU at DO by targeting only specific types of intramammary infection (IMI) that will benefit from AMX. A recent meta-analysis concluded that IMI caused by Streptococcus spp. or Streptococcus-like organisms (SSLO) do benefit from DC therapy, while IMI caused by coliform or non-aureus Staph spp. (NAS) do not. Similarly, IMI caused by other Gram-positive bacteria, in­cluding S. aureus, occur with a relatively low frequency in most herds, and often do not respond to AMX. The Minnesota Easy® Focus® media is selective for SSLO growth in milk samples. This pilot study aimed to evaluate the effect of a SDCT program that identifies and treats only IMI caused by SSLO (vs. BDCT) on quarter health and AMU.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-07-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8695</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228695</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 55 (2022): 2022 Annual Conference Proceedings; 222</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8695/8447</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
