<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7749</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:08:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Clinical Examination of the Bovine Animal</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Williams, Eric I.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">systematic examination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">organ systems</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">gastrointestinal tract</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The clinician's primary objective in dealing with a sick animal is to make a diagnosis of the ailment as accurately and as soon as possible so that suitable treatment can be initiated.
Accurate diagnosis can only be achieved by a careful and systematic examination of the patient. It cannot be overemphasized that a thorough knowledge of, and the ability to interpret, the normal animal will greatly enhance the clinician's ability to recognize the abnormal state. The recognition of clinical symptoms which, under field conditions, are often not present in classical textbook style, can only be accomplished by the astute and patient observation of the sick animal. The ability to translate the recognition of disease symptoms to a positive diagnosis of the ailment also depends on a thorough knowledge of the major features of -the disease. A basic understanding of animal behavior is a decided asset.
This paper is a brief review of the methods available to the practicing veterinarian for the examination of the bovine organ systems, with special emphasis on the gastrointestinal tract.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1977-12-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7749</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19777749</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1977; 26-31</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7749/6047</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1977 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
