<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3413</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:37:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Veterinary Feed Directive</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Apley, Michael D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">VFD</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary feed directive</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food grade</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">We will be writing Veterinary Feed Directives (VFDs) and prescriptions in December of 2016 to authorize the use of medically important antibiotics in the feed and water of our client's animals starting on January 1, 2017. The major challenge for our profession is not to master the limited number of labels we will be dealing with, or to master the VFD process; it is that we are now not only responsible forauthorizing the use of almost every antibiotic in food animals, we are also accountable.
The decision process for if we should provide a VFD or prescription is centered on applying our professional training and experience to establish a clinical justification for the use. This process centers on these considerations. Do I have a valid VCPR? Is there a reason for this use or is it just habit? Is it legal? Is it effective? Are there any issues with residues or antibiotic resistance to consider?
After these considerations, veterinarians are then responsible to lead in antibiotic stewardship. This involves assuring accurate case definitions, searching for antibiotic alternatives, selecting the appropriate antibiotic, monitoring use, and constant re-evaluation of the need for the antibiotic.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-09-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3413</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20163413</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2016; 3-6</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3413/3367</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2016 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
