<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3440</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:37:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bovine nutrition and ration formulation basics in veterinary medicine</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hill, Kevin</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nutrition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">consulting</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">One of the most needed services by clients in food animal production is nutritional consulting. While many of the management tools needed by successful food animal producers can be acquired by experience, hard work, and good instincts, the understanding and application of sound nutritional principles is not easily obtained. Because food animq} veterinarians are well educated, trusted, and in close proximity to their clients and their animals, they are in a unique position to bridge this nutritional knowledge gap. The important relationship of nutrition to disease, healing, and productivity make sub-optimal nutrition a significant deterrent to the goals of both veteriniarian and producer. While most veterinary students receive a relatively brief course on food animal nutrition, many opportunities exist to supplement that education with post-doctoral courses, both formal and informal, that can elevate their nutritional expertise to a level that can have a significant impact on the health of animals, the productivity of producers, and the growth of a veterinary practice. This presentation highlights a few of the ways that an innovative bovine practitioner can acquire and provide these needed services to the beef and dairy communities.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-09-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3440</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20163440</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2016; 124-126</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3440/3392</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2016 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
