<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4965</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:14:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RSD3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Use of Decision Tree Analysis to Improve LDA Decision Making</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Overton, M. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">economic impact</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">left displaced abomasums</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">decision trees</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management options</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In food animal practice, medical decisions are usually made on the basis of economic impact to the dairy, rather than on perceived individual animal value or emotional attachment. A decision routinely made on dairies is what to do with cows that develop left displaced abomasums (LDA). Given the variety of management options available, veterinarians have the potential to make different recommendations depending upon the cow's historical value, parity, current stage oflactation, presence of concurrent disease, level of milk price and relative replacement cost. Decision trees are systematic quantitative tools that may be used to improve the ability to select the best course of action in situations, such as LDA, where the clinical decision is complex and outcomes are uncertain. The objective of this project was to demonstrate the use of a decision tree model as a tool to help select between surgery, roll and toggle or marketing for beef as the most economically appropriate management plan, given an early lactation cow with an LDA.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2004-09-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4965</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20044965</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2004; 213-214</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4965/4854</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2004 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
