<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5555</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-09-03T00:35:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RTMCYP</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of Indwelling Uterine Infusers (IUI's) on Bovine Postpartum Reproductive Performance</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Morrow, David A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rowe, Robert F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ingalls, Winston G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine postpartum uterine conditions such as metritis usually require frequent medication to correct the problem. As a result, the indwelling uterine infuser (IUI) was developed to facilitate frequent infusion of the uterus.
This device was designed to remain in the uterus for a period of time with repeated infusions made through a cannula externally exposed from the vulva, reducing the introduction of infection and the possibility of trauma from daily medication by conventional procedures. The IUI is made of flexible polyethylene tubing which is inserted aseptically through the cervix into the uterus. The end inserted into the uterus is retained by an attached plastic coil which expands within the uterus. The exposed end of the medication tube projects a short distance from the vulva and is stoppered with a small plastic plug. When medication is administered, the plug is removed and a syringe with a 16 gauge needle can be inserted into the exposed end of the IUI.
Reports from veterinarians in the field suggested that the IUI was beneficial in altering estrous cycle length, stimulating estrous behavior, and in reducing the incidence of cystic follicles.
The objective of this study was to determine the effects of IUI's on estrous cycle length, estrous behavior, ovarian activity, and levels of luteinizing hormone in peripheral plasma.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1972; 102-104</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5555/5407</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1972 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
