<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9318</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:40:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Managing parasites in beef cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vatta, Adriano</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anthelmintic resistance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Ostertagia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Haemonchus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cooperia,</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">gastrointestinal nematodes</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Though limited in their scope, investigations in the southern United States indicate that resistance to the macrocyclic lactone anthelmintics is highly prevalent in Cooperia spp., common in Haemonchus spp., and emerging in Ostertagia ostertagi. This has important implications for sustainable beef farming in the southern United States, but also for operations which purchase calves from the South for finishing in the Midwest and southern Great Plains. It appears that producers generally do not know the efficacy status of the available drug classes in their opera­tions, and there is an overall lack of awareness of resistance in cattle nematodes. This hampers the producer’s ability to adopt sustainable deworming practices. To improve the situ­ation, there is a need for veterinarians to educate their clients about anthelmintic resistance, to encourage the use of fecal egg counts to assess the need for deworming, and to test for anthel­mintic resistance by means of fecal egg count reduction tests. Producers should be educated on the need to employ refugia in control strategies and to use combination anthelmintic treat­ment where possible.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9318</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259318</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 8-11</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9318/8937</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
