<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6302</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-15T00:34:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Scoring Lesions Considered Associated with Subclinical Laminitis in First Lactation Cows from High Production Ohio Holstein Herds: A Method of Comparison of Herds</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smilie, R. H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hoblet, K. H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">subclinical laminitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">scoring system</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sole lesions</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">heel lesions</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Subclinical laminits was studied in 203 first lactation cows and bred heifers in thirteen high producing Ohio Holstein herds. A cross-sectional observational investigation was conducted to develop and validate a scoring system for evaluation of subclinical laminitis. For purposes of this study, observable lesions considered associated with subclinical laminitis included yellow waxy discoloration of the sole, hemorrhage of the sole, separation of the white line, and erosion of the heel. The objectives of our study were to 1) evaluate the prevalence of sole and heel lesions associated with subclinical laminitis across and among cows, feet, claws, and zones, and 2) validate a scoring system which can be used to compare herds with regard to lesions considered associated with subclinical laminitis. Differences in the occurrence of lesions among herds were found to be significant in a pairwise comparison. The difference in the occurrence of lesions among herds appeared to facilitate classification of certain herds as being either better or worse than others according to lesion and anatomic location.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1994-09-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6302</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19946302</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1994; 214-216</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6302/6771</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1994 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
