<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5564</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-30T20:19:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PHHPD</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Purpose</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jessup, R. V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I appreciate being here and I certainly enjoyed the meeting.
Herd health programs are really a matter of economics. That is what you are selling and if the dairymen cannot afford us, we have a former client or member of that community who sold out and he is just farming-he is not there any more. I might say that in our area we have dairymen. About 90% of the men are in the dairy business solely and completely. They have one source of income. About 98% of their income is from milk cows and the milk that is produced. The other 2% is derived from calves and maybe they go to the races occasionally but that is a non-profit type of work! The purpose of bovine health programs is to improve the operating efficiency of the dairy. That is what they better do, because if any program that you set up is selfishly inclined, forget it! That man is out there every day, all day, and you better improve his operating efficiency and you had better have him get his CPA on your side. The figures had better balance out to show that you are improving his profit potential, otherwise you are not going to be there.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5564</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1972; 117-118</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5564/5415</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1972 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
