<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9333</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:40:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The importance of producing enough highquality dairy replacement heifers</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Overton, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Eicker, Steve</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">replacement heifers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">replacement rate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">replacement decision making</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The profitability and sustainability of dairy operations depend heavily on the availability and quality of replacement heifers. This paper explores the economic and biological implications of ensuring an adequate heifer supply and emphasizes the im­portance of strategic replacement planning. Drawing on re­cent research and modeling, we demonstrate that constrained heifer availability leads to delayed cow replacement, reduced milk production and significant financial losses. Conversely, increasing replacement rates through timely and appropriate replacement decisions leads to greater profitability through in­creased productivity. Heifer quality, particularly related to ge­netic potential, age and size at first calving (height and weight relative to predicted mature body weight potential), strongly influence lactation performance. Heifers below target size pro­duce significantly less milk in both first and second lactations. Correctly projecting heifer needs using historical replacement and completion rates is only an important first step. Ultimately, dairies must balance cost-saving measures with long-term prof­itability by investing in heifer development and replacement strategies that prioritize genetic potential, growth and optimal age at first calving. Producing enough high-quality heifers is not merely a logistical necessity but a strategic imperative.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9333</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259333</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 43-44</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9333/8949</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
