<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5000</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-18T07:12:48Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Incorporating Consulting Into Veterinary Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tyler, Donald H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">consultation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">personnel management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">professional development</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">production goals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">methodology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">camaraderie</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">emotional implications</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Our advice is important to every operation for which we provide consultation. Helping our clients make the right decision is not solely dependent on our ability to provide a logical analysis of all the factors that affect the current situation, but also on our ability to show the value, personal benefits and possible ramifications of utilizing the advice. The best advice possible has no value ifwe cannot help our clients understand it and make timely decisions concerning the welfare of their operation.
In my work in advising clients in the area of personnel management, manager coaching and professional development, transfer of the business to the next generation, and achieving higher production goals, it has become extremely important for me to help owners and managers alike make tough decisions. Though they understand the logic involved in the decision, emotion sometimes clouds the process and evokes hesitation. Many times our clients know that they must make a change, but tradition, habit, fear of failure and a natural resistance to change get in the way. This hesitation is only exacerbated by the emotions of depression, confusion and grief from extended financial distress.
An advisory methodology that incorporates an appreciation for these factors with an understanding of the emotional implications will provide greater success. Additionally, this appreciation will enhance a sense of camaraderie among all the decision-makers involved in the process.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2002-09-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5000</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20025000</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2002; 18-24</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5000/4889</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2002 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
