<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9088</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-26T17:15:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">New concepts in colostrum feeding for dairy calves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sockett, Donald</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Brix Refractometer</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">transfer of passive immunity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">strategic colostrum feeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Successful transfer of passive immunity (TPI) is essential for calf health and well-being. The current first-milking colostrum feeding guidelines for newborn dairy calves were established more than two-decades ago. The implementation of these guidelines has led to a marked improvement in calf health. Since the guidelines were established, a great deal of additional knowledge has accumulated about bovine colostrum and the benefits of transition milk feeding to newborn calves, particu­larly for the first 5-7 days of life. In addition, the Brix refractom­eter has been validated as a useful on-farm tool to estimate co­lostrum quality. One of the limitations of the current colostrum feeding guidelines is that colostrum with higher Brix scores is fed to calves the same way than colostrum with a lower Brix score (≥ 22%). This prevents calf care providers and managers from taking advantage of colostrum that contains more than 50 g/L of IgG. Identifying colostrum with an IgG concentration of ≥ 75 g/L enables the establishment of colostrum feeding pro­grams that feed a smaller volume of first-milking colostrum but still delivers a sufficient mass of immunoglobulin to have suc­cessful TPI. It will also increase the farm supply of colostrum.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9088</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20249088</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 58 (2024): 2024 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 64-65</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
