<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6158</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-14T00:37:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:OS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Welcome to Georgia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson, Dave</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Welcome to Georgia. First of all I would like to show some slides of our college. The learning resources center is used in histology, pathology, and a variety of other courses. There are now eight courses, either partially or wholly taught on the autotutorial system. The building is open from about six in the morning until 12 midnight and gets very heavy use. There are videotape systems which are handy when a student knows he has a certain surgical procedure coming up. He can pull out the tape and at his leisure review this procedure. The library reading room serves both the students and the faculty and the staff of the college. We do have the rudiments of a research farm. Again, this is an area where some research animals are kept separate from the college because of particular disease agents, or sometimes it is used as a holding area for teaching animals. As Dr. Clarkson mentioned, we do have a keen interest in the Animal Health Research Act and the one part of it that could provide some facilities, because we do not have good large animal isolation facilities. We do a lot of things with large animals but we have a pretty tough time working with any highly infectious disease because we just don't have the space or the facilities for it.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1975-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6158</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19756158</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1975; 5-7</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6158/6478</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1975 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
