<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9346</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Udder care products – formulations, applications and monitoring</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomson, Roger</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">germicides</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">formulation matters</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">skin conditioners</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">monitoring matters</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The labels on udder care products (teat dips) in the United States are limited in details compared to other countries. The ingredient selections made by the company manufacturing the dip impacts its performance more because there are many choices within each broad class of germicides, humectants and surfactants. This is why the phrase, “formulation matters” truly applies to teat dip choices.
Dairy producers tend to blame their teat dip first for increases in mastitis cases or bulk tank somatic cell counts (SCCs). This is an attempt to fix a multi-factorial problem with a single change. Beyond the formulation, the more important fact to remem­ber is, “application matters.” In the last two decades, the U.S. dairy industry has been in an expansion mode of bigger parlors milking cows faster than ever before. This has resulted in de­creasing accuracy of dip application from the gold standard of complete coverage. This change is increasing the risk of new mastitis cases across all management systems.
The first step any dairy veterinarian must take before suggest­ing a teat dip change is to remember, “monitoring matters.” Tracking new clinical mastitis rates, insisting on culturing pro­tocols and recommending regular DHIA individual SCC testing to track new infection rates must precede any dip change rec­ommendations. Otherwise, how can you assess the results of the dip change?</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9346</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259346</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 101-106</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9346/8961</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
