<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3803</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:44:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Validation of two diagnostic methods for postpartum endometritis in dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Denis-Robichaud, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dubuc, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">uterine disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive performance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Endometrial cytology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Aleucocyte esterase test</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">LE testing</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Postpartum uterine diseases can impair reproductive performance of dairy cows. Diagnostic tools have been developed to identify cows at risk of poor subsequent reproductive performance. Most of these tools focus on identification of inflammation in the reproductive tract during the postpartum period. Endometrial cytology was proposed as a good tool to identify cows with cytological endometritis; however, cytology is not an easy technique to implement for an on-farm uterine health surveillance program in dairy herds because it requires the use of a microscope. Therefore, a more convenient on-farm method needs to be identified for determination of uterine status of dairy cows. Aleucocyte esterase (LE) colorimetric test is commercially available (Multistix®, Bayer Corporation, Elkhart, IN) and could be used to detect endometrial inflammation. The objectives of this study were to determine diagnostic criteria for endometritis in dairy cows by use of endometrial cytology and LE testing, to quantify the agreement between results of these two methods, and to quantify their impact on subsequent reproductive performance.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2013-09-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3803</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20133803</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2013; 135</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3803/3742</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2013 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
