<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7567</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:31:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CCS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bovine Rumensin Toxicity: A Case Study</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kimberling, C. V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schweitzer, D. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">monensin toxicity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dose/weight relationship</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">heifers</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In reviewing the epidemiological findings on this case of monensin toxicity, it is postulated that the reason for the increased number of deaths occurring in the yearling heifer group, is a dose/weight relationship. The other factor involved is that this group of animals received the very last portion of liquid supplement at the bottom of the tank. The deaths in the yearling heifers were primarily in the larger, more aggressive heifers. This, of course, puts some question on the dose relationship but when viewing the total amount of feed bunk availability, the smaller heifers were not allowed to the first feeding which contained the toxic level of monensin. The other groups where death losses occured were in the two year old heifers with calves at side and the yearling steers. The yearling steers and cull cows running together again indicates a dose/weight relationship. Although the two year old heifers with calves at side were heavier, it is postulated there may be some relationship due to stress on this particular group of animals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1982-12-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7567</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19827567</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1982; 131-133</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7567/7300</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1982 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
