<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8310</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-10-24T20:58:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Salmonella Dublin diagnostics for the field veterinarian</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Frye, Elisha</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnostics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">host-adapted</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Salmonella Dublin</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Salmonella Dublin is a zoonotic, multi-drug-resistant bacteria. It is host adapted in cattle, and carrier animals shed bacteria in feces and milk, acting as a reservoir for the herd. Salmonella Dublin causes septicemia in young calves, who present with a high fever, increased respiratory effort and acute death. Diag­nosing Salmonella Dublin in an acutely infected calf requires aseptic collection of a blood culture sample, storage at room temperature or in an incubator, and overnight delivery to a vet­erinary diagnostic laboratory. Diagnosing Salmonella Dublin post-mortem requires submission of one or more of the follow­ing organs for aerobic culture: lung, kidney, lymph node, liver or spleen. These samples should be refrigerated or frozen and delivered overnight as well. Feces and gastrointestinal samples have low sensitivity for recovering Salmonella Dublin and are not recommended in clinical suspects. Surveillance or monitor­ing for Salmonella Dublin antibodies can be performed with the Salmonella Dublin ELISA. Appropriate samples include serum, individual milk samples and bulk tank milk samples. Serocon­version time and age of animal impact the sensitivity of the Sal­monella Dublin ELISA.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8310</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20218310</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2021 Annual Conference Proceedings; 102-105</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8310/8190</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
