<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5638</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-31T07:24:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Characterization of Antibiotic Resistance Among Veterinary Bacterial Pathogens</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">White, David G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antimicrobials</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotic resistance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bacterial pathogens</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Since the introduction of antimicrobials into veterinary medicine some 45 years ago, animal health and productivity has improved significantly.1,4,10,12 Despite considerable use, and some misuse, many antimicrobials continue to remain effective today. However, loss of efficacy through emergence of bacterial antibiotic resistance is always an ever present risk.1,2,3,6,14,15 Antibiotic resistant bacterial pathogens in animals not only pose a problem with respect to animal health but are a growing concern regarding possible transmission to humans as foodborne pathogens.7,9,15,18 The dilemma of antibiotic resistance is worsened by the growing number of bacterial pathogens resistant to multiple, structurally unrelated drugs, and to the fact that few veterinary antimicrobials are likely to be available before the end of the decade.4,8,12 Accordingly, more attention is now being paid to the ease at which resistance can develop to both single and multiple antimicrobials among bacterial pathogens. If current trends continue, we may encounter bacterial pathogens which are resistant to all known antimicrobials. This situation is being addressed by both FDA and USDA which are currently implementing strategies to head off this potential threat.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1998-09-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5638</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19985638</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1998; 67-68</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5638/5484</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1998 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
