<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7355</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:41:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Towards the Responsible Use of Veterinary Drugs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Crawford, Lester M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary drugs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug abuse</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The citizens of this world are immersed in a chemical society, a social fabric largely held together by the intelligent use of agricultural chemicals, drugs, and other useful compounds. Paradoxically, the world order is today threatened by the irresponsible use of certain of these substances. The first step in the fact-finding process was the imposition of an import alert ordering U.S. Customs inspectors to specifically look for the unauthorized importation of veterinary drugs. The import alert confirmed our suspicions-unapproved drugs were being imported for use in various species of animals in the U.S. The second step involved an FDA survey of cattle feedlots. Twenty-five percent of surveyed feedlots stocked unapproved drugs on a routine basis including prescription compounds. A survey conducted under the aegis of USDA's Residue Avoidance Program drew the same essential conclusions. Third, diversion of prescription drugs, unapproved chemicals, drugs approved for other species, and other similar deviations as reported to BVM / FDA were increasing at an appreciable rate.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1983-11-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7355</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19837355</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1983; 12-15</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7355/7226</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1983 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
