<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8638</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-07-18T01:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SRS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Small ruminant neonatal nutrition</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Van Saun, Robert J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sheep</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">goats</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">colostrum quality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">passive transfer</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">rumen development</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neonatal nutrition</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Loss of preweaned lambs and kids is a significant economic burden on small ruminant enterprises. Nutrition is an impor­tant factor impacting neonatal losses. Four critical nutritional phases can impact neonatal viability: maternal gestational diet adequacy, colostrum feeding, milk feeding and rumen develop­ment, and post-weaning feeding practices. As with any farm animal, consumption of adequate amounts of high-quality co­lostrum is the single most critical event in the life of a small ruminant. In contrast to dairy cattle, no guidelines defining volume and immunoglobulin (Ig) content for sheep and goat co­lostrum to ensure adequate passive transfer are available. Simi­larly, there are no well-defined criteria for determining success or failure of passive transfer in sheep and goats. The second most critical event of the neonatal small ruminant is adequate rumen development to facilitate a smooth transition during the weaning process. This presentation will address these 4 nutri­tional phases with emphasis on colostrum management prac­tices and rumen development as methods to improve neonatal survivability and viability.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-07-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8638</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228638</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 55 (2022): 2022 Annual Conference Proceedings; 161-164</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8638/8394</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
