<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6429</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-07T00:35:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DD</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Morphological Investigations of the Forestomach in Cows Suffering From Hoflund Syndrome</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stockhofe-Zurwieden, N.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rehage, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Yalcin, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">intramural nerve fibres</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">forestomachs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">abomasum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Hoflund's Syndrome</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vagal nerve</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Since HOFLUND's explanation (1) of a functional stenosis of either the bovine forestomach or the pylorus due to damages of the vagal nerve in 1940, this hypothesis is discussed controversially. In addition disturbances of the beforementioned extrinsic nerve system, mechanical influences are discussed to be the origin of this disease (2,3). As an extrinsic control system the vagal nerves are responsible for a coordionated contraction of the ruminant forestomach. These nerves originating from the gastric centre in the medulla oblongata are consisting of predominantly afferent fibres and some efferent, preganglionic nerve fibres ( 4). The efferent fibres are communicating with intramurally located ganglia. Recently published data present that the intramural neurons, also named as intrinsic nerve system are able to initiate reticulo-ruminal contraction (9,10).
Purpose of this study was to evaluate morphological alterations ofvagal and intramural nerve fibres, intramural neurons and inflamamtory changes in the wall of the forestomachs and abomasum of cows suffering from HOFLUND's Syndrome.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6429</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926429</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 1; 127-130</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6429/7010</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
