<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3415</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:37:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Stakeholder views, including the public, on expectations for dairy cattle welfare</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">von Keyserlingk, Marina A. G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weary, Daniel M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tail docking</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">disbudding</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Animal welfare is emerging as one of the key social concerns regarding animal agriculture. Concern for the welfare of farms animals is not new, but the last few years have seen increased interest in farm practices. One of the dairy industry's core strengths is the very positive view that many people have about dairy farming. Many consumers believe that cows spend their days grazing green pastures. This strength can also be regarded as a threat if some industry practices no longer match evolving public expectations. Every year there are fewer farms, and the ever decreasing proportion of society that works within this industry will never be able to able to 'educate' the large majority, at least not on all issues, all of the time. Moreover, the farmers themselves are part of this rapidly evolving society, and practices that were accepted by past generations as necessary may not seem so to the next generation of producers. Change will happen. During my presentation I will highlight some of our most recent work on engaging dairy farmers and the public as a means to help identify practices that do and do not come into harmony with public expectations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-09-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3415</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20163415</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2016; 9-14</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3415/3369</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2016 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
