<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4497</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:55:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Testing of Cattle Ear Notch Samples Using a Bovine Viral Diarrhea Virus NS3 Antigen ELISA Kit for Detection of Persistently Infected Animals</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Guillossou, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomson, D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomson, C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stevens, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">persistently infected</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">PI</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine viral diarrhea virus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ELISA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Ear notch samples</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnostic laboratories</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Identification and elimination of persistently infected (PI) cattle is important to controlling bovine viral diarrhea virus (BVDV) in herds. Compared to many diagnostic laboratory techniques, ELISA (enzyme linked immunosorbent assay) is convenient due to the ability to test large number of samples rapidly and consistently. A virus can be detected by probing for a specific nonstructural antigen like the NS3 (p80 in former nomenclature) or a structural antigen like the glycoprotein Erns (E0 or gp48 in former nomenclatures). Ear notch samples can be obtained easily and quickly from cattle. Another important advantage of ear notch skin biopsy samples is that they contain a high concentration of BVDV antigen. Few publications can be found describing the detection of NS3 in ear notches from cattle. The objective of this study was to compare the performance of a current commercial ELISA which specifically detects the NS3 antigen on ear notches from cattle to other tests utilized in diagnostic laboratories.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2008-09-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4497</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20084497</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2008; 302</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4497/4403</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2008 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
