<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5506</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-30T20:02:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:APC</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Dairy Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Plue, Raymond</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I would like to welcome you again to Wisconsin. I am from Chilton which is about 70 miles north of here in Calumet County and we are a three man partnership. We live in a small community of about 3,000 people in a county of about 27,000. Our practice is about 93% dairy and the rest are small animal, swine, etc. In our practice we try to stress herd health programming. Hopefully, by doing this we are increasing the image of the veterinary profession. Almost every journal that comes out has an item where they are talking about the veterinarian's image and how we would all like to have it improved. In our practice we wear a shirt and tie. My shirt gets dirty just like yours does; my shirt is white and yours might be too if it is a T-shirt, it doesn't make any difference; in other words, we all run into dirty situations. Sometimes I take it off and sometimes I leave it on and let it get dirty. It makes me feel a little better. You probably feel a little better sitting here today dressed up and it makes you act a little more professional.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5506</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1972; 15-16</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5506/5360</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1972 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
