<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9395</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Investigating metritis treatment strategies: A comprehensive approach toward antibiotic stewardship in dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thach, Massle</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Acute puerperal metritis (metritis) is a significant reproductive disorder affecting dairy cows, characterized by inflammation of the uterus within the first 21 days postpartum. Characterized by an enlarged uterus, a foul-smelling, watery red-brownish discharge, and systemic signs of illness such as fever, decreased milk production, and lethargy, metritis poses a substantial chal­lenge to the dairy industry. Previous studies have identified Escherichia coli, Trueperella pyogenes, Fusobacterium necrophorum and Prevotella melaninogenica as common causative agents. De­spite the well-documented bacterial involvement, treatment protocols vary widely and often rely on empirical antibiotic use without prior culture. Common treatments include ceft­iofur hydrochloride (Excenel®), ceftiofur crystalline-free acid (Excede®), and oxytetracycline (Liquamycin® LA-200®). This study aimed to evaluate the pathogen profile and antimicrobial resistance patterns in metritis cases pre- and post-treatment, and to assess current treatment practices among U.S. dairy vet­erinarians. Samples were collected from 12 metritic cows on a large commercial dairy farm in the Northeastern U.S. from June to August 2024. An online survey was also distributed via Qualtrics to practicing dairy veterinarians. Bacteria were iso­lated from all enrolled cows (diagnosed at 2-10 days in milk, avg. 5.25 DIM). Most cows were in their first lactation (67%). Pre-treatment cultures yielded 34 isolates, primarily Strepto­coccus uberis (26%), Trueperella pyogenes (24%) and E. coli (12%). Post-treatment cultures yielded 24 isolates, with T. pyogenes (38%), E. coli (15%) and Staphylococcus chromogenes (15%) being most common. Notably, some post-treatment isolates displayed resistance to commonly used antimicrobials. These findings highlight dynamic shifts in bacterial populations following treatment and underscore the potential for antimicrobial re­sistance. The study emphasizes the need for pathogen-directed therapy and more standardized treatment protocols in metritis management.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9395</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259395</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 210</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9395/9007</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
