<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9422</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Targeted deworming to promote fecal pat degradation and limit anthelmintic resistance in an intensive rotational grazing system</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dies, Abby</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dewell, Grant</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hindman, Megan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Anthelmintics, specifically macrocyclic lactones, are com­monly used in cattle operations to control internal and exter­nal parasites. Continuous use of these drugs creates parasitic resistance, which is often undetectable in beef cattle until late in the disease cycle, causing a need for targeted deworming treatment. Overuse of anthelmintics poses many adverse con­sequences including anthelmintic resistance and the reduction of dung beetle populations. Dung beetles are crucial to main­taining healthy pastures in intense rotational grazing systems due to their ability to quickly degrade fecal pats and promote forage regrowth, both of which reduce opportunities for para­sitic reproduction. This study evaluates the impact of a targeted deworming program over a 2-year period and their effects on pasture dung beetle population, the overall parasite load in a commercial cow herd, as well as the impact of production pa­rameters on the calves.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9422</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259422</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 237</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9422/9033</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
