<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5630</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-31T18:49:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A New Test for the Detection of the Bovine Leukemia Virus</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferrer, Jorge F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bhatt, Diane</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">We have recently developed an accurate, rapid and relatively inexpensive test for the identification of animals infected with the Bovine Leukemia Virus (BLV). This test involves the detection of serum antibodies to BLV using the immunofluorescent antibody (IFA) technique on acetone fixed, infected cells. The specificity of the test was demonstrated by the fact that it was positive in97% of adult cattle in which BLV was detected electron microscopically. On the other hand, the test was negative in all cases in which the virus was not found despite extensive electron microscopic examination. In order for the IFA test to be specific it is of utmost importance that the target cells used are infected only with BLV. Such cells (NBC cell lines) are maintained under continuous culture conditions in our laboratory.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1973-12-05</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5630</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1973; 32</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5630/5477</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1973 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
