<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9068</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-26T17:15:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">FARAD: Current updates and future directions</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mzyk, Danielle</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">FARAD</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">extra-label drug use</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">residue</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">withdrawal interval</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Food Animal Residue Avoidance Databank (FARAD) is a university-based program supported by the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)’s National Institute of Food and Agricul­ture (NIFA) that maintains and provides an array of resources for veterinarians, extension specialists, farmers, regulatory personnel and others who are the stewards of our nation’s ex­pansive commercial food animal industries and the growing number of small backyard livestock operations. Since 1982, this program has provided real time support service to veterinar­ians and related stakeholders. FARAD is supported and staffed by highly-trained veterinary pharmacologists, toxicologists, pharmacists and food animal specialists at five colleges of veterinary medicine: North Carolina State University, Kansas State University, University of California-Davis, University of Florida, and Virginia Tech. Together, the FARAD team identi­fies, analyzes and generates residue avoidance information to determine scientifically-based drug or chemical withdrawal ad­vice in situations involving legal extra-label drug use, and acci­dental contaminations in both major and minor food-producing animal species.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9068</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20249068</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 58 (2024): 2024 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 8-9</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9068/8740</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
