<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8839</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-10T20:58:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effective utilization of vaccination to protect against viral reproductive pathogens</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Walz, Paul</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bovine viral diarrhea virus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bovine Alphaherpesvirus-1</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fetal protection</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine viral diarrhea virus (BVDV) and Bovine alphaherpes­virus-1 (BoHV-1) have long been recognized as major causes of reproductive disease in beef and dairy cattle. Enhancing im­munity through prebreeding vaccination and annual revaccina­tion of the cowherd provide important contributions to limiting reproductive losses associated with these viral infections and are also important control procedures to limit transmission of these viruses among cattle populations. While providing efficacy, vaccination should also be safe. Safety concerns are often associated with the BoHV-1 fractions, while efficacy con­cerns are often associated with BVDV fractions of multivalent vaccines. Vaccination against BVDV and BoHV-1 effectively decrease risk of fetal infection, including abortions, birth of per­sistently infected BVDV carriers, and pregnancy loss. Safety con­cerns associated with viral vaccines, more specifically modified-live viral vaccines, should not overshadow the protective effects associated with sound vaccination principles and programs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8839</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20238839</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 56 (2023): 2023 Annual Conference Proceedings ; 19-21</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8839/8551</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
