<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6054</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-06T00:15:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Art of Seeing: Youngstock Programs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Guterbock, Walter M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf raising</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nutritional stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">colostrum deprivation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">housing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">crowding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">weaning stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">improper feeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">coccidiosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Most calf raising problems are related to management-induced or nutritional stress. In trouble-shooting these problems, the eyes, ears, and nose of the veterinarian are generally more useful than laboratory tests and etiological diagnoses. For most of us in practice, it takes two to three weeks from the time we send samples to a diagnostic lab until we get results. Most problems can be solved before we get the results, and many will have gone away by themselves. Etiologic diagnoses are often of limited value when the disease process is characterized by multiple organisms, or when we always get the same results. For example, calves that die because of colostrum deprivation or underfeeding of calories will yield various etiologic agents from the intestines and other organs. A diagnosis of pneumonia caused by Pasteurella multocida is not very illuminating; most pneumonic dairy calves have Pasteurella involvement. It is more important to figure out what factors are causing the calves' resistance to this commensal organism to break down. In both cases, the etiologic diagnosis adds nothing to our knowledge; we already knew that young calves were dying or that older calves had pneumonia. The predisposing factors are usually colostrum deprivation, stressful housing, crowding, weaning stress, improper feeding, or coccidiosis.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1995-09-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6054</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1995; 60-64</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6054/6852</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1995 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
