<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6870</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-17T19:53:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FBM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Proceedings of the Twenty-Second Annual Conference (1989). Bovine "Give Away" and Awards</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bovine Practitioners, American Association of</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The AABP again sponsored a "Bovine Give-Away" in the form of ten $50.00 prizes. The event was organized by Dr. Samuel Hutchins 3rd, Exhibits Manager in collaboration with the exhibitors. (vii)
At the opening ceremony, Dr. Donald Hudson, AABP Past President and Chairman, Research Assistantship Committee presented the Second Annual AABP Research Assistantship Award to Dr. William M. Sischo, Department of Veterinary Preventive Medicine, College of Veterinary Medicine, the Ohio State University.
Dr. Keith Sterner introduced the award as follows. This year marks the initiation of several new award categories and this one solves a great dilemma in recognizing some of the outstanding members of our organization. We thank American Cyanamid for their generous support of this award.
President Keith Sterner prefaced the presentation of this award with a speech honoring this year's first ever recipient of the AABP's Distinguished Service Award: Dr. John Fetrow.
MBP awards for excellence in preventive veterinary medicine, sponsored by MSD-AGVET division of Merck &amp;amp; Co., Inc., were announced during the annual business meeting on Saturday October 1.
Dr. Robert H. Keith, Monroe, Wisconsin was named the 1989 Outstanding Bovine Practitioner of the Year at the annual membership luncheon meeting on Friday, November 17.
Dr. Leland C. Allenstein, Whitewater, Wisconsin was named the recipient of the AABP Amstutz-Williams Award at the annual business luncheon meeting.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1989-11-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Front matter</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6870</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1989; vii, ix-xiv</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6870/6361</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1989 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
