<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6042</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-06T00:15:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Surgical Review of the Male Bovine Animal</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wolfe, Dwight F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">surgical review</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anatomy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">corpus cavernosum penis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A surgical review of the male bovine animal requires review of the normal anatomy of the bull. The body of the penis is made up of the dense fibroelastic tunica albuginea and trabeculae that surround the cavernous spaces of the corpus cavernosum penis (CCP). The penis is surrounded by elastic tissue which allows the penis to move from the fully retracted to fully extended positions.1 The elastic tissue is covered with glabrous skin. The glans penis and distal part of the penis are not surrounded by elastic tissue and comprise the free portion of the penis. For normal function, the length of the extended penis should be twice the length of the free portion of the penis.2 In the nonstimulated bull the penis is retracted into the sheath, a hair covered extension of the abdominal wall. Retraction of the penis is accomplished by the paired retractor penis muscles that attach to the ventrolateral surface of the penis at the distal bend of the sigmoid flexure.3</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1995-09-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6042</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1995; 20-22</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6042/6842</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1995 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
