<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5837</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-09-03T02:05:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CCFS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Implants: Birth to Finish</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mader, Terry L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">implant strategies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">production system</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Hormone level</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">androgenic</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Numerous implant strategies are available for use in cattle from suckling through finishing phases of production. Within a specific production system, implants consistently enhance animal productivity and/or efficiency. However, consistent responses to lifetime programs depend not only on product use but timing and sequence as well. Lifetime implant programs should be designed to obtain an optimum growth and efficiency response while minimizing expression oflive animal side effects and adverse effects on carcass traits. Recent studies suggest that using, in succession, implants with increasing potency allows for the greatest animal lifetime gain (&amp;gt; 50 kg) while maintaining or slightly improving post-weaning feed conversion when compared to nonimplanted cattle. Implant strategies which match implant dose or potency to animal age, weight, and/or production desired are recommended. Beginning in the preweaning period with low potency products and ending in the post-weaning period with high potency androgenic containing implant products, which complement the estrogenic response, will maintain positive carry over effects of previous implants. Implant programs should be designed to maintain hormone blood levels within an optimum response range. Hormone levels below or above this range should be avoided once implant programs are initiated.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1997-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5837</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19975837</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1997; 87-91</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5837/5657</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1997 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
