<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3892</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:47:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Difficult conversations with clients</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mays, Glennon</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">communication</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">client</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinarian</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">practitioner</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">professional</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">public service</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Public service encounters occasionally become controversial. Even the most seasoned veterinary clinician practiced in the art and science of clinical conversation faces confrontational dialogue. In this presentation, dynamics for basic conversation interaction are explored to ensure preliminary understanding of Comfort Zone communication prior to exploring reasons for conflicting communication with clientele. Two basic categories summarize conflict between veterinarians and clients: expectations are misaligned and/or flexibility is insufficient between the two parties for simple resolve. The conversation shifts from the conversational Comfort Zone category to the Challenge Zone category with the very next 'Yes, but I ...... ' that is spoken.
At least four options for response exist when conflict arises. Avoidance, Competition, Adaptation, and Cooperation generalize the choices. This discussion describes each response and its effect on the outcome, making the student of conversation dynamics internally aware which choice each party is making during the course of the conflict. Appropriate modification is then possible for redirection of communication. Overall, the presentation provides conflict analysis, enabling the trained professional to anticipate difficulty and thereby circumvent the negative encounter, or possess the tools for maneuvering when unexpected difficulty arises or bypass attempts fail. Unification of goals by both parties for the successful outcome of patient trouble produces success. Subsequent strengthening of the client-veterinary relationship ensures foundational growth for future positive encounter.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2012-09-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3892</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20123892</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2012; 170-174</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3892/3824</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2012 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
