<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6534</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-07T00:31:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CCS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effective Parasite Control For Cow-Calf Programs: An Update on Effective Anthelmintic Usage</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Corwin, Robert M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parasite control</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cow-calf performance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nematode parasites</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Deworming</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">subclinical parasitism</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Parasite control is necessary for optimal cow-calf performance. By deworming, nematode parasites are reduced in numbers perhaps by 95-99% with use of an effective anthelmintic drug per treated cow or calf. In mother cows, this should maximize reproductive potential, milk production and desirable weight maintenance. Treatment of cows before being moved to a "rested" pasture will reduce contamination and transmission to parasite-naive calves. Treatment of calves at a later time in the grazing period will improve growth performance.
Deworming should be an integral part of the overall herd health program. Too often, parasite control is eliminated from a program or not used. Yet subclinical parasitism has been shown to depress performance when not negated by effective anthelmintics and appropriate timing of their administration. When other factors such as nutrition, weather conditions (temperature, precipitation) and forage are in a steady state, the benefits of an effective anthelmintic are especially evident.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6534</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926534</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 2; 266-269</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6534/7105</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
