<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3640</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:38:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Lipidomic biomarkers in colostrum and milk from production-related metabolic disease (PRMD) resistant and susceptible dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roeder, B. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, H. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cook, A. C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Buckmiller, E. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brown, K. K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kang, H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">metabolic diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">days-in milk</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk composition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">decreased production</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lactation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biochemical changes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">colostrum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biomarkers</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Although the highest incidence for most production-related metabolic diseases (PRMDs; hypocalcemia, hepatic lipidosis, ketosis, left displaced abomasum-LDA, mastitis, laminitis) occurs within 60-days-in milk (DIM), the disease incidence has not been altered by transition diets, manipulating prepartum dietary cation anion balance, and overconditioning avoidance. PRMDs significantly affect economic returns with altered milk composition or decreased production, conception, life expectancy, and cull value. The risk for PRMD in early lactation has been correlated with increased free fatty acids (FFAs), non-esterfied fatty acids (NEFAs), triglycerides (TG), and beta-hydroxybutyrate ((3HBA) serum concentrations, hepatic TG:glycogen, and fecal stable isotope differences (13 carbon/12 carbon ratio, 613C). These observations of biochemical changes prior to PRMD onset prompted investigation of periparturient colostrum (CS) and milk (MK) lipid profiles at the beginning of lactation. The objectives of this study were to determine postpartum day 1 CS and day 4 MK lipid profiles in PRMD resistant and susceptible cows, and to determine if lipids in this CS and/or MK secreted after the transition period can be used as biomarkers to predict risk for development of PRMD.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-09-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3640</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20153640</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2015; 269-270</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3640/3584</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2015 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
