<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6105</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-06T00:15:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SfT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">New Technology for Managing Heat Detection</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bailey, Tom</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nebel, Ray</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Walker, William</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">heat detection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">artificial insemination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">physical parameters</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">estrous</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">herd monitoring</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management tool</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">If heat detection is the single greatest limiting factor in a successful artificial insemination program, the justification and expenditure in creating a system that would characterize various physical parameters of estrous (mounting activity), provide suitable management lists for herd monitoring, allow detection on a 24 hour a day surveillance,6 and be economically warranted, would be unsurpassed in recent years. Most economic reports have suggested that between $75 and $100 are lost when one estrus goes undetected.7,8 Table 1 below estimates the dollar value and the economic impact of improving the detection of estrus from 50 to 90%.11 Clearly the need exists to develop new technology that will provide an increase in heat detection efficiency and accuracy. This would eliminate the need for visual observation and unreliable aids for the detection of estrus.7,8
The testing of a system at Virginia Tech University called HeatWatch™ (HW) produced by DDx, Inc., Boulder, Colorado and marketed by American Breeders Service, DeForest, Wisconsin, has demonstrated, in our opinion, the characteristics of the ideal system for the accurate and efficient detection of estrus. This paper will identify the characteristics of this system and examine the results we have achieved with this new management tool.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1995-09-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6105</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1995; 168-173</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6105/6887</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1995 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
