<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9352</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:JTBEEFDAIRY</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Utilizing RVTs and veterinary assistants to elevate livestock practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McDaniel, Oberlin</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary technicians</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">livestock practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">time management</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The increasing demands of modern livestock veterinary prac­tice have placed significant strain on solo and small group prac­titioners. Time management, physical demands and financial pressures often limit career sustainability. This paper explores the role of registered veterinary technicians (RVTs) and vet­erinary assistants in enhancing efficiency, profitability and professional well-being in food animal practice. Drawing on practical experience, I highlight how delegation of non-DVM tasks such as herd reports, inventory and client communication can free veterinarians to focus on clinical decision-making and leadership. Case examples illustrate that employing support staff improves patient care, reduces burnout and strengthens client relationships. Economic analysis suggests return on in­vestment for hiring staff ranges from $80,000 to $150,000 an­nually per DVM, with additional intangible benefits including continuity of care, safer working conditions and improved job satisfaction. Strategies for effective staff utilization, including legal considerations, levels of supervision and DISC® profiling for team building, are presented. The goal is to demonstrate that the thoughtful integration of RVTs and veterinary assis­tants is not a cost burden, but a catalyst for sustainable growth in livestock veterinary practice.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9352</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259352</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 112-113</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9352/8966</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
