<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5519</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-30T20:03:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:APC</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Programmed Practice in Dairy and Feedlot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mackey, Don</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As the previous speaker questioned, ''How did you get into it?" Well, you more or less fall into it and things become more and more hectic day after day. You do not have the time to do all the routine things you ordinarily do and I want to dwell a little more on what the previous speaker stressed: communication. I think this is where we .fall down. If you want to get into this type of work and you are still the type of person who is treating milk fevers, you can talk to the herd owner or the herdsman about what else you can do in the way of a programmed dairy herd; for example, how to prevent milk fever; what you can do in the way of nutrition to prevent milk fever. If you are doing a lot of pregnancy checks and if he has a lot of non-pregnant cows, are you telling him that you are going to have to do something about it to get the percentage of first and second services increased or are you just pregnancy checking and forgetting the rest? I think this programmed practice encompasses everything: it includes nutrition, breed selection, preventative medicine and nutrition. I am a firm believer that through nutrition we can eliminate a lot of problems. Breed selection is another factor.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5519</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1972; 29-30</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5519/5372</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1972 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
