<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7177</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-10-16T01:02:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:NMC</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The devil is in the details: Opportunities and pitfalls of providing an in-clinic milk quality laboratory</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bennett, James W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk quality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">udder health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk culture</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">microbiological laboratory</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Microbial culture of milk for diagnosis of pathogens has been a mainstay of mastitis control for many years. Traditionally services have been provided by outside laboratories or to some degree, by local veterinary clinics. In-clinic laboratories can perform basic microbiological testing of milk and other materials related to udder health. Such services can provide valuable information for mastitis control; however, there are many pitfalls to consider when designing or operating a laboratory. Recently, increased focus on responsible antibiotic use by the dairy industry, dairy veterinarians, and society in general has created a greater need for microbial identification prior to antibiotic treatment. The aim of this article is to describe potential uses of an in-house laboratory while also describing some of the potential problems the veterinary practitioner may face. There are a variety of techniques beyond simple milk culture that can be performed in a clinic laboratory. The information provided may help practitioners provide valuable information and service to dairy producers who wish to improve or maintain udder health.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-09-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7177</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20197177</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2019; 295-300</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7177/5951</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
