<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7878</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:14:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Feedlot Stresses</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Braddy, Patrick </dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feedlot stresses</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">digestive stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Feedlot stresses include a number of different things. When I think of feedlot stresses, mostly I think about myself and management, although that is not what we are going to talk about today. I will discuss dealing with government intervention in business. The stress of dealing with manpower utilization and so on certainly leads to severe stress in management. Today I'd like to spend a little time with you talking about digestive stress. It follows a little in line with what we're talking about so far. How do we start cattle on feed and how do we optimize productivity in these animals through the feeding period? Whenever I attempt to tackle a topic like this, I usually come up with more questions than answers and that holds true in this presentation today, too. I've gone back through and done a little bit of review of the literature. Coupled with this, we will see some data that we extracted in a survey from our packing house, looking at rumen wall conditions after feeding.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-12-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7878</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19787878</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1978; 149-151</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7878/7493</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
