<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7652</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:05:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Johne's Disease (Paratuberculosis) in 1976</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Larsen, Aubrey B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">paratuberculosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">disease distribution</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Johne's disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The purpose in presenting this paper is to review recent developments in research on paratuberculosis. Some of the more recent findings that should be of interest to the bovine practitioner are discussed.
Here are two maps showing the results of two surveys on distribution of the disease in the United States, one in 1949 and one in 1971 (Figure 1). Thirty-three states reported presence of the disease in 1949 while 46 states reported it in 1971 (3). Preliminary examination of the maps might indicate that the disease is spreading in the United States. However, this is only a partial explanation. During this period existing diagnostic laboratories have been improved and new laboratories have been built. Culturing techniques have also been improved. Veterinarians are more aware of the disease and are making greater efforts to determine the cause of chronic diarrhea. Therefore, states with widespread distribution may indicate they are showing a greater awareness of the disease rather than more diseased herds than their neighbors.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1976-12-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7652</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19767652</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1976; 20-23</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7652/6068</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1976 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
