<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4741</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-15T08:42:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS2</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Efficacy of Meloxicam as an Adjunct Therapy in the Treatment of Neonatal Calf Diarrhea Complex</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Todd, C. G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McKnight, D. R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Millman, S. T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Duffield, T. F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leslie, K. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf diarrhea</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Meloxicam therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">oral electrolyte</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotic therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Neonatal calf diarrhea complex has a significant impact on the dairy industry. The National Animal Health Monitoring System reports that diarrhea accounts for greater than 60% of pre-weaned calf deaths. A recent field study in Europe has identified beneficial effects of Meloxicam therapy in calves with diarrhea. This controlled trial examined the efficacy of Meloxicam administration in combination with oral electrolyte and antibiotic therapy for the treatment of calf diarrhea. Compared to control animals, the Meloxicam-treated calves experienced significant improvements in clinical parameters, such as hydration status, fecal consistency, rectal temperature and signs of visceral pain. Overall, calfrecovery from the episode of diarrhea was improved for calves receiving Meloxicam therapy, compared to placebo-treated calves. The objective of the current study was to examine the effects of Meloxicam administration on calf health, behavior and performance in calves with neonatal calf diarrhea complex in Ontario.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2006-09-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4741</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20064741</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2006; 256-257</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4741/4638</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2006 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
