<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6079</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-06T00:15:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Factors Influencing Therapy Decisions in Clinical Cases of Grain-Positive Mastitis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wilson, David J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">gram-positive bacteria</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotic therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">non-steroidal anti-inflammatory therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">steroidal anti-inflammatory therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Therapy of clinical mastitis caused by gram-positive bacteria was reviewed, and a retrospective study was conducted. Reported cure rates for mastitis appear higher shortly after treatment. Apparent cure rates are markedly overestimated with only one follow-up culture by as much as 69%; these false cures can be attributed to antibiotic therapy. Spontaneous cure rates of mastitis are often not significantly different from those with antibiotic therapy. Most (93%) food animal veterinarians use steroidal and/or non-steroidal anti-inflammatory therapy. Clinical mastitis signs are considered responsive to this type of therapy, however, most studies of anti-inflammatory drugs concern their effectiveness against coliform mastitis, rather than gram-positive clinical mastitis. Oxytocin therapy for clinical cases of Strep sp. mastitis was compared with amoxicillin or cephapirin therapy; cure rates were not statistically different. Clinical gram-positive mastitis was found in 1464 quarters in the current retrospective study. Treatments used were: amoxicillin (n=21), cephapirin (n=122), cloxacillin (n=89), erythromycin (n=109), penicillin (n=93), unknown treatment (n=574), untreated (n=456). Bacterial cure rates for treated and untreated cases, respectively for each gram-positive agent were: Strep ag 518/691 (75%), 6/41 (15%); Strep sp. 60/73 (82%), 101/171 (59%); S. aureus 84/149 (56%), 51/ 149 (34%); Staph sp. 68/95 (72%), 72/95 (76%). Routine antibiotic treatment of these cases lost $123.50 for each case cured. Financial loss was worse for herds with no Strep ag present. Treatment of clinical mastitis caused by gram-positive organisms other than Strep ag with antibiotic therapy was not indicated by the results of this study.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1995-09-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6079</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1995; 90-93</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6079/6861</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1995 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
