<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5896</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-09T16:07:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Current Status of Brucellosis Eradication</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Becton, Paul</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Thank you very much for this privilege to present to you a report on the status of the cooperative brucellosis eradication program. I always appreciate an opportunity to discuss the brucellosis eradication effort with a group of professional people who have had and will continue to have avital part in the out-come of this program. It is also a privilege to visit Columbus again.
I lived here for almost a year back in 1954. It was one of the most stimulating experiences of my career as a veterinarian. I had the opportunity to participate in a well organized and vital effort to control and eradicate livestock diseases from this state. I have a few tables and figures which will show the current status of the brucellosis eradication program and the trends in recent years.
You will note from the information on the slides that there has been an increase in the rate at which brucellosis has been disclosed among livestock during the past two years. There are several apparent reasons for this increase.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1974-12-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5896</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1974; 33-36</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5896/5714</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1974 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
