<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6419</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-07T00:36:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Gas</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bovisalm TM and Bovisalm D Vaccines are Safe and Prevent Salmonellosis in Calves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">de Ree, J. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stuurman, B. G. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mollema, A. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zantinga, J. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">van der Valk, P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bovine salmonellosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccines</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mucosal immunity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lyophilized vaccines</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veal calves</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine salmonellosis is an important zoonotic infection1. Serious outbreaks of clinical disease may occur in cattle of all ages and result in devastating economic loss. The most important serotypes which cause disease in calves are Salmonella typhimurium and Salmonella dublin. Both serotypes can cause fever, anorexia, depression, bacteremia, diarrhoea and death.
Live and dead vaccines have been used to prevent salmonellosis in calves. It is generally believed that cell mediated immunity is necessary to provide longterm protection against salmonellosis. For this reason live attenuated strains have been used because these strains elicit a stronger cell mediated immunity than killed vaccines. Furthermore orally delivered vaccines cause a mucosal immunity, which is important for protection against enteric pathogens.
A number of different types of live vaccines have been developed. Auxotrophic mutants are dependent on metabolites not, or insufficiently present in the vaccinated animal. Recently, a Salmonella typhimurium strain was described which is auxotrophic for histidine and adenine and which also shows a high sensitivity to tensides2. Furthermore Salmonella dublin strain was described which is auxotrophic for thiamine and adenine. These strains have been used for the development of Bovisalm TM (S. typhimurium) and Bovisalm D (S. dublin); lyophilized vaccines for oral immunization of young veal calves to prevent salmonellosis. In this report we present data to show that these strains are safe and effective in preventing salmonellosis in calves.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6419</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926419</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 1; 74-79</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6419/7001</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
