<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6683</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-15T00:35:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Gas</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Descriptive Epidemiology of Salmonella Serotypes From Cattle in the USA (1982-1991)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Robinson, R. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ferris, K. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Miller, D. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Srinand, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Salmonella infections</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">subclinical</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">region</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">national data</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">epidemiology</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Clinical and subclinical bovine Salmonella infections have long been the source of concern to the industry from both the animal disease and human health perspectives. In recent years there has been a perception that these infections are being seen with increasing frequency, but this may be due to a combination of increased awareness by producers and veterinarians, improved culture techniques, and the publicity given to both beef and dairy product-associated human outbreaks. Nevertheless, the trend to larger dairies, together with increased inter-herd movements and changing feed practices may all contribute to the spread of salmonellae among cattle.
While there have been a number of single and multiple herd case reports of both calfhood and adult salmonellosis in the USA, no attempt has been made to summarize national data over time and by region. The National Veterinary Services Laboratories (NVSL) at Ames, Iowa provides a Salmonella confirmation and serotyping service to state diagnostic laboratories. Quarterly reports are made to submitters and an annual summary is published in the Proceedings of the U. S. Animal Health Association. This service has been provided without charge but submitters are required to provide basic herd/flock data as follows: name and address of owner, source animal species, number of animals in the herd or flock, morbidity, mortality, age groups affected, and whether these are considered primary or secondary infections.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6683</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926683</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Post-Convention Proceedings; 15-19</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6683/7130</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
