<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5825</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-03T07:25:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Pharmacokinetic Study of Plasma Calcium Concentration in Dairy Cows Following Four Oral Administrations at 12 Hour Intervals Around Calving of a Calcium Chloride Paste Formulation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Agger, Nicolai</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Katholm, Joergen</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lomborg, Kurt</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nygaard, Bent</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rudebeck, Kaj</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zangenberg, Niels</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk fever</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">subclinical</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calcium supplementation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">plasma calcium concentration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calcium paste product</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BOVIVET</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Despite intensive research during the last decades, milk fever is still widespread among high yielding dairy cows with considerable negative economic impact for the farmer. Furthermore, subclinical milk fever occurs more frequently than clinical milk fever.1 The negative economic impact is intensified by an increased risk of secondary diseases following milk fever at the time when the cow is ready for milk production. The incidence of dystocia, uterine prolapse, retained placenta, ketosis, mastitis, and left displacement of the abomasum is greatly increased in milk fever cows compared with cows with normal parturition.2
Oral supplementation of calcium at strategic correct times around calving for the prevention of milk fever has been practised during the last 20-25 years.3 Several calcium products containing different calcium salts have been introduced over the years.4
This article describes a pharmacokinetic study of plasma calcium concentration following oral administration of a newly developed calcium paste product (BOVIVET® Calcium Paste, Jørgen Kruuse A/S) to third or fourth parturient Holstein cows. One cartridge of calcium paste consists of 180 g calcium chloride and 6 g magnesium chloride. The salts are distributed in and protected by a special two-component oil. By using this special oil formulation the caustic effect of calcium chloride on the mucosal wall of the gut is eliminated.5 This side effect is described for other calcium chloride formulations.6'7
The calcium paste formulation was developed in cooperation with the Royal Danish School of Pharmacy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1997-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5825</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19975825</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1997; 72-75</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5825/5652</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1997 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
