<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9439</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Surveillance and risk assessment of Salmonella enterica serotype Dublin in Pennsylvania dairy herds using bulk tank testing and a mobile application</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cioletti, Grazielle</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kenney, Sophia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hovingh, Ernest</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Barrigan, Adrian</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cantor, Melissa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ganda, Ericka</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Salmonella enterica serotype Dublin (S. Dublin) is a zoonotic, host-adapted pathogen increasingly isolated in northeastern U.S. dairy cattle. It causes high calf mortality (20-100%) due to severe respiratory illness, while many infected adult animals can remain asymptomatic carriers. These carriers shed inter­mittently, often during periods of stress, complicating detection and control. S. Dublin spreads through high-risk management practices such as calf housing, maternity pens and herd move­ment, making strong biosecurity and structured risk assess­ments essential for control. In Pennsylvania, herd-level preva­lence remains unreported, and practical tools for producers to identify and manage S. Dublin risks are lacking. This project aimed to estimate S. Dublin herd prevalence using ELISA test­ing of bulk tank milk samples, and to develop a mobile applica­tion to help producers assess on-farm transmission risks.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9439</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259439</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 250</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9439/9046</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
