<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6447</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-07T00:34:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RDI</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effectiveness of an Inactivated Combined IBR/IPV Vaccine for Sanitization of a BHV 1 Infected Dairy Herd</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Menzel, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Herbst, W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Danner, K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine rhinotracheitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pustular vulvovaginitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovid herpesvirus type 1</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sanitization programs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">seroprevalence</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccine</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Infectious bovine rhinotracheitis, pustular vulvovaginitis caused by the bovid herpesvirus type 1 (BHV 1) is a contagious, febrile disease of cattle which is associated with respiratory disease, fertility disorders, abortions and, rarely, encephalitis (8). The disease occurs worldwide and, as is commonly observed with other herpesviruses, BHV 1 frequently induces latent infections after natural exposure or vaccination with live virus vaccines (8).
In many countries coordinated sanitization programs are therefore being employed. The basics of combatting IBR/IPV viral infections of cattle in Germany are culling or vaccination of seropositive animals with an attenuated and/or inactivated vaccine (7). Herds with a high seroprevalence rate are preferably vaccinated with an attenuated vaccine, whereas by low seroprevalence rates individual animals are either culled or an inactivated vaccine is used (7). Because of the lifelong latent infections after application of live vaccines (3, 5, 8) a long term investigation was geared to the question of whether an inactivated combined IBR/ IPV vaccine could reduce or prevent new infections in a dairy herd with a high seroprevalence rate for BHV 1.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6447</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926447</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 1; 219-223</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6447/7027</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
