<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5936</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-10T16:56:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DSS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Management of the Dairy Calf Prior to Weaning</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Quigley, J. D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">heifer management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">environmental factors</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management decisions</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neonatal period</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The calf and heifer enterprise is an important component of most dairy operations. On average, 25 to 35% of the dairy herd is culled each year and must be replaced. In addition, 10 to 12% of calves born, die within the first two years of life (USDA:APHIS, 1992). Thus, a ready source of high quality heifers is necessary. Unfortunately, calf and heifer management is often overlooked in the dairy enterprise, which leads to increased mortality and morbidity followed by delays in growth, breeding and delayed age at calving.
Calves are born with a predetermined genetic potential, which may be permanently affected by environmental factors and management decisions implemented throughout the rearing period. A calf's genetic potential may be considered an upper limit that is expressed only if proper decisions are implemented at the appropriate time. Studies have shown that the level of management, estimated as herd milk production average, has a profound effect on calf morbidity and mortality (Curtis et al., 1985; James et al., 1984; Jenny et al., 1981; Waltner-Toews et al., 1986a, 1986b). Proper management of young stock, particularly during the neonatal period, can markedly reduce morbidity and mortality, whereas improper management will lead to economic losses from increased cost of veterinary intervention, death losses, growth retardation, and poor reproductive performance. Ultimately, poor management of calves and heifers can reduce the lifetime productivity of the individual cow and the herd as a whole.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1996-09-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5936</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19965936</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1996; 50-58</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5936/5750</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1996 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
