<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8973</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-14T23:59:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The “how and why” of assessing micronutrient levels in beef cow-calf systems</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rethorst, Dave</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Matching the nutritional resources of protein, energy, miner­als, trace minerals and vitamins to requirements of the beef cow at various times of the year is likely the most challenging aspect of meeting the production goals in a cow-calf production system. While each system will have different goals, commonly accepted goals are 95% of females pregnant in 60 days, 65% of the cows calving in the first 21 days, and a 90 % weaned calf crop based on number of cows exposed.18 If goals are not being met, the obvious question is “why?” and a careful evaluation of the entire system should be undertaken as many times these problems are multifactorial. It is not uncommon to find nutri­tion playing a significant role in these problems whether they be reproductive, neonatal health or weaning health (Figure 1).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8973</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20248973</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 57 (2024): 2024 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 19-24</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8973/8679</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
