<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6725</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-07-22T18:34:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CCF3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Enhancement of Pre-weaning Performance</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Corah, Larry R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Blanding, Mitch R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">growth promotants</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">creep feeding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">medicated minerals</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parasite control</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">grazing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">forage quality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">genetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">age at weaning</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">When you evaluate the factors influencing profitability in the cow/calf industry, four key points need to be considered.1. Percent cows weaning calves.2. Weaning weight of calves.3. Selling price of calves.4. Annual cost of maintaining the cow.
Obviously, in evaluating weaning weight, it's important to consider both the percent of cows weaning calves and the actual weaning weight. If the goal is to improve weaning weight it cannot be at the expense of a dramatically reducing percent calf crop. The relationship of these two key profit factors is illustrated clearly in Table 1. Thus, in evaluating weaning weight it's important to look at weaning weight as actual pounds of calf weaned per cow in the herd.
In the past 20 years, it is very clear that the cow/calf industry has made considerable progress in improving calf weaning weights. The pounds of calf produced per cow nationally, (figures as summarized by Cattle Facts) were 318 lbs calf/cow in 1960, 449 lbs calf/cow in 1980 and current figures in 1989/90 are projecting 528 lbs calf/cow.
As we evaluate annual cost of maintaining the cow, very little change has occurred in the industry in the past ten years, but the current focus, such as the National IRM Program, will be addressing production costs and how the industry can improve economic efficiency by lowering annual production costs.
The following summary will look at those factors such as management, nutrition and genetics that can influence weaning weight.
Seven factors (in varying detail) will be considered: a) growth promotants, b) creep feeding, c) use of medicated minerals, d) internal/external parasite control, e) age at weaning, f) grazing systems/forage quality and g) genetic capacity to grow.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1991-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6725</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19916725</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1991; 114-121</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6725/6563</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1991 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
