<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7932</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T22:34:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CPS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">OB tips</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wiley, Caitlin E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calving</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dystocia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parturition</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Whether you are a dairy or beef cattle veterinarian, there is 1 thing you will be guaranteed to do in your career... dystocias. Numerous factors impact the reproductive successes of a herd, beginning with the initial mating decisions to nutrition during gestation to calving areas, plus many others. As a professional, your expertise may be called upon at any of these points during the process on an individual-herd basis because you are familiar with the producer's goals and limitations. Over the last 20 years, management decisions in the various areas previously mentioned have resulted in an overall decrease in the number of dystocias. However, dystocias still occur, despite all the preparatory work to avoid them. Stocking your toolbox with proper equipment and knowledge will help you when the producer calls upon you for your expertise and assistance when the calving does not go as planned.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-02-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7932</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2019 Recent Graduate Proceedings; 26-30</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7932/7515</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
