<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9338</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Setting up cows for success: Insights on first service management strategies and optimization of voluntary waiting periods</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Minela, Thaina</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Santos, Alisson</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Middleton, Emily</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pursley, J. Richard</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fertility program</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">estrus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive management</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Reproductive efficiency is central to the profitability and sustainability of modern dairy herds. Decisions regarding voluntary waiting period (VWP) length and first-service strategy critically affect fertility, milk production and herd economics. Fixed-time artificial insemination (FTAI) protocols have transformed reproduction by improving pregnancy per AI (P/AI) and overcoming limitations of estrus detection. In contrast, insemination after estrus detection (AIE), aided by automated activity monitors, allows alignment with natural reproductive behavior but yields lower P/AI. Targeted reproductive management combines FTAI and AIE after identifying cows that are likely subfertile and may not express estrous behavior. Optimizing VWP requires consideration of herd demographics. Multiparous cows often benefit from shorter VWPs, as earlier service increases opportunities for re-insemination, while primiparous cows, characterized by higher incidence of postpartum anovulation and greater lactation persistence, may benefit from longer intervals. Emerging precision livestock technologies now enable practitioners to integrate data from several software platforms to guide individualized reproductive programs. Strategic selection of first-service management and VWP tailored to herd-specific goals enhances reproductive performance, genetic progress, and the economic value of pregnancies in high-producing dairy systems.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9338</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259338</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 62-69</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9338/8954</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
