<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5569</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-30T20:19:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PHHPD</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Evaluation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Magnussen, Norman</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dr. Allenstein, friends of the dairy cow, it is true I am a dairy farmer. I am in the sale business, a cow jockey and a few other things but far from a speaker!
I have had to get my knowledge about the dairy cow from others and from personal experience and observation. If I have had any success in my day in the dairy cattle business, I must give a great amount of credit to the knowledge I gained from the men in your profession. It has been my good fortune over the years in working across the country in the sale business and before that as a test milker, as a herdsman, to meet probably ·some of the greatest men in your profession. It has been a terrific help 126 to me and I wish that all herdsmen and farmers could have the same experience. It has been a great help to me, especially in herd management, in the sale management business and in the cattle trading business too. ·Times have changed since my day. I do think that the veterinary profession has improved itself. It improved the dairy picture more than any other profession in the agricultural field. I personally feel this way. My interest lies in the purebred dairy industry. I started as a 4-H boy and had a 4-H calf and stayed with it. I do want to just take a little bit of credit and give credit to you people and the registered dairy people.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5569</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1972; 126-128</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5569/5426</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1972 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
