<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4083</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:52:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Beef Production: Changes Over the Years</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wileman, Ben</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomson, Dan</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef production</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">production technologies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">organic</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">literature review</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Modern beef production systems have seen significant changes in the last 30 years, from number of ranches and feedlots to the use of different technologies. Data from key beef production inputs and outputs were gathered from the time of peak beef cattle numbers in 1975 and compared to data from 2008. The majority of the change occurring in the last 30 years has been from the development and implementation of beef production technologies. The beef industry has significantly reduced its natural resource burden in terms of land mass and number of animals used, all while increasing production. One of the changes in the last 30 years in beef production has been the emergence of natural and organic beef production. These production systems do not allow many of the technologies used in conventional beef production, and the discussion of these technologies appears to be a major driver of future beef production. Therefore, a critical review of peer-reviewed literature on these technologies' effects on animal performance was conducted, as well as their effects on beef food safety. Findings of this research were then used as inputs into a breakeven model to illustrate the effects of these production systems relative to conventional production. And finally, these inputs were used to forecast the effect of removing these technologies from beef production and its impact on natural resource requirements. Modern beef production has achieved remarkable strides in the efficient use of natural resources to provide a safe and nutritious beef product over the last 30 years.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2010-08-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4083</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20104083</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2010; 61-68</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4083/4008</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2010 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
