<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7417</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-14T00:36:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CCS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Problems Encountered with Retaining Post-Weaned Calves on Southern Farms</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Blackwell, Jodie G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Economics is forcing great changes in the cattle industry. According to some feeders it is no longer possible to put large numbers of calves in feedlots in the panhandle region of Texas and the western states because the high cost of rations makes it economically unfeasible. It appears that there will be an unceasing and growing demand for grain on a world-wide basis. It is believed the present economic factors dictate that cattle will be kept on grass longer in order to make maximum untilization of the high priced grain. Research has been intensified during the last five years through the use of higher nitrogen rates, better grazing management and improved varieties of stocker calves. Thus with the advanced technology to grow cattle and forages, coupled with the favorable rainfall and winter climatic condition in the South, forage-fed beef is receiving more recognition (1,7).
Some economists predict that 60% or more of the cattle slaughtered this year will be non-grain fed animals. Many heavy steers are being sent from grass to packer. The 1974 calf slaughter was up 65% above that of 1973; included were many heavy weanling and yearling calves (6).</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1975-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7417</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19757417</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1975; 125-128</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7417/6515</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1975 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
