<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8972</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-14T23:59:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Working with nutritionists</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">May, Matt</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Veterinarians and nutritionists both are advisors to help feed­lots develop protocols, execute and monitor protocols, train of personnel, and identify new technologies. Nutritionists are responsible for supplement and ration formulation, feed addi­tive recommendations, growth promotants management, bunk management, overseeing quality control, and monitoring pro­tocol adherence. Veterinarians are responsible for arrival pro­tocols, treatment protocols, training crews on case definitions of sick animals, and monitoring morbidity and mortality. Nu­tritionists are judged on ADG, F:G, cost of gain, and metabolic disorders/mortality rates. Veterinarians are judged on pull rate and death loss outcomes, as well as costs of pharmaceutical us­age. There are many opportunities for nutritionists and veteri­narians to collaborate. It is important for each party to under­stand the general recommendations the other has in place, and where things could be tweaked to optimize efficiencies to help feedlot crew teams to execute these protocols. When challeng­ing one another, it is important to stay professional. It is also important that many of the disagreements could be alleviated with understanding why current protocols are in place, and to determine if there are opportunities to adjust the timing of events to compromise what makes most sense to the animal and the operation. As technology continues to improve through mon­itoring tools, data collection, new products and research, oppor­tunities for collaboration between professionals will continue to exist. Clear expectations and communication from all 3 parties (feedlot, veterinarian and nutritionist) are required for success.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8972</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20248972</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 57 (2024): 2024 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 16-18</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8972/8678</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
