<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3423</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:37:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Prudent drug use for the dairy practitioner</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gorden, Patrick J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug use</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stewardship</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As consumers become more savvy about the food they eat, dairy farmers and their veterinarians must be progressively vigilant to make sure that public health is protected. These protections, come not only from residue prevention, but also in the implementation of prudent drug practices that minimize the risk of development of antimicrobial resistance, which may be passed on to humans who consume animal-based food products. Throughout the last decade, the FDA has issued several guidance policies and implemented prohibitions in drug use in attempts to reduce the risk of development of antimicrobial resistance in humans. As dairy farms become larger, veterinarians are spending less time doing individual animal treatments and more time directing those treatments on farms. Whether animals are treated on-farm by veterinarians or by farm personnel, there are specific expectations that must be in place in order to reduce the risk of antimicrobial resistance development and drug residues in meat or milk.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-09-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3423</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20163423</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2016; 62-65</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3423/3377</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2016 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
