<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5683</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-31T07:23:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Opportunities for Cow-calf Practice: Interpreting the NAHMS Cow-calf Report</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dargatz, David A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">economic benefit</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Production efficiency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sustainability</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Production efficiency has become the watch word for cow-calf producers. Over the years the concept of initially integrated reproductive management and later integrated resource management has been adopted as a means to improve production efficiency on operations. Over time there has been a realization that maximum production is not always compatible with profitability or long-term sustainability. In addition, there has been a realization that one must focus on both components of the profit equation, revenues and costs, in order to achieve profitability in the enterprise. Many factors contribute to the potential for increased efficiency and profitability. Improved genetics, control of animal pathogens, nutrition research, and the development of reproductive technology all contribute to the potential for efficiency. However, data from the National Animal Health Monitoring System's (NAHMS) Beef '97 study suggest that relatively few producers are implementing some of the techniques that could contribute to production efficiency. The veterinarian is a key provider of information to producers and is in a position to help producers adopt technologies or improve management where appropriate. These sorts of decisions should always be based on the anticipated economic benefit to the producer.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1998-09-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5683</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19985683</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1998; 128-130</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5683/5525</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1998 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
