<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4999</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-18T07:12:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Management Guidelines During Harvest and Storage of Silage</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kung, Limin</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Neylon, Jeanne</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management techniques</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">silages</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">silo packing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">corn silage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">additives</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Management techniques during harvest and storage can have marked effects on the quality of forages stored as silage. Wilting to correct moistures and chopping forages to recommended particle lengths will help during the silo packing process. High cutting of corn silage may be an option for some producers to consider in the future. However, no recommendations can be made until more research is completed. Mechanical processing of corn silage can help to improve its nutritive value by improving starch and fiber digestion. Rapid packing to recommended densities and excluding air from the forage mass stimulates a more optimal fermentation in the silo. To help with the ensiling process, microbial inoculation encourages a more efficient fermentation. When forages are drier than 40% DM, inoculants are more effective if applied in a liquid form. All silage additives should be added such that they are distributed evenly throughout the forage mass. Covering bunk and pile silos with plastic is a cost efficient mechanism to save nutrients during storage. Finally, good feedout and silo face management can also help to maintain silages with a high nutritive value.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2002-09-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4999</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20024999</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2002; 13-17</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4999/4888</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2002 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
