<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4710</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-14T15:20:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:VetTech</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Client Education</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Czeck, Melissa</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">client education</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">large animal medicine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">teaching style</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">educated technicians</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">technician revenue</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Client education has been practiced in small animal medicine by both veterinarians and technicians for some time and is commonplace. However client education in large animal medicine especially in the cattle industry is not as common and is traditionally done by the veterinarian. Using technicians to educate producers is a management tool that veterinarians are starting to utilize.
As a technician you need to know your limitations both personally and legally. Use a teaching style that best suits you and works for the producer. Using continuing education to educate you both on teaching skills and keeping up on industry trends will help the veterinarian and technician feel more comfortable. Educating producers may be done one on one or in a group, each having benefits according to the situation. Large numbers of people can be reached by producer meetings, peer group sessions, newsletters or websites. One on one session give more personal attention and may be necessary in topics of sensitive issues or with a person who can not learn in a group setting.
Educating clients can be profitable for both the clinic and the farm if done correctly. Using the talents of educated technicians to provide client education will free up time for the veterinarian and increase technician revenue all while benefiting the producer.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2006-09-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4710</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20064710</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2006; 221-223</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4710/4608</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2006 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
