<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6732</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-07-22T18:34:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FS1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Laboratory Diagnosis of Virus Infections in the Feedlot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mock, Richard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">health program</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">herd health program</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">laboratory tests</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Laboratory confirmation of clinical diagnosis can serve an important role in the maintenance of a health program in the feedlot. There is an abundance of scientific literature and review articles documenting the involvement of viruses in bovine respiratory disease.1,2 Laboratory tests can supply information on which viruses are involved in causing clinical disease. This information can assist in making informed decisions for future vaccination, treatment and herd health programs. Routine suiveillance testing can supply data on the changing disease conditions of a feedlot and assist in maintaining client satisfaction.
To obtain good diagnostic laboratory results it is important that the appropriate samples are collected early in the course of the disease. The samples should be chosen according to the clinical conditions and the differential diagnosis. Due to the time required in conducting laboratory tests and getting the complete results, all possibilities should be thoroughly anticipated in submitting samples to assure that the laboratory results will assist in the diagnosis.
This report summarizes some of the available laboratory tests and their utilization for diagnosis of viral infections in the feedlot.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1991-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6732</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19916732</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1991; 128-130</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6732/6568</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1991 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
