<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4700</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-14T15:20:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Animal Welfare Audits: What You Should Know About Them</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reynolds, Jim</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy products</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal bodies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal natures</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal minds</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management systems</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Consumers of dairy products look to veterinarians and producers to ensure humane care is provided to farm animals. Animal welfare is a consensus of opinions, and what is considered acceptable welfare, or husbandry, changes over time. Animal welfare can be assessed or described in three different approaches: animal bodies (physiologic, production, disease), animal natures (comparison to similar animals in nature) and animal minds (feelings, suffering).
All three approaches should be considered when judging animal welfare. Audits are structured events so they can be repeatable and defendable. Auditors should have education in the given species and experience in the industry to evaluate different housing and management systems. The goal of an auditor is not to pass or fail the farm, but to determine if the agreed-on processes are being carried out. The auditor is verifying the welfare of the animals to consumers and retailers and is neutral to the farm. Training for auditors covers the welfare issues of the species, some industry standards, and how to perform an audit and comply with that company's requirements. The Professional Animal Auditor Certification Organization (PAACO) will certify the training of individual auditors and also the actual audit forms or processes of companies doing audits. PAACO will, in the future, provide training for people wanting to be certified to audit each species of farm animal, but who have not received training elsewhere.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2006-09-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4700</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20064700</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2006; 162-166</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4700/4599</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2006 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
