<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8076</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-05-28T07:35:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PMS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Factors influencing job and career satisfaction in veterinarians 10 years or fewer from graduation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gilliam, Gabryelle N.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">White, Brad J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McLellan, Jiena G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pendell, Dustin L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Larson, Robert L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary career satisfaction</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">employee retention</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Retention of veterinarians in practice is critical to longterm practice success. Understanding factors influencing satisfaction can provide information for practice managers to positively influence the work environment. The study objective is to identify potential factors influencing job and career satisfaction in veterinarians less than 10 years from graduation. Secondary outcomes include factors influencing current financial, physical, and emotional health. A cross-sectional, anonymous online survey with 82 complete responses was used for analysis. Respondents were representative of recent graduates and most respondents were satisfied with their job (83.0%) and career (84.1%). Both job and career satisfaction were higher when respondents believed they received adequate recognition. Financial health was associated with technician-to-veterinarian ratio, adequate recognition, current debt, and raise frequency. Physical health was associated with length at the current job and current debt. Emotional health was significantly associated with years at the current job, having held an internship, and technician-to-veterinarian ratio. In general, most veterinarians within 10 years of graduation were satisfied with their job and career choice. Several factors influenced job satisfaction, career satisfaction, and financial, physical, and emotional health. Understanding these factors can help employers and employees maintain a healthy working environment.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-09-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8076</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20208076</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2020; 279-282</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8076/8024</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
