<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7134</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-10-16T01:02:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SRS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Field euthanasia techniques for small ruminants</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Still Brooks, Kelly M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">euthanasia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">small ruminant</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">gunshot</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">captive bolt</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neonatal</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Goats, sheep, and camelids present unique challenges when selecting a safe, aesthetic, and environmentally responsible method of field euthanasia. Although barbiturate euthanasia products are frequently used in companion settings, access to these drugs is restricted and carcass residues limit viable disposal options. Gunshot, penetrating captive bolt, and adjunctive techniques commonly used in cattle are appropriate for use in small ruminants with modifications to reduce the risk of over-penetration and improve anatomic accuracy. While farm personnel can be trained to safely and effectively use gunshot techniques in adult sheep and goats, safe options for euthanasia of neonatal goats and lambs is severely limited by their small size. Manual blunt force trauma is an unacceptable method in these species; however, non-penetrating captive bolts devices are acceptable for stunning or euthanasia of perinatal kids and lambs. Additionally, carbon dioxide inhalation is an effective and humane technique for goat kids &amp;lt; 3 weeks of age. Intrathecal lidocaine injection is an acceptable method in anesthetized horses and early clinical experience suggests it may be reasonably applied by veterinarians in the field for all ages of small ruminants.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-09-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7134</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20197134</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2019; 187-191</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7134/5918</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
