<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3759</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:40:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:AASRPPRS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Lying behavior as an early predictor of ketosis in early lactation dairy goats</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zobel, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leslie, K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weary, D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">von Keyserlingk, M. A. G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">kidding</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">negative energy balance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk production</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ketosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">goat</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">behavior</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy goats</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lying behavior</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Goats frequently have multiple foetuses, a known risk factor for negative energy balance prior to kidding (Brozos et al, Vet Clin North Am Food AnimPract, 2011). This state, coupled with increased energy demands of milk production, also increases the risk of ketosis after kidding. Ketosis is a serious metabolic condition that when left untreated can be fatal. Regardless of severity, ketosis has been shown to negatively affect milk production in dairy cows (Rajala-Schultz et al, J Dairy Sci, 1999). Unfortunately, in goats, this disease is typically only identified when does show clinical signs, and prognosis is poor. At subclinical levels, which frequently go undetected, reduced milk production likely leads to early culling. Clinical symptoms of ketosis include loss of appetite, ataxia, and general lack of mobility, including increased lying behavior (Andrews et al, Small Ruminant Res, 1996). In dairy cows, changes in lying behavior have been shown to be useful as early indicators of compromised health status (Weary et al, J Anim Sci, 2009). Therefore, the aim of this study was to examine whether lying behavior could be used as an early predictor of ketosis after kidding in dairy goats.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3759</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20143759</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2014; 173-174</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3759/3698</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2014 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
