<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8320</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-10-24T20:58:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SRS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Reproductive management of Rocky Mountain elk (Cervus canadensis nelsoni)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bott, Isacc</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">wapiti</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Rocky Mountain elk</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">theriogenology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">artificial insemination</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Of the six subspecies of elk known to have inhabited North America in historical times, four remain, including the Roos­evelt’s (C. canadensis roosevelti), tule (C. canadensis nannodes), Manitoban (C. canadensis manitobensis) and Rocky Mountain elk (C. canadensis nelsoni). Rocky Mountain elk (Cervus canadensis nelsoni) are a subspecies of elk found in the Rocky Mountains and adjacent ranges of Western North America. Assisted repro­ductive technologies described in elk include estrous synchro­nization, artificial insemination, embryo transfer and in-vitro fertilization. Semen cryopreservation has also been described and semen sales are a large portion of the economic mainstay of elk farmers. Studies on fertility of sex-sorted elk semen are limited but most reviews note the resilience of wapitoid sper­matozoa to pass through the sorting process and maintain fer­tility. Given that profit in this industry is driven by velvet sales and the hunting market, both exclusive to males, the use of sex-sorted semen in the elk industry is increasing each year.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2021-10-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8320</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2021 Annual Conference Proceedings; 134-137</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8320/8199</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2021 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
