<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6135</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-09T16:07:28Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Fedlot</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Controlled Environment Feedlot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Herrick, John B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Cattle feeding plays an important role in the agricultural economy of many states in the United States. In Iowa alone, cattle feeders received approximately $1.56 billion of gross receipts. This generation of income also supports many jobs in the input supply and product processing sectors. It is estimated that every dollar of livestock sales generates $2.25 for those companies and industries that serve the livestock industry.
Recent developments in the economy of cattle feeding has resulted in severe financial losses for the feeder and now for the cow-calf producer. This appears to be short run in that cattle feeding will be more profitable in the long run. Further, with innovations such as recycling manure, and efforts to combat stress in open feedlots, as well as means to economize on labor, the controlled investment in cattle feeding is being considered by many cattlemen. This is particularly true in the Midwest where adverse weather adds stress to the cattle, affecting feeding efficiency.
There are many alternatives to confinement feeding. Location of the building, type of facility, cost figures applied, number of cattle, weather condition, capital, degree of management and potential advantages must all be considered for the facility.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1974-12-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6135</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1974; 167-169</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6135/5887</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1974 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
