<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9387</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PPT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Screening, cleaning and quarantining: Biosecurity in small ruminant practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pesato, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">small ruminants</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biosecurity</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Biosecurity is an essential concern for all food animal practi­tioners. In small ruminant practice, three primary diseases are important for biosecurity of the entire flock or herd. Testing for these primary diseases allows clients and practitioners to screen for infectious diseases. These diseases include caseous lymphad­enitis, Johne’s disease, and small ruminant lentiviruses. Clean­ing is another essential element of biosecurity. An ideal environ­ment allows for cleaning and disinfection (concrete flooring and walls, rubber mats, metal gates) but most small ruminant enclo­sures are difficult to clean and disinfect due wooden structures with dirt flooring. Cleaning should always come before disinfec­tion, and tuberculocidal cleaning products are ideal. Quarantine is the final element of a biosecurity program. Ideally, a quaran­tine period of 1-month allows for new animal acclimation as well as veterinary inspection and diagnostic testing.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9387</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259387</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 201-203</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9387/8999</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
