<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7847</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:14:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CCs</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Evolution of a Ranch Management Program Deep in the Heart of Texas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martin, Carl A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ranch management</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">During the ensuing years, including the 1950-56 drought, we have emphasized ranch management and improvement by reducing size and increasing the number of pastures, watering places, deferring grazing and reducing stocking rates.
In summary, now, what does all this information mean to me and how do I intend to use it?1. Historically, the profit motive is what motivates most of us to strive to do better.'Therefore, there is no room for sentimentality in an economic endeavor and certainly any livestock production program is a business operation.2. Use some form or method of identification and from this point on, many nice things can begin to happen if-and only if-we let some preconceived notions we may have had, go out the window and let Mother ature help,us.3. Set up a rigid systematic selection and culling program based upon those heritable characteristics of economic importance, because it will pay off in percent calf crop weaned and in weaning weight and quality of calves, all of which are factors which determine profit.
4. Develop two-way livestock.5. In any range breeding operation, to be successful, a conservation plan must be made and carried out to the best of one's ability under the circumstances.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1978-12-11</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7847</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19787847</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1978; 82-85</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7847/7474</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1978 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
