<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5167</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:21:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The How, What, Why, and More of Writing Farm Processes</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bennett, James</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">variation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">documentation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">protocols</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">inconsistency</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management consultant</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Deming said that when any process is in control, variability will be only 6%. He defined two types of variation. Special cause variation is unpredictable and represents a process that is out of control. 94% of the variability in a process under control is common cause. Common cause variation represents the normal ebb and flow of things that affect the process output. This could be the small number of new mastitis infections that occur on a dairy on a regular basis, for example. When a process is out of control, more of the variability in results is due to special cause variation, such as a malfunctioning milking system or irregular prep procedure. The process is in control when the product or output falls within theupper and lower control limits. Proper documentation of protocols on a dairy can help keep variability within 6%. Most dairies probably never approach this level of consistency in critical process, yet in any environment consistent execution of processes is the key to consistent results. Dairies, like any other small business must learn to define processes for critical areas of the business. If they do this, and have methods in place to ensure that employees will execute the processes correctly, they can predict results and achieve their goals. If they don't results will be inconsistent. This inconsistency will be blamed on the weather, bad luck, bad employees, or a bad advice. You, astute diagnostician, expert veterinary consultant, and super duper management consultant can help dairies achieve this consistency of results. You can help them achieve their goals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2001-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5167</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20015167</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2001; 1-5</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5167/5042</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2001 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
