<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7516</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-17T20:00:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">What the Producer Expects from His Veterinarian</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McGinnis, Charles</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinarian</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">client relationship</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">service</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">herd health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">continuing education</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Now from that a concise description of what we expect from a veterinarian might be as follows: First, we would expect service when we need it within reason. We know our own limitations as far as treatment and herd health, and we try not to call out veterinarians for frivolous reasons. We try not to call him to correct our mistakes, and we don't call him to perform miracles! We expect our veterinarian to keep us well informed on new medicines, vaccines, techniques, and herd health practices that can make our business more profitable. We think he owes it to us to have for himself an on-going self-education, continuing education program. We expect our veterinarian to be open, frank, and honest with us, and we expect to deal with him in the same manner. We expect our veterinarian to understand our particular goals and priorities, and assistance with his involvement in every way that is possible. We expect him to charge us fair rates and make a good living and have his practice profitable, but not too profitable!</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7516</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19867516</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1986; 18-20</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7516/6103</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
