<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4001</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:49:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Taking the Long View: Treat Them Nice as Babies and They will be Better Adults</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Van Amburgh, M. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Soberon, F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Raffrenato, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Karzses, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Everett, R. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">epigenetic modification</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">nutrition</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diet</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Calf nutrition and management programs have focused on early weaning and modest liquid feed intake designed to encourage dry feed intake for enhanced rumen development. This was done primarily to reduce cost and also to reduce the risk for diarrhea and other disease concerns.
Data are being generated demonstrating that early life management and nutrition, starting with colostrum, positively reinforces the genetic capacity of the calf for feed efficiency and milk producing ability. Factors in colostrum, such as certain growth factors and hormones, appear to enhance the efficiency of use of absorbed nutrients, providing a broader role for colostrum intake and composition beyond the traditional role for immune function. Published data demonstrate differences in feed efficiency of over 26% in calves with higher levels of colostrum intake, independent of Ig status. The objective of doubling the birth weight of the calf by weaning through increased milk or milk replacer intake has demonstrated positive effects on milk production in the first and subsequent lactation. In several studies, the milk yield of calves have been enhanced from 500 to over 3,000 lb in the first lactation through increased liquid feed intake and data are now available indicating the increased milk yield is extended into subsequent lactations. Overall, this data demonstrates that the calf experiences epigenetic modification of their milk producing ability through increased nutrient intake in the first 42 to 49 days of life. The economic consequences of this outcome are discussed.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2011-09-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4001</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20114001</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2011; 79-87</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4001/3928</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2011 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
