<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3686</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:42:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SRS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">What bovine practitioners need to know about traceability and scrapie</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rowe, Joan Dean</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">sheep</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">goats</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">small ruminants</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">scrapie</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Veterinarians serving clients with small ruminants or working with small ruminants at fairs, shows, auctions or other activities must be familiar with identification requirements for sheep and goats. Scrapie program identification and records serve as the sheep and goat requirements for Animal Disease Traceability. Many online resources are available through USDA-APHIS to familiarize veterinarians with National Scrapie Eradication Program (NSEP) program requirements and clinical recognition of scrapie cases. Regulatory veterinarians, designated scrapie epidemiologists, and official testing laboratories conduct many elements of the NSEP, but private practitioners play a key role in assisting owners and community members in complying with NSEP animal identification and recordkeeping standards, completing certificates of veterinary inspection for animal movement, and recognizing clinical scrapie suspects in the field. Engagement by all veterinary practitioners, whether or not sheep and goats are a significant part of their practice, is needed to succeed in the eradication of scrapie from the United States.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3686</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20143686</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2014; 95-98</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3686/3630</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2014 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
