<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4510</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-15T08:41:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Reproductive Records: Monitoring and Compliance</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nebel, Ray L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">DeJarnette, J. Mel</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive performance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">records</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">benchmarks</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">protocol</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">treatments</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">monitoring points</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive monitoring</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Reproductive performance of a dairy herd is a function of certain management policies and how well these are implemented in daily herd management. It has long been known that there is an important economic advantage to be gained by efficient reproduction in dairy herds. The ability to use records effectively is a cornerstone of reproductive management. Accurate records are necessary to obtain the history of past performance and determine if changes or adjustments need to be made in current management policies. However, one must use good judgment with monitoring to avoid changing something that is not really a problem. Change should occur as needed or warranted, and not just for the sake of change. Many parameters can be used to monitor reproductive status and trends on the dairy herd, but every parameter monitored should be proactive, measurable and result in profit to the dairy.
Benchmarks are standards by which performance can be measured or compared, and are not synonymous with goals. Benchmarks are simply the averages for different monitoring parameters and may be derived by grouping together herds that represent specific categories (herd size, production level, geographic location). Goals are target levels of performance toward which managers are striving. Complete herd records should provide the necessary tools to define herd performance historically, assist in establishing goals for monitored parameters and assist in determining the impact of the plan developed to reach the established goals.
What is compliance on the dairy? It will be defined here as the administration of treatments or actions according to a prescribed protocol. The more complicated a protocol, the greater the chances for procedural failure. Protocol compliance is critical for success. There are two types of monitoring points for compliance: the execution of the event itself, or the resulting outcome from that action that is related to the process. Most reproductive monitoring is performed on the resulting action which is indicated by the day in milk at first service (DIMFS), serum progesterone levels at time of injection or insemination, and finally, pregnancy rates in the subsequent 21-day cycles.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-09-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4510</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20074510</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2007; 50-56</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4510/4416</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
