<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3804</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:44:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of ampicillin trihydrate for treatment of metritis and subsequent fertility in lactating dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lima, F. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vieira-Neto, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Martinez, N. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Risco, C. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Galvão, K. N.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Santos, J. E. P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Metritis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">endometritis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">E. coli</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ampicillin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">ceftiofur hydrochloride</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Metritis affects 10%-30% of dairy cows and results in production losses, impaired fertility, and increased risk of culling and death early in lactation. Economic losses of metritis have been estimated at $328/affected cow. Cows that develop metritis are at an increased risk to develop clinical and subclinical endometritis. Escherichia coli expressing fimH early postpartum (1-3 days in milk [DIM]) has been associated with development of metritis, which suggests this bacterium has an important role and is a virulence factor for initial tissue damage and subsequent bacterial infection and development of uterine diseases. It is possible that reduction of the amount of E. coli in the uterus of cows with metritis in early lactation might reduce its detrimental impact. Ampicillin is efficacious against E. coli, but to date, studies to evaluate the efficacy of ampicillin for the treatment ofmetritis in dairy cows are lacking. The objective of this study was to compare the efficacy of ampicillin trihydrate (AMP) for the treatment of metritis in dairy cows compared with that of ceftiofur hydrochloride (CEFT). Our hypothesis was that AMP would be an effective treatment for metritis in dairy cows.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2013-09-19</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3804</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20133804</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2013; 136</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3804/3743</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2013 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
