<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6323</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-07-22T20:18:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Certain Factors to Consider When Designing a Bovine Vaccination Program</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schultz, Ronald D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">non-infectious vaccine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">modified live vaccine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunologic principles</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunology</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Why, when we are vaccinating cattle more than ever before, are we failing to immunize them? Some would blame the vaccines, others would blame the animals, but frequently the real problem is a failure to apply some of the basic principles of immunology in our vaccination programs. More than at any other time, because there are so many different vaccines to choose from, the basic principles of vaccination must be applied, if your vaccination program is to work as effectively as possible. The goal of every vaccination program should be to enhance protective immunity for the diseases important in your practice area.
This presentation will discuss some of the immunologic principles of vaccination with a major emphasis on differences between non-infectious (killed, inactivated) and modified live vaccines. It will concentrate on the 'Do's and Don'ts", the "Whys and Why Nots" and the ''What Will Work" and ''What Will Not Work". An improved understanding of the limitations and proper uses of current vaccines, as well as possible reasons that the vaccines may not be as effective as you had expected, will possibly provided an opportunity for improvements in your vaccination program.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1993-09-16</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6323</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1993; 19-26</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6323/6624</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1993 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
