<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6151</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-14T00:37:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:OS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Welcome and Some Insights into Georgia Livestock Production</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Irvin, Tommy</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jarrett, James</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dr. Jarrett: A gentleman who does understand the problems of agriculture-as a farmer from the hills of North Georgia, as a member of our state legislature and very active in the area of agriculture when he was there, as our state com-missioner of agriculture Mr. Tommy Irvin has been a friend to the veterinarian as well-as a friend to Georgia agriculture. It is my pleasure to introduce to you at this time, Mr. Tommy Irvin:
APPLAUSE.
Thank you very much. It is a real pleasure to have the op port unity to welcome this very distinguished group. I understand you have representatives from practically every state of the Union, and maybe some from foreign countries here in the greatest city in America, Atlanta. He didn't tell you a whole lot about me but I am a genuine country boy and real proud of it. When you look around, especially those of you who are not residents of our state or our region, you wouldn't realize how much change has transpired in the span of the last 20-30 years.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1975-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6151</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19756151</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1975; 1-2</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6151/6479</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1975 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
