<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4782</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:14:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Treatment of Mycoplasma Infections: Susceptibility of Field Isolates and Outcome of Treatment: Recovered Cattle: Risk or Bonus?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ayling, Roger D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nicholas, Robin A. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Mycoplasma species</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">small colony type</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pleuropneumonia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antimicrobial resistance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccine trials</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A number of Mycoplasma species cause disease in cattle including Mycoplasma niycoides subspecies mycoides small colony type, the cause of the OIE list A disease, contagious bovine pleuropneumonia in Africa, and Mycoplasma bovis, one of the biggest causes of calf pneumonia world-wide. Symptoms include pneumonia, mastitis and arthritis, all of which adversely affect the economics of farming. Control of M. bovis is difficult because it has systems for evading the immune system and has developed resistance to a number of antimicrobials. While strategies can be deployed on the farm to reduce or possibly eliminate disease caused by M. bovis, these approaches can be time consuming, and costly in terms of drug treatment and testing, with no guarantees of success. Although some vaccine trials have seen an exacerbation of disease, vaccines are being developed, and some are in use in the USA, although data on their efficacy is sparse.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2005-09-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4782</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20054782</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2005; 6-10</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4782/4678</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2005 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
