<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9429</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The pathologist’s approach to diagnosing the diversity of cardiopulmonary phenotypes encountered in the feedlot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Krafsur, G.M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Feedlot pulmonary hypertension (PH) frequently progressing to congestive heart failure (CHF) represents a significant health challenge to the cattle industry. Often, the condition is mis­construed as primary respiratory disease with cor pulmonale, infectious myocarditis (Histophilus somni), acute interstitial pneumonia (AIP), ionophore intoxication, neoplasia, hardware disease and even bloat, among others. There is a considerable overlap in clinical manifestations between the various etiolo­gies underlying bovine heart failure although each has a unique gross and histomorphologic cardiopulmonary phenotype, emphasizing the value of postmortem examination and his­tomorphologic interpretation for proper classification. Likely the magnitude of feedlot PH and CHF remain underestimated. Although bovine respiratory disease (BRD) underlies the great­est number of illnesses and deaths in the feedlot, the trajectory for bovine PH and CHF remains constant if not growing with a tendency to cluster among herds with high performing Angus influence genetics, accounting for up to 7% of death losses. The objective of this work was to compare and contrast gross and histomorphologic attributes of the “alphabet soup” of these im­portant cardiopulmonary disease challenges in the feedlot, dis­cuss genetic tools used by the pathologist to assist in situations with clustering of cases and utilization of machine learning to provide more robust assessment of cardiac fibrosis and adipos­ity in feedlot PH and CHF.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9429</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259429</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 243-244</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9429/9039</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
