<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6160</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-14T00:37:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:OS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Future of Agriculture as Viewed by a Pioneer</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brooks, D. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson, Dave</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">[Preceeded by an Introduction by Doctor Anderson, Dean, College of Veterinary Medicine, Univeristy of Georgia.]
One of the problems about an introduction is that you have to be rather careful that you don't inhale some of these things people say kindly about you. When I came in I went down to the exhibit hall first and I heard some strange language down there. It was sort of the English language, but had a sort of a peculiar twang to it, and I began to realize that all these people weren't from Georgia. Some of them evidently had gotten across the line and on the other side, so I thought I should at least mention that. You see many years ago-I'm a pioneer they say here-many years ago we were rather careful about how many Yankees we let into this area. One time a bunch came through here and when they got through there wasn't much left! They got so careless with fire that, brother, they just about did us in. So for a long period of time we were very careful, but we finally began to catch on.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1975-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6160</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19756160</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1975; 8-12</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6160/6480</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1975 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
