<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8679</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-07-18T01:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluating the efficacy of two footbath concentrates to control digital dermatitis in freestall dairy cows using a non-inferiority study</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ordaz, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shepley, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rendahl, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dopfer, D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anklam, K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cramer, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Digital dermatitis (DD), an infectious hoof lesion, is prevalent in U.S. dairies and compromises cow health, welfare and profit­ability. Footbaths are the main form of DD prevention and con­trol. Understanding the comparative efficacies among commer­cial footbath products in preventing and controlling DD cases within a herd is necessary to provide farms with the informa­tion required when selecting a product for use. Digital derma­titis (DD), an infectious hoof lesion, is prevalent in U.S. dairies and can rapidly become endemic to a herd if not proactively controlled, compromising cow health, welfare and profitabil­ity. Footbaths are the main form of DD prevention and control. Understanding the comparative efficacies among commercial footbath products in preventing and controlling DD cases with­in a herd is necessary to provide farms with the information re­quired when selecting a product for use. Our primary objective was to determine if a commercial footbath concentrate (Heal­max®) was non-inferior to a copper sulfate concentrate in the prevention of new cases of digital dermatitis (DD). As a second­ary objective, we sought to investigate the comparative effica­cies of the 2 products in the control of chronic DD cases.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-07-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8679</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228679</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 55 (2022): 2022 Annual Conference Proceedings; 205</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8679/8432</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
