<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4781</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:14:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Transmission of Mycoplasma bovis and the Syndromes that Result in Beef and Dairy Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rosenbusch, Ricardo F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Mycoplasma bovis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">transmission</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management strategies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Pneumonia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">polyarthritis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Infections with Mycoplasma bovis can result in several syndromes of importance for dairy and beef cattle of all ages. These diseases continue to require the attention of practitioners due to poor response to treatment and the marginal effectiveness of prophylaxis. We explore here parameters of transmission of the infections, and how practitioners can use this knowledge to develop management strategies. General concepts about transmission of the mycoplasma are followed with specific description of several different mycoplasma mastitis clinical presentations. Issues with transmission and mastitis are outlined. Pneumonia and polyarthritis, and middle ear infections in dairy calves are described next and transmission of infection differences are highlighted. Examples of presentations of pneumonia and polyarthritis in beef calves are presented together with discussion of some of the transmission questions that are commonly raised when considering this disease.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2005-09-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4781</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20054781</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2005; 1-5</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4781/4677</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2005 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
