<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5135</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:24:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:NND</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Diarrhea in the Calf Part I: Pathophysiologic Changes and Development</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Phillips, R. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lewis, L. D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neonatal diarrhea</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">intestinal transport</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">enzymes</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">jejunum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">electrolytes</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Before effective management and therapy can be initiated for neonatal diarrhea we must understand normal intestinal function as well as the changes that take place in the intestinal tract leading to the diarrhea. Of even greater importance is a knowledge of secondary and tertiary changes which occur as a result of the altered intestinal transport. First, let us review normal intestinal function in the calf. Milk by-passes the rumen or reticulum and is coagulated by rennin and the acid conditions of the abomasum or true stomach (7). As proteolytic enzymes act, the curd is liquefied and passes into the duodenum where further enzymatic activity breaks down the proteins, carbohydrates and lipids. In the jejunum these organic compounds are absorbed as the fatty acids, amino acids, and sugars (4). There is also considerable secretory activity here and some absorption of electrolytes, although the majority of the electrolytes are absorbed further down the intestinal tract in the lower jejunum and ileum (4). Final absorptive function occurs in the upper portion of the colon where feces are normally formed.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1971-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5135</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19715135</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1971; 104-108</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5135/5014</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1971 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
