<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4381</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:59:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Managing Feed Quality Issues to Maximize Health and Productivity</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Corbett, Robert B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Veterinarians are becoming increasingly involved in nutritional management on their clients' dairies, and are more frequently being consulted about feed quality and feed delivery issues. Many fresh cow problems that veterinarians treat are nutritionally related and cannot be resolved without making changes in nutritional management&amp;nbsp; around the time of parturition. Maximizing feed quality, regardless of whether the feedstuff is harvested on-farm or is purchased, is extremely important in maximizing profitability and minimizing disease on the dairy farm. Maintaining feed quality during storage and feedout is equally important. Dairy feeds can be classified into five general categories: 1) fermented forages, 2) dry forages, 3) commodities, 4) additives and 5) vitamin-mineral packages. Even though feed quality management is generally focused on forages, other categories of feedstuffs should also be addressed. Veterinarians need to be well-informed on feed quality issues, regardless of whether or not they are doing actual ration formulation on the farm.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2008-09-25</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4381</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20084381</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2008; 137-144</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4381/4295</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2008 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
