<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6919</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-17T19:53:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FS1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Applied Trace Element Nutrition in the Bovine Animal</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Coffey, Robert T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle diseases</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">epidemiology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pathogenesis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cellular physiology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">assay techniques</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">herd health</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Within the scientific and academic community there have been great accomplishments in understanding the epidemiology and pathogenesis of cattle diseases. Even so, the food animal industry continues to suffer significant monetary losses from disease pathogens and non-infectious disease disorders. As practicing veterinarians, our knowledge is limited only because of our inability to keep pace with the various disciplines within the scientific community. The area of biochemistry and cellular physiology, once thought to be subjects limited to the classroom, may hold the answer to improving the basis of effective and profitable herd health programs.
Many livestock disease situations are a result of multifactorial health damaging situations that revolve around environment, area of origin, genetics, disease exposure, nutrition and agricultural practices. More significant in our industry is the highly aggressive sales approach utilized in animal health advertising that imply production problems are handled and cured through the use of a particular product. These realities are in conflict and create a serious clinical problem for the animal health specialist. Producers expect solutions to be quick and usually revolve around vaccination and treatment programs. Understanding nutrition and the impact it has on overall health is one way in which to remove this conflict and make better use of the biologicals and pharmaceuticals we have in our arsenal.
By incoporating basic knowledge on cellular physiology, assay techniques for the protective oxidative (metallo) enzymes, and the use of computerized spreadsheet data analysis, my practice has developed an exciting and challenging approach to total herd health. It requires discipline, time, and continuing education. Resolving the conflict does not involve finding "new" cures, but rather a re-evaluation of cultural and scientific data already in existence with proper application to the intensified cattle production industry.
Accept the challenge!</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1989-11-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6919</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19896919</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1989; 153-169</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6919/6350</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1989 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
