<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7070</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:57:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DCCFSS3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Veticare System</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Labrosse, Pierre</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Quebec</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy producers</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">industrial</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Canada</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In Canada, we have two levels of government: the federal Government of Canada and the provincial governments. To accompany this fancy political governing system, we also have two internal revenue systems, one federal and one provincial. If you are working for dollars, you definitely have to collect for it.
I come from the Province of Quebec. from the iegion we refer to as the Richelieu Valley situated in the most southern area of the province which coincides with the most northern area of the Vermont State,. It is situated south-east of Montreal, limited to the west by the Richelieu River which runs from the Champlain lake to the St. Lawrence river.
In this area, most of the producers are referred to as industrial type dairy producers. The typical farm is a family farm which owns approximately 150 head of cattle. The largest farm milks 350 cows and owns approximately 800 head. In this province, nothing seems to be done like anywhere else in this country. Politicians, in the past, managed to have the western producers produce grains that were shipped to the east to produce milk. Approximately 55% of the milk produced in Canada is produced in Quebec. We do not speak the same language, and we always seem to do things in a complicated manner.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1988-09-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7070</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19887070</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1988; 174-179</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7070/6298</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1988 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
