<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7822</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:08:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Fedlot</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Drug-Related Problems and Solutions in a Large Feedlot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Oliphant, Rodney</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cleanliness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">live-virus vaccine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">contaminate</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Another problem is cleanliness. It is probably one of the biggest problems, especially with their syringes and needles. Also, tell them about putting modified live-virus vaccines through syringes and needles that have chemical disinfectants. They will ruin more information and more good quality products than it has taken 10 years for a drug company to develop. They take a lot of care to get a good product to them and then in just a matter of a few seconds they can mess it up. A lot of them have the habit of shaking up their virus vaccines when they put their reconstitute in it. They will put a dirty finger over the top and they will give it a few shakes and contaminate the vaccine. Then they will pour it into another old plastic bag of some kind that has been lying around and it is terrible! I think we as veterinarians should look for this problem and get it corrected.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1977-12-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7822</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1977; 187-189</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7822/6506</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1977 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
