<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9085</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-26T17:15:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The composition and benefits of transition milk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">White, Travis</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Transition milk, produced by cows during the first few days after calving, represents a critical nutritional resource for neo足natal calves. Research has demonstrated that transition milk plays a significant role in calf health and development due to its unique composition. This paper explores the composition and benefits of transition milk, with a focus on its role in support足ing calf immunity, growth and overall well-being.
The initial postpartum period in dairy cows is marked by the secretion of transition milk, which is produced after colostrum and before mature milk. Transition milk plays a vital role in bridging the gap between the highly concentrated nutrients of colostrum and the more stable composition of mature milk. Recent research has provided deeper insights into the composi足tion and health benefits of transition milk, highlighting its im足portance in early calf nutrition.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9085</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20249085</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 58 (2024): 2024 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 57</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9085/8752</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
