<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4664</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-26T19:02:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of Castration Technique, Pain Management, and Castration Timing in Young Feedlot Bulls in Alberta</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wildman, B. K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pollock, C. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schunicht, O. C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Booker, C. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Guichon, P. T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jim, G. K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pittman, T. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perrett, T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Morley, P. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jones, C. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lee, S. R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">commercial feedlot</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">castration technique</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">band castration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">surgical castration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pain management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">castration timing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cost-effectiveness</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A randomized commercial feedlot study was conducted to evaluate the effect of castration technique (band castration (BC) versus surgical castration (SC)), pain management (anesthesia/analgesia (AA) versus no anesthesia/analgesia (NA)), and castration timing (allocation (DO) versus 70 days post-allocation (D70)) on animal health, feedlot performance, and carcass characteristic variables of young bulls. There were 960 bulls and 48 pens used in a complete block design, with no commingling of animals from different experimental groups in the same pens.
In the preliminary feedlot performance data summary from allocation to D159, ADG ( +0.051 lb./day, P=0.188) and DM:G (-0.117, P=0.060) were improved in pens castrated at DO versus pens castrated at D70; ADG ( +0.076 lb./day, P=0.049) and DM:G (-0.069, P=0.264) were improved in pens castrated using BQ versus pens castrated using SC; and ADG ( +0.025 lb/day, P=0.511) and DM:G (-0.079, P=0.204) were improved in pens castrated with NA versus those castrated with AA. There were no significant interactions detected between castration timing, castration technique, and pain management strategies. There were minimal differences in mortality from DO to D159 between the pens in each of the castration options (DO versus D70; BC versus SC; or AA versus NA).
The preliminary data from DO to D159 are interesting; however, final data from allocation through slaughter are necessary to complete the overall assessment of each castration option. Understanding the relative cost-effectiveness of each castration option will help bridge the gap that currently exists in determining optimal castration management in commercial feedlot settings.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2006-09-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4664</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20064664</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2006; 47-49</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4664/4564</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2006 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
