<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4752</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-15T08:42:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Outcomes of Synchronization and Timed Insemination Coupled with Retained Ownership in a Commercial Beef Cattle Operation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Whittier, W. Dee</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">estrous synchronization program</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">timed insemination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pregnancy rate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">parturition outcome</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">retained ownership beef cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">GnRH-based estrous synchronization programs have allowed for outstanding success in getting cows pregnant with timed insemination (TAI). This technology allows pregnancy rates approximating those of natural service to a single insemination. The system minimizes the requirement for estrus detection with its attendant error rates and high demand for labor. The overall method allows producers to select semen from superior sires with known progeny performance to meet the outcomes that are most economical for their operations. These outcomes include traits that provide for desirable parturition outcomes, high rates of growth and feed efficiency, and the production of carcasses that are sold for a premium because they receive desirable quality and yield grades.
Retained ownership beef cattle production schemes are different from traditional beef cattle management approaches wherein calves change ownership from the cow/calf operation to the growing phase and finally to the finishing or feedlot phase. Retained ownership through the feedlot and then marketing finished cattle through a value-based program allows the cow/calf producer to be compensated for the actual value of the beef produced. Because most calf marketing schemes tend to value cattle based on industry averages, there is the potential to augment income through retained ownership if cattle have characteristics that result in performance and end-product that is superior to industry average.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2006-09-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4752</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20064752</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2006; 264-265</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4752/4649</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2006 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
