<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5533</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-07-21T20:53:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RDDS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Diagnosis of Abortion in Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McEntee, Kenneth</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A recent evaluation of diagnostic laboratory data concerning bovine abortion in five northeastern states was reported by Hubbert, et al., for an 11-year period, 1960-1970 (2). In a series of 3812 bovine aborted fetuses, an infectious cause of abortion was diagnosed in 889 (23.3%) of the cases. The majority of diagnostic laboratories throughout the world do not establish diagnosis on more than 25% of aborted specimens. A higher percentage of diagnoses can be established by concentrated efforts in obtaining more adequate aborted specimens and by conducting more detailed microbiological and pathological examinations. Ideally, the entire fetus should be submitted to a diagnostic laboratory as rapidly as possible so as to minimize decomposition and contamination. The placenta should be submitted because .in many of the infectious cases of abortions inflammatory placental lesions will be evident and the organism may be isolated. In some cases, the infectious agent can be isolated from the placenta and not from the fetus. In cases of retention of the placenta, a portion may be removed manually. Paired blood samples taken two to three weeks apart may be of value but are of less value than fresh aborted specimens. The practicing veterinarian should be supplied with forms for recording the history of the herd and the breeding record of the individual cow in question (Appendix). Since considerable effort and expense is devoted to the laboratory examination of specimens, we believe that the owner and the local veterinarian should cooperate to the extent of presenting adequate specimens and records. We have established that it costs at least $125 to conduct a detailed examination of an aborted fetus and placenta for various microbiological agents and pathologic lesions. Most laboratories have not been able to devote this amount of funding to all aborted specimens over a prolonged period of time. Therefore, it is necessary to be selective in concentrating diagnostic efforts in herds which have severe abortion problems.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5533</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1972; 54-59</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5533/5386</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1972 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
