<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6564</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-11T00:37:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GaT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Therapeutic Effects of the Moxibustion on Delayed Uterine Involution in Postpartum Dairy Cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Korematsu, Kiyoshi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Takagi, Eisyuu</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kawabe, Takashi</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nakao, Toshihiko</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kawata, Keiichiro</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">delayed uterine involution</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">PGF2a</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">moxibustion</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug residue</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A calving interval of 12 months has been considered to be a goal of reproductive management of dairy cows. Delay of postpartum uterine involution and ovarian resumption of them results in extension of calving intervals and hence, causes major economical loss. It is therefore,very important to carry out reproductive check and to give proper treatment to cows with delayed reproductive recovery. For the treatment delayed uterine involution, some antibiotics have been infused in utero with indistinct effect1,2,3. Recently, administration of PGF2a or it's analog has been provided to to be more effective on the postpartum uterine losses than the antibiotics treatment4,5.Preventive effect of GriRH on cows with endometritis following retained placenta in resumption of ovarian cycle has also been reported6. The acupancuture and the moxibustion therapy has been known to facilitate uterine contraction and ovarian function in cattle7,8,9. These methods have some advantages over the administrations. The treatments have neither side effect or drug residue, and easy to accomplish and economial. This paper reports therapeutic effects of the moxibustion on cows with delayed uterine involution.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6564</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926564</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 3; 49-53</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6564/7149</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
