<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9438</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Haptoglobin, milk yield, reproduction and herd removal: Evaluating the impact of calcium supplementation in early lactation dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Poggi, Julia</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Seminara, Jackson</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bach, Kathryn</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McArt, Jessica</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Elevated inflammatory biomarkers early postpartum have been associated with negative downstream events, but treat­ments to reduce the impact of excessive inflammation remain lacking. Oral calcium supplementation is commonly used to improve lactational outcomes despite inconsistent research supporting its application. We evaluated whether oral calcium supplementation to multiparous dairy cows at 2 and 3 d in milk (DIM) would differentially impact outcomes of cows of varying inflammatory statuses at 2 DIM, assessed using serum hapto­globin concentrations. We hypothesized that cows with elevat­ed haptoglobin would have increased average daily milk yield through 15 wk of lactation, reduced time to pregnancy, and increased time to herd removal after calcium supplementation compared to less inflamed cows.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9438</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259438</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 249</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9438/9045</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
