<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9077</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-26T17:15:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Novel immunological approaches to improve cattle health</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Woolums, Amelia</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">inflammation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunosuppression</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">specific pro-resolving mediators</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">For years veterinarians have understood that stressful experi­ences increase disease in lightweight, recently transported and commingled cattle. Increased incidence of bovine respiratory disease (BRD) in high-risk cattle has traditionally been attrib­uted to endogenous cortisol, but in fact, increased cortisol is often not measured in cattle presumed to be stressed. While high-risk cattle are often seronegative to common respiratory viruses at receiving, field trials have confirmed they can mount significant humoral response to vaccination at arrival, indicat­ing they are not too immunosuppressed to produce antibodies. However, at-arrival vaccination of high-risk cattle is not reli­ably associated with improved health over the subsequent 60-90 days. Research indicates that stress actually increases the mag­nitude of inflammatory responses to infection or other stimuli. Taken together, these findings indicate that high BRD incidence in some high-risk cattle may be more attributable to excessive or prolonged inflammation than to immunosuppression. Re­cent studies demonstrated that high-risk cattle that nonetheless stay healthy have increased expression of genes related to pro­duction of specific pro-resolving mediators (SPM), which bring inflammatory responses to a close. Research is ongoing to de­termine whether SPM can be induced by certain management practices, genetic selection, or therapeutic or prophylactic in­terventions, to improve cattle health.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9077</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20249077</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 58 (2024): 2024 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 33-36</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9077/8747</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
