<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6435</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-07T00:35:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RD</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Efficacite D'Une Nouvelle Cephalosporine (Ceftiofur) Associee Ou Non A Un Antiinflammatoire Steroidien (Succinate De Methyl Prednisolone) Dans Un Modele Experimental De Pasteurellose Respiratoire Du Veau A Pasteurella Haemolytica Bio-Serogroupe Al</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Espinasse, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bost, F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Madelenat, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schelcher, F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Valarcher, J. -F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotic</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">steroidal anti-inflammatory treatment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Pha1 isolate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Ceftiofur</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mean disease score</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">After randomization, 18 calves were inoculated with a Pha1 isolate as described in an earlier protocol. After the first inoculation 6 calves received Ceftiofur (CEF), 1 mg/kg by intramuscular route (IM) every day for 5 days together with methyl-prednisolone-succinate (MPS) 3 mg/kg IM on two consecutive days, 6 calves received CEF + an MPS placebo, and 6 calves a CEF placebo+ an MPS placebo. Twice a day before the meal all calves were clinically examined to determine a mean disease score (MOS). After their death or sacrifice, 7 days at most after the first inoculation, all calves were autopsied. The lungs were weighed, the extent of the lesions quantified by a score (mean lung score= MLS) based on combined inspection and palpation and a quantitative bacteriological examination carried out on the damaged lung parenchyma. The validity of the model was confirmed by the percentage mortality observed in the control group (83 % versus 17 % in the other groups). A similar trend was apparent in the clinical results (significant difference p ≤ 0,05 between the mean MOS of the control group and that of the other group) in the necropsy results (significant difference p ≤ 0,05 between the control group and the other groups for mean lung weight and MLS)) and in the microbiological results (significant difference p ≤ 0,05 between the mean number of cfu Pha1/g of lung in the control group and other groups). This demonstrate the efficacy of both therapeutic regimens (i.e. CEF and CEF + MPS) in our model. The advantage of the antibiotic + steroidal anti-inflammatory treatment is not clear.
Full article in French, English and German summary in PDF.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6435</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926435</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 1; 159-164</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6435/7016</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
