<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3747</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:41:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Co-administration of meloxicam and gabapentin does not compromise beef bull semen quality</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cain, A. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Comstock, J. F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">King, E. H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hopper, R. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">limb soundness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lameness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">NSAID</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">GABA analogue</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Meloxicam</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">gabapentin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmokinetic</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fertility</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">semen quality</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Feet and leg soundness are of critical importance for breeding bulls, and lameness is a common problem affecting bulls. Lameness pain in the bovine typically has both inflammatory and neuropathic components, and often coincides with a decline in fertility. As neuropathic pain is refractory to non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), y-aminobutyric acid (GABA) analogues are commonly used in conjunction with NSAIDs to treat lameness in cattle. Meloxicam, an NSAID, and gabapentin, a GABA analogue, are frequently used extra-label under the supervision of a veterinarian to mitigate pain associated with lameness. Though neither of these compounds is currently labeled for use in bovines in the United States, previous research has indicated that the pharmokinetic profiles of these drugs support further evaluation for clinical use as analgesics in bovines. A decline in fertility is often observed in lame bulls; however, the pathogenesis of this transient subfertility is unknown. Currently, no controlled studies have been conducted to evaluate the effects of meloxicam and gabapentin analgesics on bull fertility. Thus, the objective of the present study was to evaluate the effects of meloxicam and gabapentin combination therapy on beef bull semen quality. It was hypothesized that treatment with meloxicam and gabapentin might have deleterious effects on semen quality.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3747</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20143747</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2014; 163-164</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3747/3686</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2014 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
