<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5011</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-18T07:12:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Microbiological Water Quality for Optimal Livestock Production and Health: An absence of data?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">LeJeune, Jeffrey</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gay, John M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">environment</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">microbiological quality</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">microbial ecology</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Microbial contamination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle water</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Relative to standards for humans, water in the cattle environment is often of poor or unknown microbiological quality, whether it is surface drinking water, recycled flush water, wash water, cooling water or drinking water in troughs. The microbial ecology is complex and not well understood. Microbial contamination originates from the environment, the feces of cattle or other animals, and, due to oral residues, even the normal act of drinking. In many circumstances, the quality is regarded as uncontrollable at best. Although pathogenic bacteria and zoonotic foodborne pathogens are found in cattle water with some frequency, the health, production and food safety risks associated with cattle drinking or contacting water contaminated with these microorganisms remains largely undefined. As production and health consequences from the presence of these agents are certainly biologically plausible and some evidence suggests that they do exist, additional research is needed to quantify these risks. If these risks prove to be unacceptable under current management conditions and consumer expectations, methods to ensure microbiologically cleaner water for livestock will need to be identified.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2002-09-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5011</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20025011</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2002; 77-82</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5011/4899</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2002 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
