<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9484</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-10T17:14:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Dairy reproduction and protocol development</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nguyen, Blake</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The importance of reproductive efficiency in dairy herds can­not be overstated, and the veterinarian’s role in designing, di­recting and executing reproductive management programs is central to success. We have the knowledge and skills to bring evidence-based insights into this aspect of cattle manage­ment, we should be diligent in maintaining focus on appro­priate goals, and be cautious about leading dairy operations toward sustainable progress in management areas that need it. Through genetics and management, dairy cow fertility has improved dramatically in the last 20 years, and better repro is always better. However, the economic returns to a dairy opera­tion on improving reproductive efficiency get smaller at higher 21-day-pregnancy rates. My perspective is to caution the re­cent graduate to look for areas of management that are truly constraining animal and economic performance, and to apply sufficiently upstream solutions using a wholistic approach to reproduction.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9484</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20269484</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 1 (2026): 2026 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 57-58</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9484/9086</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
