<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9184</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-26T17:14:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluating the impact of mid-lactation hoof trimming on first lactation dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shepley, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Caixeta, L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bautista, D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cramer, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Routine hoof trimming around dry-off is a common preventa­tive practice for lameness on commercial dairy farms. Incor­porating a second routine hoof trimming around mid-lactation has been shown to reduce lameness. However, the addition of a second routine hoof trimming represents an additional cost to the farmer and, as a result, must benefit the farm economically and the cow from a welfare standpoint. Conflicting evidence with regard to hoof trimming frequency and timing brings into question whether all cows benefit from a hoof trimming at mid-lactation or if certain populations can be omitted from mid-lactation trims to allow for the prioritization of those cows that will most benefit from its use. The objective of this study was to determine the effects of providing a mid-lactation hoof trimming to first lactation dairy cows at 114-120 DIM on lesions occurrence at the subsequent trimming and time to next lesion occurrence.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9184</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20249184</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 58 (2024): 2024 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 231</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9184/8840</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
