<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5444</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-26T07:19:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Making AMDUCA Work in Your Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rhoda, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Animal Medicinal Drug Use Clarification Act</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">AMDUCA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">extra-label use</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">adult dairy cow</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">drug residues</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animals</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Animal Medicinal Drug Use Clarification Act (AMDUCA), which established conditions for legal extra-label use of approved drugs by licensed veterinarians, took effect December 9, 1996.
The act recognized that veterinarians need to use drugs in an extra-label fashion to alleviate pain and suffering. It contains sufficient safeguards to protect public health and food safety.
In December 1997 the Wisconsin Veterinary Medical Association (WVMA) executive board established a task force of 6 dairy practitioners, a University of Wisconsin veterinary clinician and pharmacist, 2 veterinary office practice managers, the WVMA office staff and the American Veterinary Medical Association (AVMA) staff person responsible for AMDUCA. The task force studied the act and gathered available information that would be needed by practitioners to comply.
The focus of the task force was the adult dairy cow. While AMDUCA affects all species, concentrating on 1 species was more manageable. Dairy was chosen because of public health concerns about milk and dairy beef residues.
Goals of the task force were:• gather available scientific information in 1 stand-alone report• organize withdrawal times on drug applications• develop prototypes of record systems• distribute the AMDUCA report to all dairy practitioners.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1999-09-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5444</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19995444</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1999; 17-19</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5444/5306</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1999 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
