<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9339</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Mastitis management using on-farm and inclinic mastitis pathogen detection systems: An online approach</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zurakowski, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mangement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pathogen detection</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Improving management practices at the cow level is essential to the future success of the dairy industry. With increasing social pressure to reduce antimicrobial use in dairy animals, pathogen-based management of clinical mastitis (CM) will lead to judicious treatment practices. Detecting the presence of pathogens responsible for CM cases and using this information to manage the case, reduces antimicrobial use, saves money and addresses consumer concerns while not compromising animal health. Previous studies show that pathogen-based management of CM will reduce antimicrobial use by 30-65% and increase cash flow ~$25/cow/year. Most dairy animals have limited access to mastitis diagnostics due to a farm’s inaccessi­bility to a milk testing laboratory or veterinary clinic proficient in milk culture techniques. For example, despite four strategi­cally located laboratories across the state, Quality Milk Produc­tion Services (QMPS) is able to provide timely, routine culture service to only 20-25% (100-150,000 cows) of the 630,000 dairy cows in New York due to logistical and geographical difficulties of moving milk from the farm to a testing facility. A variety of commercially available on-farm mastitis pathogen identifica­tion systems have evolved to promote pathogen-based mastitis treatment opportunities to farms lacking easy access to milk testing laboratories. But for farms to be successful implement­ing these techniques, a learning culture, on-farm training op­portunities and support is necessary.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9339</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259339</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 70-72</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9339/8955</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
