<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7400</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:41:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Use of Prostaglandin in Herd Health Programs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harris, Robert J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">prostaglandin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">herd health</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproduction</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Over a two-year period, we were able to maintain records on 450 cows which were given prostaglandin. SEE CHART. Our first objective was to reduce the number of days to the next heat by five or more. We did breed slightly over 63% of the cows by the 5th day and 72% by the 8th day. The conception was better than we had hoped for. We would have been satisfied with 3% below the normal firstservice conception rate for this herd. Instead, we were 3% above the normal rate. We had a 49% conception rate on first-service following use of prostaglandin as compared to 46% herd average on first-service. The use of prostaglandin in this now 1600-cow herd has been proven to be cost-effective, and gave very satisfactory results in this field study. Selection of recipients for prostaglandin injection is determined by rectal palpation by the veterinarian during herd checks, and is now a routine part of the herd health and reproduction program.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1983-11-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7400</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19837400</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1983; 185-187</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7400/7266</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1983 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
