<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7673</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:16:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:KA</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Beef Business in the 1980's</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Monfort, Kenny</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef business</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">1980's</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">I should be projecting dramatic changes if I were really going to impress you but I frankly do not see dramatic change ahead. I do not see changes of the magnititudeofthe establishment of the feeding industry or the establishment of quality grades or the establishment of packing plants where cattle are produced instead of where. the railroad ends and where the people live. But I do see some changes. I think that we will see a beef business that is more atoned in the 1980's to the general economy, and more apt to react to the costs ofcompeting meats and foods. I happen to think that our society in the 80's is not going to have the same affluence or growth in affluence as we have become used to. Why? We are going to spend more of our money on energy. We are going to continue to spend more of our money on transportation costs, health care, and unfortunately I think that taxes are going to mop·up more of our income. Primarily, in the 80's I think that taxes will do this because I think that we will wake up and decide that we need to re-establish our defence capabilities in this country. This is going to drain off some of our income and our people are not going to have the same affluence as they had in the 60's and 70's. I think that they will become more price conscious.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1979-11-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7673</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19797673</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1979; 7-11</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7673/7415</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1979 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
