<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5198</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:21:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RSD</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effect of Estradiol Cypionate in Postparturient Dairy Cattle at Increased Risk for Metritis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Overton, Michael W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sischo, William M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reynolds, James P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Metritis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Estradiol Cypionate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">uterine disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fetal membrane</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Metritis is a postparturient uterine disease that adversely affects fertility, milk production, and health of dairy cattle. Although few cows in most herds develop life-threatening septic metritis, many may develop anorexia secondary to metritis-related pyrexia. In an attempt to prevent or reduce the effects ofmetritis, many dairymen have adopted some form of a standardized fresh cow program that often includes administration of 4 mg Estradiol Cypionate (ECP) to postparturient cows with retained fetal membranes. Estradiol has been shown to stimulate uterine contractions, increase phagocytosis of bacteria, increase uterine blood flow, and enhance uterine immune function. However, data is not available to support the use of ECP for prevention of metritis. Recent work by Wagner, et al showed no benefit to the routine use of ECP in randomly assigned postparturient dairy cattle. However, this study contained relatively few cows with known risk factors for metritis. A study was conducted to determine whether the administration of 4 mg of ECP to cows at higher risk for metritis is efficacious in preventing or decreasing severity of metritis in the first 10 days postpartum.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2001-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5198</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20015198</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2001; 130</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5198/5069</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2001 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
