<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6541</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-07T00:31:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Fedlot</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Making Rational Product Choices</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Robert A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">product choices</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anthelmintics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccines</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management tools</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Feedyard managers and feedyard veterinarians are faced with a wide array of health care products today. Most are detailed as the "product of choice" to prevent or treat diseases. Due to the large volume and the complexity of health care products used in a feedyard, the veterinarian must serve as an advisor to management to assess the value using various products.
Cost of health care products is always a consideration. However, cost must be evaluated in respect to risk of disease, cost of the disease and the impact of disease on production. Efficacy of the product in question must also be carefully evaluated.
It is important to remember that vaccines, bacterins, antibiotics and anthelmintics are only management tools. Commercial products will not eliminate or cure diseases by themselves, but instead must be critically implemented into a comprehensive, planned management program.
In this paper, considerations for making rational product choices will be discussed. The selection considerations for anthelmintics, antibiotics and vaccines will be emphasized.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6541</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926541</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 2; 315-319</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6541/7112</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
