<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8845</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-10T20:58:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Calf Care &amp; Quality Assurance program – best management guidelines for the calf raising sector</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Herman, Julia</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Calf Care &amp; Quality Assurance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">CCQA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf raiser</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf ranch</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Beef Quality Assurance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BQA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">National Dairy FARM</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">producer education</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The cattle raising sector has played an important role for devel­oping male or female calves with dairy genetics destined for the dairy breeding herd or the beef production system. Quality as­surance programs have become commonplace for food produc­ing enterprises to build consumer confidence that food is ethi­cally and responsibly produced. Calf raisers are a critical piece to this. Healthy calves are the cornerstone of every beef, dairy and veal facility. As no single organization or program covers all calves to ensure optimal health and welfare throughout the supply chain, the Calf Care and Quality Assurance program (CCQA; funded by the Beef Checkoff) was created through the collaboration of 4 industry groups. The National Dairy Farm­ers Assuring Responsible Management (FARM), Beef Checkoff-funded Beef Quality Assurance (BQA), Veal Quality Assurance (VQA), and the Dairy Calf and Heifer Association (DCHA) are na­tional recognized programs that collaborated to create the CCQA program. Included in the program are science-based guidance for calf raisers covering employee training, continuing educa­tion, emergency preparedness, calf health, animal handling and stockmanship, and management and care. Producers and veterinarians are encouraged to review the tools and resources, get certified in CCQA, and ensure they are following best man­agement practices for calves in their care. It is important that the education that producers, veterinarians and transporters receive is current and up to date, and adapts to this changing industry.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8845</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20238845</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 56 (2023): 2023 Annual Conference Proceedings ; 44-45</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
