<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3741</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:41:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS4</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparison of two competitive enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays for Anaplasma marginale in cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Whitlock, B. K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Daniel, J. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, J. K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stensland, W. R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chung, C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Coetzee, J. F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bovine anaplasmosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tick</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">complement fixation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">CF</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">card agglutination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">competitive enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cELISA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">maltose binding protein</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine anaplasmosis, caused by Anaplasma marginale, is the most prevalent tick-transmitted disease of cattle worldwide and a major obstacle to profitable production in the U.S. Several serological assays such as complement fixation (CF), card agglutination, and competitive enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (cELISA) have been used in the detection of anaplasmosis carriers. The CF and card agglutination tests are not considered reliable due to low diagnostic sensitivities (&amp;lt;2 0% and 67%, respectively). Commercially available major surface protein-5 (MSP-5) epitope-based cELISA is more reliable with high sensitivity (99%) and specificity (89%). Recently, maltose binding protein included as fusion protein in the recombinant MSP-5 used in the commercially available cELISA was identified as the source of some false-positive results. A new cELISA test was developed to improve diagnostic specificity by reducing false positive reactions due to maltose binding protein antibodies and other non-specific antibodies in bovine sera. The objective of this study was to compare results generated using the current and new cELISA tests and real-time RT-PCR to provide veterinarians with up to date information regarding the most appropriate test to use for anaplasmosis diagnosis.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3741</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20143741</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2014; 158</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3741/3680</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2014 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
