<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4555</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-15T08:41:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:VetTech</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Understanding Bovine Behavior for Safe Handling</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wagner, Sarah</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">body language</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal behavior</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">behavioral principles</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">agitation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bulls</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Understanding behavioral principles in cattle makes working with them safer and more enjoyable. Reading a cow's body language helps indicate how much stress the cow is feeling, and can give clues as to her general health. One should be very careful around cows in a high level of stress as they may become aggressive. Cattle tend to be more agitated around strangers or people with whom they associate being stressed. Using the basic principles of flight zone and point of balance will facilitate moving groups of cattle quickly and calmly. Cows with new calves may become aggressive when protecting their calves. If a cow shows signs of agitation such as vocalization, pacing, pawing, or head-shaking, entering her flight zone may cause her to attack. Agitated or defensive cows can be dangerous and should be avoided. Sick dairy cows may develop ketosis, which can affect their temperament, making a previously docile animal behave in an agitated or even aggressive way. Bulls must always be handled carefully, particularly dairy breed bulls. A bull that shows a broadside threat to humans should be culled at once. Even if a bull calf is reared properly with other cattle, an adult bull is usually safer if he spends most of his adult life penned with other animals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-09-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20074555</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2007; 207-208</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4555/4460</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
