<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8982</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-14T23:58:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The revolution and future frontiers of reproductive management of dairy cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lauber, Megan</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">synchronized ovulation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pregnancies per AI</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The 21-d pregnancy rate is determined by an interaction be­tween the AI service rate and pregnancies per AI (P/AI) and is a key performance indicator for the reproductive efficiency of dairy farms. Over the past 2 decades, the reproductive per­formance of lactating dairy cows increased. A greater under­standing of endocrinology and the physiology of lactating dairy cows generated fertility programs (the Presynch-Ovsynch and Double Ovsynch protocols for TAI) that increase the service rate and P/AI compared with detection of estrus. Previously, synchronization of ovulation in heifers was associated with poor reproductive performance compared with detection of estrus. Several modifications determined through randomized-controlled studies gave rise to the 5-d CIDR-Synch protocol that has similar and more P/AI when heifers are inseminated with conventional and sexed semen, respectively, compared with detection of estrus. A hierarchy of reproductive needs exists for dairy farms that require fulfillment before a new need can emerge. Dairy farms must have a high 21-d pregnancy rate and good heifer management before adopting other advanced re­productive technologies such as genomic selection, sexed and beef semen, and in vitro-produced embryos. Adopting these ad­vanced reproductive technologies benefits dairy farms, howev­er, challenges still exist that need further investigation through randomized-controlled experiments to maximize the benefits</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8982</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20248982</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 57 (2024): 2024 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 52-70</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8982/8687</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
