<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3605</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:38:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Health benefits of Il-10 egg yolk antibodies administered to milk-fed dairy calves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Raabis, S. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McGuirk, S. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rieman, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cook, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sand, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cryptosporidium parvum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">C. parvum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">egg yolk antibodies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Il-10</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anti-inflammatory cytokine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">interleukin-10</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Cryptosporidium parvum infection in calves causes villous atrophy, resulting in reduced surface area and absorptive capacity of the small intestine. Prevention and treatment of C. parvum infections are hindered by a lack of approved, efficacious products and inadequate colostral immunity. An integral component of infection is the dampening of the cell-mediated response by inducing anti-inflammatory cytokines. In calves, ileal intraepithelial lymphocytes express interleukin-10 (Il-10) when infected with C. parvum. Interleukin-10 decreases production of interferon-gamma, which is a vital Thl-associated cytokine. Studies have shown that Il-10 knockout mice are resistant to C. parvum infection. Oral administration of chicken egg yolk antibodies as a means of controlling enteric disease in calves is of interest to the dairy industry. Egg yolk Il-10 antibodies have been shown to survive gastrointestinal transit, are accessible in the intestinal lumen, and remain locally active, without persistence of systemic residues. Therefore, the objective of this trial was to investigate the effect of feeding Il-10 antibodies on calf health and performance after natural C. parvum infection in pre-weaned Holstein dairy calves.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2015-09-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3605</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20153605</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2015; 229</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3605/3550</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2015 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
