<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4939</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:15:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RSD1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effect of a Monensin Controlled-Release Capsule Inserted At Dry-Off On Energy Status In Transition Holstein Cows Fed Typical Florida Diets</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Melendez, P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Goff, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Risco, C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Archbald, L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Littell, R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Donovan, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">transition  cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hypocalcemia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">non-esterified fatty acids</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calving-related disorders</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Monensin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">energy status</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The transition period in dairy cows (three weeks before and after calving) is characterized by tremendous physiological and metabolic changes. During this period, cows experience some degree of hypocalcemia, increased levels of non-esterified fatty acids (NEFA) and Bhydroxybutyrate (BHB), and decreased levels of glucose. Consequently, if prevention is not employed, cows will be at a higher risk of developing calving-related disorders (CRD).
Monensin is an ionophore that affects rumen fermentation, resulting in increased proprionic acid production and a concurrent decrease in the molar proportion of acetate and butyrate. Consequently, monensin as a controlled-release capsule has been used to prevent ketosis and other disorders in dairy cattle.
The hypothesis of the present study was that transition dairy cows supplemented with monensin and fed typical Florida diets would positively improve energy status. Therefore, the objective of this study was to determine the effect of a monensin controlled-release capsule inserted at dry-off on concentrations of NEFA, BHB and glucose during the transition period of Florida dairy cows.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2004-09-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4939</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20044939</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2004; 184-185</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4939/4829</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2004 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
