<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8148</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-05-27T18:37:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FBM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Proceedings of the Fifty-Third Annual Conference (2020). Awards and Scholarships</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bovine Practitioners, American Association of</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Annual Conference</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">awards</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">scholarship</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">It was not your normal AABP Awards Luncheon! There was a little subterfuge involved Saturday for the award winners to keep them on Zoom so they could be surprised by an AABP award. Dr. Fred Gingrich manned the computer with all of the presenters and award winners live. It was fun to see the surprise in their faces and the emotions in their voices accepting the awards.
Awards given at the 2020 53rd AABP Annual Conference include:
2020 AABP Foundation Competitive Research Grant Awards, 2020 AABP Research Summaries Graduate Student Awards, 2020 Student Case Presentation Competition Winners, 2020 AABP–Boehringer Ingelheim Bovine Practitioner of the Year, AABP—Boehringer-Ingelheim Awards for Excellence in Preventive Veterinary Medicine, AABP—Zoetis Distinguished Service Award, AABP Award of Excellence, AABP-Merck Animal Health Mentor of the Year Award, AABP James A. Jarrett Award for Young Leaders
In 2020, the AABP Foundation received 196 scholarship applications and awarded 37 scholarships, totaling $193,500:
2020 AABP Foundation-Zoetis Scholarship, 2020 Amstutz Scholarship, 2020 AABP Foundation - Merck Animal Health Bovine Veterinary Student Recognition Awards, 2020 Dr. Francis Welcome Future Dairy Practitioner Scholarship, National Cattlemen’s Foundation Veterinary Student Scholarship, </dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-09-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Front matter</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8148</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2020; 401-403,412-417</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8148/8091</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
