<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4303</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:54:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparison of Three Tetracycline Antibiotic Treatment Regimens for Carrier Clearance of Persistent Anaplasma marginale Infection Derived under Field Conditions</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Reinbold, J. B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Coetzee, J. F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ganta, R. R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Anaplasmosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tick-transmitted disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">rickettsemias</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antimicrobial regimens</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnostic assay</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">treatment strategy</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Anaplasmosis, caused by the intracellular red blood cell parasite Anaplasma marginale, is the most prevalent tick-transmitted disease of cattle worldwide. Cattle recovering from acute anaplasmosis, including those treated with tetracycline antibiotics, develop lifelong cyclic rickettsemias. Carrier cattle serve as a reservoir of A. marginale for the infection of naïve cattle through horizontal, vertical, and iatrogenic transmission. Validated antimicrobial regimens do not exist for eliminating persistent infection; furthermore, anaplasmosis disease control is confounded by the absence of effective vaccines. A diagnostic testing strategy for identification of A. marginale infection and determination of chemotherapeutic success is urgently needed. A novel, real time RTPCR diagnostic assay and oral chlortetracycline (CTC) chemosterilization strategy were developed at Kansas State University under experimental conditions through concurrent RT-PCR results and plasma CTC pharmacokinetic determination. Validation of this diagnostic and treatment strategy utilizing cattle naturally-infected is essential for assembling science-based recommendations for anaplasmosis control, treatment, and eradication.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2009-09-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4303</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20094303</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2009; 176</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4303/4217</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2009 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
