<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3347</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:33:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Design of management and preventive strategies for neonatal calf diarrhea in beef systems: How do I get to implementation</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Grotelueschen, Dale M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">neonatal diarrhea</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Sandhills Calving Ssytem</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Neonatal calf diarrhea outbreaks in beef herds are a common clinical entity that involves a complex association of factors. Calf treatments, diagnostic investigations, and prevention are frequent outcomes of involvement of veterinary practitioners. Preventive interventions to address immediate and future outbreaks are often management related and more difficult to implement. Evidence-based recommendations can be accomplished by addressing research derived risk factors that are known to impact likelihood for outbreaks. The Sandhills Calving System is 1 intervention option. Implementation of preventive strategies requires knowledge that includes, but is not limited to, client priorities, decision making, and risk tolerance. Client communication and understanding are keys to implementation. Thorough understanding of the system, including potential impacts of any interventions, is very important to insure successful implementation of preventive strategies.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-02-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3347</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20183347</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2018 Recent Graduate Proceedings; 68-70</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3347/3305</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
