<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9492</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-10T17:14:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:MX</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Small ruminant neonatal care</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Weaver, Leslie F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cesarean</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">colostrum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">passive transfer</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hypoglycemia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hyperlactatemia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tendon laxity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Neonatal care begins with safe and effective delivery of kids and lambs during parturition. This may require assistance or even a Cesarean section. When performing Cesarean surgeries clinicians must consider effects of certain drugs and anesthet­ics on the neonate. After delivery, most neonates will require some degree of resuscitation. An initial neonatal exam can help identify potential congenital issues early. Some congenital is­sues may be fixable if seen early enough while others may war­rant humane euthanasia. Colostrum should be consumed by the neonate as soon as possible after birth to provide optimal protection of kids and lambs to perinatal disease pressures. Colostrum quality can be easily assessed using a Brix refrac­tometer. Colostrum may need to be administered by bottle or orogastric intubation. If colostrum replacer is necessary, a commercially available bovine lacteal origin product should be considered. Passive transfer status in the lamb or kid can be assessed using serum total protein or a Brix refractometer. Common metabolic derangements encountered in the perinatal period are hypoglycemia and hyperlactatemia. Tendon laxity and contracted tendons are also commonly encountered con­ditions in small ruminants. Lastly, vaccination with neonates may sometimes be warranted for optimal outcomes in growing kids and lambs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9492</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20269492</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 1 (2026): 2026 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 88-90</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9492/9093</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
