<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6812</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-07-21T18:32:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FS3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Animal Welfare, Animal Rights, Agriculture, and Veterinary Medicine: Changing Social Ethics and the Food Animal Practitioner</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rollin, Bernard E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal rights</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">social thought</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Many of you have been exposed to the idea of a clear dichotomy between animal welfare and animal rights, with animal rights being the perspective of radicals; extremists, and vegetarians alone, and animal welfare being the acceptable moderate and mainstream position. I want to suggest to you that this is greatly oversimplified, and that, while many extremists do identify themseleved with animal rights, a version of animal rights philosophy, which I will outline today, is becoming the mainstream approach to social thought about animals. According to a recent Parents Magazine survey, for example, over 80% of the public believes that animals have rights. Congress gets more letters on animal welfare/rights issues than any other issue. Thus you need to understand and assess for yourselves the thinking implicit in this new idea, not simply dismiss it out of hand.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1990-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6812</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19906812</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1990; 140-145</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6812/6392</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1990 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
