<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9343</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Maternal interference and the calf – when it comes to vaccination, what makes sense and what doesn’t</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chase, Chris</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">immunity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Good calf immunity results from proper maternal care dur­ing gestation, adequate colostral intake and careful neonatal management. Although calves are born with all the essential immune components, their function is suppressed by mater­nal and placental hormones, as well as cortisol surges during birth. Innate immunity is compromised, with reduced comple­ment and interferon production and weak phagocytic ability of neutrophils and macrophages, which improve gradually over the first months of life. Adaptive immunity is more restricted: calves are born without antibodies and depend entirely on co­lostrum for immunoglobulins. B-cell numbers are initially low, delaying antibody production until 3 weeks of age, while T-cell activity is less affected. Maternal antibodies provide early pro­tection, but interfere with vaccine responses, creating a win­dow of susceptibility when antibody levels are insufficient for protection yet high enough to block vaccine efficacy. The timing of vaccination is therefore critical and pathogen-specific. In­tranasal vaccines can bypass maternal interference by priming mucosal immunity, while adjuvanted vaccines, depending on the adjuvant, can be efficacious in the face of maternal anti­body. Management factors – including nutrition, stress reduc­tion, pathogen exposure and biosecurity – further influence immune competence. Effective calf vaccination programs must be tailored to farm-specific risks, maternal antibody decay, and calf development to achieve long-term protection.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9343</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259343</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 80-86</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9343/8958</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
