<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3421</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:37:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Economics of dry lotting beef cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Rasby, R. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Warner, J. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gardine, S. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jenkins, K. H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Klopfenstein, T. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dry-lotting</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">production</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">economics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Three experiments evaluated cow and calf performance in alternative production systems; 1) early weaning on feed use; 2) a sensitivity analysis investigating profit potential of confinement cow management to changes in production prices and weaning rates, and; 3) investigate a winter management system incorporating winter cornstalk residue grazing on cow and calf performance in a summer-calving herd. In experiment 1, cows were limit fed and used two weaning time, early (EW; 91 days old) or conventionally-weaned (CW; 203 days old). Nursing pairs were fed an equivalent amount of DM that the early weaned calf plus the dams were fed. Cows limit-fed in confinement resulted in no negative impact on reproduction and early-weaning did not reduce feed energy requirements. In experiment 2, production parameters were obtained from the summer-calving cowherd in a dry lot year-round. Greater returns were projected as weaning percentage increased and a positive return for systems using distillers grains and crop residues. For experiment 3, two wintering systems on cow-calf performance in a summer-calving cowherd were evaluated. Grazing cow-calf pairs on cornstalks had lower ending weights of cows and gains of calves. Incorporating winter cornstalk grazing into the system were $137 more profitable compared to cows wintered in the drylot.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2016-09-15</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3421</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20163421</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2016; 42-54</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3421/3375</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2016 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
