<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6274</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-15T00:35:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">HPLC Comparison of Tear Film Protein Pattern in Normal and Infectious Bovine Keratoconjunctivitis Affected Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Gerds, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Davidson, H. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stokka, G. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Brightman, A. H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Iandolo, J. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tear protein pattern</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">IBK</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Infectious Bovine Keratoconjunctivitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bacterial culture</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Purpose: This project was undertaken to establish the tear protein pattern in normal cattle and changes in the pattern at different stages of IBK, and disease of great economic importance.
Methods: Non-stimulated tears were atraumatically collected with a 50μ1 capillary tube. The study included normal and infected animals in three stages of naturally occurring IBK. Analysis was performed with a TSK 3000 SWXL size exclusion HPLC column at a flow rate of 0.3ml/min with 0.5M NaCl, 0.1M NaH3PO4, pH 5. Quantitation was completed with computerized integration of peaks.
Results: In all animals 7 major peaks were found at retention times of 17, 19, 21, 27, 29, 33, and 39 minutes. During the active course of the disease, peaks 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, and 7 showed various changes. Separation for different bacterial culture result within the group had statistically significant differences.
Conclusions: The tear protein pattern in IBK affected cattle versus normal shows distinct changes. In addition to the stage of the disease changes are markedly influenced by the type of recovered organism. The first three peaks that changed in size during the course of the disease are likely to contain immunoglobulins.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1994-09-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6274</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19946274</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1994; 181-185</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6274/6757</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1994 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
