<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5210</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:20:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RSD</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Homoeopathic Remedies in the Treatment of Mastitis: Preliminary Results of a Positive Control Study and Review of Alternative Therapies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mueller, K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">organic dairy farms</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Homoeopathy</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There is an increasing demand for organic produce worldwide. In the United Kingdom, the organic food sector shows a growth in retail sale values of approximately 40% per year. Currently, there are about 150 organic dairy farms, with organic milk production predicted to reach 150 million litres in 2003.2 Mastitis affects organically managed cattle to the same degree as conventionally farmed cows, and has been identified as a major concern in organic dairy herds.1 Use of antibiotics for the treatment of sick animals is allowed under organic regulations, but milk and meat withholding periods are extended. In addition, the routine or continued use of antibiotics is prohibited.
Homoeopathy was found to be the main alternative to antibiotics for mastitis treatment in the Hovi and Roderick1 study. However, existing data on the efficacy of alternative therapies is deficient. The current study at Cambridge University aims to establish the efficacy of a commonly used homoeopathic remedy for the treatment of clinical mastitis by comparing it with intramammary antibiotic therapy.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2001-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5210</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20015210</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2001; 141-142</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5210/5080</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2001 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
