<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9444</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Associations of early postpartum inflammation measured at 2 DIM with metrics of lactational success</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Seminara, J.A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McArt, J.A.A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dairy cows experience inflammation during the postpartum period as a normal response to parturition and the start of lactation. Though more severe inflammation has been associ­ated with disease conditions, reduced reproductive success, and decreased production, diagnostic targets, thresholds and timepoints are not known. Characterized by total serum cal­cium concentrations (tCa) ≤ 8.8 mg/dL at 4 DIM, dyscalcemia is a condition also associated with impaired outcomes, and dyscalcemic cows experience elevated inflammation as early as 2 DIM. Therefore, our objective in this exploratory study was to evaluate the relationships between the inflammatory marker haptoglobin measured at 2 DIM and metrics of lactational suc­cess including milk production through 10 weeks in lactation, dyscalcemia incidence, and risk of herd removal within 60 DIM. We hypothesized that increased haptoglobin concentrations at 2 DIM would be associated with more negative outcomes across all assessed metrics..</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9444</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259444</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 256</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9444/9051</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
