<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4972</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-10-16T19:49:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Single Subcutaneous Dose of a Combination Vaccine Containing Bovine Herpes Virus- 1 (BHV-1) Provides Protection Against an Intranasal BHV-1 Challenge 72 Hours Later</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fogarty-Fairbanks, K. K.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Campbell, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chase, C. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">herpesvirus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">respiratory infections</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination programs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">subcutaneous injection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">modified-live virus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bacterial pneumonia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">commingling</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine herpesvirus 1 (BHV-1) is associated with several disease syndromes in cattle. The BHV-1 respiratory infections can result in several clinical manifestations that range from inapparent to severe respiratory disease, infectious bovine rhinotracheitis (IBR). Signs include pyrexia, anorexia, conjunctivitis with lacrimal discharge, dyspnea and nasal discharge. BHV-1 respiratory infection in calves and feedlot cattle can lead to the bovine respiratory disease complex (BRDC), with secondary bacterial infections that cause significant economic losses to the livestock industry.
Vaccination programs are a routine practice in US feedlot operations to protect cattle against BHV-1 associated disease. Unfortunately, many calves are not vaccinated prior to weaning or commingling into backgrounding lots, feedlots or pasture operations. These animals are at increased risk of BHV-1 infection and are predisposed to secondary bacterial pneumonia. The time from vaccination to onset of protection can play an important role in subsequent management of newly arrived cattle against IBR.
An experiment was conducted to determine the onset of protection against an intranasal BHV-1 challenge following a subcutaneous injection of a commercial modified-live virus (MLV) vaccine containing attenuated BHV-1.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2004-09-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4972</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20044972</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2004; 289</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4972/4861</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2004 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
