<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6450</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-07T00:34:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RDI</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pharmacokinetics of Danofloxacin in Pneumonic Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Apley, Michael D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Upson, Dan</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">danofloxacin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cranial-ventral</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">caudal-dorsal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bronchopneumonia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pneumonic lung tissue</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Two-hundred and two head of cross-bred steers and bulls were purchased in southwest Texas and shipped by truck approximately 13 hours to the study site in Manhattan, Kansas. The majority of the calves were freshly weaned and originated from numerous production units. No biologicals or pharmaceuticals were administered prior to or after shipping. Specific clinical criteria were used to select calves with acute respiratory disease.
The first 36 calves to meet clinical criteria were injected intramuscularly with danofloxacin* at a dose of 1.25 mg/kg and then sacrificed at one of 6 post-injection sample times. Two cranial-ventral and two caudal-dorsal tissue samples from each lung, as well as a plasma sample, were analyzed for danofloxacin concentration. The presence of bronchopneumonia was confirmed grossly, microbiologically, and histopathologically.
A computer generated line of best fit indicated the maximum cranial-ventral pneumonic lung tissue concentration of 1.17 μg/g occurred 1.8 hours after injection. Mean elimination halftime for pneumonic lung tissue was 5.2 hours. A trend towards slightly decreased danofloxacin concentrations in the pneumonic cranial-ventral lung samples, as compared to grossly normal caudal-dorsal lung tissue, was considered clinically insignificant.
Spanish and French abstracts on PDF</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6450</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926450</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 1; 237-239</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6450/7030</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
