<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6414</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-07T00:36:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:EaP</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Studies on Efficacy of Copper Glycinate in Clinical Babesiosis in Crossbred Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Randhawa, S. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Randhawa, C. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sawhney, S. M. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bovine babesiosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tick borne illness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">babesicidal compounds</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">copper glycinate</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine babesiosis, a tick borne infectious haemoprotozoan disease of cattle, has been reported to be prevalent in Europe, Africa, South America and Asia including India1,2. The disease is of immense importance in tropical and subtropical countries including India, causing heavy mortality and morbidity in exotic and crossbred animals. A large number of babesicidal compounds have been used effectively for treatment of bovine babesiosis1. Copper glycinate has been extensively used for the effective treatment of post-parturient haemoglobinuria (PPH) as well as for the treatment of certain copier responsive primary or secondary copper deficiency conditions3,4. However, results of preliminary clinical observations revealed its efficacy against bovine babesiosis5.
The haemoglobinuria in bovine babesiosis has been ascribed to increased intravascular destruction of red cells by the parasites with the release of free haemoglobin in urine6. It was reported that the degree of anaemia in clinical babesiosis was out of proportion to the degree of parasitaemia which could indicate that intravascular haemolysis was not only of parasitized red cells but also of some unparasitized red cells5. The present investigation was carried out to confirm the preliminary observations of the efficacy of copper glycinate against clinical bovine babesiosis and to elucidate the role of lipid peroxidation in the genesis of haemolysis in bovine babesiosis by measuring the levels of malondialdehyde in the red blood cells, plasma and urine of affected and healthy cattle. Malondialdehyde, being one of the product, is a sensitive indicator of the lipid peroxidation.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6414</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926414</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 1; 44-49</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6414/6996</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
