<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8925</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-10T20:55:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Using infrared thermography to detect teat tissue changes after machine milking in dairy cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Harper, L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">DiLeo, C.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Porter, I.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Basran, P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wieland, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Mastitis is among the costliest diseases affecting dairy cows, partly due to its permanent reduction of the quantity and qual­ity of milk produced. Most mastitis cases involve pathogenic organisms entering the cow’s mammary gland through the teat canal. The teat canal has natural defenses against these patho­gens that can be disrupted during milk harvesting. Some of these disruptions of the teat tissue morphology, also known as short-term changes (STCs), can be diagnosed through visual in­spection and palpation. Infrared thermography (IRT) has previ­ously been shown to produce precise and consistent measure­ments of skin temperatures on cows’ hind teats. Our primary objective was to determine if IRT could distinguish between presence and absence of STCs to eventually create an automat­ed monitoring system. Our secondary objective was to describe the variability in the teat skin surface temperatures (SSTs) be­fore and after machine milking.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8925</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20238925</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 56 (2023): 2023 Annual Conference Proceedings ; 213</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8925/8627</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
