<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5007</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-18T07:12:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Body Temperature in Feedlot Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Madler, Terry L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">handling</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal well-being</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cattle movement</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">heat stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tympanic temperatures</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Body temperature is often used as an indicator of animal health status. In addition, body temperature can be used as a measure of heat stress, which occurs during the summer months and significantly impacts cattle performance and well-being. In a series of heat stress management and handling studies, tympanic temperatures (TT), an indicator of body temperature, were obtained in unrestrained feedlot cattle. In management studies, restricting feed intake to 85% of ad libitum lowered TT approximately 0.9 °F (0.5 °C), even after the period of feed restriction ended. Sprinkling feedlot surfaces was more effective in cooling cattle if sprinkling was done in the morning versus in the afternoon. Also, during hot days, TT of black-hided cattle can be over 0.9 °F (0.5 °C) greater than TT of white-hided cattle. In handling studies, moving cattle through working facilities requires an expenditure of energy causing an elevation of average body temperature between 0.5 and 1.4 °F (0.3 and 0.8 °C), depending on the ambient conditions. Effects of cattle movement and handling on body temperature needs to be taken into account when evaluating animal health studies. In addition, strategies designed to reduce the detrimental effects of heat stress while maintaining animal productivity need to be implemented. Furthermore, minimal handling of cattle during hot days is recommended for promoting animal well-being and comfort.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2002-09-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5007</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20025007</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2002; 51-57</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5007/4895</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2002 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
