<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3314</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:33:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Rural veterinary practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Goehl, Daniel R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">rural practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">career</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The beef industry is steeped in tradition. This is 1 aspect that draws producers into the industry and entices generation to follow generation. While it is always good to honor tradition at the same time one must adapt to the changing times. It has been said the change is neither inherently good nor bad; just inevitable. As veterinarians we also have traditions that shape our industry. It is up to us to shape the practice that we work in to make it an acceptable environment that we are willing to work in. One of the areas that we must focus on is helping our clientele become comfortable with a mindset that will allow us to provide them the beneficial services we can offer. The challenge for the practitioner is to provide high quality service to their clientele and receive adequate financial compensation for these efforts. The practice I work in is not the model practice that every practitioner should strive for. What works for one practitioner may not fit another's personality or skill set. As veterinarians being pulled in several directions by the general public, it is easy to lose sight of trying to enjoy the journey.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-02-09</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3314</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20183314</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2018 Recent Graduate Proceedings; 62-63</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3314/3273</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
