<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8871</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-10T20:57:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CSS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">To the point – the basics of bovine acupuncture</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Villarroel, Aurora</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">acupuncture</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Chinese medicine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">complementary therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">TCVM</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">healing</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Acupuncture is recognized these days by many institutions as an effective complementary therapeutic technique both in human and veterinary medicine. Acupuncture is only one of several treatment modalities within Traditional Chinese Vet­erinary Medicine (TCVM), but it is the one that shows the fast­est effects. Although most acupuncture treatments require a careful selection of appropriate acupoints for each individual patient, there are several acupoints with such a specific and potent effect on the body that they can be used by themselves, in conjunction with Western therapy to expedite healing. This is the case with GV14 for fever or immunostimulation, GV26 for resuscitation, CV9 for edema, Shan-gen for appetite stimulation, An-shen for sedation, and BL20 and BL21 as a pair for digestive disorders. Their location and function are explained. The in­tention of this clinical skills presentation is to provide Western practitioners with additional tools that can be used along with the customary Western therapeutic approach to help our pa­tients heal faster.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8871</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20238871</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 56 (2023): 2023 Annual Conference Proceedings ; 118-120</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8871/8577</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
