<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9400</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Investigating the short-term impacts of midlactation hoof trimming in multiparous cows with no previous hoof lesion history on milk production</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cramer, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shepley, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">van de Pol, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hoof trimming (HT) of dairy cows is the most recommended preventative practice for lameness and overall hoof health. While beneficial for lameness reduction, HT has also been shown to lead to acute stress responses in the animal as well as lead to longer times spent away from the home pen, both of which can lead to short-term disruptions in behaviors such as resting and feeding. These combined effects may influence physiological outcomes, such as milk production; however, pre­vious studies have largely included, if not focused on, popula­tions of cows that were lame, which may exaggerate the impact that HT has on milk production. As such, the current study aims to determine the short-term effect of providing a mid-lactation HT on milk production compared to not providing a mid-lactation HT in multiparous cows with no previous history of hoof lesions or lameness.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9400</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259400</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 215</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9400/9012</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
