<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5168</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:21:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Developing Fluid Administration Protocols in Bovine Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McGuirk, Sheila M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dehydration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical conditions</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">farm personnel</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">administration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fluid protocols</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In a variety of clinical disorders of cows and calves, dehydration develops because of fluid losses from the body. Normally, the volume and composition of body fluids are maintained in an extremely narrow range as excretion is matched to intake. Water intake from ingested water and feeds as well as endogenous water production balances water loss through the urine, gastrointestinal tract, respiratory tract and skin. The amount of a substance added by intake and endogenous production is equal to the amount eliminated by excretion or endogenous utilization. The urinary and gastrointestinal tracts are the major means by which cattle maintain water and electrolyte balance. Excesses can be managed by increased excretion but deficits must be corrected by increased intake.
The purpose of this paper is to identify the clinical conditions that are associated with dehydration in cattle, and to provide the assessment parameters that guide trained farm personnel to chose the best route of administration for an appropriate volume and concentration of rehydration fluids. The fluid protocols discussed in this paper will be based on body weight assumptions for a calf and cow of 100 and 1200 lb ( 45 and 550 kg), respectively.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2001-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5168</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20015168</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2001; 6-8</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5168/5043</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2001 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
