<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8843</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-10T20:58:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bloodborne pathogens in beef herds – a Kansas practitioner’s perspective</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schrag, Nora</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anaplasmosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">leukosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">beef cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Management options for bloodborne diseases depend on preva­lence (herd level and geographic), disease stage and production class. Opportunities to manage disease can be classified ac­cording to disease stage. Newer studies show that, in contrast to older studies, there is not currently a known legal way to clear animals of anaplasmosis. The only currently labeled products for treatment of acute clinical anaplasmosis are injectable oxy­tetracyclines. For a time, an enrofloxacin product (Baytril-CA) was marketed with a label for treatment of anaplasmosis, but the conditional approval application has been withdrawn. Op­portunities for leukosis management are limited to exposure control as there are no effective treatments for animals in the clinical stage and no effective methods to clear infected non-clinical animals. Due to the relatively high prevalence in beef herds, a strict test-and-cull strategy is not practical. Instead identifying animals with high pre-viral load who are most infectious provides an option to decrease disease levels with reasonable economics at the farm level. More research is neces­sary to fully quantify production effects for carrier animals of both bovine leukosis and anaplasmosis.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8843</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20238843</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 56 (2023): 2023 Annual Conference Proceedings ; 35-39</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8843/8554</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
