<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6557</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-11T00:37:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PHM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Further Studies on Bovine Lipomatosis as Enzootic Herd Problem in Egypt</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">El-Sebaie, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hofmann, W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fat necrosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">biochemical</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">composition of fatty acids</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Natrium selenite</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">experimental diagnostic therapy</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bovine lipomatosis abdominal fat necrosis in cattle generally characterised by the presence of hard irrigualr massses of necrotic fat tissue in abdominal cavity, specially in mesenteric, prirenal and intestine. The disease has been reported from several countries (10, 3, 4, 15, 20).
A review of literature on he aetiology and pathogenesis of fat necrosis are incompletly understood. Genetic influences were suggested (7), disturbence of circulation (14) and hyperthermia was reported as a possible cause of fat necrosis (1). Additional causes were mentioned, hromonal disturbence (6), pressure on the tissue (12) and composition of fatty acids and disturbence in its metabolism (18).
Fat necrosis is thought to initiate a change in the composition of fat with in normal fat cells, fat composition can change as a result of number of factors pancreatitis (18), feeding long chain saturated fatty acids (19) and depression of thyroid function (8). Leberation of glycerol which is soluble and carried the short chain saturated fatty acids and unsaturated fatty acids are liquid at body temperature, while longer chain saturated fatty acids are solid (9). Yellowish color assocaited with fat necrosis is due to polymerization of unsaturated fatty acids (9). Pathogenesis of fat necrosis is closely related to Vit. E. selenium deficiency (10). Success trials for treatment of fat necrosis were applied using jsoprothialane (17).
The purpose of this study is to carry out further investigation on the biochemical aspect of bovine fat necrosis and determination the composition of fatty acids in necrosed fat as well. Experimental diagnostic therapy using Natrium selenite for treatment of clinical cases of fat necrosis is also aimed.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6557</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926557</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 3; 17-22</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6557/7141</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
