<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6560</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-11T00:37:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PHM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effects of Management Improvement on Production and Herd Health in the Largest Intensive Dairy Cattle Operation in Iran</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Razifard, R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">disease control</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Iran</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dairy cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal protein</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">There is a great demand for animal source protein, especially milk and its by products in developing countries including Iran.
To partially cover this need, large numbers of registered and non registered Holstein dairy cattle have been imported to Iran mostly from America and Europe during the past two dicades.
Meantime, the lack of knowledge in different aspects of efficient management and disease control, in addition, the sensitivity of the imported pure breed cattle to the existing pathogenic agents have caused noticeable damages to the dairy farms and national income.
To eliminate the major problems and reveal the effects of sound management and disease control on efficiency of the dairy farms under local conditions, the present study was carried out in 13 Intensive Dairy Farms owned by the Mostazafan Foundation and run by its Department of Agriculture and Animal Production. The beneficial results however, could be applied as a guideline to increase the efficiency in dairy farms throughout the country.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6560</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926560</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 3; 34-37</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6560/7144</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
