<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7422</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-14T00:36:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Health Programs and Problems Encountered with Incoming Calves and Yearlings in the Feedlot</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hundley, O. E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Perhaps a little background would help clarify our practice. In 1960 we built an animal clinic primarily for large animals. Adjacent to the sick pens we built a processing area with the idea in mind that it was better to process the feedlot cattle on arrival rather than at any later date. In 1960 this was contrary to most of the information that was being printed. They said to rest and feed the cattle for 10-14 days before working them. Our idea was that they were already stressed and that the processing didn't add that much to the existing problem. It has been interesting to see that through the years the feeders and those who research have shifted their thinking to where most of our clients do process on arrival. It used to be that our cattle feeders would get their cattle in, then after 10-15 days they would call in their neighbors fora branding party. I'm sure you have had clients who have had cattle that they didn't get processed because of other pressing things like silage, haylage, or a lack of help at the right time. Because of this delay their cattle broke with one of the diseases they intended to immunize against. It was our thinking that we could be of service by having a good facility and a crew to process the cattle.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1975-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7422</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19757422</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1975; 135-</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7422/6520</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1975 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
