<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4552</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-15T08:41:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:VetTech</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Necropsy Techniques in Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wagner, Sarah</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Necropsy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary diagnostic laboratory</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">proceedure</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Necropsy is used to diagnos disease in individual animals and to make decisions about the health and management of the herd. Veterinary technicians can and should participate in the performance of necropsy in cattle. Prior to beginning a necropsy, the veterinarian and technician should discuss which systems will be of particular interest during the necropsy examination, based on the history of the animal and the herd. The nearest veterinary diagnostic laboratory can describe which samples should be submitted for diagnosis of particular diseases, and how samples should be shipped to the lab. The most important tools for bovine necropsy are a sharp knife, pruning shears and a good working knowledge of the anatomy of cattle. It is always best to perform the necropsy as soon as possible after death, especially when the weather is warm. In both the chest and the abdomen, internal organs should first be examined as they lay in the body cavity; then they may be removed for further examination. Cattle with neurologic signs that test negative for rabies must be tested for Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy, which requires submission of the obex area of the brainstem to a veterinary diagnostic laboratory. A thorough examination of an animal by gross necropsy can provide useful information in a relatively short time. Veterinary technicians can make a meaningful contribution to their practices by providing assistance with necropsy procedures.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-09-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4552</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20074552</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2007; 203-204</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4552/4458</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
