<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6602</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-11T00:36:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DDD</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Vasopressin Response to Water and Salt Load in Normal Cows</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Kuiper, R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Breukink, H. J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vasopressin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">metabolic alkalosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">plasma AVP</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Arginine vasopressin</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">AVP</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antidiuretic hormone</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Arginine vasopressin (AVP) or antidiuretic hormone plays a primary role in the regulation of the body fluids. Little is known at present about the regulation of AVP secretion in cattle. Our interest in the regulation of the release of AVP in cattle arises from two basic questions.
First, it has been demonstrated recently that administration of AVP to adult ruminants stimulates reticular groove contraction1. This may be of interest, as suggested by others1,2 for the oral administration of drugs that should bypass the ruminoreticulum. No data are available on the role of AVP in the consistent closure of the reticular groove in the young calf.
Secondly, pyloric stenos is in cattle results in a metabolic alkalosis. A dehydration occurs, accompanied by a hypochloraemia, a hypokalaemia, a metabolic alkalosis and a uraemia. An extreme dehydration can be found, with a production of diluted urine. No data are available of the plasma AVP concentrations in these cases.
To evaluate vasopressin values from patient cases and experimental animals, reference values were collected in 5 normal dairy cows during a water or a salt load.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6602</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926602</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 3; 138-140</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6602/7167</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
