<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3148</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-09T16:31:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Epidemiology and treatment of spinose ear ticks on a California dairy</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jardon, G. H.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ray, F. M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Peyton, R. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Overton, M. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jardon, P. W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">While not widely reported on dairies, spinose ear ticks may be more prevalent in the Southwest US dairy industry than previously thought. The dairy where this research was conducted had a serious infestation and the owner was looking for guidance in the control or eradication of this parasite due to the irritation the ticks were causing the cows. The dairy owner felt that the ticks were causing a decrease in milk production and an increased culling risk. The objective of this research was to analyze various treatment options to determine the most effective method to control spinose ear ticks through 4 studies. Study 1 examined the efficacy of acaricides to determine the most effective treatment option. Study 2 focused on locating where the adult ticks were living and reproducing within the freestall bedding. Study 3 analyzed how soon cows became infested after being moved to the freestall barn from the dry lots. Study 4 looked at the efficacy of the CyLence Ultra® ear tags in relation to infestation severity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3148</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20183148</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2018; 314</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3148/3126</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
