<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3253</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-17T19:22:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:ARS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Inhibition of biofilm formation and antibacterial potentiation by 2-aminoimidazole compounds evaluated using coagulase negative staphylococci (CNS) isolated from goat mastitis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Healey, R. S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Zeng, D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson, K. L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Biofilm formation is important in the pathogenesis of many bacterial infections of both humans and animals. Coagulase-negative staphylococci (CNS) are significant biofilm-producing pathogens found in human foreign-body infections and ruminant mastitis. We have previously shown differences in biofilm production by representatives of various genotypes of Staphylococcus aureus causing bovine mastitis. We further demonstrated that 2-aminoimidazole compounds have anti-biofilm and antibacterial potentiation properties when tested in vitro using these isolates. The CNS are the bacteria most commonly isolated from goat milk, and they can be important pathogens in the goat mammary gland. Our purpose was to evaluate the biofilm-forming potential of representatives of genotypes of the most common CNS we found in goat mastitis. We hypothesized differences in biofilm-producing potential among goat CNS isolates and that biofilm formation may reflect pathogenic potential. Using the most prolific biofilm-forming CNS isolate, we hypothesized that 2-aminoimidazole compounds would inhibit biofilm production and potentiate antibacterial activity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3253</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20183253</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2018; 335</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3253/3217</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
