<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3754</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:40:52Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Validation of an activity monitoring system for detecting early behavioral markers of respiratory disease development in young dairy calves</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Prado, Maria E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wilkerson, John</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McGuirk, Sheila</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Krawczel, Peter D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Dairy calf pneumonia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">DCP</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">weaning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">productivity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">activity</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feeding behavior</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">social interaction</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dairy calf pneumonia (DCP) is a highly prevalent and economically significant problem of dairy calves. DCP commonly affects calves during the pre-weaning and/or post-weaning periods, and is one of the most diagnosed conditions postmortem in calves less than 5 months of age (Hill et al, 2009; Virtala et al, 1996). Aside from the deleterious effects that DCP has on the calf (i.e. decreased performance), the negative impact extends well into adulthood affecting its subsequent productivity and lifespan within the herd (Bach, 2011; Waltner-Toews et al, 1986; Warnick et al, 1997).The ability to identify calves during the initial stages of respiratory disease development is difficult and relies on subjective observations made by farm personnel. However, some behavioral changes in sick calves might be more associated with early disease stages, such as spending more time in the bucket and remaining standing for longer periods after feeding when compared to healthy calves (McGuirk, personal communication). Thus, objective monitoring of activity and feeding behavior may allow for earlier disease detection and intervention, potentially decreasing the consequences of DCP later in the calf’s life. Recent studies demonstrated that group housing or daily increased provision of milk decreased the incidence of disease and increased the daily gain. These findings suggest the potential for a positive effect of the social interactions stemming from group housing. The objective of this study was to identify early behavioral markers of respiratory disease using an activity monitoring device in young dairy calves subjected to standard or high-milk feeding levels (standard or high) and housing (individual or group) on the incidence of respiratory disease in young dairy heifers.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3754</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20143754</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2014; 170</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3754/3694</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2015 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
