<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4505</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-15T08:41:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Vaccine Field Efficacy: A Review of Field Efficacy Reported for Vaccine Antigens Used in Beef Cattle and Dairy Practice, 1996 to Present</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hunsaker, Breck D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tripp, Scott P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">vaccination programs</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">peer-reviewed literature</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">control group</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">statistical method</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">field studies</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">relevant outcomes</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">An evidence-based approach to design and recommendation of vaccination programs requires a thorough review of the peer-reviewed veterinary literature. Criteria for inclusion in this review are: inclusion of a valid concurrent control group, blinding of evaluators of subjective outcomes, randomization of experimental treatments, appropriate statistical methods, sufficient statistical power and external validity. Also, only those peer-reviewed articles that report clinically relevant outcomes, e.g. morbidity, mortality, average daily gain, feed efficiency, milk production, lameness, etc, are included in this review. Furthermore, only reports of field studies done in North America were included.
CAB abstracts and PubMed databases were searched using the following search terms: bovine or cattle or cal? or bull or cow AND immun? or vaccin? or vaccine AND natural or field challenge. From these searches, 21 reports of well-designed studies done in North America to investigate field efficacy of vaccine antigens with relevance to beef cattle or dairy operations were found; 13 of these studies reported a benefit in clinically relevant outcomes.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-09-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4505</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20074505</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2007; 26-32</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4505/4411</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
