<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9327</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:40:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Data-based protocols and economic modeling to manage pharmaceutical supply</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Perrett, Tye</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">supply chain</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">pharmaceutical shortages</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">evidencebased medicine</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Global supply chains enable companies to capitalize on re­gional advantages associated with lower labor costs, special­ized expertise and natural resources. As global supply chains become increasingly complex, they are vulnerable to currency fluctuations, regulatory compliance across multiple jurisdic­tions, cultural and language barriers, geopolitical risks and natural disasters. Pharmaceutical products manufactured for the animal health industry are part of a global supply chain and thus inherit the same advantages and disadvantages. Given the importance of pharmaceutical products to animal health and wellbeing, veterinarians must have plans in place to use evidence-based medicine principles to maintain effective proto­cols amid supply disruptions. The strength of evidence pyramid is a valuable tool to guide veterinarians in their decision-mak­ing process. In production medicine, economic models allow for the determination of relative cost effectiveness of product options based on biological outcomes.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9327</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259327</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 26-28</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9327/8943</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
