<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4547</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-09-03T02:35:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:VetTech</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Implementing Your Veterinarian's Synchronization and AI Protocols</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Stevenson, Debbie</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Synchronization</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">synchronization protocols</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">estrous cycle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">genetics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As the saying goes, "change is good ... you go first." We all fall into the trap of doing things the way they've always been done. After all, doesn't the bull do a pretty good job? Almost any bull can breed a cow, but not every bull will improve the herd. By adding artificial insemination (AI) to your management tool belt you will have access to genetics that would otherwise be cost prohibitive. Artificial insemination has been around for over 65 years, but for many of those years it was labor intensive. Heat checking twice a day is very time consuming; however, great strides have been made in the area of estrus synchronization. Synchronization is the key to having a successful AI program - both for your clinic and the producer. With the improvement in synchronization protocols it is a tool your clinic can offer not only to seed stock and club calf producers, but commercial producers as well. With heightened awareness and education of the estrous cycle, access to an AI technician and clarity of protocol administration, this is sure to be a service your clients will appreciate.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-09-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4547</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20074547</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2007; 188-190</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4547/4453</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
