<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6923</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-17T19:53:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FS3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Necropsy Procedure for Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Edwards, Alvin J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">necropsy examination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">diagnosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">disease control</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">herd problems</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">post mortem</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The key to disease control is the diagnosis. While history and clinical signs, possibly supplemented by laboratory tests, may lead to the diagnosis, it is often only the post mortem examination which can determine the nature of an animal's disease. Necropsies should therefore be regarded as standard diagnostic procedure, particularly in the case of herd problems. A skillfully conducted and intelligently interpreted post mortem examination will always give the stock owner a surprisingly high degree of satisfaction and will greatly enhance his confidence in the veterinarian.
The performance of a necropsy is both a science and an art. As a science, it requires a thorough knowledge of general and special pathology of organs and organ systems. It assumes a familiarity with the infections, metabolic and parasitic diseases of different species. It demands the ability to recognize normal and pathological tissues with or without post mortem changes.
As an art, it requires facility in standardized necropsy procedure to effectively illuminate pathological conditions so they may be studied accurately. It necessitates a concern for precision, neatness, and thoroughness so that a complete diagnosis can follow.
The necropsy examination looks easy when one watches an experienced prospector at work. Familiarity and repeated use of a procedure increases proficiency and dispels the useless pulling, cutting, and destruction of lesions which greatly reduce the possibility of arriving at a diagnosis. The veterinarian who learns and adheres to a definite necropsy protocol will be uniform, rapid, systematic, and complete.
Completeness facilitates diagnosis, or problem solving of cases, and is the key to consistent interpretation of lesions. Following a standard protocol assures that each organ system will be grossly observed in turn. Short cuts lead to a lack of thoroughness and a consequent missed diagnosis, or no diagnosis at all.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1989-11-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6923</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19896923</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1989; 176-182</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6923/6353</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1989 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
