<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6892</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-17T19:53:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:CCF3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Experience with an Established and on-going IRM Program in the Midwest</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hudson, Don</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Integrated Reproductive Management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cow/calf systems modeling</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">weaning weights</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">management practices</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A major effort in Integrated Reproductive Management (IRM) began at the University of Nebraska under the Cooperative Extension Service and the Agricultural Research Division in 1983. Research in cow/calf systems modeling and reproductive management was developed and continues. Extension developed a five year demonstration herd project. A steering committee composed of beef producers, University extension specialists and researchers, and researchers from USDA (MARC) assembled to help guide the project. In February of 1984, the steering committee selected 9 cow/calf producers to cooperate as demonstration herds from 80 nominated by agricultural agents and veterinarians across Nebraska. Selected herds had resources "typical" of their respective areas.
An IRM team was developed for each cooperator composed of the local agricultural extension agent, an extension beef specialist, the veterinarian used by the cooperator, other university and non-university personnel (producer, industry representative) and the technical coordinator. The IRM team analyzed the cow/calf enterprise and recommended alternative management practices for the producer to consider that would optimize use of the available resources and increase reproductive efficiency.
Production information on the cow/calf enterprise was collected beginning in 1984 and ended in 1988. Financial inputs and feed used by the cow/calf enterprise were collected in 1987 and 1988 for enterprise evaluation. This information was used to monitor changes in the cow/calf enterprise of cooperating herds. On average, percent calves weaned of females exposed increased 11.5 percentage points between 1984 and 1988. Actual and adjusted weaning weights increased 93 and 100 pounds, respectively, over the 5 years. Pounds of calf weaned per cow exposed increased 139 pounds between 1984 and 1988. Net cost per calf weaned in 1987 and 1988 was $.73 and $.74, respectively, for low cost producers and $.99 and $.92 for high cost producers.
Eight field days were held to discuss IRM concepts and profitable management practices. Numerous news articles, radio tapes, proceedings, extension publications, and educational meetings were developed using information collected in the IRM demonstration herd project. A cow/calf record-keeping program (PC-COWCARD) for microcomputer was develop~d and made available commercially to producers. Cooperators "integrated" recommendations made by agents, specialists, veterinarians, nutritionists, lenders, ..... into a working management practice for their resources.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1989-11-14</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6892</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19896892</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1989; 73-76</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6892/6336</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1989 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
