<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9481</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-10T17:14:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Turning veterinary brain power into production management prowess</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nguyen, Blake</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">production management</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">leadership</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">career development</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">protocol development</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The veterinarian brain has proven that it has immense capabil­ities in analytical thinking, nimble adaptability to new circum­stances, and the emotional intelligence required for teamwork. We are part of an incredible profession that can open doors to almost anything and close almost none. Good veterinarians will continue to thrive in bovine production medicine because our skills are well-suited to providing value in all the areas that are critical to the future of cattle production: 1. production of safe, nutritious food, 2. animal welfare, 3. environmental stew­ardship, 4. economics, 5. leadership and personnel manage­ment. It is important to develop a vision for what kind of impact you would like to have. When looking for cattle production processes to streamline or improve, look for bottlenecks first. Equally important is learning to focus on the specific details of implementing recommendations. Standard operating pro­cedures and protocols are usually too complicated and compli­ance is usually imperfect; learn from the protocol drift that is regularly observed on farms. Detailed understanding and an incredible opportunity to impact outcomes is available in the production management career path for bovine veterinarians.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9481</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20269481</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 1 (2026): 2026 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 45-46</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9481/9083</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
