<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3128</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-04-09T16:31:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:BS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Nutritional management between health and performance</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Fox, J.Trent</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">feedlot cattle</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">acidosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bovine respiratory disease</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The goals of finishing beef cattle include improving cattle performance and efficiency, producing a product that meets the standards of the consumer, and creating good animal husbandry and health for the cattle. Proper management and feeding of finishing cattle can have a huge impact on disease incidence. Feeding high energy diets will drive an improvement in efficiency by reducing losses of carbon dioxide and methane gas. This improvement reduces the cost and resources of producing beef. An issue is that cattle are accustomed to consuming grasses and not nutrientrich diets, thus they require an adaptation period. Good management of formulation and delivery of feed is key to reduce the likelihood of negative impacts during this period. Bovine respiratory disease is the most prominent disease in this population of cattle. This paper attempts to outline the impact of acidosis and bovine respiratory disease as well as other feed-related diseases commonly seen in feedlot cattle such as rumen tympany or bloat, acute or atypical intersitial pneumonia, and laminitis.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3128</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20183128</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2018; 151-156</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3128/3109</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
