<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6772</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-07-21T18:25:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FBM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Proceedings of the Twenty-Third Annual Conference (1990). AABP Amstutz Enrichment Opportunities Program and Social Events</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bovine Practitioners, American Association of</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The AABP Amstutz Enrichment Opportunities Program was announced by Dr. Simon Kenyon, Visiting Associate Professor of Population Health, Purdue University. The awards under this program are designed to encourage and help students to prepare themselves for careers in bovine practice. The program is named in honor of the unique leadership role of Dr. Harold E. Amstutz in the maturation and development of national and international organizations in the area pf bovine veterinary practice.
The Social Calendar was off to a great start when "one and all" were welcomed at the opening ceremony following the very sumptuous "Hoosier Ribeye" sandwiches grilled by members of the Indiana Cattlemen's Association along with a cash bar, soft drinks and ice cream on Thursday evening. The day had been spent on a tour of Hoosier Highlights, encompassing a panoramic view of Indianapolis, including stops at the Indianapolis Motor Speedway and the Museum of Art.
Several AABP members and guests spent a most enjoyable and instructive visit to the Blanco Research facility at Greenfield, Indiana on Thursday, September 13, guests of the Eli Lilly Company. The tour was organized by AABP President-Elect David McClary.
On Friday, September 14 the Board of Directors hosted a public relations breakfast for media personnel which was funded by the Indiana Veterinary Medical Association.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1990-09-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Front matter</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6772</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1990; viii-xi</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6772/6415</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1990 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
