<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5635</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-31T18:49:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PT</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Application of Certain Enzyme Tests in Bovine Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sterner, Edward</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Having read the article on serum enzymes in The Bovine Practitioner of November 1972 by Dr. L. J. Rich and Dr. M. L. Dunavant, I decided to attend the seminar on Laboratory Medicine in Bovine Practice given by Dr. G. W. Osbandiston held at the Milwaukee meeting in 1972. From these two exposures, I decided to further explore the value of kinetic enzymes and their meaningfulness in our practice. We spent considerable time evaluating the different types of equipment to determine which would be the most satisfactory in our type of operation. We decided on the Coleman Spectrophotometer, Model 55. Even though it was more expensive, we felt that its accuracy and ease of cleaning and care justified this expense. From our experience I feel that it is important to have an available competent service representative who is fully qualified and experienced to give service as well as information on the performance of these tests and on the equipment sold.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1973-12-05</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5635</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1973; 35-37</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5635/5480</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1973 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
