<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8059</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-05-28T07:35:44Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Dry-cow management and the unborn and neonatal calf</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Robison, Jon D.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">calf</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dry cows</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The dry period of cows has not received the level of attention in management of other classes of dairy cattle over the years. The primary measurements of dry-cow management effectiveness have primarily been focused on the cow’s ability to transition from the dry period into lactation. Little to no emphasis has been granted to the management of dry cows for the mutual benefit of the cow and the unborn and neonatal calf. Dry-cow management strategies must be founded upon a rational understanding and application as to the physiological dynamics of late-term gestation, cow transitioning from non-lactating to a high level of lactation, colostrogenesis, birth and calf transitioning from in utero through the first 30 days of life. When properly designed, implemented, and monitored, these dry-cow management strategies will result in success for both the cow and the calf. Monitoring measurements beyond those commonly employed should be added in order to more completely evaluate the impact of management on both the cow and the calf. These should include, assessment of colostrum quality and quantity, calf birth weight, and 24 to 48-hour serum IgG in the calf.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-09-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8059</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20208059</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2020; 221-223</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8059/8007</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
