<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6691</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-07-22T15:58:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FBM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Proceedings of the Twenty-Fourth Annual Conference (1991). Awards and Pre-Convention Tour</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bovine Practitioners, American Association of</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The 1991 recipient of the Distinguished Service Award was Dr. John C. Dahl, Madison, Wisconsin.
Dr. Kenneth E. Leslie, Guelph, Ontario, Canada was presented with the 1991 Award of Excellence.
AABP Awards for Excellence in Preventive Veterinary Medicine, sponsored by MSD-AGVET division of Merck &amp;amp; Co.Inc. were presented during the annual business awards luncheon meeting on Saturday, September 21.
The Awards recognize member practitioners who have developed outstanding preventive veterinary medicine programs for their clients in beef or dairy practice. Each award consists of a $1500 scholarship contribution by MSD-AGVET in the name of the recipient of his/her veterinary college of choice and a specially designed bronze plaque in bas-relief.
Dr. Keith Sterner, Ionia, Michigan is the 1991 Bovine Practitioner of the Year.
Walt Disney did not include meat and milk production, Florida-style, in his plans so on Wednesday, at the crack of dawn, several registrants left Orlando and traveled by bus to Okeechobee to visit two dairies and a cowcalf operation.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1991-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Front matter</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6691</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1991; x-xiv</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6691/6539</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1991 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
