<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8898</identifier>
				<datestamp>2024-05-10T20:56:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of treatment with propylene glycol and cyanocobalamin on disease, milk production and reproductive outcomes of dairy cows diagnosed with hyperketonemia and hypoglycemia</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hubner, A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Canisso, I.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Coelho, W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ribeiro, L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Aldridge, B.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lima, F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Almost all periparturient dairy cows experience a period of negative energy balance, and despite improvements to fresh cow management, some dairy cows still experience clinical dis­ease associated with the periparturient period (Duffield et al., 2009; Taylor et al., 2004). Hyperketonemia (HK) remains an im­portant production and animal welfare concern (McArt et al., 2012; Tatone, Duffield, Capel, et al., 2016; Tatone, Duffield, LeB­lanc, et al., 2016), and recently several handheld meters which measure beta-hydroxybutyric acid (BHBA) have been validated in dairy cows and can be used to detect pre-clinical HK (Bach et al., 2016; Tatone et al., 2015). Several studies have explored the screening of post-parturient cows to detect HK and adminis­ter treatment in order to ward off clinical disease and increase milk production (Capel et al., 2021; Gordon et al., 2017; McArt et al., 2012). However, these studies have been inconsistent in their findings, and treatment may not be economically beneficial for farms with a relatively low incidence of HK (McArt et al., 2014). A 2017 study indicated that cows may have variable production responses to HK treatment based on blood glucose concentra­tion (Gordon et al., 2017). Because blood glucose can also be mea­sured cow-side, measurement of blood glucose concurrent with measurement of blood BHBA may be a means to target treatment to cows that will respond to current treatments. Therefore, our objective was to explore the effects of treatment with propylene glycol and cyanocobalamin in early post-partum cows based on both HK and glycemic status. We hypothesized that improve­ments to health, milk production, and reproduction would be greatest among cows that were hypoglycemic.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2024-05-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8898</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20238898</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 56 (2023): 2023 Annual Conference Proceedings ; 188</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8898/8602</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2024 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
