<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9399</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The effect of mid-lactation hoof trimming of multiparous dairy cows on risk of subsequent lesion development</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cramer, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Shepley, E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">van de Pol, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Hoof trimming (HT) is often seen as the most impactful man­agement practice for good hoof health in dairy herds, but also represent a cost to producers and is a stressful event for cows. While HT around dry-off is the most common preventive prac­tice on farms that practice routine HT, many farms implement an additional HT at mid-lactation. Studies have found that a second HT at mid-lactation can reduce hoof lesion risk and de­crease lameness prevalence; however, other studies report lit­tle to no effect. These conflicting results suggest that the level of benefit of mid-lactation HT may be dependent on multiple cow-level factors, allowing for a more selective targeting of cows that will benefit from a mid-lactation HT and those for which this trim can be omitted. While our previous research showed no differences in hoof lesion risk or time-to-lesion in first lacta­tion cows with no history of hoof lesions, it is unknown if this trim can similarly be omitted from multiparous cows with no hoof lesion history. Thus, the objective of our study was to de­termine the effect of routine HT at mid-lactation versus no HT at mid-lactation in multiparous cows without any history of hoof lesions.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9399</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259399</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 214</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9399/9011</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
