<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8534</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-12-22T03:05:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluating the decision to not use antibiotics for management of clinical mastitis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Wavrin, Bill</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">clinical mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antibiotics</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Managers of livestock and their veterinarians take on a re­sponsibility that involves “the protection of animal health and welfare, the prevention and relief of animal suffering, the conservation of animal resources, and the promotion of public health.” Prima facie, everyone involved at all levels strives to reduce incidence of any disease. Despite this, it remains true that clinical mastitis still occurs at high frequency on most farms and over most species, including humans. When these disease events occur, a conflict arises among the competing in­terests of improving animal wellbeing (conservation) and com­promising future public and animal health through decreased effectiveness of available antimicrobial therapeutic modalities. It is well accepted that increased antimicrobial use intensity is associated with decreased antimicrobial efficacy in a range of circumstances. This discussion paper will visit that conflict and consider alternative resolutions.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8534</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228534</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2022 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 108</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8534/8326</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2022 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
