<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6610</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-11T00:35:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RD</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Efficacite Comparee De La Flunixine Meglumine Et de L' Acide Tolfenamique Chez Les Bovins: Etude A L' Aide De Cages Tissulaires</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Espinasse, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thouvenot, J. P.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dalle, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Garcia, J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schelcher, F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Salat, O.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Valarcher, J. F.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Daval, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">flunixine meglumine</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tolfenamic acid</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">inflammatory reaction</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">tissue cage</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">antiinflammatory drugs</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">A comparison of the effects of two antiinflammatory drugs, flunixine meglumine (FM) and tolfenamic acid (TA) has been conducted in cattle using a tissue cage model. "Practice" polypropylene golf balls have been implanted subcutaneously in the neck of 12 young males calves. After a 3 weeks stabilisation period, an acute inflammatory reaction has been induced with an injection in the tissue cage of a 2% carragenine sterile solution. After randomisation of the animals in 3 groups : one received an intramuscular injection of distilled water (placebo), another group was treated with 2 mg/Kg FM intramuscularly, the third group received TA at the same posology and through the same route. Starting half an hour after the carragenine injection the tissue cage exudate were collected seven times during the first 48 hours to measure the prostaglandine E2 level using a radioimmunologic method. To decrease the variability between animals the study has been conducted in a cross-over way, each series starting three weeks after the other. A statistical analysis of all datas has been done using a paired series test after a log10 transformation of the prostaglandine E2 concentrations. The comparisons between placebo and FM groups and between placebo and TA groups are in accordance with the validity of the model. The inhibition of the production of prostaglandine E2 for both antiinflammatory drugs confirm their action on the cyclo-oxygenase. The statistical comparisons demonstrate as well the superiority of FM on TA.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1992-08-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6610</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19926610</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1992: Volume 3; 159-163</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6610/7172</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1992 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
