<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9127</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-26T17:15:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Setting yourself up for success in farm animal practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Leicht, Jonathan</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This presentation aims to provide veterinary students and new graduates with practical insights and strategies to confidently embark on their careers in farm animal practice. We will begin by discussing how to make informed decisions when picking your first practice. This decision goes beyond location or pay— it’s about aligning your values with a practice that supports your professional growth and offers the right balance between clinical work and personal development. From understanding the role of mentorship to learning how to integrate work and life in this demanding field, we’ll touch on the pillars of a suc­cessful start in farm animal practice.
We will also dive deep into the art of negotiation, focusing on the latest trends in salary structures, including the differences between fixed salaries and pro-sal (production-based com­pensation). The importance of “extras” such as vacation time, continuing education, benefits, signing bonuses and reloca­tion allowances will be highlighted. In addition, we’ll explore common concerns, such as the fears new graduates face when entering the field and discuss long-term prospects like practice ownership. Our session aims to empower you to make confident career choices that not only provide financial stability but also pave the way for a fulfilling and sustainable career in veteri­nary medicine.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9127</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20249127</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 58 (2024): 2024 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 162</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9127/8788</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
