<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9122</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-03-26T17:15:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:SS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Spanglish 101</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Dotterer, Katherine</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Spanish</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">communication</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">English</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">language</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">learning</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The rapid growth of the Hispanic population in the United States, particularly in the agricultural sector, presents both challenges and opportunities for veterinary professionals. Herein we, explore the nuances of English and Spanish lan­guages, advocating for a pragmatic approach to cross-cultural communication. Drawing from personal experience and lin­guistic analysis, we challenge conventional language learn­ing norms by promoting the use of “Spanglish” – a hybrid of Spanish and English – as an effective interim communication strategy. The efficiency of the Spanish language in contrast to common English language pitfalls can make communication difficult, however the concept of “Caveman Talk” as a means of building confidence in bilingual interactions, can be a start­ing point to improve communication. We emphasize the im­portance of cultural sensitivity and the willingness to actively engage in learning basic Spanish, while also evaluating the role of translation tools. By embracing imperfect, yet earnest, at­tempts at communication and demonstrating a commitment to language learning, veterinarians can significantly improve their relationships with Spanish-speaking clients and staff. This approach ultimately enhances animal care and professional ef­ficacy in an increasingly diverse agricultural landscape.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-03-26</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9122</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20249122</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 58 (2024): 2024 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 144-145</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9122/8783</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
