<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4893</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:16:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Leveraging Your Time and Improving Your Practice with Veterinary Technicians</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Farrell, Patrick S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">mixed animal practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food animal practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">licensed staff</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">technician</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">training</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">business model</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinary practice</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">&amp;nbsp;Many changes occurring within the veterinary industry have caused a reassessment of traditional food and mixed animal practice procedures and norms. Fewer graduates interested in these practice areas have increased the focus on this topic today. Some groups lament the lack of adequate numbers of veterinary graduates while conflicting groups have discerned that the amount of veterinary care available is appropriate. Veterinary technicians are educated, licensed, capable professionals whose role has been morphing and expanding in recent years. Small animal practices have integrated these technicians into their business model successfully, yet many practitioners have not yet embraced the benefits others have noted. Mixed animal practices offer perhaps the easiest entry for a licensed technician since duties can often be flexibly changed between species as their job description expands and additional training occurs. Many DVM's are finding that their billable professional time is substantially increased with the addition of licensed staff who are able to work under indirect as well as direct supervision. This has added to the bottom line in many instances. Careful attention to the law of the state of residence will help guide the process of integrating these professionals into a changing practice environment.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2004-09-23</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4893</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20044893</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2004; 23-25</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4893/4784</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2004 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
