<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5345</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:16:51Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Performance of a Timed Artificial Insemination Program for First Service Followed by TAI Combined with Natural Heat Detection versus TAI with Natural Heat Detection for First Service and Subsequent Breedings in a Commercial Dairy</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Capel, Michael</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nydam, Daryl V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Saltman, Roger</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive program</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">timed insemination</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">heat detection</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">natural heat</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Designing effective reproductive programs is an important role for dairy veterinarians on dairies today. Given a wide variety of ovulation synchronization and estrus detection aids, it is unknown if timed artificial insemination (TAI) programs and natural heat detection should be blended or used separately. Therefore, it would be very useful to veterinarians and producers to evaluate how natural heat detection and timed insemination programs work in concert, in contrast to timed insemination programs in the absence of heat detection. The goal of this study was to evaluate the potential effects of breeding dairy cattle with a 100% TAI program on first service, followed by natural heat detection and TAI if diagnosed open at pregnancy examination. This was compared with the current reproductive program of natural heat detection after a Presynch program and TAI on all cows not bred after an observed natural heat, followed by natural heat detection and TAI if diagnosed open at pregnancy examination.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2003-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5345</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20035345</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2003; 252-253</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5345/5212</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2003 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
