<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5366</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-21T07:23:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Conjugated Linoleic Acid: Cancer Fighter in Milk</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">McGuire, M. A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">protein content</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fat content</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">conjugated linoleic acid</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">anticarcinogen</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">As an important source of nutrients, milk provides high-quality protein, energy, calcium and a variety of vitamins and minerals. Recent research has focused on altering the fat and protein content of milk and other dairy products in order to improve the nutrient content of these foods so that they more aptly reflect current dietary recommendations and trends. For example, diet is a contributing factor to the onset or progression of some cancers, with epidemiological studies indicating diet composition may be related to 35 percent of human cancer deaths.11 A few substances in our diet have been identified as anti-carcinogens, but most are of plant origin and are only present in trace concentrations. However, conjugated linoleic acid (CLA), a component of milk fat, introduces an exciting twist to what we know about diet and cancer. Unlike most naturally occurring anticarcinogens, CLA is potent at extremely low levels and present in foods from ruminant animals.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2000-09-21</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5366</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20005366</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2000; 79-84</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5366/5233</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2000 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
