<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8623</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-07-18T01:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:PMS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Familiarization and update of USDA NIFA Veterinary Medicine Loan Repayment and Veterinary Service Grant Programs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Smith, Robert</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Azevedo, Marline</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bjork, Kathe</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Farley, Danielle</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">veterinarian</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">student loan</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">rural</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">food/large animal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">appropriations</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">In order to address the national need for food/large animal vet­erinary services for the public and private sectors of animal agriculture in the United States and Insular Areas, Congress passed into law the National Veterinary Medical Services Act (NVMSA) nearly 20 years ago. This Act allowed for the forma­tion, authorization of funding and appropriations of funds to allow the National Institute of Food &amp;amp; Agriculture (NIFA) to support the implementation of the Veterinary Medicine Loan Repayment Program (VMLRP) in 2010. The 2014 Farm Bill au­thorized the development of the Veterinary Services Grant Pro­gram (VSGP) in 2016. In coordination with State Animal Health Officials (SAHO), the VMLRP and VSGP support veterinarians through competitively awarded educational loan repayments and grants to fill the most serious veterinary shortage situa­tions in the United States. In addition, the program determines the best possible match between specific shortage situations and applicants’ knowledge, skills, abilities and experiences to enhance the likelihood that awardees will achieve sufficient professional success and satisfaction during their term of ser­vice so that they will continue in their service to the area. The goal of this presentation is to familiarize stakeholders of these two competitive veterinary service programs offered by USDA-NIFA to encourage their involvement and suggestions for en­hancements to the programs.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-07-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8623</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228623</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 55 (2022): 2022 Annual Conference Proceedings; 118-120</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8623/8379</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
