<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9403</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Measuring pathogen specificity of IgG in milk replacers and the potential for supplementing with pathogen-specific IgY</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Saltman, R.L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jones, S.W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tollefson, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Milk Replacers (MRs) are formulated to provide calves with the nutrients necessary for growth. Milk-based protein sources contain varying amounts of IgG that can provide the calf with enteric immunity by binding to pathogens for removal from the GI tract. There is very little literature that refers to this poten­tial passive immunity offered by milk-based MR components and no previous work to demonstrate the relative levels of this passive immunity in specific MR formulations.
The objective of this study was to develop a method to deter­mine the total amount of IgG present in five commercial MRs as well as the specificity of the IgG against common calf scour pathogens. Next, the improvement in specific antibody titers was evaluated by adding IgY, the avian equivalent to IgG, to the MR. The IgY egg powder (EggTek®-C) was harvested from the eggs of chickens inoculated with multiple killed enteric calf pathogens.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9403</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259403</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 218</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9403/9015</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
