<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3726</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:41:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Prevalence of bacteremia in dairy cattle with acute puerperal metritis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Credille, Brent</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Giguere, Steeve</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hurley, David J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Woolums, Amelia</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">post-partum</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Acute puerperal metritis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">APM</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">uterine lumen</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">bacteria</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">retained placenta</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">hypocalcemia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">negative energy balance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">coliform mastitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dairy cattle are susceptible to numerous disorders in the immediate post-partum period. Acute puerperal metritis (APM), defined as the presence of a fetid, watery uterine discharge, an enlarged, flaccid uterus, and overt signs of systemic illness that may include fever, dehydration, depression, and toxemia, is one of the most commonly encountered infectious diseases in modern dairy practice. After calving, more than 90% of cattle experience some degree of contamination of the uterine lumen with bacteria. Through the processes of uterine involution and normal immune function, most cattle clear this contamination and experience no complications. However, cattle with retained placenta, hypocalcemia, and significant negative energy balance fail to clear uterine contamination and develop APM. Bacteremia has been documented in approximately 32% of adult dairy cattle with coliform mastitis. In cows with acute coliform mastitis, the presence of bacteremia, particularly blood borne infection with organisms such as E. coli, Pasteurella multocida and Mannheimia hemolytica, had a significant impact on cow survival. The purposes of the study reported here were to investigate the prevalence of bacteremia in dairy cattle with naturally occurring APM, determine if an association exists between the bacteria cultured from the bloodstream and those present in uterus and identify factors that may be of use in predicting occurrence of bacteremia in cattle with APM.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2014-09-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3726</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20143726</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2014; 145</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3726/3667</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2014 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
