<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8585</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-07-18T01:22:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:GS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Young practitioners membership evaluation: A qualitative exploration</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Thomas, James</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">qualitative research</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">stress</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">burnout</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">young practitioner</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;The overarching objectives for this research were to explore the perceptions of newly minted bovine veterinarians regarding the American Association of Bovine Practitioners (the Associa­tion), determine its salient features and benefits, and ascertain if the Association has a non-renewal issue with this population.
This was the first investigation of this sort conducted by the As­sociation with this audience regarding these issues – the area in question was basically unexplored. The information previously available was mostly anecdotal, therefore In-Depth Interviews (IDIs), a qualitative research methodology was employed. A total of 19 IDIs were conducted with bovine veterinarians who had practiced for less than 5 years and had been a member of the American Association of Bovine Practitioners. Thirteen in­dividuals were current members, while 6 respondents were no longer members.
Although there were a number of suggestions for improvement, all respondents pointed out the many positive attributes of AABP and would recommend membership.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-07-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8585</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228585</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 55 (2022): 2022 Annual Conference Proceedings; 1-9</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8585/8348</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
