<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4606</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-15T08:40:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS3</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation and Use of an Automated Human β-hydroxybuturate (BHBA) Test for Cowside Detection of Subclinical Ketosis in Dairy Cattle</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Heuwieser, W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Falkenberg, U.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Iwersen, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Voigtsberger, R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Padberg, W.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">subclinical ketosis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">milk production</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">reproductive performance</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">cowside diagnostic test</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">accuracy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">BHBA measuring system</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Prevalence of subclinical ketosis in dairy herds ranges from 6.9% to 34%. Subclinical ketosis can lead to decreased milk production and reproductive performance, increased risk of displaced abomasum and clinical ketosis. The gold standard diagnostic test for subclinical ketosis is the measurement of BHBA in serum or plasma. Thresholds to distinguish between normal and ketotic cows range from 1000 to 1600 Qmol/1 of blood BHBA. Serum BHBA measurement is useful for examining individual cows and evaluating herd health. However, it is not convenient and is expensive for use as a routine cowside diagnostic test for the early detection of subclinical ketosis. Cowside diagnostic tests for ketosis (dipsticks or tablets) are based on the degree of color change. These tests can be used semi-quantitatively because the color change is more intense in the presence of higher levels of ketone bodies. Accuracy of the tests vary from test to test and from study to study. In human medicine electronic handheld blood glucose and ketone systems are used for diabetes monitoring. The objective of this study was to evaluate the precision and accuracy of an electronic BHBA measuring system (Abbot, Wiesbaden) for the use in dairy cattle.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2007-09-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4606</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20074606</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2007; 253-254</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4606/4509</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2007 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
