<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/4270</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:55:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Joint</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Surgical Management of Reproductive Emergencies</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Anderson, David E.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">birthing</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">llamas</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">alpacas</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">South America</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">crias</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">dystocia</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">fetal malpositioning</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">uterine torsion</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Birthing in llamas and alpacas is a rapid process. Studies in South America documented that&amp;gt; 80% of crias (neonatal llama or alpaca) are born between 6 am and 1 pm. Stage II labor ( expulsion of the cria) occurs over a period of 10 to 15 minutes (range, six to 47 minutes). Dystocia is an uncommon event in llamas and alpacas. Studies in South America found that dystocia in alpacas (1660 birthings observed) occurred in 1.6% of birthings and that 25% of these occurred in primiparous females. Data in a smaller number of llamas (234 birthings observed) demonstrated dystocia in only one female (0.4%). Interestingly, causes of dystocia differ in South America and North America. Uterine torsion is rarely found in descriptions of dystocia in South America. Causes of dystocia in these populations include fetal malpositioning, with 30% of those occurring with the fetus in a posterior presentation and 70% in anterior presentation. Markedly less information is available documenting causes of dystocia in North American herds. What data is available seems to indicate that uterine torsion is a common cause for veterinary intervention of dystocia. The author's opinion is that fetal malpositioning is associated with the majority of dystocia in llamas and alpacas and that uterine torsion is over-represented in the literature, because these cases are more likely to be presented to teaching hospitals for treatment.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2009-09-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4270</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20094270</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2009; 136-142</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/4270/4185</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2009 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
