<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9408</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">How much milk would it take? Estimating the improvement in lactating herd performance needed to offset the cost of raising additional replacement opportunities</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Adamchick, J.S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Briggs, K.R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Nydam, D.V.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Dairy farms can meet their baseline replacement needs and have surplus calves. One source of value from surplus calves is to sell crossbred beef calves; another is to build flexibility into the herd’s replacement decisions by raising more dairy females (additional replacement opportunities [AROs]) above baseline requirements. ARO costs include raising the additional animal and the opportunity cost of not having produced and sold a crossbred beef calf. AROs can then either replace a cow whose slot would improve if occupied by an average replacement or be sold as a surplus springer.
Our objective was to estimate a) the required annual increase in milk production to offset the cost of producing and raising the AROs if used as replacements, and b) the “flexibility premium” (percent increase in net youngstock cost above baseline) of hav­ing the AROs available if instead sold as surplus springers.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9408</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259408</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 224</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9408/9020</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
