<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7740</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-08-27T21:08:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FBM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Proceedings of the Tenth Annual Convention (1977). Social Events</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bovine Practitioners, American Association of</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Ladies' Events: The spirit of St. Louis smiled on the ladies as they gathered to resume acquaintance with friends who have become seasoned AABP conventioneers and to meet new members of the wonderful AABP family.
Post-Convention Tour: A fitting climax to an outstanding, record-breaking AABP convention was a visit to the Purina Research Farm at Gray Summit, Missouri, 43 miles southwest of St. Louis.
The annual general meeting was held on Wednesday afternoon, December 14, 1977, Dr. Robert Harris presiding.
Dr. Elmer Woelffer, Oconomowoc, Wisconsin, was unanimously elected an honorary member of the American Association of Bovine Practitioners during the annual convention in St. Louis.
The X World Congress of Buiatrics will be held in Mexico City on August 16-19, 1978. The organizing committee has chosen five main topics: Reproduction; Problems of Dairy Cattle Production; Mastitis; Improvement of Milk and Beef Production in the Tropics; Nutrition and also Miscellaneous Communications. The Congress will be held at the Congress Unit of the National Medical Center.
Photos of Convention Highlights.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1977-12-12</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Front matter</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7740</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1977; v-vii, xiii-xx</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7740/6526</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1977 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
