<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/7512</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-17T20:00:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:FBM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Proceedings of the Nineteenth Annual Conference (1986). Social Events and Annual Membership Luncheon Meeting.</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bovine Practitioners, American Association of</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Following the opening ceremony on Tuesday evening, November 18, the spouses viewed a slide presentation on Louisville by Marilyn Fox, Louisville Tours, and enjoyed light refreshments provided by the local hostesses and the Kentucky Veterinary Medical Association Auxiliary.
Class-Kentucky Style was an evening of good food, with Kentucky beef and trimmings, served by the professionals of the Galt House.
The Annual Membership Luncheon Meeting was held on Friday, November 21 , with Dr. Neil G. Anderson presiding and presenting a blessing.
This talk today is going to differ from the usual address of the President of the AVMA. In the first place it will be shorter. In the second place, it will treat the perennial subjects of Insurance, Public Relations, Political Action and Budgeting Considerations with dispatch. Please don't interpret this as a lack of interest on my part in these subjects. All of you who know me know that I am vitally interested and totally committed to AVMA's pre-eminence in each of these areas.
Saturday morning-it was all over except for a grand finale [Post Convention Tour] for those who love the sport of Kings and anxious to know more about Kentucky, the horse capital of the world.
Finally, included are four pages of convention photos.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1986-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Front matter</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7512</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1986; vii-xii, xvii-xx</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/7512/6155</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1986 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
