<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9495</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-10T17:14:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:MX</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Poultry 101</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Quercia, Hailey</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Backyard poultry keeping continues to grow in popularity. However, access to veterinary care for these animals lags be­hind. Many clients seek medical care for these animals, which are viewed as beloved pets. When they are unable to find it, they turn instead to the internet and social media, which can lead to poor outcomes, misuse of therapeutics, and animal wel­fare issues. Many of the veterinary skills and tools needed to work with these patients are the same as those used with other species. By providing care for this population, veterinarians can improve bird health while also increasing client base and in­come. In this paper, techniques to evaluate and treat poultry are discussed, along with aspects of proper husbandry to allow for counseling of owners. The purpose is to prepare a large or mixed animal practitioner for working with these patients and clients.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9495</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20269495</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 1 (2026): 2026 Recent Graduate Conference Proceedings; 96-98</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9495/9096</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
