<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6294</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-08-15T00:34:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS1</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Comparison Between Intraperitoneal and Intravenous Fluid Administration in Moderately Dehydrated Calves on a California Calf Ranch</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Koenig, Gerard J.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Holmberg, Charles A.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Medeiros, Ron L.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Guterbock, Walter M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">intraperitoneal administration</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">electrolyte solutions</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">weight gain</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">survival rate</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">peritoneal surfaces</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Several California calf ranches have utilized intraperitoneal (IP) administration of electrolyte solutions to dehydrated calves with favorable clinical response in most patients. Calf ranch records were inadequate, however, to evaluate medium and long term effects of IP treatment, and comparison with IV administration was not made. Objectives of this study were to: 1) compare weight gain to 28 days post-treatment, 2) compare rates of survival to 60 days post-treatment, 3) evaluate pathologic changes to peritoneal surfaces and 4) determine primary cause of death in calves treated with fluids administered by IV or IP routes.
Fifty-five male, Holstein calves, 1 to 16 days of age were used in this trial. Study calves were randomly assigned to treatment with a commercial electrolyte solution by the intravenous route (IV, N=27) or the intraperitoneal (IP, N=28) route of administration. Calves were weighed on day 28 posttreatment and monitored daily for 60 days after treatment. All study calves that died during this period were submitted for a complete post-mortem evaluation.
Weight increase at 28 days post-treatment was .9 kg greater in the IV group, and four more IV treated calves survived to 60 days post-treatment as compared to IP treated calves. Statistical analysis of weight gains and survival rate showed no difference between treatments. Gross and histopathologic changes to the peritoneum at necropsy were similar between IV and IP treated calves. Some differences in the primary cause of death were noted between groups.
In conclusion, this study showed no significant differences in weight gain to 28 days post-treatment, in survival to 60 days post-treatment, and in changes to the peritoneum in calves treated with fluids by either intravenous or intraperitoneal routes.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1994-09-22</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6294</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro19946294</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1994; 199-200</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/6294/6763</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1994 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
