<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/9342</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-04-28T17:39:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:DS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Nutritional approach to disease</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Schcolnik, Enrique</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Over the past 3 decades, dairy herd health has undergone a sig­nificant transformation. Initially, veterinarians focused on re­productive work, emergency care, and treating sick cows, with a high incidence of metabolic disorders like displaced aboma­sum. This highlighted the critical role of nutrition in disease ex­pression. In the early 2000s, advancements such as DCAD diets, the CNCPS dynamic model, NRC guidelines, forage testing labs, feed management software, and Ovsynch programs collectively improved clinical disease prevention and overall herd health.
Despite these advancements, the delivery of diets to cows re­mains inconsistent, emphasizing the need for a science-based approach to feeding processes to maintain rumen health and overall herd performance. The ruminal epithelium, acting as the first barrier against pathogens and toxins, is influenced by feeding behavior, microbial populations, and exposure to noxious substances. Maintaining rumen homeostasis through consistent substrate availability, buffering via bicarbonate ex­change, and saliva production is essential.
Critical control points in feeding include accurate diet delivery, continuous feed availability, feed free of contaminants, appro­priate feed particle size and homogeneity, and palatability. Uti­lizing feed management software and regular feed audits can improve diet delivery precision. Ensuring constant feed pres­ence along the bunk prevents erratic feeding and maintains ru­men substrate. Systematic checks of ingredient storage, equip­ment sanitation and feedbunk cleanliness are vital for feed hygiene and safety.
Veterinary professionals must be involved in developing sci­ence-based approaches to the feeding process to protect rumen health and improve overall herd performance. This collabora­tive effort with nutritionists and dairymen and women is essen­tial for the next leap in herd health and productivity.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9342</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20259342</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; Vol. 58 No. 2 (2025): 2025 AABP Annual Conference Proceedings; 76-79</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/9342/8957</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
