<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/5485</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-03-30T20:01:50Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:APC</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Programmed Dairy Practice</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Larson, Wallace R.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">We are about 60% dairy, 30% beef and the rest horses. I think that if there is one concept that I find in the herd health management, or herd health practice or whatever term you want to call it, is a positive entity. Fire engine, or a called practice, is a negative entity. I think clients respond to this program very quickly and if you think back about your relationship with the old boy who called and knew he was going to spend money, they are not too good; it is a very negative thing then! When you are on a positive aspect, attempting to prevent problems from happening, I think he respects this approach; I think that he has been geared to this like he has been geared to having his automobile service problems or he has been geared to defrosting his refrigerator! I think the general public is now geared for prevention of problems. We are geared to prevent these problems but that is neither here nor there. There is one other factor which to me is very, very important. These individuals are working on my clients.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>1972-12-13</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5485</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 1972; 7-8</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/5485/5340</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 1972 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
