<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3966</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-02-06T08:45:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:Post</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">An evaluation of the preventative and curative properties of 3 foot bath products used to control digital dermatitis</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cramer, G.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Lopez Benavides, M.</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">lameness</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">foot bath</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">digital dermatitis</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">animal welfare</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Lameness in the dairy industry has been identified as a disease with both detrimental economical and animal welfare implications. Digital dermatitis (DD) is a common cause oflameness in the dairy industry affecting 90% of free stall herds, and approximately 20% of cows within an affected herd. Common control strategies include the use foot baths with various chemical products including formalin, copper sulfate, antibiotics or commercially available products. Unfortunately, there is very little evidence in the literature supporting the use of these products. Evidence exists to support the use of formalin, copper sulfate, and antibiotics but few studies have been done to determine the efficacy of other commercially available products. The objective of this study was to evaluate the preventative and curative properties of two experimental products in comparison to formalin.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2012-09-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3966</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20123966</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; 2012; 258</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/3966/3894</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2012 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
