<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/8642</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-07-18T01:21:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>aabp:RS</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Association of THI and light intensity with colostrum production in 18 New York farms</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Womack, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Westhoff, T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mann, S.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The optimization of colostrum quantity in dairy cows is of great concern to the dairy industry due to the importance of transfer of passive immunity to the newborn calf. Previous research has explored various prepartum environmental variables associ足ated with colostrum production including season, temperature and humidity index (THI), and light intensity. Research shows that cows produce less colostrum during the fall and winter, leading to a decrease in farm-wide supply and greater need for careful colostrum management during colder months. In pre足vious work investigating this problem, researchers used local weather data to determine THI and light intensity, rather than measuring these parameters directly on the farm. The objec足tive of this study was to determine if prepartum THI and light intensity in the close-up barn are associated with observed an足nual changes in colostrum production.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-07-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8642</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier>10.21423/aabppro20228642</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">American Association of Bovine Practitioners  Conference Proceedings; No. 55 (2022): 2022 Annual Conference Proceedings; 168</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1079-9737</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://bovine-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/aabp/article/view/8642/8398</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2023 American Association of Bovine Practitioners</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
