<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/235</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-07-08T15:16:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Value Co-creation Experience and Service Performance in a Tourism Oriented Social Enterprise</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tseng, Yung-Ping</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The present study examined the Newhomeland Foundation (NF) which was focused on community reconstruction following the Jiji Earthquake. In recent years, the NF transitioned into a social enterprise by adopting the concepts of community education to transform a small village into an eco-destination focusing on butterflies, frogs, and fireflies. This research integrates the old marketing dominant logic and social enterprise for verification. Therefore, we analyzed the NF to test and validate the hypothetical “servicescape (SS)–co-creation experience (CE)–experiential value (EV)–service performance (SP)” model. A total of 181 NF volunteers were recruited as survey respondents. Partial-least-square structural equation modeling (PLS-SEM) was adopted. The findings of our study revealed that by participating in the activities arranged by the NF, the volunteers resonated with the ideologies of the foundation and acknowledged its persistence in preserving the land. Through the interaction with the NF, the volunteers also identified the value created by the social enterprise and the concepts it has endeavored to deliver.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-07-08</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/235</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 15 No. 4/5 (2018)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/235/69</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
