<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/428</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-12-30T18:54:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Motivations of agro-tourists in visiting agricultural fair: A case study of an agricultural fair in Chiang Mai, Thailand </dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Siri, Raktida </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Current research on special events often focuses on an urban area, and there is a lack of studies on special events in agriculture, especially those that concern tourist behavior in an agricultural context. This paper, therefore, studies the motivation of agricultural tourists (or agro-tourists). A self-administered survey was conducted with a total of 310 respondents. A factor analysis was utilized to recognize tourist motivation towards an agricultural fair. The majority of respondents was unmarried female, with an average age of 28 years old, and was a first-time visitor to the agricultural fair. The results showed three main motivations of the tourists to attend the agricultural fair; to find new experiences, participate in leisure activities, and maintain relationships. The study also found that statistically, there were significant differences in giving the importance to different motivations to visit agricultural fair across genders and tourist group types.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-30</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/428</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 18 No. 2 (2020); 269-289</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/428/225</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
