<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/885</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-08-28T18:10:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluating Demand Side Enablers for Medical Tourism: Case Study of Medical Tourists from Bangladesh to Kolkata, India</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Choudhury, Nabanita</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Majumdar, Sudipa</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ghosh, Ishita</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Globalization has brought about transformations in medical infrastructure, with foreign collaborations in ownership of healthcare. The resulting world-class medical services helped India to secure the 6th rank amongst 46 nations. Such demand-pull factors have attracted tourists from across the world to come to India to seek high-quality treatment at affordable costs. The trend has been particularly strong for Kolkata, a preferred healthcare destination for medical tourists from Bangladesh. However, this aspect has been largely ignored in the existing literature. The present research investigates demand-pull and demand-push factors based on the motivations and experiences of Bangladeshi medical tourists. Primary research was conducted through a purposive snowball sampling to interview 207 patients and 11 hospital staff from different Kolkata hospitals. Field observations, telephonic discussions, survey questionnaires, focus group discussions, and in-depth interviews were carried out at outpatient departments, reception desks of diagnostic centers, lodges, and guesthouses where families of international patients stayed for the tenure of their treatment. The key findings of this study provide important policy recommendations for stakeholders and lay down the pathway for future research for cross-border services trade.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-08-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/885</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 20 No. 1 (2023); 1-22</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/885/276</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
