<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/828</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-05-05T20:07:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:COM</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Industry Perspective: Vietnam Confronts Dual Forces in Tourism Development: Sustainable Initiatives Versus Megaproject Investments</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bowerman, Gary</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article assesses the challenges of creating and delivering small-scale sustainable tourism initiatives while private investors fund expansive tourism service megaprojects. These challenges are highlighted in Vietnam, where the government is eager to reinvigorate its travel industry after a two-year pandemic shutdown of international travel. The nation’s transport and tourism infrastructure deficit was evident before COVID-19. Domestic and international investment flows will be forthcoming as Vietnam strives to expand all three pillars of its travel sector: domestic, inbound and outbound. A proliferation of tourism megaprojects will raise tough questions about the compatibility of large-scale tourism sector growth with achieving vital greenhouse gas reduction targets and preserving Vietnam’s diverse natural environment.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-05-05</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/828</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 18 No. 6 (2021): Special Issue- Sustainable Tourism Development in Vietnam; 887-896</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/828/260</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
