<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/795</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-08-28T18:11:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">An Examination of The Effect of Iso-Ahola's Motivation Theory, Perceived Value, Destination Image, and Satisfaction on Tourists' Loyalty</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bui, Bao</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The current study aims to explain the interrelationship between the motivation and loyalty of domestic tourists by combining Iso-Ahola’s motivation theory with two additional variables, perceived value and destination image, as the new conceptual framework. The partial least squares structural equation modeling (PLS-SEM) approach has been a widely accepted method to evaluate and validate a complex model, combining Iso-Ahola’s motivation theory, perceived value, and destination image to predict domestic tourist loyalty. The data was collected from 554 domestic tourists who visit Dong Thap province. The study's findings revealed that Iso-Ahola's motivation and tourist satisfaction are core concepts for understanding tourist loyalty. In addition, tourist satisfaction had the strongest impact on tourist loyalty in this study. The current study took a unidimensional destination image and perceived value to understand domestic tourist loyalty. Future research should consider other constructs to understand tourist loyalty. The current study provided a new theoretical framework to evaluate and validate domestic tourist loyalty.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-08-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/795</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 20 No. 1 (2023); 51-79</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/795/278</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
