<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/436</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-08-20T12:01:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Investigating the Impact of Destination Image on Travellers’ Intention to Revisit South Africa: A Case of International Tourists</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chuchu, Tinashe</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chiliya, Norman</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Chinomona, Richard</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Destination image is widely accepted as an important aspect of successful tourism development and marketing of destinations. This research therefore seeks to investigate how experiences at a South African international airport influence travellers’ image of South Africa as a tourist destination and their willingness to revisit the country. The study adopted the positivist philosophy where it was quantitative nature. Participants were randomly selected through convenience sampling on-site at the airport. Findings of the study revealed that cognitive destination image, affective destination image and conative destination image all have a direct and positive influence on a tourist’s intention to revisit a destination. The main contribution of the study was that cognitive destination image (pre-conceived ideas about a destination) had the most influence on a traveller’s intention to revisit that destination. This implies that tourism organisations and airport management companies in South Africa have to focus more on marketing the country as a travel destination in the home countries of those travellers before they visit South Africa.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/436</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 16 No. 6 (2019)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/436/129</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
