<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/759</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-10-01T15:54:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The  effect of risks on tourists’ travel decision choices in Durban, South Africa</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Phoofolo, Taemane</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ndlovu, Joram</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Tourism is an important economic sector in many countries worldwide. Many governments are placing a higher priority on tourism development because it leads to increased foreign exchange income and creates employment opportunities. However, the tourism sector is prone to both natural and human-made crises and risks, which invariably affect the functionality, sustainability, and competitiveness of a destination. The purpose of this paper is to provide an empirical analysis of the tourists' perceptions of crises and risks affecting the tourism sector in Durban. The paper used a mixed-method through the use of surveys and direct interviews with a sample of local, regional, and international tourists and key informants in the tourism sector within Durban. The results show that the level of risks in the city is perceived to be high and was found to have a significant impact on destination decision- choices. First-time visitors might be discouraged by mediatised risks. However, repeat visitors were likely to visit Durban since they were more conversant with the local conditions. Domestic tourists were likely to visit the destination since they have various mechanisms at their disposal to deal with perceived risks than first-time visitors. Furthermore, the results indicated that tourists are resilient to negative media coverage of risks. The study concludes that several factors influence the image of a destination, so tourist visitation cannot be affected by crises and risks alone. The study recommends a multi-pronged strategy to mitigate the impact of crises and risks on the destinations.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-10-01</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/759</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 19 No. 1 (2022); 1-29</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/759/263</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
