<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/724</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-03-03T14:19:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the tourism industry in the Czech Republic</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roncak, Miroslav</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hobza, Vladimir</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The coronavirus pandemic had a devastating impact on the tourism industry worldwide. The present work analyses the evolution of the COVID-19 pandemic in the Czech Republic. This paper also discusses the stimulus packages offered by the Czech government and initiatives undertaken by Czech regions. The results indicate that despite intensive economic support and a large number of regional campaigns, the COVID-19 pandemic has had a profoundly negative effect on the tourism industry in the Czech Republic. The drop in tourism expenditure reached more than 50%, from 308 billion to 136 billion CZK. The number of foreign tourists arriving in the Czech Republic has fallen dramatically. In 2021, foreign tourism reached only 24% of the pre-pandemic numbers. Around 10% of businesses did not survive the COVID-19 crisis. Many employees moved to other sectors. Available analyses of the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on the Czech Republic suggest that it will take at least three years to recover from the decrease in performance.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/724</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 19 No. 2 (2022); 261-279</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/724/274</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
