<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/501</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-12-07T12:51:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Identifying the Marketing Channels that Will Attract Millennials to National Parks</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Douglas, Anneli</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mostert, Pierre</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Slabbert, Liandi</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Marketing channels</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Millennials</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">social media</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">South African National Parks.</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Millennials will soon become the biggest tourist group to be served because of their sheer numbers as well as their current and potential future income. At the same time, previous studies have shown a decline in national park visitation worldwide which necessitates an investigation into why these numbers are dwindling and how to attract different consumers to the Parks so that appropriate marketing and operational strategies can be drafted. The purpose of this paper was thus to identify the marketing channels that millennials are most likely to use, the types of information that they look for and the marketing methods that will inform and persuade them to visit a holiday destination, and more specifically a National Park. Six focus groups were held with millennials from different life stages, with findings showing that social media seems to be the most popular channel and marketing method to use. The research holds implications for destinations. Proactive participation in social media is needed and tourism marketers should consider how to incorporate millennials’ requirements into their general marketing plans and specifically their social media engagement.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-12-07</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/501</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 17 No. 2 (2019)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/501/143</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
