<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/814</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-03-08T13:12:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Perspectives of Key Stakeholders on Ecotourism Sustainability and Stakeholder Management: A Case Study of Penang Hill</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Salman, Ahmad</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Jafaar, Mastura</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Mohamad, Diana</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Penang Hill, one of Malaysia's most well-known natural and cultural tourist sites, is a popular destination for both domestic and foreign visitors. The study's objective was to explore the perspectives of key stakeholders regarding ecotourism sustainability and stakeholder management. In-depth semi-structured interviews were conducted with three key stakeholders, and content analysis was done to explore the key findings. It was observed that PHC engages stakeholders through meetings, workshops, and seminars and tries to understand their interests for better management. Keen interests of stakeholders were observed towards activities that generate monetary rewards. It was also noted that all stakeholders showed great interest in the environmental conservation of the destination. The study concludes by stating that even though Penang Hill management is on the right path and trying hard to achieve ecotourism sustainability, stakeholders still need more support from the management authority to work towards the destination's sustainability, especially in this Covid-19 pandemic. The findings have ramifications for stakeholder management to implement long-term ecotourism in the destination.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/814</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 19 No. 2 (2022); 159-193</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/814/270</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
