<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/829</identifier>
				<datestamp>2022-05-05T20:07:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ESP</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Emerging Scholar Profile-Dr. Huong T. Bui</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bui, Huong T. </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">&amp;nbsp;
Huong T. Bui is a professor at the College of Asia Pacific Studies, Ritsumeikan Asia Pacific University (APU), Japan. Being an anthropologist by training from Vietnam National University (VNU), she has developed her career in tourism with an MA and PhD in Tourism Management from Griffith University (Australia). Huong also earned an MBA degree from Waseda University (Japan). Huong’s professional career in tourism encompasses her expertise as a travel writer, consultant as well as instructor, and researcher. Before embarking on academia, Huong worked in the tourism industry and was a consultant for tourism development projects in Southeast Asia for the World Bank, Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) and the Netherlands Development Organization (SNV). She has been a contributor to major news agencies in Vietnam and Southeast Asia. Her writing and commentaries center on topics of tourism products, policies, and market analysis.
Over twenty years of an academic career in Vietnam, Australia, Europe, and Japan, Huong makes much effort to bridge the gap between practical requirements from the industry and the theoretical orientation of tertiary education. She was the founder of the Faculty of Management and in Vietnam used English as a medium of instruction. At Ritsumeikan Asia Pacific University (APU), she is actively involved in the establishment of the College of Sustainability and Tourism, a new initiative of the university bridging the global sustainability movement and the local tourism industry in the hot spring resort town of Beppu, Oita, Japan. In the role of an educator, she has received several awards recognizing her effort in curriculum development and teaching delivery.
Over a decade involved in tourism research Huong has been an active researcher with more than sixty papers and book chapters published in international peer-review journals and books by renowned publishers. In her editorial role, three volumes on tourism in Asia, namely: Tourism and Development in Southeast Asia (Routledge, 2020), Nature-based Tourism in Asia Mountain’s Protected Area (Springer, 2021, Springer), and Vietnam Tourism: Policies and Practices (CABI, 2022) are published. In these books, Huong served as a leader of the editorial team, a key editor working on theoretical reviews, and a contributor for special topics on ecotourism and heritage tourism. Introducing Social-Ecological Systems (SES) theory in tourism research, Huong adopts the viewpoint of human and nature dysnamic interaction in understanding a complex relationship between resource and resource users. She critically validates and revises the SES theory in various settings of living cultural heritage in Vietnam and post-disaster resource convergence in Japan. Her work was published in top-tier journals including Annals of Tourism Research and Journal of Sustainable Tourism as cited below:
Bui, H.T. &amp;amp; Saito, H. (2022). Post-disaster resource convergence. Annals of Tourism Research. doi.org/10.1016/j.annals.2022.103375
Bui, H.T., Jones, T., Weaver, D. &amp;amp; Le A. (2020). The adaptive resilience of living cultural heritage in a tourism destination. Journal of Sustainable Tourism 28(7), pp. 1022-1040. https://doi.org/10.1080/09669582.2020.1717503
Located in Japan, Huong is entitled to various research grant schemes from national agencies such as the Japan Society for Promotion of Sciences (JSPS). Her funded research area includes heritage tourism, educational dark tourism, and post-crisis recovery. Recently, the project title From Crisis to Resilience: The Social-Ecological Systems (SES) Approach to Tourism Recovery in East Asia was selected to fund by JSPS on a highly competitive basis. This project builds on her theoretical strengths and research networks connecting Japan and Southeast Asia. The grant from Japan Foundation for the United States – Southeast Asia and Japan Collaboration and Exchange Initiative (2017 – 2020), where she is a key member has recognized and supported Huong’s effort in promoting research exchange and capacity development for Southeast Asian educational institutions.
Besides her professional career, Huong has a passion for creative writing and is taking the pathway to become a travel writer. Also, being an amateur pianist and guitarist has enriched her life and career in tourism research and education.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-05-05</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/829</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 18 No. 6 (2021): Special Issue- Sustainable Tourism Development in Vietnam; 897-898</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/829/261</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
