<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/432</identifier>
				<datestamp>2020-11-18T16:59:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Tourists’ Perceptions of the Translation Quality of Indonesian Tourism Brochures</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Napu, Novriyanto</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ngiu, Rhafiq T.</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">An increasing number of foreign tourists who visit Indonesia, especially Gorontalo (an emerging regional destination), has increased tourist brochures' importance. Brochures are produced in multiple languages, and translation plays a crucial role in delivering the intent and purpose of the brochures to potential readers. The present study investigates the opinions of target readers regarding the text and content. Qualitative methods were used, and participants were asked to read tourism brochures and complete a survey with questions related to the content of the brochures, particularly the English translation. The findings reveal both positive and negative readers’ responses regarding the quality of the brochures. Regarding non-linguistic aspects, design and layout were most attractive to the readers. Regarding English translation, grammatical errors prevented tourists from understanding the brochures, thus undermining the text's function as promotional material.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-11-18</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/432</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 18 No. 1 (2020); 96-122</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/432/216</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2020 e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
