<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/860</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-08-28T18:11:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">An Overview of ‘All-For-One Tourism’ Development and Possible Future Research Directions for Ningxia’s Tourism using VUP (Visual Urban Perception)</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Ji, Guangyao</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Manan, Mohd Shahrudin Abd</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This study intends to explore using visual urban perception (VUP) to develop a place branding framework to promote Ningxia's tourism industry in the context of the "All-for-one tourism" policy. Based on the review of "All-for-one Tourism," "Visual Urban Perception," and "Place Branding for Tourism Development," this paper tries to provide a new perspective and potential direction of research for future studies about all-for-one tourism. This research used a literature review descriptive analysis method, searching the Scopus database with English as the language. Due to the limited research on the topic, only a few relevant publications were chosen for inclusion in this study. However, the selected papers still provided helpful insight into the current state of the research area. The results showed that more research currently needs to be done utilizing VUP to develop a place branding framework, an excellent method to promote the tourism industry. This study is original in this field and has theoretical and practical significance and value when combined with an all-for-one tourism policy. This study adds to the existing literature on all-for-one tourism, VUP, and place branding. Furthermore, the findings will also provide a new perspective and potential research direction for future studies.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-08-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/860</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 20 No. 1 (2023); 23-50</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/860/277</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
