<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/840</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-03-03T14:18:53Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Qualitative Study on E-Reviews of Mid-Segment Hotels</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tariyal, Amit</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Singh, Shalini</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bisht, Swati</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The main purpose of this study is to evaluate the e-reviews for the mid-segment hotels of Mussoorie and to explore the major themes addressed by the consumers in the e-reviews. The qualitative data in the form of user-generated e-reviews was acknowledged through TripAdvisor.com. The data was collected for the past six months, i.e., from December 2021 to June 2022. A total of 993 reviews have been analyzed using the content analysis technique and RQDA (R Qualitative Data Analysis) package of R software to explore positive and negative e-reviews and evolve the top discussed themes of the e-reviews. The results revealed the categorization of e-reviews into positive and negative categories and highlighted the major aspects of these e-reviews to be addressed. Frequencies of the top-used words in both positive and negative e-reviews have been evaluated. Top themes discussed in the e-reviews have also been identified to provide significant insights into the hotel industry. The study encapsulates e-reviews given by those tourists who particularly stayed in mid-segment hotels. The data was collected from one travel portal site Trip Advisor.com for a relatively short period. Further studies should include more data by incorporating the other hotel categories. The study reveals some significant insights for mid-segment hotel management at the hill station of Mussoorie to attract and improve the tourist inflow.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2022-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/840</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 19 No. 2 (2022); 214-236</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/840/272</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
