<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/546</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-12-20T19:08:39Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:LBR</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Sustainable strategies of restaurant food surplus platform as a framework for responsible tourism in the sharing economy</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Huang, Ching-Hsu</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Food surplus</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Food waste</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Responsible Tourism</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Food sharing economy</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Restaurant food surplus platform (RFSP)</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The main purpose of this two-phrases longitudinal study is to reduce the amount of food waste and food surplus in the restaurants in Taiwan.  In study one, the systematic literature reviews, in-depth interviews, focus group interviews and simple survey were conducted simultaneously to construct the food waste critical control point and the factors influencing food waste.  Based on the results of study one, this study will build the Restaurant food surplus platform to collect all the food waste information.  Data will be examined and identified the particular points of food waste in the restaurants.  The hierarchy of restaurant food waste and the food waste critical control point will be promoted all around the hospitality industry in Taiwan.  At the end, the implication for the sustainable foodservice model of the sharing economy will be suggested for all the members in the hospitality industry.  All of the major finding, implication, discussion, and recommendations will be provided for the government and restauranteurs in hospitality field.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-12-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/546</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 17 No. 4 (2020)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/546/183</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
