<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/721</identifier>
				<datestamp>2021-01-16T19:38:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">One-way Communication or Co-Creating Tourism Experience Already? Polish Perspective on the Use of ICT by DMOs</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Pawłowska-Legwand, Aneta</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Nowadays, ICT is used by Destination Management Organisations, not only to provide tourist information, but also to co-create tourism experiences. The main purpose of the paper is to discuss the approach of Polish Destination Management Organisations to co-creation of tourism experience with the use of ICT on the example of Małopolska Voivodeship, Poland. The approach of Destination Management Organisations to digital tourism marketing should be based on the awareness of both the potential of ICT-based tools and the context they operate in. ICT-related solutions implemented by Destination Management Organisations have to be matched to the ICT infrastructure that exists at the destination or region as well as to the needs of tourists who visit the area. The co-creation of tourism experience is beneficial both for Destination Management Organisations and tourists, but this approach should only be applied when both sides are ready to cooperate.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2020-12-31</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/721</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 18 No. 3 (2020): Special Issue: ERPBSS 2020- Sustainability, Mobility, and Opportunity; 342-362</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/721/229</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
