<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/796</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-08-28T18:11:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Dark Branding: A Proposed Conceptualization </dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Bintang Handayani</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Korstanje, Maximiliano E </dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This paper aims to incorporate dark branding into the dark marketing spectrum. The study's research question is: How do fake reviews in news media and the recency of non-existent hospitality establishment reviews influence the behavioural intentions of the viewer? The findings of a qualitative study on the place of interest, namely, a (non-existent) restaurant with fake reviews in news stories, were used as a background analysis. A purposive sampling technique and thematic analysis approach were adopted. Dark branding is conceptualised as a form of branding involving questionable ethical practices such as fake online reviews and forms a basis for consumer activism within the dark marketing spectrum. The approach of using emotional marketing, for example, selling mood/comfort instead of tangible products such as food, the novelty of service delivery, servicescape, and signature storytelling, are attributes of dark branding. Adopting an exploratory research method, this study is a first step towards defining the problem statement as a deceptive technique in information technology used by content creators to promote brands, and it is suggested that dark branding in tourism is a dimension of dark marketing.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-08-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/796</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 20 No. 1 (2023); 235-249</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/796/284</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
