<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/886</identifier>
				<datestamp>2023-08-28T18:10:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Positive Impacts of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Czech Hospitality Industry</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Roncak, Miroslav</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Scholz, Petr</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Linderová, Ivica</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Masilka, David</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Hobza, Vladimir</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Vrabcová, Pavla</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This article aims to examine the positive impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on accommodation and catering facilities in the Czech Republic. Data collection took place via the Czech Association of Hotels and Restaurants (AHR CR) between June 2020 and March 2021. A total of 422 questionnaires were completed. Almost three-quarters (72.7%) of the questionnaires were completed by accommodation facilities, 20.6% by catering facilities, and the rest by accommodation and catering facilities together. In this research, we used mathematical and statistical methods, Correspondence Analysis (CA), and the method of generalization. According to the research, almost one-third of the respondents (31.0%) did not identify any positive effects of the COVID-19 pandemic. On the other hand, this study confirmed that hospitality managers were more focused on reconsidering their lifestyle. The COVID-19 pandemic helped people to analyze and change their values. More than a tenth of the respondents (11.4%) said that they considered the positive benefits of the COVID-19 pandemic to be family support and that they had enough time to spend with their families.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2023-08-28</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/886</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 20 No. 1 (2023); 176-201</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/886/282</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
