<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/433</identifier>
				<datestamp>2019-08-20T12:01:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The analysis of customers’ e-complaints and service quality at spa services in Thailand</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Sangpikul, Aswin</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Many past studies have explored customers’ e-complaints in hospitality businesses such as hotels and restaurants. However, there has been a limited examination of these issues in wellness tourism, particularly in the spa business. This study aims to examine customers’       e-complaints at day spas in Thailand's major tourism cities and to analyze them in relation to service quality dimensions. Content analysis and descriptive statistics were employed to analyze the data collected from TripAdvisor. The findings indicate that major e-complaints are related to the poor skills of spa therapists, poor services, and non-recommendations for using spa services. Through the analysis of service quality dimensions, major e-complaints were found to be associated with reliability, assurance, and responsiveness. The study adds to the understanding of spa complaints and their constructs as well as providing new insights into their relationships with the service quality dimensions. Suggestions for spa businesses are provided in order to improve spa service quality.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2019-08-20</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/433</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; Vol. 16 No. 6 (2019)</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/433/126</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2019 e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
