<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/118</identifier>
				<datestamp>2018-02-05T09:12:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ertr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Information Communications Technology (ICT) and Tourism Experience: Can Serotonin become a measurement for tourism experience?</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tran, Xuan</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tran, Ha</dc:creator>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Tran, Tram</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">serotonin evaluation</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">power</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">affiliation</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The fact that tourist evaluations are different for the same service quality creates difficulties for tourism business in benchmarking their ranking standard. The present study examines the difference of tourists’ evaluations through the serotonin concept.  Serotonin (5-HT) is a neurotransmitter to play a key role in inhibiting aggression and regulating mood. Inhibiting aggression implies decreasing power motive and regulating mood implies increasing affiliation motive. The two study hypotheses are (1) an increase in serotonin would increase friendliness and (2) a decrease in serotonin would increase anger. Serotonin levels were scored by evaluation rate of 14340 hotel guests for two years (2015-2016) and Linguistic Inquiry Word Count was used to score affiliation and power motives. Findings indicate that a tourist with a high serotonin evaluation would possess affiliation resulting in overestimate service quality and a tourist with low serotonin evaluation would have a power resulting in underestimate service quality</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2018-02-05</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/118</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">e-Review of Tourism Research; 2018: ENTER 2018 Volume 9 Conference on Information and Communication Technologies in Tourism RESEARCH NOTES</dc:source>
	<dc:source>1941-5842</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ertr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ertr/article/view/118/25</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2018 e-Review of Tourism Research</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
