<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/3</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-01-17T23:12:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>tndr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">The Federal Writers Project Helps Fashion Twentieth Century Texas: Texas, A Guide to the Lone Star State, 1940</dc:title>
	<dc:title xml:lang="es">English: Texas, A Guide to the Lone Star State, 1940</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Matthews, Brenda</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Texas, A Guide to the Lone Star State (Texas) was one of forty-eight state guides published by the WPA Federal One Writers Project giving “assistance to educational, professional, and clerical persons; a nation-wide program for useful employment of artists, musicians, actors, entertainers, writers…and others in these cultural fields.”&amp;nbsp; In an analysis of Texas, there are four topics of exploration: Project One’s Washington guidelines, its researchers and writers, its description of the state’s cultural reality, and its role in the continuing creation of the state’s historical image. The fourth, its contribution to the refashioning of Texas semblance from the South and the “Lost Cause,” is the subject of this article. The state’s Progressive Party officials and business community had begun to reference the triumphant West in the 1920s as part of their boosterism. Seeking to portray Texas as a modern, optimistic state, embracing its conquest of the frontier, state leaders were eager for new investment and the growing population that came with it. Texas began shifting from the defeatism of the “Lost Cause” to creating western icons where vigorous “…cowboys gradually displaced defeated soldiers in gray.” The essays, images, and photographs in Texas revealed a jettisoning of an Old South ethos and a reinforcing of state leadership’s glorification of the Old West.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas New Deal Symposium</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-01-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/tndr/article/view/3</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Texas New Deal Review ; Vol. 1 No. 1 (2025): Texas New Deal Review; 1-12</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/tndr/article/view/3/3</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Texas New Deal Review </dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
