<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/2</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-01-17T23:12:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>tndr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">"Where Are the New Deal Historians of Texas? Revisited"</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Volanto, Keith</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This essay is a follow-up to an article I wrote twelve years ago which appeared in the East Texas Historical Journal entitled “Where Are the New Deal Historians of Texas?: A Literature Review of the New Deal Experience in Texas.”&amp;nbsp; In that article, I highlighted the books and articles covering various aspects of the New Deal in Texas that had been published up to that time, but also emphasized the relative dearth of scholarship then existing on such an important era in the state’s history.&amp;nbsp; In the four decades leading up to 2010, an average of six books and articles per decade were published on the New Deal in Texas—an appalling figure.&amp;nbsp; Since then, there has been heightened awareness among the scholarly community, as reflected in the existence of the annual Texas New Deal Symposium, the collection of Texas New Deal essays appearing in the edited volume Conflict and Cooperation: Reflections on the New Deal in Texas, the appearance of the online journal Texas New Deal Review, and finally, the significant increase in Texas New Deal scholarship (over forty essays, journal articles, and books) published over the past dozen years surveyed in this piece.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas New Deal Symposium</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-01-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/tndr/article/view/2</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Texas New Deal Review ; Vol. 1 No. 1 (2025): Texas New Deal Review; 13-20</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/tndr/article/view/2/4</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Texas New Deal Review </dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
