<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/10</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-24T14:54:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>tndr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">Texas Exceptionalism - the Texas Centennial and the New Deal</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Johnson, Helen</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">The Texas Centennial Celebration in 1936 became a watershed moment for Texans and Texas history. From beginning to end the celebration was a white elite male controlled endeavor, aided greatly by the state’s newspapers and their publishers. All this effort served to fix in the public’s mind, in a way not attempted or accomplished prior to this, an exceptionalist view of the state and the history they wanted told. “Texanizing” Texans became a prominent goal of Centennial’s organizers, along with educating youngsters in the state to an elitist, heroic Anglo narrative version of Texas history. With the three million dollars appropriated by Congress and additional grants, in kind aid, and appropriations from New Deal agencies, the federal government became a silent partner in the whole endeavor. The federal money funded hundreds of projects dedicated to the elite’s version of Texas history. Many of those buildings, monuments, markers still stand, including the cenotaph in San Antonio and the San Jacinto monument. They remain as powerful symbols of Texas exceptionalism.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas New Deal Symposium</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/tndr/article/view/10</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Texas New Deal Review ; Vol. 2 No. 1 (2026): Texas New Deal Review</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/tndr/article/view/10/7</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 Texas New Deal Review </dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
	
