<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/1</identifier>
				<datestamp>2025-01-17T23:12:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>tndr:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">English US With Stone, Canvas and Mortar:  : When Art and Architecture Went to Work for the New Deal in Texas</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Cummins, Light</dc:creator>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">PWA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">WPA</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">CCC</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">H.P. Drought</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">New Deal</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Fair Park</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">artists</dc:subject>
	<dc:subject xml:lang="en">architects</dc:subject>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">This essay deals with the work of artists and architects in Texas who engaged in projects funded by the New Deal. It concentrates on the built environment. In the over three quarters of a century since the inauguration of March, 1933, the resurrecting of New Deal programs to put people to work has from time to time been referenced in policy discussions as possible panaceas for economic problems that have faced the nation from the 1940s until to the present time. Can the New Deal be repeated? Should it be? One is reminded of a well-known comment by Harry Hopkins regarding the work of the W.P.A. During a press conference, a reporter once asked him: “Will your programs make a difference in the long run? Hopkins replied: “People do no eat in the long run.” That response does not belie the fact that many of W.P.A. programs in Texas and elsewhere have indeed stood the test of time in the long run. Whatever the future of public works holds, there will surely be as time passes more and more historians writing about the material culture and built environment of the New Deal in Texas. This will add to the growing understanding of the New Deal’s significant legacy in the state, including an increased appreciation for its art and architecture. The New Deal programs that sponsored these activities created a living legacy for us that daily reminds us of an earlier time when art and architecture went to work for the American people.
&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Texas New Deal Symposium</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2025-01-17</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:type xml:lang="en">Peer-reviewed Article</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/tndr/article/view/1</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Texas New Deal Review ; Vol. 1 No. 1 (2025): Texas New Deal Review; 21-32</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://tndr-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/tndr/article/view/1/2</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2025 Texas New Deal Review </dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
