<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
			<header>
				<identifier>oai:ch-ojs-tamu.tdl.org:article/6947</identifier>
				<datestamp>2026-06-27T16:26:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>ch:ART</setSpec>
			</header>
			<metadata>
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
	<dc:title xml:lang="en">A Comparative Curriculum Analysis of a Community Organization Citizenship Course and a Secondary School Civics Course</dc:title>
	<dc:creator xml:lang="en">Evans, Rebecca</dc:creator>
	<dc:description xml:lang="en">Community organizations have long offered alternative spaces for citizenship education for democracy. The author presents a comparative curriculum analysis of the air cadets’ citizenship course and the secondary school grade 10 civics course in Ontario, Canada, drawing on Alan Sears’ (2014) four domains of civic engagement framework. Findings are discussed across three main themes: developing thinking habits, citizenship in practice, and experiencing agency. While the community organization provided opportunities for authentic practice for young people to make change and act as agentic members of the local community, the development of thinking skills was notably absent from the air cadet citizenship curriculum. In contrast, the secondary school civics course focused on the development of thinking skills but placed less emphasis on practice and agency. The author argues for further inclusion of community organizations in education scholarship, given the prominent role these organizations play in educating young people for democratic citizenship.</dc:description>
	<dc:publisher xml:lang="en">Society for the Study of Curriculum History</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date>2026-06-27</dc:date>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/article</dc:type>
	<dc:type>info:eu-repo/semantics/publishedVersion</dc:type>
	<dc:format>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document</dc:format>
	<dc:identifier>https://ch-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ch/article/view/6947</dc:identifier>
	<dc:source xml:lang="en">Curriculum History; Vol. 2026 No. 1 (2026): Curriculum History 2026</dc:source>
	<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
	<dc:relation>https://ch-ojs-tamu.tdl.org/ch/article/view/6947/6109</dc:relation>
	<dc:rights xml:lang="en">Copyright (c) 2026 Curriculum History</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
			</metadata>
		</record>
		
